<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:00:19Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720h37b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis focuses on the significance of the cinematic medium for Elizabeth Bowen's novels, from the level of prose and formal representations to broader aspects of narrative and character. The chapters on To the North (1932) and The House in Paris (1935) examine complementary issues of motion and stillness and the consequent impact on subjective experiences of time, space, knowledge, and identity. The final chapter expands the issue of genre revision in The Heat of the Day (1949) to the greater problem of precedent and the reconstruction of identity through storytelling; the novel not only uses formal cinematic techniques by evoking the tone of film noir, but also reconfigures narrative and character tropes of the genre. Thus the advent of cinema not only opened up formal possibilities in the language of fiction but also expanded the types of worlds and effects an author could depict.</description><creator>Rangwala, Shama.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Bowen, Elizabeth, 1899-1973 -- Television adaptations.</subject><subject>Bowen, Elizabeth, 1899-1973 -- Film adaptations.</subject><title>Elizabeth Bowen and cinema</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm72j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720h37b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225f57b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Atherosclerosis is a complex disease which develops silently over decades and can lead to acute myocardial infarction or stroke, the main cause of death worldwide. Apoliporotein E (apo E) is a glycoprotein known for its major role in lipid metabolism and its pro-atherogenic effects. Swine make a unique and viable research model as it shares most of the anatomic and physiologic characteristics with humans, notably for the the cardiovascular system. In addition, it is the only animal species, other than nonhuman primates, that develops atherosclerosis spontaneously. In this study we examined the feasibility for creating an apo E-deficient pig model of atherosclerosis using RNA interference (RNAi) and somatic cell nuclear transfer (SCNT). The knockdown efficiency was tested in porcine granulosa cells. It varied from 45% to 82% compared to control cells, as revealed by real-time PCR analysis. Accordingly, short hairpin RNA-expressing vectors were constructed and used to transfect porcine fetal fibroblast cells. Cell lines with stable chromosomal integration were established and used to produce embryos by SCNT. Development of SCNT embryos to the blastocyst stage (33%) was comparable to non-transgenic embryos. The integration of the shRNA into the genome of GFP-expressing embryos was revealed by PCR and gel electrophoresis. These findings indicate that porcine embryos harboring shRNA-specific to apo E created by SCNT may lead to the production of apo E-deficient pigs. These pigs would be a promising new animal model for advancing atherosclerosis research.</description><creator>El-Beyrouthi, Nayla.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Apolipoprotein E.</subject><subject>Swine as laboratory animals.</subject><subject>Atherosclerosis -- Animal models.</subject><title>RNA interference and somatic cell nuclear transfer to generate an apolipoprotein E deficient pig : a new model of atherosclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk737.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225f57b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jc39d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work, we investigate effects of strong correlation to quantum transport from atomic first principles. In order to accomplish this task, we use a well established state-of-the-art formalism of quantum transport where density functional theory (DFT) is carried out within the Keldysh non-equilibrium Green's functions (NEGF). To deal with certain strong correlation phenomenon, we integrated an local density approximation plus Hubbard U (LDA+U) exchange-correlation potential into the existing NEGF-DFT formalism. The LDA+U potential correctly accounts for the electronic structure of correlated material. We will present the theory and numerical implementation associated with the NEGF-DFT-(LDA+U) in detail. Extensive tests on the well known correlated material FeO crystal have been carried out and results compared with previous literature as well as to experimental data. We then apply our NEGF-DFT-(LDA+U) technique to investigate transport physics of spin resolved tunnelling in Fe/MgO/Fe magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJ). We found that interfacial oxygen atoms are enough to localise the 3d electrons of infacial Fe atoms due to strong correlation. This surprising result substantially changes quantum transport properties of the MTJ, in particular it reduces magnetic resistance ratio by about 33%. This strongly correlated physics is absent if the conventional local spin density approximation (LSDA) is used in the NEGF-DFT analysis. Results of LSDA and LDA+ U exchange-correlation potential will be compared. Furthermore, through investigating contributions to scattering states by various atomic orbitals, we clearly identify the reason why LDA+U changes quantum transport in both quantitative and qualitative ways. Finally, we believe this strongly correlated physics should be general in other MTJs involving different oxides.</description><creator>Marcotte, Étienne.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Electron transport.</subject><subject>Quantum theory.</subject><subject>Green's functions.</subject><title>First principles theory for quantum transport : effects of strong correlation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445ch73c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jc39d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q5097</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this Master's project was to investigate the effects of a l2-week Pilates training program on neck-shoulder posture and motion, core strength and neck-shoulder kinematics and muscles activity associated with a shoulder flexion task performed under six different conditions. After the training, scapula anterior tilt and upper and lower thoracic extension were reduced and there was increased activity of the rectus abdominis, serratus anterior and rhomboid muscles during the shoulder flexion task; passive shoulder range of motion increased in flexion and internal rotation; static thoracic kyphosis was smaller and abdominal strength was greater. Theses results suggest that Pilates is effective in improving core strength, thoracic static and dynamic posture, and shoulder flexibility as well as in stabilizing core posture as limb movements are performed. Our results support the use of the Pilates method in the rehabilitation, and possibly in the prevention, of neck-shoulder disorders.</description><creator>Emery, Kim.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Neck.</subject><subject>Exercise.</subject><subject>Posture.</subject><subject>Shoulder.</subject><title>Effects of Pilates training on neck-shoulder posture and movement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763b342.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q5097</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rc44h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective: To investigate the association between functional foods and dental caries experience in Quebec children. Methodology: A cross-sectional analysis of the baseline wave of the QUALITY cohort was conducted and included a total of 195 children aged 8-10 years. Dietary information was collected by the use of 24--hour recalls. The adequate and inadequate intakes of specific nutrients were assessed in order to create a functional foods index. Dental caries experience was measured by DMF-S index and further categorized into presence and absence of caries. Data were collected on socio-demographic, oral health behaviour and anthropometric measures (height and weight). Data analysis involved logistic regression. Results: Girls eating functional foods were 89% less likely to have 1 decayed or filled tooth. [OR= 0.11 95% CI= (0.01-0.92)]. Conclusion: Functional foods had a protective effect against dental caries, specifically among girls in this sample of children.</description><creator>Hitimana, Hilina.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Dental Caries -- prevention &amp; control.</subject><subject>Health Food.</subject><title>The association between functional foods and dental caries experience /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pf117.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc44h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g606h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research was conducted to better understand the food insecurity (FI) experience among women in a small indigenous Canadian Arctic community. A descriptive, cross-sectional study was conducted in January-February 2006 with 54 women (20-40 years). Interviews were conducted on food insecurity, lifestyle, health, dietary self-efficacy and traditional food (TF) frequency; anthropometry data were also gathered. FI affected 55% of participating households in the community. Issues of food availability, quality and variety; lack of consumer skills; and lack of TF access were recognized as potential barriers to food security. Women from FI households were more likely to report an inability to access TF (p=0.0171). No associations were found between food security status and dietary self-efficacy or TF frequency of use. Current measures, programs and policies addressing FI need to consider unique barriers facing Indigenous Peoples living in northern Canada, including the barriers that affect access to TF resources.</description><creator>Goodman, Lauren Gabrielle, 1981-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Women -- Northwest Territories.</subject><subject>Food security -- Northwest Territories.</subject><subject>Gwich'in Indians -- Northwest Territories.</subject><subject>Diet -- Northwest Territories.</subject><title>Factors associated with food insecurity among women in a small indigenous Canadian Arctic community</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq177.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g606h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hk08j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Uveal Melanoma (UM) is the most common malignant intra-ocular tumor in adults. Forty-five percent of UM patients develop metastasis within fifteen years of the initial diagnosis. Cutaneous Melanoma (CM) is a highly metastatic cancer that accounts for the majority of skin cancer deaths. Current treatments are not especially effective for the metastatic phase of the disease. Therefore, the identification of new molecular targets that can be exploited in the clinic are needed. KISS1 is a putative human metastasis suppressor gene. The purpose of this study was to investigate the expression of KISS1 in melanoma and its potential value as a prognostic marker. From results in vitro and in vivo we were able to characterize KISS1 in UM for the first time as well as its expression at the protein level, in CM. The correlation between KISS1 expression and UM survival rate suggests an important role for KISS1 as a prognostic marker in this tumor.</description><creator>Martins, Claudia Maria de Oliveira, 1961-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Uveal Neoplasms -- genetics.</subject><subject>Tumor Suppressor Proteins -- physiology.</subject><subject>Melanoma -- genetics.</subject><subject>Skin Neoplasms -- genetics.</subject><subject>Gene Expression Regulation, Neoplastic.</subject><title>Expression of the metastasis suppressor gene KISS1 in uveal and cutaneous melanoma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nj23s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk08j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268878n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>BACKGROUND: Pain intensity, functional status and beliefs and attitudes towards pain are dynamic elements involved in the experience of chronic pain. Lidocaine infusion (LI) is a therapeutic intervention used to relieve pain. OBJECTIVES: The primary objective of this study was to determine if people with chronic pain who received LI and reported a decrease in pain intensity at 4 days post-infusion differed from those who did not report a decrease in pain intensity with respect to the following: a) baseline beliefs and attitudes towards pain; b) changes in belief and attitudes towards pain; c) and changes in functional status. This study also investigated if these differences were associated with being a novel or repeat LI user. A secondary objective was to estimate the sample size required for a larger study. METHODS: This project was an exploratory study. Thirty-three subjects were monitored for pain intensity using the Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) just before the infusion, and then at four days, two weeks, and three weeks after the infusion. The subjects were separated into groups depending on the criteria of whether or not they had: a) criterion-based pain intensity decrease or not on the fourth day post infusion, and b) received a previous LI or not. Since no subjects who received their first LI reported pain intensity decrease four days later, three groups emerged from this classification: first time LI users with no pain decrease, repeat LI users with no pain decrease, and repeat LI users with pain decrease. The subjects completed two self-administered questionnaires the Survey of Pain Attitudes (SOPA-32) and the Short Musculoskeletal Function Assessment (SMFA) - before the infusion, and at two and three weeks post-infusion. The most important change at two or three weeks post-infusion was used for comparison purposes. RESULTS: No significant changes in function (SMFA) were found. However, changes in specific beliefs and attitudes towards pain (SOPA-32) were associated with the group variable as follows: 1) All three groups showed a significantly stronger belief that 'others, especially family members, should be solicitous in response to their experience of pain' after the infusion. 2) Those who received their first LI and did not report pain intensity decrease also showed a significantly stronger belief that 'medications are an appropriate treatment for chronic pain' after the infusion. 3) Subjects who had previous LI and did not report pain intensity decrease were the only ones to believe significantly less that 'medications are an appropriate treatment for chronic pain' and more 'in a medical cure for their pain problem' after the infusion. 4) Subjects who had previous LI and did report pain intensity decrease had a significantly stronger belief in the appropriateness of medications and that 'that they should avoid exercise' after the infusion. 5) Finally, subjects who believed more that 'medications are an appropriate treatment for chronic pain' and less 'that they should avoid exercise' at baseline, had significantly higher chances of experiencing decrease in pain intensity 4 days after a LI. CONCLUSION: The impact of a LI on the individuals' beliefs and attitudes towards pain differs depending if their pain intensity decreased or not four days after the infusion, and if they had previous LI or not. By contrast, their pre-infusion beliefs and attitudes profile impacts on the efficacy of this intervention. Because of the small sample size, the heterogeneity of the subjects in terms of the localization of their pain, and our choice of measurement tool, it is not possible to determine if LI impacts on function. Nevertheless, this exploratory study generated some novel observations and questions that are of great interest for future research. A particular question of interest would be to determine if repeated LI fosters a more passive attitude towards pain management. It was also determined that a sample size of 70 subjects per group would be necessary for future research on this question. Keywords: Chronic pain, lidocaine, beliefs and attitudes towards pain, function, pain intensity.</description><creator>Masse, Julie.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Chronic Disease -- psychology.</subject><subject>Lidocaine -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Pain -- prevention &amp; control.</subject><subject>Pain -- psychology.</subject><title>Associations between pain intensity, functional status, and beliefs and attitudes towards pain in people with chronic pain, after a lidocaine infusion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k15p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268878n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj242</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Decorin, is an extracellular matrix proteoglycan with important biological functions. Decorin deficiency affects collagen fibrillogenesis, airway mechanics, airway-parenchymal interdependence, and airway smooth muscle proliferation and apoptosis. We questioned whether decorin deficiency would alter allergen-induced asthma in a mouse model. Decorin-/- and decorin+/+ mice (C57Bl/6) were sensitized and challenged with ovalbumin. Control animals received saline. Responsiveness was assessed at baseline and after delivery of increasing concentrations of methacholine. Histological analyses were also performed. Decorin deficiency resulted in more modest hyperresponsiveness. Respiratory resistance and elastance along with tissue damping and tissue elastance, were increased in ovalbumin decorin +/+ and decorin-/-, but more so in decorin+/+ . Airway resistance was increased in ovalbumin decorin+/+ only. Inflammation and collagen staining within the airway wall, were increased in ovalbumin decorin+/+ mice only; whereas biglycan was significantly increased in ovalbumin decorin-/- mice only. These results reflect the role of decorin in the development of allergen-induced asthma.</description><creator>Marchica, Cinzia Loreta, 1984-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Airway Resistance -- physiology.</subject><subject>Asthma -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Proteoglycans -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Allergens -- adverse effects.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred C57BL.</subject><subject>Extracellular Matrix Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Respiratory System -- physiopathology.</subject><title>Allergen-induced asthma is decreased in decorin-deficient mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752m384.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj242</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1072595</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Detection of B-mode polarization from the cosmic microwave background would provide compelling evidence for the inflationary paradigm and has thus become a principal goal for experimental cosmologists during the last 5-10 years. A number of high sensitivity experiments have been developed and many are under construction, including the E and B EXperiment (EBEX), a balloon-borne experiment scheduled to take data in 2010. The design of EBEX is presented here, including the scientific motivation for the experiment, and an overview of all its components, with particular attention paid to the read out electronics for its array of over 1300 biometries detectors. In the read out of such a large array of bolometers, which must be kept at ~250mK, running many signals down the same wire (i.e. multiplexing) is vital. The digital frequency multiplexing (dfmux) electronics designed and tested at McGill addresses this as well as providing the control required to tune the bolometers and super conducting quantum interference devices (SQUIDs) used in readout. How these electronics accomplish both of these goals is described with an in-depth description of the recently designed tuning algorithms required to take the detectors from initialization to fully-operational. Finally, some tests of the readout system on cold bolometers in a test cryostat are presented. These measurements are encouraging with 98% success rate of automated tuning on a test sample of 47 bolometers. Improvements to achieve a 100% success rate have been proposed and will be implemented for the upcoming integration of the bolometer camera with the telescope in November 2008. A test-flight for the experiment is planned for spring 2009, and the science flight for 2010 from Antarctica.</description><creator>MacDermid, Kevin.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Cosmic background radiation.</subject><subject>Bolometer.</subject><title>Design and testing of tuning algorithms for the E and B EXperiment (EBEX)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xn084.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1072595</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w523</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tissue factor (TF) is a cell-associated receptor for coagulation factor VIIa (FVIIa) that initiates the coagulation cascade and transmits intracellular signals through protease activated receptors (PARs). This thesis documents for the first time that in human glioma cells (U373) oncogenic epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFRvIII) simultaneously upregulates the expression of several elements of the TF pathway (TF, FVIIa, PAR-1 and PAR-2). In the absence of EGFRvIII, TF triggers tumor formation, albeit with a long latency, while treatment of glioma cells with FVIIa activates MAPK phosphorylation and stimulates the expression of angiogenic factors (VEGF and IL-8). Moreover, selective targeting of the host (mouse) TF reveals its independent role in glioma tumorigenesis. We propose that TF may represent an attractive potential target to treat human brain tumors.</description><creator>Magnus, Nathalie.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Glioblastoma -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Thromboplastin -- analysis.</subject><subject>Receptor, Epidermal Growth Factor -- metabolism.</subject><title>The role of tissue factor in the progression and angiogenesis of malignant glioma /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dz74z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w523</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763b35b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the design, fabrication, and testing of a micromixing device intended for use in investigating protein dynamics on a microsecond timescale by Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy. Numerical modeling of flow was implemented to predict the influence of flow rates and geometric variations on mixing performance in three passive mixers. The simulation models were validated by experimental measurements using optical and infrared detection. The optimum level of mixing was observed in a multi-lamination mixer that combined thin filaments of differing fluids in an alternating manner. The multi-laminates were transferred onto polished calcium fluoride infrared-transparent optical windows by lithographic processing of an Epon-based polymer, SU-8. A rigid seal between two microchannels was accomplished through thermal bonding of an unexposed resist layer, which acted as a thermal epoxy under the influence of temperature. The multi-lamination mixer was used to study the changes in the secondary structure of beta-Lactoglobulin in deuterated phosphate buffer under varying physicochemical conditions by time-resolved FTIR spectroscopy using focal plane array detection. Upon a pH jump from pH 2 to neutral pH, a gradual loss of alpha-helical content, accompanied by an increase in random coils and turns was observed within 2 ms of mixing. In a second kinetic experiment, mixing of a neutral-pH solution of beta-Lactoglobulin with a 60% trifluoroethanol solution resulted in the formation of an alpha-helical intermediate with an accompanying increase in intramolecular beta-sheet structure within 500 mus of mixing. These results indicate that the multi-lamination mixer designed and fabricated in this study is well suited for investigations of protein dynamics on the micro- to millisecond timescale by time-resolved FTIR spectroscopy.</description><creator>Haq, Moeed.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Focal planes.</subject><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Protein folding.</subject><subject>Infrared imaging.</subject><subject>Microfluidic devices -- Design and construction.</subject><title>Design and fabrication of a continuous flow mixer for investigating protein folding kinetics using focal plane array Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cp444.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763b35b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:736668181</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The physicochemical parameters of fifteen honey samples from a wide range of botanical origins were characterized to identify the influence of composition on the formation of alpha-dicarbonyl compounds during heating. Color, pH, moisture content, water activity, hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF), sugar and amino acid content were determined before and after storage at various time and temperatures. The effects of storage time and temperature on the formation of Maillard reaction product were also investigated. Analysis of the data has indicated that they have a significant impact on the rate of production of Maillard related compounds such as alpha-dicarbonyls and HMF. The content of free amino acids was also decreased 'over time with concomitant increase in color intensity. Furthermore, nine alpha-dicarbonyl compounds were detected in honey samples. The analysis of these compounds after derivatization with o-diaminobenzene resulted in the identification of three previously unreported derivatives in honey such as 3-deoxypentulose, 1,4-dideoxyhexulose and 3,4dideoxyglucosone-3-ene. More importantly, the detection of 5-hydroxycyclohexane-1,2,4-trione was to our knowledge the first cyclic alpha-dicarbonyl compound ever reported in literature. Characterization of this molecule by different mass spectrometric techniques and spiking experiments provided evidence that supported the precursor, the structure and proposed mechanism of formation.</description><creator>Marceau, Eric.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Honey -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Maillard reaction.</subject><title>Chemical characterization of honey and identification of novel [alpha]-dicarbonyl compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk684.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736668181</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cf40p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: The causes of childhood brain tumors (CBT) are essentially unknown. Exposure to extremely low frequency magnetic fields (ELF-MF) (3-3000Hz) is an ubiquitous part of modern life. However, very few studies have investigated the possible effect of maternal occupational ELF-MF exposure on CBT and the available findings are inconsistent across studies. Methods: We examined the role of maternal occupational exposure to ELF-MF shortly before and during pregnancy on the incidence of childhood brain tumors. A total of 548 incident cases and 760 healthy controls recruited between 1980 and 2002 from two Canadian provinces (Quebec and Ontario) were included and their mothers were interviewed. Tumors were classified as astroglial tumors, primitive neuroectodermal tumors (PNET), and other gliomas. Quantitative occupational ELF-MF exposure in microtesla units was estimated using individual exposure estimations or a job exposure matrix. We used three metrics to analyze exposure: cumulative, average, and maximum level attained. Results: Using the average exposure metric measured before conception, an increased risk was observed for astroglial tumors (OR=1.5, and 95% CI=1.0-2.4). During the entire pregnancy period, a significantly increased risk was observed for astroglial tumors as well as for all childhood brain tumors with the average metric (OR=1.6, 95% CI=1.1-2.5 and OR=1.5; 95% CI=1.1-2.2, respectively). Based on job titles, a two-fold risk increase was observed for astroglial tumors (OR=2.3, 95% CI=0.8-6.3) and for all childhood brain tumors (OR=2.3, 95% CI=1.0-5.4) among sewing machine operators. Conclusion: Results are suggestive of a possible association between maternal occupational ELF-MF exposure and certain brain tumors in their offspring. Keywords: brain tumors, occupational exposures, maternal exposures, magnetic fields, childhood cancer, job exposure matrix. We used three metrics to analyze exposure: cumulative,
average, and maximum level attained. Results: Using the average exposure metric measured before conception, an increased
risk was observed for astroglial tumors (OR=I.5, and 95%CI=1.0-2.4). During the
entire pregnancy period, a significantly increased risk was observed for astroglial
tumors as well as for all childhood brain tumors with the average metric (OR=I.6,
95% CI=I. 1-2.5 and OR=1.5; 95%CI=1. 1-2.2, respectively). Based on job titles, a
two-fold risk increase was observed for astroglial tumors (OR=2.3, 95% CI=0.8-6.3) and for all childhood brain tumors (OR=2.3, 95% Cl=I.0-5.4) among sewing machine
operators.
Conclusion: Results are suggestive of a possible association between maternal
occupational ELF-MF exposure and certain brain tumors in their offspring.
</description><creator>Li, Pei Zhi.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Maternal Exposure.</subject><subject>Brain Neoplasms -- epidemiology.</subject><subject>Canada -- epidemiology.</subject><subject>Prenatal Exposure Delayed Effects.</subject><subject>Electromagnetic Fields -- adverse effects.</subject><subject>Occupational Exposure -- adverse effects.</subject><title>Maternal occupational exposure to extremely low frequency magnetic fields and risk of brain tumors in offspring</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rs35n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf40p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784q04t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interferon regulatory factor-8 (Irf-8), a hematopoietic transcriptional regulator, controls myeloid-cell proliferation and coordinates innate and adaptive host immune responses. Mice from the BXH-2 recombinant inbred strain carry an endogenous R294C mutation in Irf-8. This loss-of-function mutation induces clonal infiltration of undifferentiated Mac-1+/Gr-1 + granulocytic precursors in BXH-2 mice, extramedullary hematopoiesis, and splenomegaly similar to those seen in human chronic myeloid leukemia. It also renders the host permissible to the otherwise avirulent Mycobacterium bovis (BCG), and negatively affects survival or recovery of these mice to other infectious pathogens. Here, we generated a polyc1onal anti-Irf-8 antibody to better characterize the effects of the R294C mutation on Irf-8 protein expression, stability, and inducibility in hematopoietic and non-hematopoietic tissues. We found that mutant Irf-8C294-expressing tissues consistently displayed reduced Irf-8 abundance compared to their wild-type counterparts in both primary splenocytes and following transfection into heterologous cells, presumably due to decreased stability or increased rate of degradation of the mutant isoform. Results also indicate that native Irf-8 is also expressed in the heart, and to a lesser extent, in the kidneys. Since neither of these organs is well-known to be associated with hematopoietic or immune functions, this finding strengthens the possibility that Irf-8 may exert additional regulatory functions in other cellular contexts. Taken together, our study provides a better understanding about the molecular features of the mutant Irf-8 C294 protein and contributes to a growing body of evidence in support of Irf-8 expression in non-hematopoietic tissues.</description><creator>Liu, Dien.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Mice, Inbred Strains.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Mycobacterium tuberculosis -- immunology.</subject><subject>Mycobacterium bovis -- immunology.</subject><subject>Interferon Regulatory Factors -- genetics.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred C57BL.</subject><title>Effects of R294C mutation on expression and stability of interferon regulatory factor-8 in BXH-2 mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q530.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784q04t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p3826</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: As a part of the Gene Regulators in Disease project (GRID), this study aims to create a novel high throughput method to discover the genetic effect on gene translation, taking advantage of the rationale that efficiently translated mRNAs associate with multiple ribosomes, while less active ones with fewer or none. Methods: Lymphoblastoid cell lines (LCLs) from 44 HapMap European individuals were used for polyribosomal fractionation and establishing the sample bank for the future study. The fractionated mRNA samples of 10 out of the 44 individuals were run on an Illumina GoldenGate Beadarray to detect allelic imbalance (developed by the group of T.J. Hudson and T.M. Pastinen). Results: This study established a high-quality RNA bank, including 1,100 RNA fraction samples. By the Illumina chip, translational imbalance was detected in 75 out of 1483 (5.06%) assays, and 63 out of269 (23.4%) genes. The translational effect was well replicable by the resequencing method. Conclusion: This study found that genetic effect on gene translation is a common mechanism of expression regulation. Our best hit found in the integrin beta 1 binding protein 1 gene (ITGB1BP1 ) highlights the role of mRNA 3'UTR secondary structure in gene translation. </description><creator>Lu, Yang, 1972-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Genome, Human -- genetics.</subject><subject>Sequence Analysis, DNA -- methods.</subject><subject>Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide -- genetics.</subject><title>High throughput study of the translational effect of human single nucleotide polymorphisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds95j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p3826</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644w173</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A bioactive paper is a paper that can detect, capture and deactivate water and airborne pathogens. In this project, we presented a model "bioactive paper" made by attaching T4 bacteriophages to a cellulose substrate. T4 bacteriophages can be genetically engineered to possess copies of cellulose-binding modules (CBM) on their capsids. This allows them to bind specifically onto cellulose surfaces. Our model surface is a thin film of regenerated cellulose made by spin coating a glass or quartz substrate with a cellulose triacetate and subsequently hydrolyzing the surface back to cellulose. We successfully demonstrated the attachment of the CBM-T4 bacteriophages onto cellulose substrates by the phage viability test. The deposition kinetics were measured using an impinging jet apparatus combined with an evanescent wave light scattering (EWLS) system. We first tested the apparatus by using amidine latex particles deposited on the cellulose at different flow rates and found them to be in a good agreement with the constant potential double-layer model. The adhesion experiments were also performed in an impinging jet apparatus in which the CBM-T4 bacteriophages and the unassembled protein complexes from a suspension of 4.08 x 10 8 PFU/mL were allowed to diffuse to the cellulose surface, The competitive diffusion kinetics were again studied by the EWLS technique. For CBM-T4, the blocking time was found to be around 58 minutes and the maximum surface number density of phages was 5.9 x 1010 per m 2. Key phrases: bioactive paper, cellulose film, cellulose binding module, bacteriophage T4, evanescent wave light scattering, unassembled protein complex, diffusion kinetics were again studied by the EWLS technique. For
CBM-T4, the blocking time was found to be around 58 minutes and the maximum
surface number density of phages was 5.9 ? IO10 per m2.
</description><creator>Li, Zhuo, 1982-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Biosensors -- Design and construction.</subject><subject>Escherichia coli.</subject><subject>Cellulose.</subject><subject>Organic thin films.</subject><subject>Bacteriophage T4.</subject><title>Deposition of model viruses on cellulose</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x4738.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w173</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hw160</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neutrophils (polymorphonuclear leukocytes) are short lived granulocytes that playa primordial role in host innate defense against invading pathogens. Freshly isolated neutrophils spontaneously undergo apoptosis when cultured, which is associated with oxidative stress. We found that there is a dramatic shift in the metabolism of the 5-lipoxygenase product 5-hydroxy-6,8,11,14-eicosatetraenoic acid (5-HETE) from its biologically inactive o-oxidation product in freshly isolated neutrophils to the potent granulocyte chemoattractant 5-oxo-6,8,11,14-eicosatetraenoic acid (5-oxo-ETE) in neutrophils cultured for 24 h. o-oxidation of the chemoattractant leukotriene B4 (LTB4) was also reduced in aging neutrophils incubated with arachidonic acid, resulting in higher levels of LTB4. The reduced o-oxidation activity appeared to be due to a decrease in active LTB4 20-hydroxylase. In contrast, the increased 5-oxo-ETE formation was not associated with an increase in the amount of active 5-hydroxyeicosanoid dehydrogenase, which is required for its formation, but rather with a dramatic increase in its cofactor NADP +. NAD+ levels also increased, but NADPH levels remained unchanged after 24 h. There was also evidence for increased oxidative stress (high GSSG/GSH) in aging neutrophils. The changes in 5-HETE metabolism and pyridine nucleotides in cultured neutrophils could be inhibited by neutrophil survival factors and antioxidants. These results suggest that in severe inflammation, aging neutrophils that have evaded rapid uptake by macrophages may produce increased amounts of the chemoattractants 5-oxo-ETE and LTB4, resulting in delayed resolution of inflammation. Similarly, we found that the NADPH oxidase activator PMA caused a very rapid and dramatic increase in NADP + levels in both freshly isolated and cultured neutrophils, accompanied by a rapid increase in 5-oxo-ETE synthesis and reduced o-oxidation activity. Surprisingly, this was not accompanied by a corresponding decline in NADPH levels, which instead initially increased, but rather by a precipitous reduction in NAD+, which mirrored the increase in NADP+. These results suggest that the phosphorylation of NAD+ by NAD kinase may be very important for providing both NADP+ for 5-oxo-ETE synthesis and NADPH for the respiratory burst.</description><creator>Graham, François.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Arachidonic Acids -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Hydroxyeicosatetraenoic Acids -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Pyridines -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Neutrophils -- physiology.</subject><subject>Chemotactic Factors -- metabolism.</subject><title>Regulation of 5-oxo-ETE synthesis by pyridine nucleotides in aging neutrophils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs288.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw160</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b2164</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Learned taste avoidance (LTA) was studied by allowing rats to drink a novel sweet solution followed by induction of gastric malaise (training). When the solution was presented again (test), normal rats reduced their consumption. Ultrasonic vocalizations indicated that the rats experienced positive affect during training which shifted to negative affect during the test. Basolateral amygdala lesions eliminated the LTA and the negative affective shift when the rats were 23 hr water deprived during both training and test suggesting amygdala-based Pavlovian conditioning, but only attenuated the LTA and eliminated the aversive shift when the rats were 3 hr deprived on the test, suggesting instrumental learning. When rats were 3 h deprived during training the lesions had no effect on either the LTA or the negative affective shift, suggesting an amygdala-independent form of LTA based on latent learning.</description><creator>Hamdani, Selma.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Avoidance (Psychology)</subject><subject>Taste.</subject><subject>Amygdaloid body.</subject><title>Effect of basolateral amygdala lesions on learning taste avoidance under various water deprivation schedules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483n673.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b2164</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k5923</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Purpose: Exercise testing modalities to assess the effects of a given intervention should prove to be reliable and reproducible. This study reports on test-retest reproducibility of the 3-min shuttle walking and step testing exercise protocols to assess exertional dyspnea and exercise physiology in COPD patients. Methods: Stable COPD patients (N=43; 65 +/- 6.5 years; FEV1 = 49 +/- 16% pred.) equipped with a portable Jaeger Oxycon MobileRTM metabolic system repeated the walking or stepping tests on two occasions separated by 7 to 14 days. At each visit, participants performed, in a randomized order, four externally paced 3-min bouts of shuttle walking at speeds of 1.5, 2.5, 4.0 and 6.0 km·h-1 or of stepping at a constant rate of 18, 22, 26 and 32 steps·min-1, respectively. Each exercise bout was separated by a 10-min rest period. Ventilation, heart rate, gas exchange parameters and Borg dyspnea score were obtained for each bout during the last 30-seconds of exercise. Results: The majority of patients completed stepping or walking at the slowest cadence but only 33% completed walking at 6.0 km·h -1 and 40% completed stepping at 32 steps·min-1. Test-retest Pearson correlation coefficients for ventilation, heart rate, gas exchange parameters and dyspnea scores over the four exercise bouts, all exceeded 0.80 with the highest coefficient found for ventilation (r≥.95). Intra-class correlation coefficients were similar to Pearson. Bland &amp; Altman representation showed that a similar proportion of dyspnea data points (92 vs. 96%) lied within 2 SD of the mean difference between test-retest values for dyspnea Borg scores during walking and stepping. Conclusion: Results show very good reproducibility for both 3-min shuttle walking and stepping exercise protocols in patients with COPD. This study was supported by an unrestricted grant from Boehringer-Ingelheim/Pfizer.</description><creator>Henophy, Sara Catherine, 1983-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Lungs -- Diseases, Obstructive.</subject><subject>Dyspnea -- Testing.</subject><title>Test-re-test reproducibility of constant rate step and shuttle walking tests for the assessment of exertional dyspnea in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mg39x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k5923</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xd17r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) is the causing agent of the acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS). Like all retroviruses, HIV carries two copies of viral genomic RNA in each virion. HIV genome encodes three structural genes, including gag, pol and env, as well as two regulatory genes (rev and tat) and four accessory genes (vif, vpr, vpu and nef). It is noted that none of these nine viral proteins bears the helicase activity. Helicases are able to unwind RNA duplex and remodel the structure of RNA-protein (RNP) complexes using energy derived from hydrolysis of nucleotide triphosphates (NTPs). They are involved in every step of cellular RNA metabolisms. It is conceivable that HIV needs to exploit cellular RNA helicases to promote the replication of its RNA at various steps such as transcription, folding and transport. In this study, we found that a DEAD-box protein named DDX24 associates with HIV-1 Gag in an RNA-dependent manner but is not found within virus particles. Knockdown of DDX24 inhibits the packaging of HIV-1 RNA and thus diminishes viral infectivity. The decreased viral RNA packaging as a result of DDX24-knockdown is observed only in the context of the Rev/RRE (Rev response element)-dependent but not the CTE (constitutive transport element)-mediated nuclear export of viral RNA, which is explained by the specific interaction of DDX24 with the Rev protein. We propose that DDX24 acts at the early phase of HIV-1 RNA metabolism prior to nuclear export and the consequence of this action extends to the viral RNA packaging stage during virus assembly.</description><creator>Ma, Jing, 1978-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>RNA, Viral -- metabolism.</subject><subject>DEAD-box RNA Helicases -- metabolism.</subject><subject>HIV-1 -- physiology.</subject><subject>Virus Assembly -- physiology.</subject><title>The requirement of the DEAD-box protein DDX24 for the packaging of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 RNA /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mb37v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xd17r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d3477</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Development of specific DNA methylation patterns is required for normal spermatogenesis. DNA methyltransferases (DNMTs) use S-adenosylmethionine (SAM) produced in a pathway requiring 5,10-methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR). This thesis describes: testicular phenotype differences derived from Mthfr-deficiency in different mouse strains; the cellular Mthfr expression pattern during male germ cell development; and finally, changes to the DNA methylation of Mthfr-deficient sperm. Mthfr-deficient BALB/c, but not C57BL/6, mice have reduced neonatal germ cell proliferation but both have abnormal germ cells as adults. Germ cell MTHFR expression differed developmentally in parallel with DNMTs associated with de novo methylation. Sperm from mice with reduced Mthfr levels or dietary folate deficiency had differential DNA methylation at multiple loci, compared to wildtype mice, indicating that maintenance as well as acquisition of methylation can be altered by SAM-reduction. These results highlight the important role of folate in sperm development throughout life.</description><creator>Cushnie, Duncan Wells.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate Reductase (NADPH2) -- deficiency.</subject><subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate Reductase (NADPH2) -- genetics.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred C57BL.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred BALB C.</subject><subject>Spermatogenesis -- genetics.</subject><title>On the expression and deficiency of 5,10-methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase in murine sperm development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xw44m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d3477</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sx36s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of Indian hedgehog (Ihh) signalling in the regulation of endochondral bone formation is well established. Ihh controls the rate of bone growth by negatively regulating differentiation and positively regulating growth plate chondrocyte proliferation. It has been well documented also that mutations resulting in constitutive activation of signalling through FGFR3 in chondrodysplasia, lead to a significant decrease in this important signalling factor accompanied by reduced proliferation of the chondrocytes and a dwarf phenotype. In an attempt to rescue the chondrodysplasia phenotype hedgehog agonist Hh-Ag 1.4 was injected subcutaneously into mice with achondroplasia (ACH) or with severe achondroplasia with developmental delay and acanthosis negricans (SADDAN) with mixed results. Administration of a hedgehog agonist in SADDAN mice led to a significant up-regulation of both Ptch and Gli1, as measured by quantitative PCR, indicating that Hh-Ag 1.4 does indeed stimulate hedgehog signalling in vivo. Also, in situ hybridization for Ihh seems to show a down regulation of native Ihh expression in pre-hypertrophic chondrocytes, possibly due to the activation of the negative PTHrP feedback loop. In our study, Hh-Ag 1.4 treatment resulted in an increased growth plate length and reduced size of the hypertrophic zone. The cortical bone flanking the growth plate in mice injected with Hh-Ag 1.4 was 2-3 times thicker than in control mice, which may be attributed to the positive effect of increased Ihh signalling in osteoblastogenesis. Contrary to our expectations, there was also a noticeable reduction in chondrocyte proliferation in mice treated with the agonist. Overall, the effect on the growth of long bones was not beneficial and the treatment with high doses of Hh-Ag 1.4 did not result in an amelioration of the chondrodysplastic phenotype.</description><creator>Morrison, David, 1981-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Mice, Mutant Strains.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Achondroplasia -- genetics.</subject><subject>Receptor, Fibroblast Growth Factor, Type 3 -- genetics.</subject><subject>Bone Development -- physiology.</subject><subject>Hedgehog Proteins -- agonists.</subject><title>The use of a synthetic hedgehog agonist in mouse models of chondrodysplasia /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483n68c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sx36s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp484</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies measures of musical rhythm complexity. Informally, rhythm complexity may be thought of as the difficulty humans have performing a rhythm, listening to a rhythm, or recognizing its structure. The problem of understanding rhythm complexity has been studied in musicology and psychology, but there are approaches for its measurement from a variety of domains. This thesis aims to evaluate rhythm complexity measures based on how accurately they reflect human-based measures. Also, it aims to compare their performance using rhythms from Africa, India, and rhythms generated randomly. The results suggest that none of the measures accurately reflect the difficulty humans have performing or listening to rhythm; however, the measures do accurately reflect how humans recognize a rhythm's metrical structure. Additionally, the results suggest a need for normalization of the measures to account for variety among cultural rhythms.</description><creator>Thul, Eric.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Music theory -- Mathematics.</subject><subject>Musical meter and rhythm.</subject><title>Measuring the complexity of musical rhythm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301491t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp484</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bx84c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:31:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Epigenetic modification of DNA plays an important role in gene regulation. During gametogenesis and early embryogenesis epigenetic states are reset to ensure embryonic-specific gene expression patterns after fertilization. However, certain genomic regions may resist epigenetic reprogramming. This may result in transgenerational epigenetic inheritance. Earlier, a grandparental origin dependent (GPO) transmission ratio distortion (TRD) of alleles in the distal region of mouse chromosome 12 had been found (Croteau et al ., 2002). The distorted region overlaps with the imprinted region of chromosome 12. The mechanism underlying this TRD is unknown, and we hypothesized that it was due to failure to reset imprints in the imprinted region in a proportion of germ cells. Such an imprint resetting failure would represent a particular case of transgenerational epigenetic inheritance. DNA (Cytosine-5) methyltransferase 1 (DNMT1) plays a key role in the maintenance of epigenetic states in mammalian genomes. To test the role of DNA methylation and DNMT1 in the genesis of TRD and its relationship to epigenetic inheritance we investigated the effect of Dnmt1 loss-of-function mutations using two mouse models: GPO (grandparental origin dependent)-TRD (transmission ratio distortion) and epigenetic inheritance at the agouti locus. Here, we report that Dnmt1 mutations have a modifying parental effect on the transmission of grandparental chromosome 12 alleles. However, the same Dnmt1 mutation did not affect the agouti coat color inheritance patterns in mice that inherited the Avy (agouti viable yellow) mutant allele from the father. Our results suggest that Dnmt1 is a trans-acting modifier of allelic transmission and support the role of epigenetic states in the genesis of TRD.</description><creator>Yang, Lanjian, 1976-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>DNA (Cytosine-5-)-Methyltransferase -- genetics.</subject><subject>Genomic Imprinting -- genetics.</subject><subject>Crosses, Genetic.</subject><subject>Inheritance Patterns -- genetics.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred C57BL.</subject><title>Effect of DNA methyltransferase 1 on transmission ratio distortion and epigenetic inheritance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547v951.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx84c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>