<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:52:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25950" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k15t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermal conductivity is a powerful tool to probe the phonon and electron exitations in a solid, especially in superconductors were one can basically tune the respective electronic and phononic contributions by applying a magnetic field below Tc. After a short review on the concepts of superconductivity, thermal conductivity and amorphous matter, we present a study of the thermal conductivity of an exotic material, the amorphous metallic superconductor Fe0.5Ni 0.5Zr2. The results indicate an unexpected dominant electonic contribution to the thermal conductivity across the superconducting transition, in accordance with an inhomogeneous sample composed of a bulk normal phase with inhomogeneous superconducting phases.</description><creator>Alonzo-Proulx, Olivier.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Low-temperature thermal conductivity of the amorphous superconductor FexNi₁-xZr₂</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Olivier Alonzo-Proulx, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f374d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k15t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k306</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses The Development and The Future of English and Islamic Law within the given historical, political, social and legal context of the Sudan. In so doing it uses a comparative methodology. Part I highlights the genesis and the development of Islamic Law in the Sudan over three centuries. Emphasis is on the legal aspect of this long history, though other relevant factors are highlighted as well. The characteristics of this era are significant in understanding later developments of both English and Islamic Law as well as their future in the Sudan. Part II focuses on the factors that were conductive to the development of English Law from 1899 to 1956. It examines how the British investment in English legal education, legal training, dissemination of English language and different aspects of the Sudanese public life created a factor of unexpressed consciousness of legal training and affinity which led to the ultimate adoption of English Law and the assimilation of the Sudan into the English legal heritage. Part III presents how the generation of the Sudanese lawyers who were reared in the colonial era enhanced the development of English Law after the independence. Their methodology of adopting and not adapting English Law is thoroughly examined. [...]</description><description>Cette thèse traite du développement et de l’avenir de la loi anglaise et islamique dans le contexte historique, politique, social et légal du Soudan. Pour se faire, elle utilise une méthodologie comparative. La partie 1 souligne l’origine et le développement de la loi islamique au Soudan sur une période de trois siècles. L’emphase porte sur l’aspect légal de cette longue histoire, bien que d’autres facteurs significatifs soient également mentionnés. Les caractéristiques de cette période sont nécessaires afin de comprendre le développement ultérieur de la loi anglaise et islamique ainsi que leur avenir au Soudan. La partie il traite des facteurs qui ont mené au développement de la loi anglaise de 1899 à 1956. Elle analyse la facon dont l’investissement britanique dans l’éducation et la formation juridiques anglaises, et dans la dissémination de la langue anglaise, ainsi que les différent aspects de la vie publique soudanaise ont créé une certaine affinité dans les milieux juridiques soudanais avec la loi anglaise; ce qui a abouti à son adoption ultime et à l’assimilation du Soudan dans l’héritage juridique anglais. La partie III présente la facon dont les générations d’avocats soudanais, formés au cours de la période de colonisation, ont participé au développement de la loi anglaise après l’indépendance. Leur méthodologie dans l’adoption et l’adaptation de la loi anglaise est analysée entièrement. [...]</description><creator>Elkhalifa, Abdel Rahman Ibrahim</creator><contributor>Bradley, Martin A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1988</date><subject>Social Sciences, Law.</subject><title>Development and future of English Law and Islamic Law in the Sudan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn106z41x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k306</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j556</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a study of the development of fish resources of Manitoba during the period of commercial fishing. Staples and dependency paradigms constitute the theoretical background for this study. A political economy approach to resource issues locates this particular hinterland economic activity within the broader economic system. A computer based data set provides a statistical framework to evaluate the performance of the industry. Historical records support a reconstruction of the development of a commercial fishing industry. Ultimately, geographical/environmental and economic questions, such as depletion, incomes and foreign control help to define the changing pattern of resource development. The spatial development of the industry indicates certain structural weakness. Resource management policies do not reflect a desire for conservation as much as the inability of the government to deal with the distorted organization of the industry. Finally, staples and dependency theories provide a new geographical approach to the development problems of the fishing industry.</description><description>Cette thèse est une étude sur le développement des ressources poissonnières du Manitoba pendant la période de pêche commerciale. Les paradigmes de les produits de base et de dépendance constituent le fonds théorique de cette étude. C’est en abondant les problèmes de ressources par l’économie politique que nous replacerons cette activité économique particulière d’arrière--pays à l’intérieur d’ un systéme économique plus général. Une serie de données informetiques nous offrire une base statisique servant à évaluer les performances de cette industrie. Un développement de l’industrie de la pêche commerciale est reconstitue à l’aide de faits historiques. Enfin les questions d’environnement et d’économie telles que baisses de production revenus et réglementation étrangère contribuent à definit les modification subies par le système de développement des ressources. Le développement en espace de cette industrie décile quelques faiblesses dans ses structures. Les règles d’exploitation des ressources refletent moins un désir de préservation que l’incapacité du gouvernement à remédier à l’organisation défectueuse de cette industrie. Enfin les théories de produits de base et de dépendance permettent une nouvelle approche des problèmes concernant le développement de l’ industrie de la pêche.</description><creator>Tough, Frank, 1952-</creator><contributor>Bradbury, John (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Armstrong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1980</date><subject>Social Sciences, Geography.</subject><subject>Fisheries -- Manitoba.</subject><title>Manitoba’s commercial fisheries : a study in development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm63g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j556</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k288w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Master's thesis aims to demonstrate that the history of the suburb happened in two phases, creating two kinds of suburbs: "countryside-suburbs" and "new generation suburbs," which can be found in literary texts. The first chapter traces the social history ofthe suburb. The second chapter analyzes texts by Jacques Ferron in which he describesthe countryside-suburb. The third chapter takes a look at Dee by Michel Delisle, whichnot only portrays the countryside-suburb (like Ferron), but also evokes the newgeneration suburb. The countryside-suburb has a natural, rural aspect, and it has a certainin stability due its bordering the city. The new generation suburb is a place where the rural aspect is vanishing, and where the sense of instability seems more ideological than material. It is a place where the American Dream has been realized according to the script, but has generated a feeling of emptiness.</description><description>Ce mémoire vise a demontrer qu'il existe deux types de banlieues dans la littérature québecoise: les "banlieues-campagnes" et les "banlieues nouvelle generation". Le premier chapitre considère la socio-histoire de la banlieue québecoise. Le deuxième explore quelques textes de Jacques Ferron ou des traces de la banlieue campagne peuvent etre observées. Le troisième chapitre fait ressortir, dans le roman Deede Michael Delisle, des éléments définitionnels de la banlieue-campagne semblables à ceux décelés chez Ferron: un aspect natural, une certaine ruralité et une instabilité attribuable au caractère limitrophe de ce lieu par rapport a la ville. Ce chapitre traite aussi des aspects de la banlieue nouvelle génération, une nature domptée, un lieu ou la ruralité n'a plus préseance, une instabilité moins materielle qu'ideologique. Ce mémoire conclut que la banlieue nouvelle génération est le résultat d'un American Dream consommé ou un grand vide s'est immiscé. </description><creator>Halin, Francis</creator><contributor>Leclerc, Catherine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2008</date><subject>Ferron, Jacques.</subject><subject>Delisle, Michael.</subject><subject>Suburbs in literature.</subject><title>la banlieue: de Jacques Ferron à Michael Delisle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w51q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k288w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n144s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the formation of the German Empire in 1871, Germany remained, in theory at least, a federation of the larger German kingdoms, each of which could have its own relations with foreign powers. The British Government naturally conducted its business with the German Empire through the Imperial Foreign Office at Berlin, but it nevertheless found it extremely useful to keep a minister at Munich-Stuttgart. It may be remembered that, while this minister had not the rank of an ambassador, his office was not a mere appendage of the Embassy in Berlin, in the manner of consulates of to-day. It had independent and direct contact with the Foreign Office in London. The practice of sending Ambassadors to all nations, large and small, is a relatively recent one, for in the 19th century and early 20th century Ambassadors were appointed only to the capitals of the great Powers.</description><creator>Vogel, Robert</creator><date>1954</date><subject>Cartwright, Fairfax L., Sir.</subject><subject>History, European.</subject><title>The diplomatic career of Sir Fairfax Cartwright from 1906 to 1913</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827b99c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n144s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268546r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis argues that the securitization of migration is a discourse that has gained a near monopoly over how the physical spaces of the territorial border are imagined and how the border itself is understood as a site of exclusion and control. Narratives about who undocumented people are and why they arrive at the border play a central role in justifying the anxious regulation of the border and migration as a national security issue. Taking Australia's policy of territorial excision as a representative instance of border policy that is dictated and defined by the securitization of migration, this thesis traces the various and over-determined narratives of the territorial border and the undocumented person that were articulated in the parliamentary debates surrounding this policy. It argues against securitization's constructions of these subjects, to show that neither the border nor the undocumented migrant exist independently of the narratives that constitute them. These narratives work not only to justify the exclusion of undocumented people at the border as sensible and legitimate, but also actively obscure and discredit other ways of imagining people who arrive at the border, as well as the functions and spaces of territorial borders.</description><description>Ce mémoire soutient que la sécurisation de la migration est un discours qui a obtenu le quasi-monopole sur la manière de percevoir l'espace physique des frontières territoriales ainsi que la compréhension de la frontière elle-même en tant que site d'exclusion et de contrôle. Les narrations portant sur l'identité des sans-papiers et les raisons qu'ils peuvent avoir d'arriver à la frontière jouent un rôle central pour justifier le fait que la réglementation de la frontière et de la migration est une question de sécurité nationale.Prenant la politique australienne d'excision territoriale comme exemple de politique frontalière dictée et définie par la sécurisation de la migration, ce mémoire analyse les discours divers et passionnés sur la frontière territoriale et les sans-papiers qui ont été articulés dans les débats parlementaires ayant eu lieu autour de la formation de cette politique. Elle plaide contre les constructions de sécurisation de ces sujets démontrant que ni la frontière, ni le migrant sans-papier n'existe indépendamment des discours qui les constituent. Ces discours non seulement œuvrent à la justification de l'exclusion des sans-papiers à la frontière comme étant sensée et légitime, mais de plus ils masquent et discréditent les autres manières de percevoir les gens qui arrivent à la frontière ainsi que les fonctions et les espaces des frontières territoriales.</description><creator>Vogl, Anthea</creator><contributor>Robert Leckey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Anywhere but here: locating the border and narrating asylum seekers under Australia's policy of territorial excision</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj74h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268546r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354f55x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les systemes a entree multiple et sortie multiple permettent d’augmenter le debit de transmission de donnees dans les reseaux de communication sans fil. Ces systemes sont caracterises par une grande flexibilite de conception, ce qui leur permet d’accommoder une grande variete de techniques de signalisation et d’attribution de ressources. Dans cette these, nous considerons la capacite et les debits de transmission possibles pour les systemes a entree multiple et sortie multiple utilisant une variete de formats de modulation espacetemps multidimensionnelle. Ces formats correspondent a differentes manieres d’ attribuer les dimensions orthogonales du signal aux antennes de transmission. Pour un systeme ayant un seul usager et moyennant une puissance de transmission fixe, nous examinons comment attribuer la puissance et les dimensions du signal aux antennes de transmission, de maniere a maximiser les debits de transmission en tenant compte de 1’information sur l’etat du canal dont dispose le transmetteur. Dans plusieurs situations, nous demontrons qu’utiliser toutes les dimensions du signal sur chaque antenne de transmission permet d’atteindre de plus hauts debits de transmission. [...]</description><description>Multiple-Input Multiple-Output (MIMO) systems have shown a great potential for increasing the data transmission rates in wireless communications. These systems are characterized by a high design flexibility which allows a wide variety of efficient signaling techniques and resource allocation methods. In this thesis, we consider the capacity and transmission rates for MIMO systems using various multi-dimensional space-time modulation formats. The latters refer to various allocations of orthogonal signal dimensions (or modulating waveforms) to transmit antennas. For a single-user system with a fixed transmit power, we investigate the most efficient allocations of power and signal dimensions to transmit antennas so that transmission rates can be maximized under different cases of channel state information at the transmitter (CSIT). In many situations, we show that using all the signal dimensions on all the transmit antennas yields the largest rates. An analysis of the capacity and transmission rates is also provided at low and high SNR, where the effect of the spatial channel parameters is pointed out. For a broadcast system, we consider the power and signal dimensions allocations not only for transmit antennas, but also among users. [...]</description><creator>Kassouf, Marthe</creator><contributor>Leib, Harry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2008</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Capacity and information rates for multiple antenna wireless systems with multi-dimensional modulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687h73r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f55x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95050899</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Existants approches théoriques au droit international des droits humains régissant l'obligation de l'État de respecter et de garantir le droit de ne pas être privé arbitrairement de la vie ne fournissent pas un cadre analytique satisfaisant dans lequel de considérer le problème d'un aéronef civil à passagers renégat  – un aéronef civil portant des passagers et sous le contrôle effectif d'un ou plusieurs individus ayant l'intention utiliser l'aéronef-même comme une arme contre des personnes et des biens à la surface. Une approche plus satisfaisante est fournie par l'ajout d'une norme de proportionnalité des effets qui est analogue à celle qui a été développé dans le cadre du droit international humanitaire et le droit moderne des droits constitutionnels. Cette norme supplémentaire s'applique que lorsqu'il y a un conflit insoluble entre les devoirs de l'État en respect du droit à la vie et tous les cours d'action disponibles se traduira par des personnes innocentes étant privé de leur vie.</description><description>Existing theoretical approaches to international human rights law governing the State's duty to respect and ensure the right to not be arbitrarily deprived of life do not provide a satisfactory analytical framework within which to consider the problem of a rogue civil airliner  – a passenger-carrying civil aircraft under the effective control of one or more individuals who intend use the aircraft itself as a weapon against persons and property on the surface.  A more satisfactory approach is provided by the addition of a norm of proportionality of effects that is analogous to that which has been developed within the framework of international humanitarian law and modern constitutional rights law.  This additional norm would apply only where there is an irreconcilable conflict between the State's duties in respect of the right to life and all of the courses of action available will result in innocent persons being deprived of life.</description><creator>Holman, Robin</creator><contributor>Rene Provost (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Law enforcement, the rogue civil airliner and proportionality of effects: an analysis of international human rights law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580m941.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95050899</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xc160</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mutant quaking viable mice (qkV) develop a tremor phenotype in their hind limbs 10 days after birth, likely resulting from severe myelination defects. Genetically, quaking viable mice contain a deletion in the promoter/enhancer region of the quaking gene. The quaking gene is alternatively spliced, producing QUAKING isoforms that differ in their C-terminal amino acid sequence. The QKI-5 isoform is nuclear, whereas the QKI-6 and QKI-7 isoforms are predominantly cytoplasmic. The QKI isoforms contain a single KH RNA-binding domain, which suggests a role in RNA metabolism. Although the dysmyelinating phenotype of the mutant mice suggests a role in myelination, the function of the protein remains largely unknown. The objective of this thesis is to characterize the role of the RNA binding proteins QKI in the differentiation of glial cells and their involvement in the process of myelination. Moreover, this study describes the quaking viable defects and how the isoforms contribute to the observed phenotype. [...]</description><description>Les protéines liant l’ARN jouent un rôle central afin de contrôler l’expression génique, l’épissage alternatif et la localisation des ARN messagers. Pour qu’une cellule se différencie, les gènes doivent être régulés au niveau de leur expression et de la localisation de leurs ARNm. Un des phénomènes physiologique de différentiation au niveau du système nerveux est la myélinisation des axones. En vulgarisant, la gaine de myéline serait l’isolant entourant le fil électrique étant l’axone. [...]</description><creator>Larocque, Daniel</creator><contributor>Richard, Stéphane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>The functions of quaking proteins in gliogenesis and myelination</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w520.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xc160</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881m27r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ibuprofen (IBP) is one of the most prescribed drugs. It has been shown that IBP resist physicochemical wastewater treatment (Gagnon and Lajeunesse 2008). Also, IBP has a known negative effect on algae (Brown et al. 2007). This research focused on removal of aqueous IBP using five different oxidative techniques: ozonation, ozonation with hydrogen peroxide, ozone with sonication, sonication with hydrogen peroxide and sonication alone. IBP and chemical oxidation demand (COD) removals were monitored for experiments performed over a range of operating conditions: pH (4 to 7), temperature (5 to 25ºC), applied ozone dose (8 to 16 mg/L) and applied power 5 watts. Solutions of 5 mg/L IBP were treated in a custom-designed semi-continuous 900-mL reactor. The design allowed the application of ozone and ultrasounds from the bottom of the reactor either separately or simultaneously. A synergic effect was observed for the combined treatment O3/sonication. This might be explained by the higher mass transfer of ozone in the solution observed in presence of ultrasounds. Although H2O2 significantly increased the IBP removal when used in combination with O3, the addition during sonication did not result in increased IBP removal. Four transformation products were detected as new peaks on the HPLC chromatograms. Oxo-ibuprofen, 4-acetylbenzoic acid, 4-ethybenzaldehyde and oxalic acid were identified as products using LC/MS. COD analyses indicated low degrees of mineralization in the range of 11 to 41%. The highest IBP and COD removals of 95% and 41% were obtained with O3/H2O2 performed at 15ºC and pH 7. Optimized parameters for each technique were applied to IBP contained in first wash-water produced at an ibuprofen processing plant (Wyeth, St-Laurent, Quebec, Canada). The industrial first wash water had an IBP concentration of 582ppm. All experiments with first-wash-water were compared to results obtained in a synthetic solution of equivalent IBP concentration in pure water. For all oxidation techniques, a higher IBP removal was obtained in the wash-water and the highest IBP removal of 16% was obtained with O3/H2O2. To the author's knowledge, this project was the first study comparing all these techniques and considering the treatment of first wash-water of an industrial plant.</description><description>L'ibuprofène (IBP) est un des composés pharmaceutiques les plus prescrits. L'IBP résiste au traitement physico-chimique des eaux usées (Gagnon and Lajeunesse 2008). L'IBP a également été identifié comme ayant des effets négatifs sur des algues (Brown et al. 2007). Cette recherche s'est concentrée sur l'élimination de l'IBP aqueux par cinq techniques d'oxydation dont l'ozonation, l'ozonation couplée au peroxyde d'hydrogène, l'ozonation couplée à la sonification, la sonification couplée au peroxyde d'hydrogène et la sonification seule. La diminution d'IBP et la demande chimique en oxygène ont été déterminées pour chaque technique oxydative opérées sous les paramètres d'opération suivants : pH (4 à 7), température (5 à 25ºC), dose d'ozone (8 à 16 mg/L) et puissance de sonication (0-5 Watts). Une solution de 5 ppm d'IBP a été traitée dans un réacteur semi continu de 900 mL conçu pour ce projet. Le design de ce réacteur permet au bas du réacteur l'alimentation d'ozone et l'émission d'ultrasons, séparément ou simultanément. Un effet synergique a été observé lorsque l'ozone est combiné à la sonification. Cette synergie peut être expliquée par l'augmentation du transfert de masse de l'ozone dans la solution due au champ d'ultrasons. L'ajout de H2O2 a augmenté significativement l'élimination d'IBP lorsque combiné avec l'ozone. L'addition durant la sonification a démontré aucun effet. Quatre produits de transformation ont été identifiés par LC/MS : oxo-IBP, acide 4-acetylbenzoïque, 4-athylbenzaldehyde et l'acide oxalique. Les analyses de COD ont indiqué un degré de minéralisation allant de 11 à 41%. L'élimination la plus significative d'IBP et de COD a été de 95% et 41%, obtenu lors du traitement avec l'O3/H2O2 à une  température de 15ºC et un pH de 7. Les paramètres optimaux pour chaque technique d'oxydation ont été appliqués à une eau de premier lavage d'un procédé industriel de comprimés d'ibuprofène fourni par Wyeth, St Laurent, Québec, Canada, ayant une concentration d'IBP de 582 ppm. Une plus grande élimination d'IBP a été obtenue dans l'eau de lavage comparativement à une solution synthétique de même concentration et ce, pour chaque technique étudiée. La plus importante élimination d'IBP dans l'eau de lavage, d'une valeur de 16%, a été obtenue avec le traitement d'O3/H2O2.  Selon l'auteur, cette étude constitue une première comparaison systématique de ces techniques et la première étude du traitement d'une première eau de lavage industrielle. </description><creator>Danylo, Félix</creator><contributor>Viviane Yargeau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Treatment of ibuprofen containing industrial first wash-water by ozonation, sonication, ozonation/H2O2 ozonation/sonication and sonication/H2O2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w538.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m27r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k06987831</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clathrin-coated vesicles (CCVs) are responsible for the transport of proteins between various compartments of the secretory and endocytic systems. Clathrinforms a scaffold around these vesicles and is linked to membranes by clathrin adaptors. The adaptor complexes, AP-2 and AP-1, are key hubs in CCV formation at the plasma membrane and trans-Golgi network (TGN), respectively. They recruit cargo, clathrin and a multitude of accessory proteins. The adaptin, or ear, domains play a critical role in recruiting accessory proteins through binding of specific peptide motifs, such as the FXDXF motif. NECAPs are a family of accessory proteins that enrich in CCVs and associate with AP-2 and AP-1. NECAP1 expression levels are highest in the neuronal cells while NECAP2 is ubiquitously expressed. Structural studies of NECAP1 reveal the fold to be part of the pleckstrin homology (PH) domain superfamily and it mimics AP-2 α-ear binding of FXDXF motifs. Therefore the globular region of NECAP is termed the PHear (PH fold with ear-like function) domain. NECAP1 consists of the PHear domain between amino acids 1-133, and a conserved region that is intrinsically unfolded between 134-178, with the entire unfolded region between amino acids 134-275. This thesis has found using nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) that the NECAP1 construct 1-178 has a two-fold weaker binding affinity to an FXDXF peptide in comparison to the construct 1-133, with binding constants (KD) of 620 micromolar and 330 micromolar respectively. The decrease in binding affinity is attributed to an interaction between the unfolded region and the PHear domain, with a KD between 4000 and 1000 micromolar.  </description><description>Les vésicules enduites de clathrine (CCVs pour Clathrin-coated vesicles) sont responsables du transport de protéines entre divers compartiments des systèmes sécréteurs et endocytiques. Les protéines clathrine forment un échafaudage autour de ces vésicules ces dernières sont liées aux membranes par des adaptateurs de clathrine. Les complexes d'adaptateurs, AP-2 et AP-1, sont les points de jonction principaux dans la formation des vésicules enduites de clathrine à la membrane de plasma et au réseau transport-Golgi (TGN), respectivement. Ils recrutent la cargaison, la clathrine et une multitude de protéines accessoires. Les domaines adaptin (aussi appelés domaines oreilles) jouent un rôle critique dans le recrutement des protéines accessoires en se liant à des motifs peptides spécifiques, tels que le motif FXDXF. Les NECAPs sont une famille de protéines accessoires qui se concentrent dans les CCVs et qui s'associent à AP-2 et à AP-1. Les niveaux d'expression NECAP1 sont les plus élevés dans les cellules neuronales tandis que NECAP2 est présente unanimement. Des études structurales de NECAP1 indiquent le pli de la protéine fait d'elle un membre de la superfamille des domaines homologues de pleckstrin (pH). Ces dernières ont comme fonction d'imiter le point d'attache du domaine « α-ear » de AP-2 aux motifs FXDXF. Par conséquent, la région globulaire de NECAP se nomme le domaine PHear (PH fold with ear like function, ou pli PH avec fonction similaire au domaine « ear »).Le domaine PHear de NECAP1 est délimité par les acides aminés 1-133. De plus, la proteine comprend une région conservée qui est intrinsèquement non structurée entre les acides aminés 134 et 178; la totalité de cette région non structuré est comprise entière entre les acides aminés 134 et 275. Cette thèse démontre, en utilisant la résonance magnétique nucléaire (RMN), qu'un segment de NECAP1 composé des acides aminés 1 à 178 a une affinité envers un peptide FXDXF deux fois plus faible que celle d'un segment composé des acides aminés 1 à 133. Les constantes KD étaient de 620 micromolaire et de 330 micromolaire respectivement. La diminution de l'affinité de liaison est attribuée à une interaction entre la région non structurée et le domaine de PHear, avec une constante KD entre 4000 et 1000 micromolaire.</description><creator>Murphy, Sebastien</creator><contributor>Kalle Burgess Gehring (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</subject><title>Influence of an intrinsically disordered region on peptide binding by the PHear domain of NECAP1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tp65z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06987831</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860725q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ice hockey is a sport characterized by high speeds, sharp turns and abrupt stops. As a result of these explosive and agile movements, the interaction of the foot and ankle with the skate boot is fundamental for optimal stability and propulsion.  The purpose of this study was to determine the nature of this mechanical coupling in both a conventional and prototype skate models.  In phase one, a Biodex System 4 Pro dynamometer was used to isolate the foot and ankle / boot dynamics in sagittal and frontal plane movements. Three footwear conditions were evaluated (control shoe, a skate boot in production and a modified skate boot prototype).  In phase two, lower body kinematics were assessed using 3D motion capture to determine if the above skate models would yield different joint movement coordination during skating push-offs using the two skate boot models. When comparing the three foot conditions, there was a significantly greater range of motion observed in the shoe control and modified skate boot than the regular skate boot (65.2 deg vs. 52.4 deg vs. 35.7 deg, p &lt; 0.05). The total work done was only significant in the shoe control over the regular skate boot (16 kJ vs. 8.9 kJ, p &lt; 0.05). In phase two, only the maximum plantar flexion was greater with the modified skate (11.3 deg vs. 1.3 deg, p &lt; 0.05). The biodex dynamometer was able to discern differences between the three types of footwear using the dependent variables selected. Using a combination of the active and passive modes, this system has provided a valuable measurement of quantifying boot stiffness characteristics. </description><description>Une vitesse de jeu rapide, les virages brusques ainsi que les arrêts soudains sont des caractéristiques bien particulières au hockey sur  glace. Considérant ces mouvements explosifs et agiles, l'interaction entre le pied, la cheville ainsi que la botte du patin devient fondamentale pour obtenir une propulsion et une stabilité optimale.  Le but de cette études était de déterminer la nature cette interaction mécanique pour un modèle de patin a glace conventionnel ainsi que pour un prototype.  Dans un premier temps, un dynamomètre Biodex System 4 a été utilisé pour isoler de façon dynamique le pied et la cheville/patin dans les plans sagittal et frontal.  Trois conditions expérimentales ont été évaluées (soulier contrôle,  patin commercialisé ainsi qu'un patin modifié).  Par la suite, la cinématique des membres inférieurs fut mesurée en utilisant une système de capture du mouvement pour déterminer  si les différentes botte de patin affecteraient la coordination motrice lors d'un départ.En comparant les trois conditions de botte, une différence significative a été observée pour l'amplitude de mouvement entre le soulier et le patin modifié et le patin commercial (65.2° vs. 52.4° vs. 35.7°, p &lt; 0.05). Le travail total était seulement significatif entre le soulier et le patin commercial (16 kJ vs 8.9 kJ, p &lt; 0.05).  Pour la deuxième phase, seulement la flexion plantaire maximale était plus grande avec le patin modifié 11.3° vs. 1.3°, p  &lt; 0.05).Le dynamomètre Biodex a pu clairement discerner des différences entre les différentes conditions de botte pour les variables dépendantes sélectionnées.   En utilisant les modes passifs et actifs, le système a permis de générer une méthode de quantification caractéristique de la rigidité de bottes. </description><creator>Baig, Zubair</creator><contributor>David J Pearsall (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Functional mechanical assessment of foot and ankle stiffness and work production in ice hockey skate boots</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752g991.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860725q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm263</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the present research, the onset of detonation downstream of a perforated plate subsequent to the reflection of a Chapman-Jouguet (CJ) detonation upstream was investigated. Single-frame schlieren photography was used together with pressure and velocity measurements to examine the phenomena in detail. Experiments were performed with two different mixtures: C2H2 + 2.5O2 + 70%Ar and C3H8 + 5O2. The former is known to have a piecewise laminar structure with a regular cellular structure while the latter has a much more irregular transverse wave pattern. Upon reflection of the CJ detonation upstream, a turbulent reaction front propagates downstream at a quasi-steady velocity which corresponds to about the sound speed of the detonation products and half the CJ detonation velocity. There is found to be a critical value of the initial pressure in which the detonation is re-initiated downstream of the perforated plate. Below the critical initial pressure, the quasi-steady reaction front decays into a deflagration after a certain period of propagation. For the high argon diluted mixtures, the onset of detonation is found to always occur in the vicinity downstream of the perforated plate, when the turbulence generated by the plate has not yet decayed. In contrast, for the propane-oxygen mixtures at critical condition, the quasi-steady reaction front is found to propagate for relatively long distances from the plate prior to the onset of detonation. Thus it is concluded that high argon diluted mixtures may not be able to self-generate the critical conditions that are required for the transition to detonation.</description><description>Dans cette recherche, des détonations Chapman-Jouguet (CJ) sont réfléchies par une plaque perforée afin d'étudier le phénomène de la formation des détonations en aval. Pour ce faire, la photographie schlieren ultra-rapide est utilisée et combinée à des mesures de pressions et de vitesses. Les expériences sont réalisées avec deux mixtures explosives différentes: C2H2 + 2.5O2 + 70%Ar et C3H8 + 5O2. La première est connue pour avoir une structure cellulaire laminaire et régulière, tandis que la seconde possède un tracé cellulaire bien plus irrégulier. Lorsque la détonation CJ est réfléchie par la plaque en amont, une zone de réaction turbulente est propagée enaval à une vitesse plus ou moins constante correspondant à la vitesse du son dans les produits de détonation ainsi qu'à environ la moitié de la vitesse CJ de détonation. Cette étude démontre qu'il existe une valeur critique de la pression initiale pour laquelle la détonation est ré-initiée en aval de la plaque perforée. Sous cette pression critique, la zone de réaction turbulente décroît en une déflagration après une certaine période de propagation. Pour la mixture diluée d'argon, la formation de la détonation se fait toujours à proximité de la plaque, avant que la turbulence générée par la plaquene se soit complètement dissipée. Pour les mixtures de propane-oxygène à pression critique, il apparaît que la zone de réaction turbulente peut se propager sur une distance relativement longue avant que la formation de la détonation débute. Cette recherche démontre donc que les mixtures hautement diluées d'argon pourraient ne pas être en mesure de générer par elles-mêmes les conditions critiques requises pour la transition en une détonation. </description><creator>Grondin, Jean-Sébastien</creator><contributor>John H S Lee (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Energy</subject><title>The onset of detonation downstream of perforated plates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xx651.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm263</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jp028</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Premature infants receive numerous painful procedures while in the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU).  Pain may lead to long-term negative consequences that include cognitive, social, and learning deficits and a higher incidence of depression.  The mechanisms by which pain can exert these effects are currently unclear.  To examine more precisely the effect of neonatal pain on brain morphology and adult behaviour, a rat model of acute neonatal inflammatory pain was used to mimic pain experienced by preterm infants in the NICU.  Male rat pups were injected with either a low formalin dose (0.75%-1.5%), saline (0.9%), or remained uninjected during the first 2 weeks of life.  First, we performed magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) on postnatal days (PND) 15 and 35 to identify potential changes in brain volume in response to pain.  In a second study, we examined cellular proliferation (using Ki67, an endogenous marker of cell proliferation) and neurogenesis (using survival of BrdU-labelled cells) in response to pain in regions identified from our MRI analysis.  Neurons were also counted using NeuN (a marker of mature neurons).  Our final study investigated changes in anxiety and fear related behaviours in adult offspring subjected to pain as neonates.  We consistently found that neonatal pain causes moderate hypertrophy in the basolateral amygdala (BLA) in PND 15 pups.  These volumetric changes were not observed on PND 35.  Similarly, neuronal counts (NeuN) showed a moderate increase in the BLA of PND 15 pain-exposed pups compared to controls (p=0.062), however, this effect was not seen on PND 35.  However, there was no significant treatment effect of pain on Ki67-positive cells on PND 15, suggesting that neuronal proliferation induced by early pain occurred prior to PND 15.  In addition, pain had no effect on the number of NeuN and BrdU positive cells on PND 35, suggesting that pain has transient effects.  In adulthood, rats that were exposed to pain as neonates did not differ from controls (either saline injected or uninjected) in behavioural tests measuring anxiety (social interaction and elevated plus maze) and fear (fear conditioning).  Overall, these results show that repeated exposure to mild inflammatory pain during the neonatal period produces transient changes in BLA morphology, the consequences of which do not affect adult behaviours mediated by this structure.  The early transient hypertrophic response to pain in the BLA may trigger plastic changes sufficient to protect the animal from any potentially negative functional consequences. Keywords: pain, neonate, amygdala, anxiety, fear, proliferation, survival, neuron</description><description>Lors de leur séjour dans l'unité des soins intensifs, les bébés prématurés sont soumis a de nombreuses procédures douloureuses qui ne sont pas toujours bien contrôlées et qui ont des conséquences a long terme sur les fonctions cognitives, l'apprentissage et les interactions sociales.  Les mécanismes qui sont impliqués sont encore peu connus.  Au cours de ce travail, nous avons utilisé un modèle animal de douleur inflammatoire répétée au cours de la période néonatale chez le rat pour comprendre les effets à long terme sur la morphologie du cerveau et le comportement relié à l'anxiété à l'âge adulte.  Nous avons injecté les pattes arrières des ratons entre le jour 3 et 14 de la vie postnatale avec soit de la saline (0.9%) ou de la formaline (0.75-1.5%) une fois par jour.  Un groupe contrôle n'a pas été injecté.  Dans une première étude, nous avons mesure les changements de volume du cerveau induits par la douleur au jour 15 et 35 de vie postnatale.  À l'aide de la résonance magnétique (scanner de 7T), nous avons pu démontrer une augmentation presque significative du volume de l'amygdale basolatérale (BLA) chez les ratons de 15 jours soumis à la douleur compares aux contrôles injectes à la saline.  Par contre, cette hypertrophie amygdalienne n'était que transitoire car les différences de volume avaient disparu au jour 35.  En quantifiant le nombre de neurones matures (en immunohistochimie avec NeuN) dans la BLA à ces mêmes âges, nous avons pu confirmer que le l'exposition à la douleur durant le 2 premières semaines de vie produit une hypertrophie neuronale dans la BLA au jour 15 mais que celle-ci n'est plus observée après le sevrage au jour 35.  Nous avons également déterminé que l'hypertrophie au jour 15 était probablement due a une prolifération cellulaire qui avait eu lieu avant cette période car le nombre de cellules avec un marquage positif pour le Ki-67 (un marqueur endogène de prolifération) était semblable entre les groupes douleur et contrôles au jour 15.  De même, le nombre de cellules ayant incorpore le BrdU au jour 15 n'était pas différent au jour 35 selon les traitements.  Ceci suggère également que l'effet de la douleur sur la morphologie de la BLA se limite à la période pendant laquelle les ratons sont soumis à la douleur.  Finalement, à l'âge adulte, nous n'avons pas observé de différence significative entre les groupes contrôles et douleur en ce qui a trait à l'anxiété (par le test de interaction sociale et « elevated plus maze ») ou par rapport au conditionnement à l'anxiété (par le test de « fear conditioning »).  Ces résultats nous permettent de conclure qu'une douleur de type inflammatoire modeste au cours des deux premières semaines de vie chez les ratons produit une hypertrophie neuronale transitoire de la BLA, une structure impliquée dans les émotions et les comportements relatifs à l'anxiété.  Nous n'avons pas détecté de conséquences à long terme sur le morphologie neuronale ou les comportements d'anxiété suite a cette expérience néonatale.</description><creator>de Medeiros, Cynthia</creator><contributor>Barry Joseph Bedell (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Claire Walker (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Acute and long-term effects of early life inflammatory pain on brain morphometry and adult behaviour</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r824d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jp028</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hv611</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les mécanismes d'endocytose sont essentiels à la survie neuronale.  Durant la neurogénèse, Numb, une protéine adaptatrice impliquée dans l'endocytose, détermine le destin cellulaire des progéniteurs neuraux. La ségrégation de Numb dans une seule des cellules-filles durant la division cellulaire assymétrique y est alors l'élément-clé. Toutefois, le rôle de Numb dans les neurones post-mitotiques demeure à ce jour inconnu.  Numb pourrait occuper des fonctions différentiellement régulées au cours du développement dans les progéniteurs neuraux et les neurones post-mitotiques. Nous avons donc investigué si Numb est impliqué dans le maintient in vivo des neurites des neurones adultes. Dans la rétine mature, nous avons observé que Numb est fortement exprimé dans la couche synaptique (plexiformes interne (IPL) et externe (OPL)), et dans différents types de neurones rétiniens, tels que les cellules bipolaires et les cellules ganglionnaires de la rétine (RGC).  Afin d'étudier la fonction de Numb dans les neurones post-mitotiques, nous avons inactivé conditionnellement le gène numb dans les microcircuits bipolaire-amacrine-RGC, via le système Cre-loxP. Nous avons observé une dégénérescence des dendrites des mutants pour les RGC, causant une désorganisation de la couche synaptique. Les axones des mutants pour RGC démontrent également des varicosités, lesquels rappellent certains phénotypes observés dans les pathologies associées à des perturbations dans le transport axonal. Cet effet semble cellule-autonome, puisque la dégénération et les varicosités sont également observées dans les cultures dissociées de neurones de rétines de mutants. Nous avons alors conclu que Numb est essentiel à la maintenance de l'intégrité des neurites des neurones matures. Ces résultats suggèrent que Numb régulerait le mécanisme d'endocytose permettant le recyclage des protéines-clés impliquées dans le maintient de l'intégrité structurale, de l'élongation et/ou de la guidance dendritique. En influençant le transport dirigé des récepteurs vers les compartiments pré-synaptiques, Numb pourrait être essentiel à la formation des synapses. De futures expériences pourront répondre à ces importantes questions. Ceci pourrait avoir un impact sur notre compréhension de la façon dont de nombreuses maladies neurodégénératives impliquant des défauts dans la morphologie des neurites se développent.</description><description>Endocytic mechanisms are crucial for neuronal motility, function, survival, and polarity. During neurogenesis, the endocytic adaptor protein Numb acts as a cell-fate determinant in neural progenitors, where it segregates into only one daughter cell during asymmetric cell division. However, its role in post-mitotic neurons remains unclear. Like many other proteins involved in neural development, it is likely that Numb has different temporally regulated functions in progenitors and post-mitotic neurons. Here we investigate the role of Numb in the context of an in vivo system, specifically its possible involvement in neurite maintenance in adult neurons. In the mature retina, we report that Numb is strongly expressed in the synaptic layers, such as the inner and outer plexiform layers (IPL and OPL), and in different retinal neurons such as bipolar and retinal ganglion cells. To study Numb function in post-mitotic neurons, we conditionally inactivated the numb gene in the bipolar-amacrine-RGC microcircuit, using the Cre-loxP system. Although analysis of the mutant retina displayed no changes in cell number, mutant RGC dendrites display a degeneration-like phenotype, which disrupt the organization of the synaptic lamina. Similarly, mutant RGC axons show swellings and varicosities reminiscent of phenotypes observed in conditions where axonal transport is disrupted. This effect appears to be cell autonomous, as the degeneration and varicosities are observed in dissociated neurons from the mutant retinas. Thus we conclude that Numb function is essential for the maintenance of neurite integrity in mature neurons. These results suggest the possibility that Numb might function to regulate endocytic recycling of key proteins involved in keeping structural integrity, axon and dendrite elongation, and/or guidance. It may also be important in synapse formation by influencing directed transport of receptors to the pre-synaptic compartment. Future experiments should help address these important questions, which could have an impact on our understanding of various neurodegenerative diseases in which neurite morphology is affected.</description><creator>Cai, Ouhua</creator><contributor>Michel Cayouette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>The role of the endocytic adapter protein numb in mature neurites of the retina</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sq427.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hv611</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k290x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le but de cette étude était d'explorer des expériences vécues par les entraîneurs de rugby en fauteuil roulant dans le développement de leurs athlètes ayant une lésion de la moelle épinière. Quatre entraîneurs d'élite de rugby en fauteuil roulant au Canada ont été interviewés en utilisant un format d'entrevue semi-structurée à entretien ouvert. L'approche interprétative phénoménologique de Smith et Osborn (2008) a été utilisée pour analyser et interpréter les données par induction. Les résultats ont révélé trois catégories d'ordre supérieur: (a) Attributs et développement des entraîneurs, a souligné l'évolution des entraîneurs et de leurs méthodes d'acquisition des connaissances dans le sport du rugby en fauteuil roulant; (b) Entraînement du sport, a décrit l'environnement sportif de rugby en fauteuil roulant, y compris les rôles d'encadrement des participants et de leurs responsabilités, et (c) Entraînement de l'individu, a décrit la philosophie des participants sur le développement de leurs joueurs, comme athlètes sur le terrain et comme individus dans leur vie quotidienne. Les résultats ont fourni des preuves de l'importance de l'acquisition de connaissances informelles dans le développement de ces entraîneurs. Les résultats ont été similaires à ceux déjà mis en évidence dans les recherches précédentes, soulignant l'importance d'entraîner un «athlète», par opposition à une «personne handicapée». En outre, les entraîneurs se sont investis dans la croissance globale et le développement de leurs athlètes et ont responsabilisé les joueurs afin qu'ils maximisent leur potentiel, tant sur le terrain que dans leur vie quotidienne. D'un point de vue pratique, les résultats actuels peuvent être utilisés afin d'améliorer la qualité et le niveau de l'éducation des entraîneurs de personnes handicapées et fournir les connaissances sur de meilleures pratiques de coaching spécifiques au sport du rugby en fauteuil roulant.</description><description>The purpose of this study was to explore wheelchair rugby coaches lived experiences in the development of their athletes who had acquired a spinal cord injury (SCI). Four elite wheelchair rugby coaches in Canada were interviewed using a semi-structured open-ended interview format. Smith and Osborn's (2008) Interpretative Phenomenological Approach (IPA) was used to inductively analyze and interpret the data. Results revealed three higher-order categories: (a) Coach Attributes and Development, highlighted the evolution of the coaches and their methods of knowledge acquisition in the sport of wheelchair rugby; (b) Coaching the Sport, described the sporting environment of wheelchair rugby, including the participants' coaching roles and responsibilities; and (c) Coaching the Individual, described the participants' philosophies on developing their players as both athletes on the court and as individuals in their daily lives. Results provided evidence to support the importance of informal knowledge acquisition as central in the development of these coaches. Findings were similar to those highlighted in previous disability sport literature, stressing the importance of coaching an „athlete' as opposed to a „person with a disability.' Furthermore, coaches were thoroughly invested in the holistic growth and development of their athletes and empowered their players to maximize their potential both on the court and in their daily lives. From a practical perspective, the current findings can be used to enhance the quality and standard of formal disability sport coach education and provide knowledge on best coaching practices specific to the sport of wheelchair rugby.</description><creator>Tawse, Holly</creator><contributor>Gordon Bloom (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Psychology </subject><title>An investigation into Canadian wheelchair rugby coaches: their role in the development of athletes with a spinal cord injury.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc51t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k290x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x1781</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we will follow a paper by Bryant et al. in finding the necessary and sufficient conditions for the existence of a Levi-Civita connection within a given projective structure [gamma] on a surface. We will give an explicit formulation of a necessary condition, as an obstruction of order five in the Christoffel symbols of an arbitrary element of [gamma]. Our approach in finding this obstruction allows us to find sufficient conditions in the real analytic case as well. In terms of the Christoffel symbols of an arbitrary element of [gamma], the explicit forms of the sufficient conditions are of order six in generic case, and of order eight in non-generic case. All the formulations will be projectively invariant and will be expressed in point invariants of the second-order ODE whose integral curves are geodesics of [gamma]. We will use a machinery developed by Hitchin and LeBrun, that we call minitwistor theory, to find the moduli space of these integral curves. Using this machinery and the notion of densities on a manifold, we give geometric interpretations of the formulation of the problem and derive a projective property of the space of metrics whose Levi-Civita   connections belong to [gamma].</description><description>Dans cette thèse, nous analysons un travail de Bryant et al. portant sur l'obtention de conditions nécessaires et suffisantes pour l'existence d'une connexion de Levi-Civita au sein d'une structure projective [gamma] sur une surface. Nous donnons une formulation explicite d'une condition nécessaire sous la forme d'une obstruction d'ordre cinq sur les coefficients de Christoffel d'un élément arbitraire de  [gamma]. Dans le cas analytique, notre approche nous permet d'obtenir des conditions suffisantes. En termes des coefficients de Christoffel d'un élément arbitraire de  [gamma], ces conditions suffisantes sont d'ordre six dans le cas générique et d'ordre huit dans le cas non-générique. Toutes les formulations obtenues sont projectivement invariantes et exprimées en termes d'invariants ponctuels des equations différentielles ordinaires d'ordre deux dont les solutions les géodésiques de [gamma]. Nous utlisons une technique développée par Hitchin et LeBrun, appelée théorie des mini-twisteurs, pour trouver l'espace des modules de ces courbes intégrales. En utlisant cette technique et la notion de densité sur une variété, nous donnons des interprétations géométriques de la formulation du problème et dérivons une propriété projectivement invariante de l'espace des métriques dont la connexion de Levi-Civita appartient a [gamma].</description><creator>Makhmali, Omid</creator><contributor>Niky Kamran (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics </subject><title>On the metrizability problem for projective structures on surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m198j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x1781</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn106z43g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En radiothérapie, l'intégration en données fonctionnelles de la PET au FDG au processus conventionnel de délimitation anatomique du GTV peut conduire à l'optimisation de la dose aux volumes biologiques cibles. Nous proposons une méthode pour découvrir des sous volumes tumoreaux, en utilisant des données fonctionnelles. Pour une cohorte de vingt-sept patients histo-pathologique ateints de carcinomes pulmonaires (à cellules non petites) prouvées histologiquement, les valeurs absorption de fond ont été prélevés sur les tranches contenant la tumeur dans le poumon sain controlatéral, puis amplifiée par le rapport des densités entre des tissus pulmonaires sains et tumoraux. Les valeurs d'absorption du signal de fond dans les volumes d'intérêt englobant la tumeur ont été choisies et utilisés pour calculer des histogrammes de volumes différentiels d'absorption. Ils furent ensuite décomposés en un nombre minimum de fonctions requises pour produire un ajustement analytique acceptable, tel qu'évalué par les valeurs du chi ^ 2. Pour notre population de patients, au moins quatre sous-volumes sur le volume de l'échantillon d'intérêt ont constamment évolué. Il est possible que les seuils de sous volume peuvent être extraits à partir d'histogrammes différentiels d'absorption spécifiques à chaque patient et par la suite utilisés pour la délimitation des volumes biologiques cibles. À ce stade, cependant, nous ne pouvons faire l'hypothèse que le point de passage du deuxième pic au troisième de l'histogramme de volume absorption peut aider à l'identification les tissus nécrosés, alors que le point de passage entre la fonction de montage de niveau trois à quatre peut aider à l'identification du sous volume glycolytique de la tumeur. Des études préliminaires cliniques approfondies seront nécessaires pour établir une corrélation entre ces sous-volumes et leur vraie physiologie sous-jacente.</description><description>The integration of FDG-PET functional data into conventional anatomically-based GTV delineation may lead to optimization of dose to biological target volumes in radiotherapy. We are proposing a method for uncovering tumor sub-volumes using functional data. For a cohort of 27 histo-pathologically proven non-small cell lung carcinoma patients, background uptake values were sampled over slices containing tumor within contra-lateral healthy lung and then scaled by the ratio of tissue densities between healthy lung and tumor. Signal-to-background uptake values within volumes of interest encompassing the tumor were scored from which differential uptake volume histograms were constructed. These were subsequently decomposed into the minimum number of analytical functions that yielded acceptable net fits, as assessed by chi^2 values. For our patient population, at least four sub-volumes over the sampled volume of interest consistently evolved. It is possible that sub-volume thresholds may be extracted from custom-made differential uptake volume histograms for individual patients and then subsequently used for delineation of biological target volumes. At this point, however, we can only make a hypothesis that crossing point of the second and third fitted peak of the uptake volume histogram may help in singling out necrotic tissue, while the crossing point between third and fourth fitting function may help in identification of the glycolytic sub-volume within the tumor. Extensive pre-clinical studies are needed to establish correlation between these sub-volumes and their true underlying physiology.</description><creator>Mohammed, Huriyyah</creator><contributor>Slobodan Devic (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jan Peter Frans Seuntjens (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Physics - Radiation </subject><title>Differential uptake volume histograms: a novel avenue for integration of PET data into radiotherapy treatment planning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr244.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z43g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jx34v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The combustion of modern jet fuel, known as Jet A, in aero-derived gas turbine engines is a complicated process that is not fully understood. While many attempts have been made to produce numerical and chemical models of Jet A, the current lack of consensus within literature suggests that more work remains. This work will study three pure substances, which are representative of the chemical components that comprise typical jet fuels. n-Decane represents the alkanes present in Jet A, methylcyclohexane the cyclic hydrocarbons, and toluene the aromatics. All three compounds are used to stabilize flames in a stagnation flow burner, with their velocity profiles measured using particle image velocimetry. These velocity profiles are then compared so that the relative reactivity of these three compounds can be established. It was found that the most reactive substance was n-decane, followed by methylcyclohexane, with toluene being the least reactive. In addition, the predictions of an analytical hydrodynamic model are compared to experimental results. The analytical model was found to be in good agreement under stoichiometric and fuel rich conditions, but diverges as the flames become increasingly fuel lean. This result can be explained either by issues which remain in the experimental apparatus, or by inaccuracies within data collected from literature, and this warrants further investigation. The experience gained in assembling the apparatus will be used to continue its development to facilitate future studies.</description><description>La combustion du carburant d'aviation, connu sous le nom de Jet A, dans les turbines à gaz aro-drives est un processus complexe qui n'est pas entièrement compris. Bien que de nombreuse études on été faites pour produire des modèles num ́eriques et chimiques du Jet A, l'absence de consensus dans la littérature montre qu'il reste encore du travail. Ce travail est une étude de trois substances pures, qui sont représentatifs de la composition chimique qui constituent les carburants d'aviation. Le n-décane représente les alcanes présents dans le Jet A, le méthylcyclohexane les hydrocarbures cycliques, et le toluène les aromatiques. Les trois composés sont utilisés pour stabiliser les flammes dans un brûleur à écoulement stagné, avec les profils de vitesse mesurés à l'aide de la technique de vélocimétrie par images de particules. Ces profils de vitesse sont ensuite comparés de telle sorte que la réactivité relative de ces trois composés peut être déduite. Il a été constat que la substance la plus réactive est le n-décane, suivie par le méthylcyclohexane et le toluène étant le moins réactif. Aussi, les prédictions d'un modèle analytique hydrodynamique sont comparèes aux résultats expérimentaux. Le modèle analytique a donné un bon accord sous les conditions stœchiomtrique et riche mais diverge dans les conditions de flammes pauvres. Ce résultat peut s'expliquer soit par des problèmes qui restent dans le dispositif expérimental, ou par l'inexactitude des données collectées dans la littérature, ce qui justifie plus d'investigations. L'expérience acquise dans le montage de l'appareil sera utilisé pour continuer son développement afin de faciliter les études futures.</description><creator>Fishbein, Bryan</creator><contributor>Jeffrey Bergthorson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Aerospace</subject><title>Combustion of surrogate jet fuel components in premixed stagnation flames</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c00x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jx34v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322d563</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les forces de patinage ont été mesurées directement sur glace avec un Bauer One95 (Régulier) et un second One95 qui détenait un protecteur du tendon d'Achille modifié et une configuration différente des œillets pour lacets (DROM).  Le but était de déterminer si des différences mécaniques existent dans la force de propulsion et la cinématique de la cheville entre les deux modèles. Le patin droit était instrumenté d'un système calibré d'estimation de la force qui permettait la mesure dynamique des forces durant le patinage. De plus, un goniomètre était installé autour de la cheville pour mesurer la cinématique durant le patinage. Les dix sujets accomplissaient le patinage avant et le croisé-avant dans les deux directions. Le patin DROM démontrait des gains significatifs en flexion plantaire et amplitude de mouvement frontale. En général, ces résultats ne se sont pas reflétés en bénéfices cinétiques, à l'exception des forces médio-latérales.  La force totale maximale était délayée avec le DROM, suggérant une production de force prolongée qui résultait de l'amplitude de mouvement supplémentaire. Les augmentations de 14 à 20% en travail et puissance avec le DROM ne se sont pas traduites en amélioration de vitesse. Ces trouvailles apparemment contradictoires pourraient être attribuables au manque d'accoutumance des joueurs avec le patin modifié qui procure une mobilité supérieure à la cheville.  Afin de déterminer le potentiel optimal du DROM sur la performance, une étude longitudinale avec un groupe de joueurs s'entraînant avec le DROM est nécessaire.</description><description>Dynamic forces were measured during skating directly on-ice using a Bauer One95 and a second One95 with a modified tendon guard and eyelet configuration (DROM). The intent was to determine if mechanical differences exist in push-off force and ankle kinematics between the two skates. The right skate of each type was instrumented with a calibrated force transducer system to measure medial-lateral and vertical forces during ice skating. In addition, a goniometer was installed about the ankle to measure kinematics during skating. The ten subjects executed three skills: forward skating and forward crossovers in both directions. The DROM skate demonstrated significant gains in plantarflexion and net plantar-dorsiflexion ROM. In general this was not reflected in greater kinetic output except for greater medial-lateral forces. Total peak force occurred later during plantarflexion, suggesting that the increased ROM resulted in a more prolonged force generation during a given skating stride. The 14 to 20% increases in work and power output while wearing the DROM skates did not translate into improved times for these skating tasks. These apparently contradictory findings may well be attributed to lack of player familiarity with the modified skate's greater ankle mobility. Hence, to determine the DROM skate's true performance benefits, a longitudinal study of a cohort of players training with the DROM skate is required.</description><creator>Robert-Lachaine, Xavier</creator><contributor>Rene A Turcotte (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Physical</subject><title>Force measurement and ankle motion of the forward skating and crossovers with a standard hockey skate and a modified hockey skate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g053w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d563</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386j44x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les programmes communautaires sont une approche populaire pour fournir des soins et du soutien aux orphelins du SIDA et aux orphelins et enfants vulnérables (OEV) car ils sont en mesure de fournir un service à grande échelle et ils sont informés par des réponses appropriées au niveau local  En utilisant les capacités et les théories anti-oppressives de la pratique du travail social, cette étude vise à explorer la question, "Quel est l'effet des programmes communautaires pour les orphelins du SIDA et des OEV en Afrique sub-saharienne sur les enfants ciblés et les communautés dans lesquelles ils résident?"  Une revue systématique de la littérature a été effectuée pour déterminer 39 évaluations représentant 29 différents programmes communautaires avec les financés par l'extérieur. Les résultats et l'analyse considèrent les points forts et les limites des approches locales, la participation des membres de la communauté locale et les relations entre le Nord et le Sud en ce qui concerne les partenariats de collaboration à travers les concepts de formation des capacités, la propriété et le pouvoir.  Implications pour la politique, pratique et théorie, ainsi que les limites et les possibilités pour de futures recherches, sont présentées.</description><description>Community-based programmes are a popular approach to providing care and support to AIDS orphans and vulnerable children (OVC) as they are able to operate on a large scale and are informed by locally-appropriate responses.  Using strength based and anti-oppressive theories of social work practice, this study aims to review community-based programmes for OVC in sub-Saharan Africa and explore the experiences of the targeted children and the communities in which they reside.  A systematic review of literature was completed to ascertain 39 evaluations representing 29 different externally funded community-based programmes.  The findings and analysis consider the strengths and limitations of local approaches, participation of local community members and the relationship between the North and South in regards to collaborative partnerships through the concepts of capacity building, ownership and power.  Implications for policy, practice and theory, as well as limitations and opportunities for future research, are outlined.</description><creator>Wisken, Kimberley</creator><contributor>Wendy Ann Thomson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</subject><title>A review of community-based programmes for children orphaned and made vulnerable by AIDS in sub-Saharan Africa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687h741.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j44x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zn70x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is a considerable interest in developing bioactive papers with active recognition and/or functional capabilities. Despite their distinct portability and practicability, direct sensing or recognition platform are often restricted to precisely aligned components or specific reactions. Motivated by photonic band gap materials, a non-specific color can be obtained by controlling ordered structures and further applied as an optical indicator for biosensing. In this work, polymerized colloidal crystal arrays (PCCAs) were for the first time integrated with a paper support. Since the continuous hydrogel phase can change and recover its volume by reversible hydration, the accompanying change in crystal lattice spacing imparts a visible color change due to Bragg diffraction. This material also possesses excellent salt anti-interference, extended cycling performance, and robust mechanical properties. Compared to other rigid substrates, only PCCAs on paper exhibit significant color change between the dry and hydrated states. These characteristics make paper-based polymerized colloidal crystal arrays (PB-PCCAs) promising for a new generation of sensing and anti-falsification applications. A future challenge is to develop optical changes that correspond to specific molecular recognition, perhaps by decorating the hydrogel or particles with functional groups.</description><description>Il y a un intérêt considérable dans le développement des papiers bioactifs avec des reconnaissances actives et/ou des capacités fonctionnelles. Malgré leur distinctions sur la portabilité et la praticabilité, la détection directe ou la plate-forme de reconnaissance sont souvent restreint avec composants précisément alignés ou aux réactions spécifiques. Motivé des matériaux la bande photonique écartée, une couleur non spécifiques peut être obtenue en contrôlant des structures ordonnés et d'un indicateur optique plus appliqué pour biosensing. Dans ce travail, les baies polymérisées du cristal colloïdal (PCCAs) ont été intégrée pour la première fois avec un support papier. Depuis la phase hydrogel continue peut modifier et restaurer son volume par hydratation réversible, le changement d'accompagnement en treillis de cristal en espace apporte une modification de la couleur visible en raison de la diffraction Bragg. Ce matériau possède également de l'excellente anti-interférence de sel, des performances étendues de cyclisme et des propriétés mécaniques robustes. Seul le PCCAs sur papier, par rapport aux autres substrats rigides, présentent des changements significatifs de couleur entre les états secs et hydratées. Ces caractéristiques rendent les baies polymérisées du cristal colloïdal sur papier (PB-PCCAs) prometteur pour une nouvelle génération d'applications de télédétection et anti-falsification. Un défi futur est de développer des modifications optiques qui correspondent à des reconnaissances de molécules spécifiques, peut-être par l'hydrogel ou particules avec les groupes fonctionnels de la décoration.</description><creator>Li, Mohan</creator><contributor>Theodorus G Van de Ven (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Reghan James Hill (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Paper-based polymerized colloidal crystal arrays</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gg666.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zn70x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dm64r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans de nombreux pays en voie de développement, les accouchements à domicile sont fréquents et entrainent souvent des complications imprévisibles, blessures ou autres évènements indésirables qui contribuent à la morbidité et mortalité à la fois maternelle et infantile. L'objectif de cette étude était d'identifier d'importants déterminants associés avec les accouchements à domicile afin d'éclairer les politiques de santé dans l'Amazonie péruvienne.Une étude de cas-témoins appariés a été réalisée (cas = accouchement à domicile et contrôle = accouchement à l'hopital). Les données ont été collectées par des questionnaires pré-testés administrés par un intervieweur auprès de 112 femmes qui ont accouché dans les deux mois précédant l'entrevue. Des modèles de régression logistiques simples et  multiples ont été effectués.Les résultats suggèrent que les femmes ayant un nombre réduit de visites prénatales, une scolarité peu élevée, une parité plus élevée, et un partenaire agriculteur étaient plus susceptibles d'accoucher à domicile.Ces résultats fournissent les données nécessaires à l'élaboration d'interventions locales appropriées ainsi qu'aux discussions politiques et pratiques du Ministère de la Santé concernant les accouchements à domicile.</description><description>In low-and-middle-income countries childbirth can still occur at home where unpredictable complications, infections, and other adverse events contribute to both maternal and infant morbidity and mortality. The objective of this study was to identify important determinants associated with home-based deliveries to inform health policy in the Peruvian Amazon. A one-to-one matched case-control study was conducted (case = home delivery and control = hospital delivery). Data were collected from pre-tested interviewer-administered questionnaires given to 112 women who had delivered within two months prior to the interview. Appropriate univariate and multivariate conditional logistic regression models were performed. The results suggest that women with lower number of antenatal care visits, lower education, higher parity, and partner being an agricultor were more likely to deliver at home. These findings provide much-needed local evidence to inform the development of appropriate interventions as well as local Ministry of Health discussions on policies and practices regarding home births.</description><creator>Rollet, Kathleen</creator><contributor>Theresia Gyorkos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Exploring health inequalities: determinants associated with home-based versus hospital-based deliveries in the Peruvian Amazon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569479p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dm64r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v162</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines further enhancement to ITU-T G.711.1 speech coder. The original G.711 coder is effectively a low band μ-law quantizer. The G.711.1 extension adds noise feed-back and lower band enhancement layer apart from the higher-band. To further improve the core lower-band coding performance the use of both vector quantization and delayed decision multi-path tree encoder in the above coder at the low band portion is studied.  The delayed decision multi-path tree encoding is implemented by the (M,L) – algorithm.  The new quantizer takes into account past history, and hence, the error propagation due to noise feed-back, and codes multiple samples under μ-law. The final bitstream is compatible with the G.711.1 decoder and, hence, with the original G.711 decoder. An evaluation method, ITU-T P.862 perceptual evaluation of speech quality (PESQ), is used to evaluate the performance. Both the vector quantizer and tree encoder have better performance than the original core layer encoder in terms of perceptual quality, though they are limited by the increased computational complexity. Future studies are suggested.</description><description>Cette thèse étudie en détail les améliorations apportées au codeur de la parole ITU-T G.711.1. Le codeur original G.711 est en fait un quantificateur μ-law. Le prolongement large-bande G.711.1 utilise le façonnage du bruit ainsi qu'une couche d'amélioration de la bande-basse en plus de la bande-haute. Afin d'améliorer le codage de la bande-basse principale, nous étudions l'utilisation de quantification vectorielle et la décision à retardement.  Le codeur arboriforme avec décision à retardée est réalisé par l'algorithme(M,L). Le nouveau quantificateur considère l'information passée et par conséquent, il considère également la propagation de l'erreur engendrée par le façonnage du bruit. Il code plusieurs échantillons par μ-law. Le flot binaire final est compatible avec le décodeur du prolongement large-bande G.711.1 et donc naturellement avec le décodeur du G.711 original. Une méthode d'évaluation, ITU-T P.862 (PESQ) est utilisée pour évaluer la performance. Les résultats montrent que la quantification vectorielle et le codeur arboriforme sont perceptuellement plus performants que le codeur original de la bande principale. Nous notons tout de même qu'ils sont numériquement plus complexes à réaliser. Des études supplémentaires sont suggérées.</description><creator>Khan, Abdul Hannan</creator><contributor>Peter Kabal (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Tree encoding in the ITU-T G.711.1 speech coder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66343981.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v162</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913q201</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire a pour objet le portrait dans À l'ombre des jeunes filles en fleurs. Il veut mettre en lumière le paradoxe par lequel le portrait contribue à la construction des personnages tout en faisant d'eux des êtres inaccessibles et inconnaissables, les révélant et les dissimulant tout à la fois. Le mémoire se divise en deux grandes parties. La première est consacrée au mouvement de construction du portrait, c'est-à-dire aux effets descriptifs qui consolident notre vision des personnages. La deuxième partie porte plutôt sur la « défaite du portrait » en tant qu'instrument épistémologique. Elle s'intéresse aux effets de brouillage (provoqués par les illusions optiques, le mouvement de la personne décrite ou l'empreinte de la subjectivité du narrateur) qui créent un décalage entre le portrait et le personnage décrit et qui mettent en doute l'unité et l'identité des personnages. Cette étude propose donc une lecture du roman proustien centrée sur la visualité de ce qui est décrit et utilise des concepts qui relèvent à la fois de l'art visuel et de la théorie littéraire.</description><description>This thesis examines the physical descriptions - or portraits - of the characters in À l'ombre des jeunes filles en fleurs. It explores the paradox in which these descriptions both build and reveal the characters, and, at the same time, blur them into unrecognizable personalities. The thesis is divided into two sections. The first one deals with the construction of our perception of body images through the examination of Proust's descriptive techniques. The second section discusses the "defeat of the portrait" as an epistemological tool. In particular, this section looks at the "interference" (caused by optical illusions, subject movement or narrator subjectivity) which creates a lag between the image and the person described, casting doubt on the identity and the individuality of the characters.   Finally, this study proposes a reading of the Proustian novel focused on the visuality of each character using concepts borrowed from the visual arts as well as literary theory.</description><creator>Jacques, Emmanuelle</creator><contributor>Isabelle Daunais (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Literature - General</subject><title>Le portrait dans À l'ombre des jeunes filles en fleurs</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257f36g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q201</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25975</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>