<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:00:11Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43775" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dg19p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the supranational policy engagement of  Turkish migrant associations in France and Germany in EU immigration policy process  from a comparative perspective. It seeks the answer to the following question: What  explains similarities and differences in terms of forms and levels of participation  by migrant associations in different national contexts as they engage in the EU  immigration policy process? In addressing this question, it analyzes the forms and  levels of migrants' supranational engagement by focusing on the combined impact of  emerging macro-level political opportunity structures (EU institutional context and  EU) and micro-level (collective action problems of nationally organized  stakeholders) variables. The study claims that in spite of the newly introduced  supranational channels into the EU policy process, the collective organizational  experience at the national level locks-in a certain path dependency that holds back  the new policy actors (migrant groups) from making full use of EU-level  opportunities. Consequently an incompatibility surfaces between the supranational  opportunities provided by the EU and the capabilities of national-level stakeholders  who intend to use them. Through an examination of two cases, this study claims that  there exists a supranational opportunity/national capability rift in terms of  stakeholder participation in EU policy processes. Underlying this rift are the  problems intrinsic to the design of supranational opportunities which impair their  potential to cater to national-level clients. At the same time, while national-level  capabilities allow actors to operate in the domestic context (albeit with problems),  they are not readily transposed so as to permit reaping supranational  benefits. Accordingly, this study claims that despite the variety and  extensiveness of EU efforts, the re-definition of the dynamics of policy involvement  and the expansion of the policy space to include multiple stakeholders remain at an  incipient stage. The problems and limits of activities at the supranational level  continue to originate from constraints associated with the nation state as much, if  not more, than the problems of the supranational channels  themselves.</description><creator>Ozcurumez, Saime</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Europe -- Emigration and immigration</subject><subject>Foreign workers, Turkish -- Germany -- Societies, etc.</subject><subject>Foreign workers, Turkish -- France -- Societies, etc.</subject><title>Opportunities re-structured, policy actors re-defined : EU immigration policy and Turkish migrant associations in France and Germany</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053g530.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dg19p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v62f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clients involved with child protection systems due to issues of  neglect are known to have multiple needs. The issues that they confront are  personal, situational, and social in nature. The emphasis on risk reduction in many  jurisdictions within North America has meant that needs have been given less  priority. The aim of the exploratory study was to gain a better understanding of  both the nature of needs and risks in cases of child neglect in Ontario, as well as  the similarities and differences in the views of clients and child protection  workers. It is posited that through the acquisition of knowledge in those areas,  that improvements can be made in assessing and planning, in creating agreed upon  expectations about the objectives of intervention, and in developing a better  balance between the addressing of needs and risks. For the study, an instrument was designed to measure client  perceptions of their problems and needs. It was compared with workers' perceptions  of risk as contained in the risk assessment instrument completed by all child  protection workers in Ontario. The Client Perception of Problems and Needs Scale was  administered to 77 parents receiving services from Family and Children's Services of  Renfrew County due to concerns about child neglect. The finding that participants felt their needs were greatest in  dealing with issues of stress, child behaviour and mental health issues, and in  coping with socio-economic disadvantage was congruent with the few studies that have  been conducted on the perceptions of child protection clients about their needs and  problems. The analysis of the risk assessment data provided evidence that reliance  on risk reduction at the expense of needs-based approaches, is not warranted. Few  similarities were found in the perceptions of clients and workers about the issues  of greatest concern. However, it was surprising that few concerns emerged about the  clients' living conditions, or the affective interaction between clients and their  children. Finally, the study demonstrated that the participants were able to  recognize their problems, used various coping strategies for dealing with them, and  were able to articulate strengths and resources on which they  relied.</description><creator>O'Brien, Michael J., 1952-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Child welfare workers</subject><subject>Child abuse -- Prevention</subject><subject>Child welfare</subject><title>Exploring and comparing client perception of need and social worker perception of risk : a key to improved intervention in cases of child neglect</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qx98c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v62f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nv095</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From our everyday life, we know that our hearts beat with a  rhythm which is not perfectly periodic. Even an isolated spontaneously beating  cardiac cell, devoid of neural, hormonal, and intracardiac regulatory input, does  not beat perfectly regularly. I investigate the hypothesis that the beat-to-beat  fluctuations in transmembrane potential of spontaneously beating cardiac cells are  due to stochastic gating of the ionic channels in the cell membrane. Recordings of transmembrane potential from small clusters of  spontaneously beating 7-day-old embryonic chick ventricular cells were analyzed to  characterize the voltage waveform and the regularity of beating. I constructed a  deterministic Hodgkin-Huxley-type ionic model which reproduces spontaneous activity  in our experimental recordings, as well as the experimental results of applying  various ion channel blockers (D-600, almokalant, and Ba2+). The model consists of  six currents: a calcium current (ICa), three potassium currents (IKs, I Kr, IK1), a  background current ( Ib), and a seal-leak current (I seal). The deterministic Hodgkin-Huxley-type model was then  reformulated into a stochastic single-channel model. The single-channel model  reproduces the irregularity of beating seen experimentally: e.g. the coefficient of  variation of interbeat interval was 4.4% vs. 3.9% in the clusters. In the model, IKs  is the current giving the major contributions to fluctuations in interbeat  interval. Phase resetting of the spontaneous activity of cardiac pacemaker  cells by a brief stimulus pulse was simulated in Hodgkin-Huxley-type models and  single-channel models of slow-upstroke (central) and fast-upstroke (peripheral)  rabbit sinoatrial node cells. In the Hodgkin-Huxley-type models the phase-resetting  response is continuous, but can be extremely delicate in the fast-upstroke model, in  that a tiny difference in the stimulus timing can change the stimulus response from  a delayed action potential to an advanced one. Therefore, the noise in the  fast-upstroke single-channel model can cause a stimulus with fixed amplitude and  fixed timing to have widely different effects: sometimes it will induce an action  potential but in other cases it will delay an action potential, as seen previously  in experiments on cardiac preparations.</description><creator>Krogh-Madsen, Trine</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Effects of single-channel noise on spontaneous beating and the phase-resetting response of cardiac oscillators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc66f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nv095</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w521k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biophysical simulations of memory must choose which aspects of  known neurophysiology and neuroanatomy to model. Relevant aspects were constrained  by functional requirements determined for on-line acquisition in context dependent  memory, memory that is retrieved by contextual cues. In an on-line task, the  protocol of data presentation and the tunes at which encoding or retrieval in memory  is needed are not predetermined. A sequence of neuronal spike patterns representing  items may be presented only once. Yet, episodic memory of the sequence immediately  encodes the temporal context of familiar items, a process known to depend on  hippocampal function. For this, interference caused by overlapping spike patterns  must be avoided, a requirement that suggested the relevance of coincidental spiking.  Overlap in the input to the hippocampus was reduced by recruiting such spikes in a  model of encoding in dentate gyrus. Durable encoding is required in the hippocampus,  since hippocampal damage can cause retrograde amnesia in context dependent memory  that spans years. Long-lasting synaptic changes involved modeling relevant  neurophysiology concerning protein production elicited by the spaced reactivation of  spike patterns. The likelihood of reactivation was increased by the well-known  process of long-term potentiation of synaptic transmission. Such potentiation is  elicited when a presynaptic spike precedes a postsynaptic spike within a specific  time window repeatedly. The intervals in a sequence of spike patterns must be  compressed and the sequence repeated, requirements that were achieved with a model  of short-term memory based on persistent spiking. Retrieval may be concurrent with  these encoding processes due to effects of different phases of a brain rhythm at  theta frequency (3-12 Hz) that modulate transmission and plasticity. A model of  short-term memory by Lisman and Idiart (Science 267:1512-15), extended by Jensen et  al. (Learning and Memory 3:243</description><creator>Koene, Randal A.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Memory.</subject><subject>Hippocampus (Brain)</subject><subject>Neurophysiology.</subject><title>Functional requirements determine relevant ingredients to model for on-line acquisition of context dependent memory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dw03k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w521k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q681b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Seniors 75 years of age and older, the majority of whom live in  the community, constitute a segment of the population that is vulnerable to loss of  autonomy. Indeed many community dwelling seniors have difficulty performing daily  living activities, such as bathing, toileting, walking, preparing meals and  housekeeping. In the setting of a population based cohort study of  community-dwelling seniors 75 years of age or older, we examined the effect of unmet  needs for community services for activities of daily living (ADL) and instrumental  activities of daily living (IADL) on health services utilization. Self-perceived  unmet need status was determined using a baseline in-home interview. A total of 839  subjects were recruited from the Greater Montreal Region, Quebec, Canada, using  random telephone number dialling. Health services utilization data were obtained from  administrative databases from the Quebec Health Insurance Board (Regie de  l'Assurance-Maladie du Quebec - RAMQ). Multivariable negative binomial regression  models were used to examine the association between unmet need status and health  services utilization during the six month period following the baseline  interview. The results of this study indicate that unmet needs are  associated with higher rates of emergency department visits, hospitalization and  prescription drug use. No statistically significant association was found between  unmet needs and physician utilization among single seniors, although married seniors  with unmet needs in activities of daily living had 2.8 times the rate of medical  specialist visits as compared to those who reported no unmet ADL  needs. Unmet need for community services among the elderly has  implications for the use of more expensive acute and long-term health care services.  The results of this research suggest that developing programs to address unmet needs  in the elderly population can potentially reduce health services utilization by the  elderly.</description><creator>Podoba, John E.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Gerontology.</subject><title>Unmet needs for community services among the elderly : impact on health services utilization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pg70s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q681b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dm79c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pituitary gland is a very convenient model to study  mechanisms implicated in cellular differentiation. This endocrine gland is composed  of six cell lineages, each committed to the production of a different hormone:  thyrotrophs (TSH), somatotrophs (GH), lactotrophs (PRL), gonadotrops (LH, FSH),  melanotrophs (alpha-MSH) and corticotrophs (ACTH). ACTH and alpha-MSH are both  processed from the same precursor, proopiomelanocortin (POMC). Pituitary  hormone-producing cells differentiate sequentially from a common epithelial  primordium, Rathke's pouch, under the combinatorial action of a subset of tissue-  and cell-restricted transcription factors. In corticotrophs, Tpit and NeuroD1 are  important for POMC transcription. Their expression closely precedes that of POMC,  suggesting a role in the differentiation of this lineage. In order to better define  the role of Tpit in POMC cell differentiation, we generated Tpit-null mice. These  mice are deficient in POMC-expressing cells while other pituitary lineages are  normal. Analysis of other corticotroph markers, such as NeuroD1, showed that lineage  commitment was preserved in absence of Tpit. We next tested if Tpit and -NeuroD1  could be jointly required for corticotroph determination by producing Tpit-/-  NeuroD1-/- mice. This experiment revealed that these two factors are not essential  for early determination of corticotroph cells, suggesting different levels of  control for commitment of POMC lineages compared to cell survival or to  cell-specific transcription of POMC. Further investigation of Tpit-/- mice has  revealed that Tpit is a negative regulator of the gonadotroph fate. These studies  suggest a binary model of cell fate decisions for pituitary cell differentiation,  suggesting the presence of a pituitary pluripotent precursor. Finally we have shown  that mutations in the coding sequence of human TPIT are associated with isolated  ACTH deficiency, a pathology very similar to that found in Tpit-null m</description><creator>Pulichino, Anne-Marie</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Implication du facteur Tpit dans la différenciation hypophysaire et la pathogenèse du déficit corticotrope</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225b53m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dm79c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p5172</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Canadian government introduced its Multicultural and  Employment Equity policies in a series of attempts to induce federally-controlled  institutions to reflect the racial diversity of the Canadian population in their  programs and workforces. This is a case study of one institution's response to these  policies. It examines the implementation of the six-year New Initiatives in Film  (NIF) program begun in 1990 by the now-defunct women's filmmaking unit, Studio D of  the National Film Board of Canada (NFB) and exposes the fault lines along which the  goals of the NFB's various constituent parts clashed and meshed with the diverse  goals of various parties in NIF's target communities (i.e. "emergent aboriginal  and 'of colour' women filmmakers"). I argue that because the NIF program was  structured according to the politics of identity ("race" in this case),  "artworld" issues of unfair hiring and funding practices in the Canadian  film industry, became distorted and expressed as issues of identity. Obfuscating the  professional dynamics in the world of Canadian filmmaking by using "race"  as an organizing principle did not, in the long-term, assure the sustained inclusion  of excluded groups within mainstream institutions. A more effective strategy, the  data suggests, would have been for underrepresented groups to cultivate alliances  with professionals in the filmmaking industry based on concrete occupational, rather  than hypothetical race-based interests.</description><creator>Nambiar, Gleema</creator><date>2004</date><subject>National Film Board of Canada. Studio D.</subject><subject>Motion picture industry -- Canada -- Sociological aspects.</subject><subject>Multiculturalism -- Canada.</subject><title>Using identity politics to address artworld issues : a case study of the New Initiatives in Film program at the National Film Board of Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634416r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p5172</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064661q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis highlights novel synthetic routes towards the facile  synthesis of lariat DNA and RNA oligonucleotides, and the utilities of branched  (bNAs) and circular (i.e. dumbbell-shaped) nucleic acids for targeting biologically  relevant processes (i.e. HIV proliferation, alternative RNA splicing) with potential  therapeutic applications. An innovative synthetic strategy for the synthesis and  cyclization of a medium-sized (21-nucleotide) DNA lariat starting from a  CPG-tethered, convergently synthesized branched DNA (bDNA) molecule was devised in  Chapter 2. This synthetic route exploited the differential cleavage rates of two  CPG-oligonucleotide tethers, namely the base-labile hydroquinone-O,O'-diacetate  (Q-linker) and the more robust succinate (S-linker ) linkages, as well as  phosphitylation of the 5'-oligonucleotide terminus and cyclization under standard  phosphoramidite coupling conditions to effect new phosphodiester bond construction.  The results clearly indicate a disadvantageous correlation between high branching  efficiency on a densely loaded CPG and the production of dendrimeric (i.e.  hyperbranched) oligonucleotide species rather than effective  cyclization. Given the entropic disadvantage of synthesizing medium-sized DNA  lariats on solid-support using the method described in Chapter 2, unique  intermolecular (i.e. DNA dumbbells) and intermolecular template-mediated approaches  for lariat cyclization commencing with convergently and divergently synthesized  bDNAs and bRNAs were developed in Chapter 3. Both methods lead to the exclusive and  high-yielding formation of medium sized (46--57 nucleotides) DNA and RNA lariats.  Parameters for successful phosphodiester bond construction were also elucidated in  both systems. A novel class of highly specific and potent  oligonucleotide-based HIV-1 reverse transcriptase inhibitors, RNA dumbbells,  comprising of a 10 base-pair stem and two flanking UUCG hairpin-loop motifs are  described in Chapter 4. Explicitly, such constructs were capable of selectively  hampering the RNase-H mediated activity of the retroviral enzyme without consequence  to its DNA polymerase function with an IC50 in the 3 muM range. Its precise  interaction with the RNase H domain of RT was authenticated via a UV-crosslinking  assay. Furthermore, the RNA dumbbells did not inflict any effect on mammalian RNase  H activity, suggesting that such compounds would not obstruct cellular RNase H  function. Chapter 5 describes the utility of synthetic bRNA for the  inhibition and modulation of pre-mRNA splicing in yeast and mammalian in vitro  systems. Most notably, synthetic bNAs can be suitably exploited as agents for the  study of branchpoint recognition during in vitro splicing of a pre-mRNA transcript.  The results clearly indicate the requirement for a fully formed branchpoint (i.e. 5  '-, 2'- and 3'-extensions; Y-shaped molecules) off the conserved branchpoint  adenosine for efficient splicing inhibition. Specific methods for stabilizing bNAs  against ubiquitous cellular exo- and endonucleases as well as the 2'-scissle  (2'-debranching) activity present in the HeLa extract milieu are also described.</description><creator>Carriero, Sandra</creator><contributor>Damha, Masad J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Chemical synthesis and biological evaluation of circular, branched and lariat oligonucleotides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c20d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064661q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s0723</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the effects of performance feedback on  negotiator emotions, interpersonal influence, negotiator behavior, and negotiation  outcomes. A model based on the role of emotions in dyadic negotiation is proposed  that comprises relationships amongst variables before, during, and after  negotiation. This model is based on four major elements: namely, cognitive  appraisal, emotional specificity, emotional flux, and interpersonal influence, and  their influence on negotiator behavior and negotiation outcomes. A 2 x 4 x 4 (Negotiation Role x Feedback Conditions for the  Negotiator x Feedback Conditions for the Counterpart) experimental study was  designed to examine the effects of performance feedback during negotiation in a  simulation based on an employment contract negotiation. The experiment consisted of  two negotiation tasks that were completed sequentially. The emotions of the  participants were manipulated after Task 1 by providing them four types of  performance feedback in Task 1. These feedbacks were based on two valences (success  or failure) and two agency attributes (other locus of responsibility or self locus  of responsibility). Four hundred and fourteen participants from executive and  academic programs at a Pakistani university took part in this study. The data were  analyzed using general linear models, linear multiple regressions, and Pearson  correlational analysis to test: (1) the arousal of negotiator emotions after Task 1  as a result of appraisal of the performance feedback, (2) the influence of  negotiator emotions on negotiator behavior during Task 2, (3) the interpersonal  influence of counterpart emotions and behavior during Task 2 on negotiator behavior  in Task 2, (4) the effect of negotiator behavior in Task 2 on negotiation outcomes,  (5) the effect of negotiation outcomes on post-negotiation emotions and the desire  for future interaction. The results supported the hypothesized relationships in the  proposed model. The treatment effect was successful in producing the four factors of  emotions: namely, anger, guilt-shame, gratitude, and pride-achievement emotions,  corresponding to the four types of performance feedback. The negotiator behavior was  predicted by these emotions along with counterpart emotions and behavior according  to the proposed model. The negotiation outcomes were related to negotiator and  counterpart behaviors. Negotiator satisfaction was the main predictor of  post-negotiation emotions and the desire for future interaction, although economic  negotiation outcomes played some role as well.</description><creator>Butt, Arif Nazir</creator><contributor>Jaeger, Alfred M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Negotiation -- Psychological aspects</subject><subject>Emotions.</subject><title>The role of emotions in dyadic negotiation : an empirical study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj476.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s0723</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nb72q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mining and mineral exploration have been a source of  considerable tension in the developing world and specifically where they take place  on indigenous lands. This thesis investigates the nature of the relationships  between different stakeholders to a mineral exploration project in Fiji. It is an  examination of the obstacles to community participation, a key component of  even-handed development, in the planning and policy-making process. It is argued  that the Namosi exploration project has been the locus for emergent social  disruption. It is also argued, that the causes of this conflict are anchored in a  flawed process of policy-making between the state and exploration companies and the  contest for authority between key actors, which has led to the disempowerment of  some villagers from both within and outside the community. Equally, the political  ideology of the state and the contentious history of mining in Fiji, have played a  part in the tendency towards social conflict in association with minerals  exploration. The starting point for analysis has been a comparison with the  social conflict literature as it applies to Papua New Guinea. The purpose has been  first, to confirm the relevance of that work to situations encountered in Fiji, and  second, to provide a broader critique of the literature than previously available;  one that further develops understanding of social conflict related to natural  resource development. Given the circumstances of state and village politics in  Melanesia, the question is asked, whether the normative 'fully realised communities'  anticipated by Selznick in his communitarian idyll can be achieved. The thesis  concludes that the nature of community involvement in development planning for  mineral exploitation, creates a very different type of participation than that  outlined in the literature of mining corporations and states. Although some actors  have recourse to other means of empowering themselves, this is not a prelude to  development for the wider community.</description><creator>McShane, Francis Bernard</creator><contributor>Wenzel, George (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Milne, Simon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Natural resources -- Management -- Citizen participation.</subject><subject>Prospecting -- Fiji</subject><subject>Mines and mineral resources -- Fiji</subject><subject>Social conflict -- Papua New Guinea</subject><title>Mining tradition or breaking new ground? : minerals exploration and stakeholder realtionships in Fiji</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451j049.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nb72q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r1420</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyses the process of social construction of  women's citizenship rights in Peru under the regime of Alberto Fujimori  (1990--2000). It builds on an existing body of literature on democratization and  women's movements in Latin America, to develop an understanding of the forms of  women's mobilization under new democratic regimes and the impact of the pattern of  state-society relations on the advancements and losses in women's citizenship  rights. More specifically, it shows that the 1990s witnessed a significant range of  advances in women's civil and political rights, while social and economic rights  suffered serious reversals. It is argued that the strategies and opportunities of  different sectors of the women's movement in Peru, as well as the objectives pursued  by the state under Fujimori's rule, combined to generate this evolution of women's  citizenship. The forms of mobilization of these different sectors followed the  course of their own constraints and choices, while they were also importantly shaped  by the broader political framework: a neopopulist model of political rule together  with the implementation of a neoliberal program of structural adjustment and  liberalization. The influence of a set of international factors also contributed to  structuring the political incentives and resources of the different actors involved  in the social construction of women's citizenship in Peru. The thesis concludes that  the democratic or authoritarian nature of the political regime as such cannot  explain the pattern of construction of women's citizenship rights, as witnessed by  an increased space of women in the public sphere and advances in civil and political  rights under the restricted version of political democracy which characterized most  of Fujimori's rule. Contrary to the literature on other Latin American women's  movements, which detected a marginalization of women's movements in the political  sphere following the transitions to d</description><creator>Rousseau, Stéphanie</creator><contributor>Oxhorn, Philip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Women's rights -- Peru -- History</subject><subject>Peru -- History -- 1980- -- Women</subject><subject>Women -- Peru -- History</subject><subject>Women in public life -- Peru -- History</subject><title>Women and the public sphere in Peru : citizenship under Fujimori's neopopulist rule</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh61g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r1420</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fx35p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This longitudinal inquiry into the academic literacy practices  of ten Turkish scholars of International Relations (IR) attempts to answer three  broad questions: what factors have affected the participants' acquisition and  maintenance of academic reading and writing skills; what patterns of similarities  and differences can be found among their literacy practices; and what relationships  might be discovered between the various factors and the scholars' literacy  practices. Data for the study were collected through observations, autobiographical  accounts of the participants' literacy practices via interviews, and textual  analysis of the participants' published works. The theoretical framework for the study draws on neo-Vygotskian  Activity Theory and Bakhtinian Dialogic Theory, to create a model for uncovering and  understanding the contextual factors mediating scholars' academic literacy  practices. The model begins with the assumption that scholars operate within  multiple "activity systems" (Engstrom, 1990), in this case: (1) the core  American IR discipline; (2) the local Turkish IR discipline/particular Turkish IR  departments; and (3) Turkish society. The model reconceptualizes the idea of  activity systems as "filters," which mediate individuals' production and  reception of texts, i.e. their literacy practices. Conflicts may arise according to  the "thickness" of a filter and depending on the "operational  means" acceptable within it. By contributing to a deeper understanding of how people acquire  and maintain academic literacy skills in a second language the study ultimately aims  to aid in the construction of pedagogical models and approaches that reflect the  complex nature of these multi-lingual literacy practices.</description><creator>Mathews, Julie</creator><contributor>Maguire, Mary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</subject><subject>Language and culture -- Turkey</subject><subject>Communication in learning and scholarship -- Turkey</subject><title>Mediating academic literacy practices in a second language : portraits of Turkish scholars of international relations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f3998.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx35p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967417g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores insecurity about four types of involuntary  work transition. These are labeled here domain insecurities and include job facet  insecurity, job loss insecurity, occupation insecurity and employment insecurity.  The primary purpose was to distinguish the insecurities conceptually and demonstrate  their independence empirically. The domain insecurities were defined and their  features identified from a review of literature on various work attitudes. Viable  cognitive and affective measures of insecurity were suggested from the conceptual  discussion. Data were collected through a self-report questionnaire distributed  using a snowball methodology. Validation of the proposed insecurity measures against  reliable correlates of insecurity (pessimism and anxiety) supported operationalizing  insecurity by affect alone. Correlation analysis clearly distinguished the domain  insecurities. The secondary purpose of the thesis was to explore the content and  nomological network of the domain insecurities. To this end, key features of the  domain insecurities were scrutinized. This analysis particularly set employment  insecurity apart from the other insecurities. Data were collected on antecedents and  coping with the insecurities. Multiple regression analysis using a repeated-measures  design yielded common antecedents of the four insecurities. A significant  interaction emerged between age and domain, reflecting different occupational and  employment concerns across age groups. Factor analysis with varimax rotation of the  coping checklist developed for this thesis supported the formation of four coping  scales: palliation, job search, self-development through education, and withdrawal.  Multiple regression analysis using a repeated-measures design revealed that people  cope with all insecurities through palliation, withdrawal and self-development  activities. Significant interactions emerged that confirmed the targeted use of job  search activities in</description><creator>Milton-Feasby, Christine</creator><contributor>Jaeger, Alfred (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Career changes.</subject><subject>Adjustment (Psychology)</subject><subject>Security (Psychology)</subject><subject>Job security.</subject><title>An exploration of the domains of work insecurity /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb57m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967417g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b655t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My dissertation focuses on the rise and spread of Aboriginal  mobilization in Canada between 1951 and 2000. Using social movement and  social-political theories, it questions the relationship between contentious actions  and formal organizational growth comparing among social movement and political  sociological perspectives. In most accounts, contentious action is assumed to be  influenced by organization, political opportunity and identity. Few scholars,  however, have examined the reverse relationships, namely the effect of contentious  action on each of these. Drawing upon time-series data and qualitative interviews  with Aboriginal leaders and representatives of organizations, I found that critical  events surrounding moments of federal state building prompted contentious action,  which then sparked mobilization among Aboriginal communities. I argue that three  events: the 1969 White paper, the 1982 patriation of the Constitution, and the 1990  'Indian Summer' led to mass mobilization and the semblance of an emerging  PanAboriginal identity. This finding returns to older collective behaviour  perspectives, which note that organizations, opportunities, and identities are  driven by triggering actions and shared experiences that produce emerging norms.  Nevertheless, in the case of Canadian Aboriginal mobilization, unlike that of  Indigenous movements in other countries, building a movement on triggering actions  led to mass mobilization but was not sustainable because of a saturation of  efficacy. As a result, Aboriginal mobilization in Canada has been characterized by  divergent interests and unsustained contention.</description><creator>Ramos, Howard</creator><contributor>Staggenborg, Suzanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- Canada</subject><subject>Indians of North America -- Canada -- Politics and government</subject><title>Divergent paths : aboriginal mobilization in Canada, 1951-2000</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n3880.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b655t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139245q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study of 120 early adolescents (59 girls, 61 boys), 81  of whom were identified as gifted, overall psychosocial maturity (or  social-perspective coordination) was measured and related to academic ability and  adolescents' perceptions of friendship quality and self-concept. Gifted status, sex,  and grade significantly* predicted overall psychosocial maturity in multiple  regression analyses. Conversely, as a group, overall social-perspective  coordination, perceptions of one's ability to make and keep friends (close  friendship self-concept), academic ability, sex, and grade level predicted the  overall quality of adolescents' friendships. Being a female, seventh grader, or  adolescent not identified as gifted, significantly predicted friendship quality. In  addition, higher developmental levels of psychosocial maturity and close friendship  self-concept predicted higher levels of friendship quality. Finally, when a measure  of interpersonal negotiation strategies in hypothetical situations was entered into  the prediction model in place of overall psychosocial competence, it appeared to be  a better predictor of friendship quality. Specifically, higher levels of  psychosocial competence were associated with higher levels of help, closeness, and  lower levels of social comparison in friendship experiences. Likewise, the ability  to think of higher levels of negotiation strategies was associated with higher  levels of closeness and help, and with lower levels of social comparison and  conflict in friendship experiences. *Throughout the text, the term significance refers to  statistical significance, rather than a meaning of importance.</description><creator>Masden, Catherine A.</creator><contributor>Shore, Bruce M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Gifted teenagers.</subject><subject>Friendship in adolescence.</subject><subject>Interpersonal relations in adolescence.</subject><title>Social-perspective coordination in gifted early adolescent friendships</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bv084.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139245q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pw58k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dissertation A Broad Aesthetic: beauty, truth, and goodness  , takes into consideration three distinct but related aspects of aesthetics:  perception, appreciation, and evaluation (beauty, truth, and goodness respectively).  A central concern in an avowedly broad aesthetics is to attend, equally, to the  bounds of the experiences or activities under consideration. Hence, this  dissertation is a exploration of the breadth, but also of the limits, of certain  aesthetic experiences and art-based activities (e.g., the appreciation and  evaluation of artworks). It is a consideration of what shapes these experiences,  and, also of the delimitation of these experiences and activities. Section one  (beauty) considers the nature of aesthetic perception, and the limits of its reach.  Section two (truth), looks at the role of style, both its scope and limit, in the  classification and appreciation of a certain genre of fine writing (philosophy), as  well as a certain genre of filmmaking (the documentary). Section three (goodness)  looks at the role and relevance of moral values and interests in the evaluation, as  well as in the curation, of artworks.</description><creator>Risser, Rita</creator><contributor>Stroud, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Davies, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Truth (Aesthetics)</subject><subject>Art and morals.</subject><subject>Aesthetics</subject><title>A broad aesthetic : beauty, truth, and goodness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm82p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pw58k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bp76j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a study of educational change that was carried out at  the School of Education (SOE) of the University of Cape Town's (UCT) in July 1998.  It is about institutional and human transformation in South African higher education  in 1998. The context of this inquiry is situated in South African society and polity  from the start of the Apartheid era in the late nineteenth century colonization by  the Britain, through the 1948 period of minority Afrikaner nationalist government,  and to the time of the historic democratic election in 1994. It deals with  postapartheid policies aimed at eliminating apartheid in all areas of society and  education. The thesis examines new educational policies and practices that resulted  from postapartheid transformational initiatives that addressed past inequities and  injustices committed against the African and black majority  population. South African universities were charged with the responsibility  of increasing access to formerly excluded students and staff, in circumstances of  declining economic fortunes. My central research question was concerned with the  changes that had been brought about in the educational system to enable the process  of transformation to come about. More specifically, I inquired whether changes had  occurred at UCT and if they did, to what extent could they be indicative of a  transition from apartheid to a democratic ideal. The research targets the  respondents' (students, teachers, administrators) views of transformational  experiences, whether positive or negative. The research adopts a case study approach  to gain insights into transformation in South African universities' reform  process. UCT was chosen as the focus of this study because as the  country's first university established in 1829, it has distinguished itself in many  fields and yet has remained largely a historically all white university, up to 1994.  The University was also the first to be led by an African female academic leader,  the Vice-Chancellor, Dr. Mamphela Ramphele, to transformation. This study found that  the University had been greatly transformed at an intellectual and administrative  level. Notably, access for disadvantaged South African students has been improved;  teaching and learning encouraged critical thinking and participation, and  administrators demonstrated dedication to democratic change. However, the study also  reveals that there is still a gap between the expectations of a top-notch research  university and preparation of students; financial restraints still limit students'  learning opportunities. Race, gender, and class issues still constrain efforts to  fully democratise the University. Also, the constructs and content of knowledge  require changes that reflect a democratic ethos. The significance of this study lies in its attempts to form a  part of the growing body of research concerned with conflict resolution, peace, and  the maintenance of stability in South Africa and indirectly, in the world. This  study furthermore exposes a view of what open education means within the South  African context. In highlighting the example of UCT's SOE, the most outstanding  feature of this work is that it formulates questions about the actual nature and  process of educational, pedagogical, and administrative transformation taking place  in contemporary South African universities.</description><creator>Taylor, Philip J.</creator><date>2002</date><subject>Educational change -- South Africa -- Cape Town</subject><subject>University of Cape Town. School of Education</subject><title>Fruits of democratic education transformation in a South African university in 1998 : perspectives of administrators, teachers, and students in the School of Education : University of Cape Town</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mj51s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bp76j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kq90c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Five "critical" utopias by Quebec women writers (  L'Euguelionne and Le pique-nique sur l'Acropole by Louky Bersianik; Le silence de la  Cite and Chroniques du Pays des Meres by Elisabeth Vonarburg and L'Espace du diamant  by Esther Rochon) make up the corpus of this thesis which aims to explore how the  three novelists exploit the possibilities of this particular form of contemporary  utopian writing. For these authors, the transformation of society depends upon the  transformation of the individual. We therefore propose to examine the ways in which  Bersianik, Vonarburg and Rochon represent, through the experiences of their  characters, the social construction of individual identity. For our corpus, this  entails a study both of the representations of gender and of the role of language in  the construction of identity. We explore gender from a feminist perspective by  examining the initial dystopian situation of the individual living in society; we  then analyze the positive (i.e. eutopian) process of change undergone by the  individual. This thesis begins by exploring a definition of literary utopia.  We then trace the major periods in the history of literary utopia to provide  background for our corpus. In chapter two, we examine the ways in which Bersianik,  Vonarburg and Rochon denounce, through their fictional representations of the  individual, dystopian configurations of gender. In particular, we study various  "structural" metaphors used by the authors to interrogate the social role  of women and the status of the female body in patriarchal society. In chapter three,  we examine the new configurations of social and sexual identity proposed by the  authors. We then study the author's treatment of the role of language in the social  construction of individual identity in chapter four. After defining  "sociolect" and introducing "sexualect", we apply these concepts  to the study of the critique of sexist language and discourses of authority in our  corpus. In chapter five, we explore how the authors employ discursive strategies,  such as parody and "defamiliarization", to alter language and thus  inscribe female subjectivity in language (Bersianik and Vonarburg) and to liberate  individuals from the imprisonment of authoritarian discourses (Bersianik, Vonarburg  and Rochon). Lastly, we find that after having examined the human condition in  dystopian societies, our authors propose social projects that are infinitely dynamic  and mutable rather than fixed models of an ideal social state.</description><creator>Taylor, Sharon C.</creator><contributor>Everett, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Vonarburg, Elisabeth, 1947- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Rochon, Esther, 1948- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Women in literature</subject><subject>Utopias in literature</subject><subject>Dystopias in literature</subject><subject>Bersianik, Louky -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Dystopies et eutopies féminines : L. Bersianik, E. Vonarburg, E. Rochon</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tf936.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kq90c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq067</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative study researched the meaning of instruction in  a cycle one classroom. The following questions guided my research: How is literacy  instruction implemented in a cycle one classroom? (a) What events take place in the  class? (b) How does the teacher provide for instruction? (c) How do students and  parents perceive instruction? Literacy instruction was defined as any support or intervention  on the part of a teacher or more capable other that helped students to more  skilfully engage with a range of texts in purposeful and socially responsible  ways. I collected data through classroom observation, collection of  classroom artefacts, and interviews. Observations and informal interviews were  recorded in my researcher's journal. Formal interviews were audio or videotaped. I  used complementary approaches of analysis. (a) Two inter-related types of literacy  events occurred in the classroom: formatted and open-ended activities. Formatted  activities required students to participate in a way that could potentially be  assessed. During open-ended activities students were free to select their oven  activities and to participate to the extent that they wished. Analysis of the data  revealed that, even during formatted activities, students had a great deal of choice  in how they could participate in literacy events. As a result, almost all literacy  events were tailored to meet diverse individual needs. (b) Bea simultaneously  deepened and thickened instruction to support the literacy development of students.  Deepening instruction refers to the fine-tuned precision that characterized the  instruction she offered, and ensured that activities were neither too easy nor too  difficult for students. Thickening instruction refers to how Bea enriched teaching  by attending to variety and interest around activities and appealing to broader  social, emotional and embodied needs. This seemed to contribute to learning by  keeping alive a spirit of excitement and purpose in students, parents and Bea. The  concept of deepening and thickening reflects instruction that is consistent with a  socially situated view of literacy. (c) Students provided fresh insights by  emphasizing the need to attend to embodied aspects of learning and instruction.  Parents' contradictory expectations of instruction also suggested the need for  continued ongoing collaboration between parents and educators.</description><creator>Stewart, Mary Sheilah</creator><contributor>Butler-Kisber, Lynn (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Language arts (Elementary)</subject><subject>Reading (Elementary)</subject><title>Literacy instruction in a cycle one classroom : a qualitative study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rh51x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq067</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k56b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines institutional change in forest management in  Tlalmanalco, Mexico, over the period 1877--1999 based on qualitative methods. The  level of analysis is the domain of forest management, a level of analysis  intermediary between macro/national policy and micro/local organizations and groups.  I examine the domain composed of local organizations stakeholders in forest  management in Tlalmanalco. The dual research methods include (1) a contextualist approach  revealing long institutional cycles over the long run (1877--1996) while (2)  grounded theory procedures reveal micro-processus of institutional change in the  transition period 1996--1999. At the macro level, I have identified three institutional cycles  of forest management: (1) the entrepreneur elite cycle (1877--1910); (2) the  community-based management (1910--1940); and (3) the centralized industrial cycle  (1940--1991). Each institutional cycle represents a management template which  includes: (1) a management philosophy, (2) a dominant organizational template, (3) a  configuration of interorganizational relations, (4) included groups, (5) excluded  groups and (6) blind spots. At the micro-institutional level, the detailed study of the  change process (1996--1999) in forest management reveals that two forms of  interorganizational collaborations co-exist in the current domain. First,  transformational collaboration is a form of open participation coordinated around  charismatic leadership, and based on shared values. It aims to build a collective  vision for the future of forest management. Second, transactional collaboration is a  form of participation restricted to specific tasks, coordinated by the exchange of  material and expertise resources. The contributions of this ideographic study highlight two themes  neglected so far by previous research on institutional change. First, this study  shows the links between policies formulated at the macro/national level and their  implications at the micro/local level. Second, it explores the process of  institutional change between two long term institutional cycles.</description><creator>Raufflet, Emmanuel. 1967-</creator><contributor>Westley, Frances (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Forest management -- Mexico -- Tlalmanalco de Velázquez.</subject><title>Institutional change and forest management : the case of Tlalmanalco, Mexico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jb940.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k56b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430528d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During development of the visual system of Drosophila  melanogaster , growth cones at the tips of advancing photoreceptor axons respond to  instructive cues in the environment and are guided toward appropriate synaptic  partners within the optic lobe of the brain. Research has focused on the  identification of these molecular cues, their receptors and the signaling processes  that mediate their function. This thesis describes the Drosophila line GSd447, which  possesses a P element that can support GAL4-mediated transcriptional activation of a  gene near the site of insertion. GAL4-driven misexpression of GSd447 in the eye disc  causes the R1-R6 photoreceptor axons to be mistargeted. The mistargeted R1-R6 axons  fail to terminate in the lamina, and project to a deeper layer in the medulla of the  optic lobe. To identify the gene(s) causing these axon targeting defects, two  different approaches were used; a candidate gene analysis using UAS-transgenes, and  a chemical mutagenesis screen to suppress the mistargeting defects caused by GSd447.  Both approaches strongly suggested the NF-kappaB transcription factor, Dorsal, was  responsible for the axon targeting defects. In addition, a mutation of cactus, which  encodes the inhibitor of Dorsal, was found to genetically interact with GSd447  misexpression to enhance the observed axon targeting defects. Both dorsal and cactus  are expressed in photoreceptor cell bodies. Studies of dorsal mutants revealed  moderate axon targeting defects using the dorsal alleles identified in the  suppression screen. No defects have been found to date in cactus mutants, but severe  loss-of-function cactus alleles have not yet been tested. Together, these results  and recent studies by others provide evidence for an important role for components  of the NF-kappaB signaling pathway in the development of the nervous system in both  vertebrates and invertebrates.</description><creator>Mindorff, Elizabeth</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>NF-kappaB signaling and photoreceptor axon guidance in Drosophila melanogaster</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096756z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430528d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bx69r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When one learns a novel motor skill, retention of that skill  requires consolidation of motor learning. Previous reports have shown that preceding  sessions of motor learning can interfere with the acquisition of new tasks and that  new motor learning can disrupt previously retained skills. A recent study by  Caithness et al. (2004) shows that new learning, even after long delays, can totally  disrupt prior retention. This finding is consistent with the idea that re-activated  memories become labile and subject to displacement. However the result is difficult  to reconcile with day-to-day experience in which skills improve with repetition and  are not disrupted by unrelated activities. In this experiment, we show that when  subjects learn new dynamics the influence of one task on another depends on the  similarity of the force fields involved. We used a robotic manipulandum to define  environments in which subjects learned to move. We used an AB design in which  subjects learned field A on day one and B on day 2. We show that the effect of  having learned environment A 24-hours prior to learning B varies along a continuum  from facilitation when they are identical, through little effect when they are  unrelated, to total interference when they are opposite. These findings thus  indicate that the nervous system encodes information about dynamics in a fashion  that is predictable on the basis of the similarity between the initial and final  training environments. One month following their initial training, we tested  subjects environment C, whose dynamics were opposite to B. Performance on this task  suggests that the nervous system retained neither discrete instances of past  training nor solely the most recent motor learning, but instead constructed a  running average of learned dynamics to build an individual's motor  repertoire.</description><creator>Mattar, Andrew A. G.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Memory.</subject><subject>Motor learning.</subject><title>On the retention of learned dynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q544.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bx69r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v8423</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydroxamate siderophore receptor FhuA is a TonB-dependent outer  membrane protein of Escherichia coli composed of a C-terminal 22-stranded  beta-barrel occluded by an N-terminal globular cork domain. During transport of  siderophores into the periplasm, FhuA is proposed to undergo conformational changes  that may form a pathway across the barrel. To probe structural changes,  site-directed cysteine mutants of selected amino acids in the cork domain (L109C and  Q112C) and in the barrel domain (S356C and M383C) were created within the putative  siderophore transport pathway. Molecular modeling predicted that double-cysteine  mutants FhuACys109,356 and FhuACys112,383 would form disulfide bonds, thereby  tethering the cork and barrel domains. Double-cysteine FhuA mutants denatured under  non-reducing conditions were labelled with thiol-specific Oregon Green maleimide and  subjected to SDS-PAGE analysis. Two distinct species were observed: FhuA containing  a disulfide bond and FhuA with free sulfhydryl groups. To address the role of the  putative siderophore transport pathway and to evaluate possible rearrangements of  the cork domain during ferricrocin transport, an oxidation catalyst was used to  enhance disulfide bond formation. After disulfide tethering of cork to barrel,  ferricrocin transport was equivalent to transport by untreated cells. Furthermore,  cells containing double-cysteine FhuA mutants that were subjected to oxidation  during ferricrocin transport exhibited disulfide bond formation to near completion.  These results demonstrate that blocking the putative siderophore transport pathway  did not abrogate siderophore uptake. We propose that during ferricrocin transport  through FhuA, the cork domain remains within the barrel rather than its being  displaced.</description><creator>Eisenhauer, H. Anne</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Siderophore transport through Escherichia coli outer membrane receptor FhuA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nr491.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v8423</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161667m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>CDP/Cux binds DNA and acts as a transcriptional repressor of  some target genes while it activates others. The MMSET protein was identified as a  protein-binding partner of CDP/Cux. The goal of my project was to characterize the  interaction between MMSET and CDP/Cux. I confirmed the association in  co-immunoprecipitation and affinity chromatography assays, but not in pull-down  assays. MMSET increased CDP-mediated transcriptional activation of the DNA pol alpha  promoter in reporter assays. Mutation in the SET domain did not abolish this effect.  These results suggest that MMSET functions as a transcriptional coactivator with  CDP/Cux. Short CDP/Cux isoforms were previously shown to be  over-expressed in some cancer cell lines and human tumors. I characterized CDP/Cux  expression and activity in the MV4-11 acute myeloid leukemia cell line. In contrast  to all cell lines thus far tested, proliferating MV4-11 cells did not express the  full-length p200 isoform, but expressed only short isoforms, one of which  co-migrated with p110. However, the full length CDP/Cux mRNA transcript was  detected. That the gene was intact was also confirmed by the finding that p200  expression was increased upon treatment of cells with PMA or ectopic expression of  various CDP/Cux isoforms. The effect of FLT3 receptor signaling on CDP/Cux  expression was observed at both the protein and mRNA levels, although the role of  this receptor in CDP/Cux regulation was not characterized.</description><creator>Markovicova, Jelena</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Interaction between CDPCux and MMSET and expression and activity of CDPCux in the MV4-11 acute myeloid leukemia cell line</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kq91n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161667m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mv68q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prostate carcinoma (CaP) is the most frequently diagnosed  malignancy in men in Western countries. Increased activity of the androgen receptor  (AR) and/or AR gene (AR) amplification in the majority of both androgen-dependent  and androgen-independent prostate cancers suggest that the AR plays an important  role in CaP. The polymorphic AR CAGn, repeat correlates inversely with AR  transactivation. To better understand the contribution of this repeat to CaP, we  propose to replace the stable mouse AR CAG/CAA/CAC tract with various lengths of  CAG, using gene knock-in methodology. The neo-NTR-HSV-tk cassette from the  pPGKneoNTRtkpA vector was introduced into the ploxPneo-1 vector such that loxP sites  flanked it. Various CAG repeats were then cloned into mouse AR genomic 5' end clone.  Finally, the 5' and 3' mouse AR genomic DNA fragments were cloned into the targeting  vector, upstream and downstream of the cassette with flanking loxP sites. Knock-in  mice with various CAG repeat lengths will be generated using these  constructs.</description><creator>Mousavi, Gity</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Generating vectors for production of transgenic mouse models to investigate the role of the androgen receptor and its CAG repeat in human prostate cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf44x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv68q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43800</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>