<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:52:00Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):100" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f794g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Potato requires high levels of nitrogen fertilizer. Up to now in Quebec, no nitrogen fertilizer recommendation has been based on nitrogen availability in the soil, even those soil nitrogen testing is available. The objectives of this study were: (1) to determine the relation between soil nitrate-N content, nitrogen fertilization and potato yield; and (2) to determine the time and the sampling depth of soil most appropriate to predict potato yields and response to nitrogen fertilizer under Quebec conditions. Soil samples were taken at two depths at planting and at hilling time in 28 sites fertilized at four levels of nitrogen. Laboratory measures of nitrate-N were carried out on those samples. A combination of nitrate-N and nitrogen fertilisation gave the best explanation of the variation potato yields. A maximum of 46% of yield variation was attributed to the combination of those two factors in general. Best coefficients of determination were obtained when the sampling of nitrate-N was done at planting time compared to time. Regression models predicted nitrogen fertilizer needs of 89 to 200 kg ha$ sp{-1}.$ The same conclusions were found in the case of the variety Superior alone. The variation of yield explained was up to 62%. Regression models predicted nitrogen fertilizer needs of 77 to 224 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ for Superior. It was concluded that the analysis of soil nitrate-N can improve the prediction of nitrogen fertilizer needs for an optimum potato production.</description><creator>Painchaud, Jacques.</creator><contributor>Mackenzie, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Potatoes -- Fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Nitrogen fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>L'azote du sol et la fertilisation de la pomme de terre</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9031899.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f794g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t720</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An on-line beam to target portal verification technique has been developed for stereotactic radiosurgery. Conventional radiosurgery employs a stereotactic frame in order to obtain sufficient spatial accuracy in dose delivery. Frame based verification methods attempt to ensure accurate target positioning with respect to the frame but they do not account for possible movement of the frame with respect to the anatomy and isocenter. We account for this possibility by superimposing digitally reconstructed radiographs (DRRs) over orthogonal edge detected digital portal image pairs. By developing a process for interactively manipulating the CT-data in three dimensions (rotations and translations) new DRRs are generated and overlaid with orthogonal portal images. This method is able to account for ambiguities in matching due to rotations and translations outside the imaging plane because of the availability of DRRs at any possible orientation. This matching procedure is performed using only the anatomy and is used in tandem with a fiducial marker array attached to the stereotactic frame. The method is evaluated using portal images simulated from patient CT-data and then tested using a radiographic head phantom. Results show that repositioning precision of the system is at the level required by stereotactic radiosurgery.</description><creator>Otto, Karl, 1972-</creator><contributor>Fallone, B. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>3-dimensional anatomy-based verification in stereotactic radiosurgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm250.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t720</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj606</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I investigated the effect of defoliation by the gypsy moth, Lymantria dispar L. (Lepidoptera: Lymantriidae) on the radial growth of tree species that differ in their acceptability as hosts for gypsy moth larvae. Annual growth rings were measured from 1950 to 1992 on increment cores taken from three species: red oak (Quercus rubra L.), a preferred species, sugar maple (Acer saccharum Marsh.), an acceptable species, and white ash (Fraxinus americana L.), an avoided species. The number of gypsy moth larvae on these same individual trees had already been recorded from 1979 to 1992. To remove the potentially-confounding effects of climate on radial growth, I developed regression models of growth on climate in a pre-gypsy moth period (1950 to 1975), and then used these models to predict growth in a post-gypsy moth period (1978 to 1992). The residuals from these growth models were then examined with respect to gypsy moth numbers. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Naidoo, Robin.</creator><contributor>Lechowicz, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Hardwoods -- Climatic factors -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><subject>Gypsy moth -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><subject>Hardwoods -- Diseases and pests -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><title>The effects of gypsy moth defoliation and climatic conditions on radial growth of deciduous trees /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f795r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj606</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k004q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The world-wide dissemination of the human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) has led to a wide number of approaches aimed at controlling and understanding viral replication. Although antiviral drugs have been important in the treatment of HIV-1-infected individuals, toxicity and resistance have mandated new efforts and strategies. We have tried to develop a trans-dominant gene therapy approach, by showing that mutated Gag-Pol polyproteins can be incorporated into viral particles. In our studies, Gag-Pol proteins that were mutated in protease (PR) and combinations of mutations in PR and reverse transcriptase (RT) inhibited the production of fully processed and infectious viral particles when coexpressed with the infectious HIV-1 molecular clone, pBH10. Viral particles produced after cotransfection of COS-7 cells with both pBH10 and Gag-Pol, mutated in PR alone or in both RT and PR, showed abnormal processing and lower infectivity, suggesting that a trans-dominant negative effect had occurred. These effects were not seen when Gag-Pol with a deleted integrase ($ Delta$IN) and the same RT and PR mutations were co-expressed with pBH10. Complementation experiments in which pBH10 mutated in PR was co-expressed with wild-type Gag-Pol showed that the latter could be incorporated into viral particles. Finally, COS-7 cells stably transfected with Gag-Pol mutated in PR or in both PR and RT, and subsequently transfected with pBH10, showed diminished production of viral particles.</description><creator>Morin, Nicolas.</creator><contributor>Wainber, Mark A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Expression of mutated HIV-1 gag-pol proteins and their effects on virus replication and infectiousness : implications for gene therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f89p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k004q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df52r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Meat Juice Medium (MJM), an aqueous extract of meat, was inoculated with Pseudomonas aeruginosa and incubated for 7 d at 4$ sp circ$C under shaking conditions (100 rev.min$ sp{-1}$). Two predominant compounds produced during spoilage of MJM were detected using HPLC. These compounds with retention times (RT) of 21.48 and 32.04 min were tentatively identified as acetic and butyric acids, respectively. These compounds were also produced when MJM was replaced with Brain Heart Infusion Broth medium. In later experiments, the effect of glucose supplementation on the rate of MJM spoilage was examined. Glucose 0.5% (wt/vol) was added to the MJM, inoculated with P. aeruginosa and incubated at 30$ sp circ$C under shaking conditions (100 rev.min$ sp{-1}$). HPLC of samples after 1d of incubation indicated the presence of 8 predominant compounds including acetic and butyric acids. Their concentrations were, in general, higher in control samples of MJM without added glucose. Using HPLC, TLC, Pyrolysis/GC/MS, FTIR and GC-MS methodologies, the compounds with RT of 8.91, 9.67, 11.96, 13.33, 17.74, 21.48, 26.07 and 32.04 min were tentatively identified as cadaverine, 2-keto gluconic acid, fructose, lactic acid, acetic acid, methanol and butyric acid. In contrast to the results of previous researchers, cadaverine was produced in large amounts while no putrescine was produced by P. aeruginosa. During the spoilage period, the levels of glucose, fructose and total carbohydrate were monitored. Addition of glucose to MJM delayed slime production by 4 days and increase to maximum pH of 8.3 by 7 days. Results suggest that addition of glucose to MJM delays spoilage by P. aeruginosa.</description><creator>Moosavi-Nasab, Marzieh.</creator><contributor>Idziak, E. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Meat -- Microbiology.</subject><subject>Pseudomonas aeruginosa.</subject><title>Identification of low molecular weight compounds produced or utilized by pychrotrophic meat spoilage organisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq128.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df52r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064777t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dietary selection involves the process of relating the postingestional consequences of eating a food to its sensory characteristics. Diet texture, the most plausible sensory characteristic affecting ingestion, may play an important role in the control of food selection. In this study, we compared the circadian rhythmicity of protein- and carbohydrate-rich diet ingestion of adult male Wistar rats presented with diets in different textural forms (high-protein powder and high-carbohydrate granular (HPP-HCG) diets vs. high-protein granular and high-carbohydrate powder (HPG-HCP) diets) during 15 days. Rats fed HPP-HCG diets selected significantly less protein (kcal) vs. rats fed HPG-HCP diets, during the 24 h, 12 h dark phase and the 4 h early and late dark phases. Carbohydrate intakes of the two dietary groups were not significantly different. Total caloric intake for HPG-HCP group was significantly higher than that of HPP-HCG group during the 24 h and 12 h dark phase. In conclusion, macronutrient-rich diets presented in different textural forms alter the circadian rhythmicity of protein-rich diet ingestion and total energy intake.</description><creator>Mok, Elise.</creator><contributor>Thibault, Louise (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Food texture.</subject><subject>Circadian rhythms.</subject><subject>Rats -- Food.</subject><subject>Ingestion -- Regulation.</subject><title>Effect of diet textural characteristics on the temporal rhythms of feeding in rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784n68z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064777t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s77g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The economic feasibility of lupins in a cropping system as a protein supplement for a representative dairy cattle herd in Southwest Quebec (SWQ) to substitute for soybeans was investigated using a single period linear programming (LP) model. At current prices, lupins were not a profitable base case scenario. The gross margin of the dairy farm was $147,918. This resulted in a total soil loss of 3,504 tonnes (t), 50 percent higher than soil tolerance, T (acceptable level of soil loss) of 14 t ha$ sp-1,$ and produced 541 kg of Nitrogen (N). Sale of corn grain (CG) was 442.3 t, constituting about 39 percent of the gross margin but had a negative effect on the soil. The farm purchased 59 t of straw for animal bedding. When the environmental constraint of soil erosion, 14 t ha$ sp{-1},$ was imposed, the gross margin was estimated to be $131,148 while total N and soil loss were 2,454 kg and 1,708 t, respectively. Lupins were produced on 18.3 ha with this soil loss level constraint. The tradeoff between soil loss and gross margin and lupins was observed. The N fixation constraint reduced the gross margin while it increased soil loss. CG sales were reduced from 442 to 244.5 t but milk production increased by 163 hectolitres (HL). Sensitivity analysis on labour supply and farm size indicated that lupins became an alternative to soybeans when farm size and labour supply were larger and fewer respectively. Lupins would substitute for soybeans if yield is increased by 5 percent; cost of production is reduced by 10 percent and home grown clean lupin seed is used for 2 or 3 more years or government provides a subsidy of $328 ha$ sp-1.$ This is approximately equal to the CG subsidy.</description><creator>Messele, Teklay.</creator><contributor>Thomassin, Paul J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Soybean -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Lupines -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Dairy cattle -- Feeding and feeds -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Economic and environmental viability of substituting soybeans for lupins : the case of dairy farming in southwest Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06989494.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s77g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th45z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pollination of greenhouse sweet pepper (Capsicum annuum L. var. grossum cv. Superset) by Bombus impatiens Cr. was investigated in Ste. Scholastique, Quebec for two periods, 27 June-15 July and 4-18 August, 1995 to determine the pollination effectiveness of B. impatiens compared to a mechanical method (vibration wand) and natural greenhouse ventilation (NGV) and to determine the foraging activity of B. impatiens throughout the pollination period. B. impatiens pollination resulted in a significantly greater number of seeds per fruit and a greater percent marketable fruit, due to a positive quadratic relationship between seed number and fruit weight, than both vibration wand and NGV. Both B. impatiens and NGV resulted in a significantly greater fruit set than vibration wand. Per fruit, an extra profit of $0.06 for green and $0.13 for red sweet peppers could be made by B. impatiens pollination over NGV, due to greater marketable fruit and greater mean fruit weight. B. impatiens pollination was more effective than both vibration wand and NGV even though both the daily activity of the insect at the hive (hive traffic) and their foraging on plants (greenhouse foraging) decreased throughout the pollination period and attained a maximum of only 3 B. impatiens foraging in the greenhouse during the second period. It was estimated that a B. impatiens colony of 30-40 workers could optimally pollinate 17475 plants or a greenhouse size of about 9470 m$ sp2.$</description><creator>Meisels, Susan.</creator><contributor>Chiasson, Helene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Bombus.</subject><subject>Pollination.</subject><subject>Bell pepper.</subject><title>Using Bombus impatiens Cr. as a pollinator of greenhouse sweet peppers (Capsicum annuum L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074x189.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th45z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k19c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The southwestern region of the Manicouagan reservoir occupies the structurally uppermost position in the Parautochthonous belt, in the Grenville province, in eastern Quebec. The region consists principally of well banded grey gneisses composed essentially of plagioclase, quartz and biotite. An assemblage of rocks consisting of dolomitic marbles, quartzites, iron formations and pelites, occurs throughout the region. This assemblage can be correlated to rocks in the tectonic foreland to the north of the Grenville Front, that were deposited on the continental margin of Laurentia during the Paleo-Proterozoic. The east-striking, and moderately south-dipping, Utishku fault zone runs through the middle of the region, and juxtaposes eclogite-facies rocks to the north with amphibolite-facies rocks to the south. Kinematics on the Utishku fault zone are unclear. The relationship, however, of high-pressure rocks in the footwall, and lower-pressure rocks in the hangingwall, indicates a predominant normal fault motion. Mineral lineations on the Utishku fault zone plunge due south. Normal faulting was, therefore, oblique to the regional northwest-directed compression of the Grenville in eastern Quebec. Mafic rocks from the Utishku fault zone preserve a prograde P-T path. In contrast, pelitic rocks from the Utishku fault zone preserve a retrograde P-T path. The mafic rocks were probably incorporated into the fault at a relatively late stage. It seems likely that the mafics were initially buried by a thrust fault, structurally below the Utishku fault zone, that was active synchronous to normal motion on the Utishku fault zone. The eclogite-facies rocks, to the north of the Utishku fault zone, may, therefore, be bounded by a thrust fault below and a normal fault above, that were coeval. It is suggested that normal faulting and rapid exhumation of eclogite-facies rocks occurred synchronous to regional compression and relatively early in the history of the Grenville orogen.</description><creator>McKee, G. (Gavin)</creator><contributor>Hynes, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Evolution of the southwestern region of the Manicouagan reservoir, Grenville province, eastern Quebec : structural and metamorphic controls on the exhumation of high-pressure metamorphic rocks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v747j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k19c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r621</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chlorisondamine (CHL) is a nicotinic antagonist that blocks for several weeks most of the centrally-mediated behavioural effects of nicotine. However, the mechanism for the long-lasting action of CHL in vivo and the brain regions it targets are largely unknown. We hypothesized that the persistent blockade produced by CHL may result from uptake by neuronal terminals, followed by retrograde transport and accumulation of CHL (or metabolite) in the perikarya. The hypothesis was tested in rats, using locomotor tests to measure nicotinic antagonism within mesolimbic dopaminergic neurons. Results did not entirely support the hypothesis. Our hypothesis also predicted that CHL would block the stimulatory effect of nicotine on cerebral glucose utilization only in regions where CHL accumulates in appreciable amounts. To determine which brain regions are targeted by CHL, we used the 2-deoxy-D- (1-$ sp{14}$C) glucose method (Sokoloff et al., 1977). Again, the hypothesis was not supported.</description><creator>Marenco, Ted.</creator><contributor>Clarke, Paul B. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Chlorisondamine : possible mechanism and sites of action in the rat brain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz51g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r621</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k4625</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following generalization of Hardy's inequality is due to I. Klemes (6) (1993); "There is a constant $c&gt;0$ such that for any function $f in L sb1$(T), eqalign{ sum sbsp{j=1}{ infty} left(4 sp{-j} sum sb{4 sp{j-1} le n&lt;4 sp{j}} vert f(n) vert sp2 right) sp{1/2} le c Vert f Vert sb1+c sum sbsp{j=1}{ infty} cr qquad qquad qquad left(4 sp{-j} sum sb{4 sp{j-1} le n&lt;4 sp{j}} vert f(-n) vert sp2 right) sp{1/2}.'' cr} The proof was based on an elegant construction, (L. Pigno and B. Smith (11)), of a certain bounded function whose Fourier coefficients have desired properties. The chief object of this thesis is to record another proof of the above result by using the construction that was originally used to prove the Littlewood conjecture (8). In addition, a proof is given that the same generalization is equivalent to another one involving the norm of the Besov space $B sbsp{21}{-1/2}</description><creator>Mal-Alla, Ebrahim.</creator><contributor>Klemes, Ivo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A generalization of Hardy's inequality for Fourier series /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg50z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k4625</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b804r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectives. To estimate children's exposure to traffic, and to determine the role of exposure in pedestrian injuries. Methods. A questionnaire was distributed to 4,080 children in grades 1 and 4 in a stratified, random sample of 43 schools in Montreal. Results. The mean number of streets crossed was similar by sex and increased with age. Children who attended schools in neighbourhoods ranked as disadvantaged crossed, on average, 50% more streets than those attending non-disadvantaged schools. Similar trends emerged in other SES variables. When analyzed by police district, injury rates and exposure were positively correlated (r$ sp2$ = 0.53). Conclusion. Differences in injury rates by sex or age are poorly explained by exposure to traffic, whereas exposure appears related to socio-economic status. The number of streets crossed is related to injury rates. These results suggest that although a reduction in children's exposure to traffic would possibly diminish the number of pedestrian injuries, a more promising strategy involves reducing the risk of traffic through environmental changes.</description><creator>Macpherson, Alison K. (Alison Katherine), 1963-</creator><contributor>Pless, I. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Children's exposure to traffic and pedestrian injuries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h18q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b804r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827d59t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have used a new type of torque magnetometer: a piezoresistive cantilever. It detects the force and torque applied to the end of the cantilever beam by changes in its resistance. We report the first use of this device at temperatures below 1 K. We observed a hysteretic behavior of the resistance at low magnetic field (less than 10 mT) in that temperature range. At higher field it has a smoothly varying magnetoresistance which permitted us to measure the de Haas-van Alphen (dHvA) effect in two superconductors: $ kappa$-(BEDT-TTF)$ sb2$Cu(NCS)$ sb2$ and Sr$ sb2$RuO$ sb4.$ These measurements demonstrated that a large excitation current can be used if the sample is well thermalized but that torque interactions (TI) can affect the signal. TI can be reduced by the use of feedback. We also present measurements above 75 K of $H sb{c1}$ of YBa$ sb2$Cu$ sb3$O$ sb{6.9}$ obtained by modulating the field and measuring the torque signal at an harmonic of the modulation frequency.</description><creator>Lupien, Christian.</creator><contributor>Taillefer, Louis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Piezoresistive torque magnetometry at low temperature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t119d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d59t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p6666</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stromal reticular cells in mouse bone marrow and follicular dendritic cells (FDC) in peripheral lymphoid tissues both interact with B lymphocytes and influence their development at various stages of the B cell lineage. The possibility that BM reticular cells and FDCs may share common surface properties has been examined in mouse bone marrow by in vivo administration of $ sp{125}$I-labelled purified monoclonal antibodies (mAb) raised against mouse FDC, detecting mAb-binding by light microscope (LM) and electron microscope (EM) radioautography. Young mice were injected intravenously with $ sp{125}$I-mAb FDC-M1, FDC-M2, FDC-M3 and then perfused to remove unbound antibody. Quantitative analyses of radioautographic LM sections of femoral bone marrow revealed discrete FDC-labelling throughout bone marrow sections, especially in outer areas near the surrounding bone and intermediate areas, forming both linear arrangements and irregular patches. Electron microscopy revealed labelling aligned over delicate processes of certain reticular cells intimately associated with lympho hemopoietic cells, as well as localized regions of sinusoidal endothelium, particularly in central areas and at sites of contact with hemopoietic cells. The results demonstrate that a subset of stromal reticular cells in mouse BM express FDC-associated surface determinants, suggesting possible common lineage or functional properties.</description><creator>Liu, Limin, 1954-</creator><contributor>Osmond, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Expression of follicular dendritic cell determinants by mouse bone marrow stromal cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x863.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p6666</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb78j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In vitro selection for multidrug resistance (MDR) and retroactive clinical studies have established an important role for both P-glycoprotein (P-gp) and the Multidrug Resistance-associated Protein (MRP) in conferring pleiotropic resistance to several structurally dissimilar hydrophobic drugs. Both P-gp and MRP are ABC transporters which when overexpressed in tumour cells are capable of enhancing drug efflux, resulting in a drug accumulation deficit. Paradoxically, acquisition of the MDR phenotype frequently results in newfound hypersensitivity to a different group of drugs. This thesis investigates the collateral sensitivity of the P-gp-bearing CHO cell line CH$ sp{ rm R}$ C5 to the calcium channel blocker, verapamil (VRP). In addition, the hypersensitivity of the MRP-bearing SCLC line H69AR to BSO, a depleter of glutathione (GSH), is herein examined. Although VRP clearly induced heightened levels of p53-independent apoptosis in CH$ sp{ rm R}$ C5 cells, blockage of calcium channels was not involved in the cytotoxicity of the drug. BSO clearly killed through depletion of GSH, apparently resulting in heightened levels of necrosis in H69AR cells. In both cases, decreased expression of the Bcl-2 gene appeared to result in hypersensitivity of MDR cells to the toxic effects of BSO and VRP.</description><creator>Lincoln, Maximilian Christian.</creator><contributor>Georges, Elias (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Drug resistance.</subject><subject>Glycoproteins.</subject><title>Multidrug resistance and collateral sensitivity of tumour cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb317.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb78j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p910c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A lesion interface consisting of a glia limitans lined by a laminin-rich basal lamina forms within 3 weeks after leptomeningeal cells infiltrate into penetrating wounds in the adult mammalian CNS. This impedes axon regrowth. We have examined the effects of steroids on the formation of the lesion interface in the adult rat cerebral cortex. Topical glucocorticoids were applied on the surface of cortex encompassing stab wounds. Three weeks later, cryostat sections through the lesioned area were labeled with anti-laminin, anti-GFAP, anti-ED-1 and Nuclear Yellow. Steroid treatment attenuated all components of the lesion, including leptomeningeal cell infiltration. In vitro, steroid treatment did not alter laminin secretion but reduced cell proliferation in leptomeningeal cultures. These results suggest that steroids modulate lesion interface formation in the CNS in part by decreasing leptomeningeal cell proliferation.</description><creator>Li, Maria S.</creator><contributor>David, Samuel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Topical glucocorticoids modulate the lesion interface after cerebral cortical stab wounds in adult rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z38k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p910c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc643</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the most important problems to be faced when building a speech recognizer is the lack of sufficient training data to estimate all of the parameters of the system. One of the most successful techniques addressing this problem is to decrease the number of parameters in the system by the use of classification-tree based acoustic models. In this thesis, several variations on this theme will be presented, the first few ones dealing with trees classifying whole HMMs (tree units), the others with trees classifying states of HMMs (tree states). Results obtained on the Air Travel Information System (ATIS) task show that using classification trees produces systems with up to 90% less models (and proportionally less parameters to estimate) with no loss of performance.</description><creator>Lazaridès, Ariane.</creator><contributor>Normandin, Yves (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>De Mori, Renato (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Physics, Acoustics.</subject><title>Classification trees for acoustic models : variations on a theme</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t827p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc643</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd12p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An amorphous-Selenium (a-Se) based portal detector, which uses the metal substrate as a conversion plate, is studied using Monte Carlo techniques. The optimal thickness and material of the metal plate and a-Se thicknesses are investigated by modelling dose deposition in the a-Se layer for a 6 MV exit beam. Simulations of Detective Quantum Efficiency DQE(f) show that although DQE(0) increases with metal thickness up to $d sb{max},$ there is a cross-over near 1 cycle/mm which indicates that smaller metal thicknesses are more useful to visualize edges and small objects. A similar cross-over, though not as prominent, is also observed with constant metal thickness while varying a-Se thickness. Tungsten front plates are shown be optimal in terms of DQE for the plates under investigation. The effect of the scattered beam, described by the Scatter Fraction SF and Scatter-to-Primary Ratio SPR, is also modelled to ensure that the front-plate, which also acts as a scatter-rejection tool, satisfactorily filters out the scatter component. The SF is measured experimentally with a prototype imager for four metal plate/a-Se combinations and agrees with the Monte Carlo results within experimental uncertainties.</description><creator>Lachaîne, Martin.</creator><contributor>Fallone, B. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Monte Carlo optimization of a metalamorphous-selenium portal imager</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz542.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd12p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f321p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments were conducted to assess the variation for resistance to Fusarium graminearum ear rot among selfed lines from the Zapalote Chico corn population. It was already known that Zapalote Chico possesses some resistance to corn earworm (Heliothis zeae) and variation in Fusarium graminearum ear rot symptom severity had been observed within the population. During two years of experiments, 47 S4- and S5-generation lines were inoculated and ear rot severity was assessed. In addition, eight pigmentation traits and eight morphological traits were recorded. Lines showed significant differences for all recorded traits. Associations were not strong among morphological traits, but were fairly strong among pigmentation traits. Ear rot symptom severity did not seem to be associated with any other trait. The source population and inbred lines exhibited broad ranges of variation and similar bimodal distributions of ear rot symptom severity ratings. Despite significant differences among lines within experiments none of the lines showed distinct and consistent resistance over two years of experiments. It seems that Zapalote Chico lines do not have environmental stability and sufficient potential to be considered worthwhile source of resistance for ear rot.</description><creator>Krsikapa, Nenad.</creator><contributor>Mather, D. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Fusarium graminearum.</subject><subject>Corn -- Disease and pest resistance -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Variation for resistance to Fusarium graminearum ear rot in selfed families from the corn population Zapalote Chico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66345729.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f321p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515q40q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sea water samples were collected from different sampling stations along the Lebanese coast in the summer of 1994. Chemical, biological and physical analysis were conducted to assess the recreational water quality in Lebanon. Some 125 samples were then analyzed for the presence of Cadmium and Mercury by atomic absorption spectrophotometry. Cadmium content, holding a mean 0.77 $ mu$g/L, was generally low for most areas with only a few elevated readings in Tripoli (1.89 $ mu$g/L), Checca (1.83 $ mu$g/L), Kaslik (0.79 $ mu$g/L), Beirut (1.19 $ mu$g/L) and Ramlet Al-Bayda (1.77 $ mu$g/L). Mercury content, holding a mean value of 0.06 mg/Kg (wet weight), was below the accepted tolerance limit of 0.5 mg/Kg for all sampling sites. Some 128 samples were then analyzed for fecal coliforms (Escherichia coli and Streptococcus feacalis). Approximately, 50% of the sampling stations showed satisfactory results (less than 100 colonies/100 ml). High counts of fecal coliforms, over 500 colonies/100 ml, collected at Dora, Ramlet Al-Bayda and Antelias, reveal poor sea water quality and a public health hazards to swimmers and fishermen. Some 36 samples were collected and analyzed for dissolved oxygen (DO), pH, salinity and temperature. For all sites sampled, DO averaged 4.03 mg/L, pH averaged 7.97, salinity averaged 38.77 ppt and temperature averaged 27.9$ sp circ$C. The degree of pollution was found to be related to population density, industrial and human activity, continental runoffs and hydrological and meteorological conditions.</description><creator>Kortbaoui, Ziad S.</creator><contributor>Barrington, Suzelle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Marine pollution -- Mediterranean Sea.</subject><subject>Marine pollution -- Lebanon.</subject><title>The sea shore contamination of the Lebanese coast /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967572r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q40q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc65c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mammalian Cut proteins appear to function as transcriptional repressors that play a role in determining cell type specificity. Recent evidence suggests that cut genes are tumour suppressor genes. This hypothesis was further examined by using functional assays to evaluate the abilities of human Cut to: (a) suppress oncogene-mediated cell transformation, and (b) interact with the SV40 Large T (LT) antigen. The results indicate that: (a) there was a decrease in the number of transformed colonies and foci when rat embryo fibroblasts (REFs) were transfected with ras/c-myc or ras/E1A and cut; (b) the homeodomain region of Cut interacted with SV40 LT in vitro; and (c) Cut protein levels were elevated and Cut DNA binding was increased in cells transfected or transformed with SV40LT. These observations suggest that Cut proteins may regulate cell proliferation and that the Cut homeodomain may mediate protein interactions.</description><creator>Kelman, Marni J.</creator><contributor>Nepveu, Alain (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Functional assessment of the tumor suppressor activity of the CUTL1 gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf95r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc65c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p667g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A water-methanol solution of glycine and scD-glucose was refluxed for seven hr. The solvent was evaporated under vacuum at room temperature and the residue was dialyzed against distilled water. After dialysis, the solvent was evaporated under vacuum at room temperature. The non-dialyzable fraction was further fractionated by gel filtration. The process yielded three polymeric materials (10,000 $&lt;$ M $&lt;$ 20,000) whose purity was verified by HPLC. The isolated polymers were further analyzed by UV-VIS and FTIR spectroscopy and by pyrolysis/GC/MS. Elemental analysis indicated that polymer A has the following empirical formula $ rm C sb6H sb{11}N sb1O sb4$ and polymers B1 and B2 have the same empirical formula as glucose $ rm C sb1H sb2O sb1.$ The origin of nitrogen containing polymer A was assigned to Amadori intermediate or to some of its derivatives and the origin of polymers B1 and B2 was assigned to Glucosone and to 3- or 1-deoxyglucosones; common non-nitrogen containing reactive intermediates during Maillard reaction. Plausible mechanisms were proposed for the formation of polymers.</description><creator>Kaminski, Eva.</creator><contributor>Yaylayan, V. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Maillard reaction.</subject><title>Isolation and identification of non-volatile water soluble Maillard reaction products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv58n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p667g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q8287</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A dendrochronological and dendrochemical study was undertaken near the village of Kuujjuaq, northern Quebec. Changes in climate, radial growth and mineral nutrition of trees, as well as the contamination in Mn and Zn of tamarack and black spruce forests of the region during the last forty years were investigated. A growth model based on climatic variables was produced for each species. The regional climate didn't show any steady trend of increase in temperature and precipitation with time. However, the 1953-1964 decade was the warmest one and the 1964-1973 decade received the most precipitation. Radial growth of both species have probably increased during the investigated period. Growth of larch was primarily associated with May and June precipitation (R$ sp2$ = 0.134) when spruce growth was associated with spring temperature and July and August evapotranspiration (R$ sp2$ = 0.352). Wood chemistry (concentration, burden, and elemental ratio) suggests a stable soil fertility in base cations during the last forty years as well as a stable or increased availability of Zn during the last decade. More extensive research, in terms of number of sites and variables studied could confirm the observed trends in growth, soil fertility, and Mn and Zn availability in this part of northern Quebec.</description><creator>Kaminski, Gregory.</creator><contributor>Cote, Benoit (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Dendrochronology -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Tamarack -- Québec (Province) -- Growth.</subject><subject>Black spruce -- Québec (Province) -- Growth.</subject><title>Dendrochronology and dendrochemistry of tamarack and black spruce in the open boreal forest of northern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd75g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q8287</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt76g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of high N fertilizer in sweet corn (Zea mays L.) and wheat (Triticum aestivium L.) production often results in leaching losses and contamination of ground water. Cover crops planted after harvest of sweet corn and wheat may reduce residual soil NO$ sp- sb3$-N levels by crop N uptake and subsequently minimize NO$ sp- sb3$-N content in gravitational water. Field experiments were conducted on a Ste. Rosalie heavy clay (Humic Gleysol) and a St. Bernard sandy clay loam (Melanic Brunisol) to determine the contribution of the six cover crops to nutrient uptake, subsequent N release, leaching losses, denitrification rates and soil properties such as aggregate stability, organic matter. The cover crops were red clover (Trifolium pratense L.), crimson clover (Trifolium incarnatum L.), forage radish (Raphanus sativus L.), canola (Brassica rapa L.), barley (Hordeum vulgare L.), annual rye grass (Lolium multiflorum L.). Three replicates were used in a split plot arrangement of a randomized complete block experiment. Sweet corn and wheat were grown at three fertilizer N rates, 0-75-150 kg N ha$ sp{-1}$ for sweet corn and 0-45-90 kg N ha$ sp{-1}$ for wheat. Cover crop of forage radish, canola and barley were more effective at absorption or soil N than rye grass and clover species at all sample times. Levels of soluble N in the soil were reduced with cover crop in the off-season. Cover crop plots had higher NO$ sp- sb3$-N levels than control plots in the spring, indicating net mineralization and nitrification. Gravitational water NO$ sp- sb3$-N contents were higher in the control plots relative to cover crop plots at both sites. Therefore growing cover crops after harvest of sweet corn and wheat can reduce residual NO$ sb3$-N level in the soil and thus restrict ground water contamination with fertilizer N.</description><creator>Isse, Abdullahi.</creator><contributor>MacKenzie, A. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Soils -- Leaching.</subject><subject>Cover crops.</subject><subject>Nitrogen fertilizers.</subject><subject>Soils -- Nitrate content.</subject><title>Capacity of cover crops to capture excess fertilizer and maintain soil efficiency</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n312x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt76g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032493p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:01:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Free radicals are thought to be involved in the destructive process of beta cells in Type 1 diabetes mellitus. Studies were performed to test the hypotheses (1) that malondialdehyde (MDA), a by-product of lipid peroxidation, affects $ beta$-cell function and integrity in vitro and (2) that such effects might be prevented in the BB rat (a model of spontaneous autoimmune diabetes) in vivo by administration of $ alpha$-phenyl-N-tert-butylnitrone (PBN), a free radical spin trap. First, islets of Wistar-Furth rats were studied at 12, 24 and 40 hr of culture in either 5.5, 11 or 16.5 mM glucose, and MDA at a range of concentrations ($6 times10 sp{-12}$-10$ sp{-3}$M). High concentrations of MDA inhibited glucose-stimulated insulin release without corresponding decreases in islet insulin content, suggesting that in situations with high predicted islet free radical content (e.g., autoimmune insulitis) beta cell function may be affected even before the cells are destroyed. Second, 28 diabetes-prone (BBdp) and 13 non diabetes-prone (BBn) rats were given PBN (20 mg/kg) s.c. 2x/day and 27 BBdp and 12 BBn rats received an equal volume of saline. PBN was able to decrease MDA in the absence of the autoimmune process and is remarkably non-toxic. However, it did not prevent diabetes for reasons which may include its concentration at the site of the inflammatory process or specificity to types of radicals trapped. Because it did decrease MDA, either a higher dose or a combination of PBN with other agents may hold promise for disease prevention.</description><creator>Iovino, Giugetta.</creator><contributor>Kubow, Stan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Free radicals (Chemistry)</subject><subject>Islands of Langerhans.</subject><subject>Lipids -- Peroxidation.</subject><subject>Diabetes -- Pathophysiology.</subject><title>The role of lipid peroxidation in pancreatic islet function and destruction in type 1 Diabetes Mellitus /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw45z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032493p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):125</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>