<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:01:01Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43925" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k58w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An important number of Canadian dairy farms manage their manure  as solids and in doing so, must handle large volumes of manure seepages and milk  house wastewater (dairy farm effluent-DFE). The present project adapted surface  irrigation as a more economical and sustainable method of disposing of this large  volume of DFE on cropped land near their storage facility. The experimental surface  irrigation system consisted of a gated pipe installed perpendicular to the slope of  the field allowing the discharged DFE to run down the slope. The adaptation of the system and the measurement of its  environmental impact were conducted on two dairy farms, A and B, in the region South  West of Montreal where their DFE were characterized. In 2003 and 2004, DFE was  applied on one of two 0.5 and 0.3ha plots, on each farm, to observe losses through  the subsurface drainage system, by means of sampling wells, and effects on soil  nutrient levels. The DFE collected in 2002 and 2003 had a lower nutrient content  than that collected in 2004 because of higher precipitations. The DFE generally  contained between 150-500 mg/L of TKN, 15 to 40 mg/L of TP and 500 to 700 mg/L of  TK. DFE losses through the subsurface drainage system were observed  on both farms during each irrigation test. Nevertheless, outlet losses were observed  only when irrigating under wet soil conditions or when applying more than 50mm of  DFE. Outlet losses represented at the most 1.2% of the total DFE volume applied and  0.32% of the nutrient and bacterial loads. Although only 65 to 75% of the soil surface was covered by the  applied DFE, the irrigation sessions did provide some additional soil moisture for  crops, increasing yield by 31% in 2004. Once absorbed by the soil, the applied DFE  did not increase the soil nutrient level and variability in the presence of crop.  Thus, the DFE contributed to the irrigation and fertilization of the  plots. Surface irrigation to spread low nutrient DFE, as compared to  the conventional tanker system reduced the application costs from $3.05/m3, to  $0.95/m3.</description><creator>Ali, Inamullah</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Dairy cattle -- Manure -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Sewage irrigation -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Surface irrigation adapted to the land spreading of dairy farm effluent</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m4684.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k58w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n392k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hypothesis. We hypothesized that contrary to "normal  aging," frail elderly women would have a heightened resting energy expenditure  per kg fat free mass (REE/kg FFM) and thermic effect of food (TEF)  response. Methods. 13 healthy (H) [X +/- SEM: 81.4 +/- 1.1 yr] and 9 frail  elderly women (F) [84.7 +/- 1.6 yr], free from acute conditions underwent REE and  TEF measurements (liquid standard mixed meal: 720 kcal, 58% carbohydrate, 14%  protein, 28% fat) using ventilated hood indirect calorimetry. Anthropometric and  body composition measurements, thyroid hormones, cortisol, cytokines and  catecholamine concentrations, and physical activity (PASE) and mobility ("time  up and go" TUG) scores were related to the results obtained. Results. H had a faster TUG: 10.2 +/- 1.6 vs. 21.0 +/- 9.3 s  (p=0.001), greater PASE score: 179.2 +/- 116.1 vs. 47.1 +/- 26.2 (p=0.003), greater  triiodothyronine [T3]: 5.1 +/- 0.6 vs. 4.3 +/- 0.4 rhomol/L (p=0.003) and lower  cortisol concentrations: 351.1 +/- 19.9 vs. 474.5 +/- 43.6 nmol/L (p=0.011). In H  vs. F: REE/kg FFM was 1044 +/- 20.4, 1021 +/- 23.7 kcal/day (NS) and TEF response as  expressed as % of REE was 18.4 +/- 5.6, 19.5 +/- 4.2 (NS). The time course of  glucose (p=0.043) and insulin from 90 minutes onwards (P=0.013) suggested insulin  resistance in F. REE was positively correlated with FFM, percent body fat and [T3]  (r&gt;0.499, p&lt;0.021). Conclusion. REE/kg FFM and TEF response was not different  between H and F and thus the greater prevalence of malnutrition in F, cannot be  explained by these parameters.</description><creator>Khursigara, Zareen</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Energy metabolism.</subject><subject>Older women -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Frail elderly -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Factors regulating resting energy expenditure and thermic effect of food in elderly women</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c22z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n392k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c099r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Huntingtin interacting protein-1 (HIP1) is an endocytic protein  that associates with clathrin on coated vesicles, but it also binds directly to  actin and microtubules. Close histological examination of the testis of HIP1-/- mice  from 7-30 wks of age revealed that HIP1-deficiency was particularly detrimental to  spermatids. The testis showed a significant decrease in the diameter of seminiferous  tubules, a reduction in the number of late spermatids and the sloughing of germ  cells, which were evident as round cells in the epididymal lumen. Major  abnormalities in spermatids included structural deformations of heads, bent  flagella, the presence of proacrosomic vesicles with the complete or partial absence  of an acrosome or its detachment from the nucleus, and retention of the cytoplasm  enveloping the spermatid head. Abnormalities with respect to the association of  elongating spermatids with ectoplasmic specializations of Sertoli cells were noted  as well. Sperm counts and sperm motility parameters were significantly decreased in  HIP1-/- mice compared to their wild-type littermates and these differences accounted  for reduced fertility levels noted in HIP1-/- mice. Taken together, differences in sperm counts, morphology and  their motility parameters suggest a functional role for HIP1 in relation to actin  and microtubules during sperm development in the testis.</description><creator>Khatchadourian, Karine</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Abnormalities in the testis, reduced sperm counts and decreased motility parameters in huntingtin- interacting protein 1 (HIP1) deficient mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r145t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c099r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kt37x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectives. (1) To Determine the presence of HPV 6, 11, 16, 18,  31, 33, 35, 52b, 58 subtypes in resected oral/oropharyngeal SCCA cancer and  associated lymph nodes. (2) To Determine if a relationship exists between  koilocytosis, tumor grade, stage, or prognosis. Methods. Retrospective analysis and pathology review of patients  with SCCA of the oral cavity at McGill in the last 5 years was performed. Age at  diagnosis, risk factors, tumor stage, grade, koilocytosis, treatment, outcome, and  presence of HPV by PCR were analysed. Results. 199 patients included were included in the analyses; 5  years mortality was 18.5%. 146 cases reviewed by pathology revealed 67%  koilocytosis. One sample was positive for HPV subtype 35 as determined by PCR.  Radiotherapy (p&lt;0,5) and complications from radiotherapy (p&lt;0.5)  significantly affected survival. Conclusions. Many oral SCCA's do not contain HPV 6, 11, 16, 18,  31, 33, 35, 52b, 58 subtypes. Given the high prevelence of koilocytosis, probe for  other subtypes should be utilized. Mortality rates and survival are similar to those  published in the literature. The presence of koilocytosis, it is not related grade,  stage or prognosis. Only radiotherapy and its complications affect  survival.</description><creator>Al-Qahtani, Khalid Hussain</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Detection of human papillomavirus in primary site of oraloropharyngeal cancer and in cervical lymph nodes : correlation with clinico-pathological parameters and prognostic significance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz01g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt37x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g337</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of conformal radiation techniques is to improve local  tumor control through dose escalation to target volumes while at the same time  sparing surrounding healthy tissue. Accurate target volume delineation is essential  in achieving this goal to avoid inadequate tumor coverage and/or irradiation of an  unnecessary volume of healthy tissue. Respiratory motion is known to be the largest  intra-fractional organ motion and the most significant source of uncertainty in  treatment planning for chest lesions. A method to minimize effects of respiratory  motion is to use four-dimensional (4D) radiotherapy. A novel scanning procedure for 4D CT data acquisition is  described in this work. Three single-slice helical scans are acquired simultaneously  with the real-time tracking of several markers placed on a moving phantom. At the  end of the three scans. CT data is binned into different respiratory phases  according to the externally recorded respiratory signal and the scanned volume is  reconstructed for several respiratory phases. The 4D CT images obtained show an  overall improvement when compared to conventional CT images of a moving  phantom.</description><creator>Stroian, Gabriela</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Optimized scanning procedures for 4D CT data acquisition in radiation therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s57m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g337</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m467v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My research goal was to functionally dissect the regulatory  region of the gene encoding the muscle protein troponin I (TnI) in the simple  chordate Ciona intestinalis. Based on evolutionary sequence conservation and  computational prediction of cis-elements in the regulatory region, I designed  mutants and assayed their effects in a recombinant DNA construct reporter system. I  electroporated TnI DNA-linked reporter constructs into Ciona zygotes and assayed  reporter activity following 12-14 hr of development. These studies showed that a  conserved E-box is essential for high-level embryonic tail muscle-specific  expression whereas conserved MEF-2 and overlapping CREB/TEF-1 sites were not. I  carried out functional promoter identification experiments and 5' RACE studies and  localized the core-promoter/transcription start-site in the Ciona TnI gene. My  results point out the similarities/differences between Ciona and vertebrate Tnl gene  regulation, which presumably reflect the conservation/modification of TnI gene  regulatory mechanisms during chordate/vertebrate evolution.</description><creator>Khare, Parul</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Ciona intestinalis -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Muscle proteins.</subject><title>CIS-regulatory elements driving muscle-specific expression of an ascidian troponin I gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50ts162.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m467v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547r898</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Red clover (Trifolium pratense L.) contains isoflavones, which  are of interest because of their benefits for human health as well as their adverse  effects on the fertility of farm animals. Isoflavone concentration in 10 cultivars  ranged from 8923 to 12753 mug g-1 DM averaged across sites, harvests, and years. One  cultivar, 'Start', distinguished itself with particularly low isoflavone levels.  Concentrations varied according to plant part with leaves having the highest levels  followed by stems and inflorescences, when averaged across maturity levels and  cultivars (11970, 4896 and 3297 mug g-1 DM, respectively). Greatest content was  found in leaves and stems during vegetative stages. Fresh herbage contained higher  isoflavone content than either silage or hay (14464, 12200 and 11604 mug g-1 DM,  respectively). Foliar application of yeast extract, chitosan, and acetic acid  elicitors overall showed modest (12-15%) increases in isoflavone concentration over  untreated control plants. Differences were not observed between elicitor  concentrations used.</description><creator>Sivesind, Evan</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Isoflavones.</subject><subject>Red clover.</subject><title>Factors affecting isoflavone concentration in red clover (Trifolium pratense L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999721k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547r898</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk36k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human-computer interaction (HCI) is a research topic whose  eventual outcome will allow users of computer systems for more natural interfaces  than the traditional keyboard and mouse. Ideally, those interfaces would exploit the  same communication channels used in everyday life, which are speech, gestures or any  other expressive feature of the human body. In this thesis, a continuous dynamic  gesture recognition system is presented. Positioning devices such as a mouse, a data  glove or a video camera are used as input streams to the recognition module, from  which it extracts the most interesting features. Gestures are recognized  continuously, which means that no prior temporal segmentation is necessary. Training  facilities are also available in order to build gesture models from known segmented  gesture sequences. In order for users to effectively reuse code and build new  modules that share common interfaces, a software framework was built that allows for  multimodal inputs and outputs as well as configuring the virtual world and how will  data coming from the real world influence virtual world entities, The data flow  originating from the real world uses a common data format that is standard from the  configuration file to the network packets. The virtual world is modeled such that  the actions that affect the virtual entities given input data from the real world is  configurable and extensible. Sharing the environment through the network is also  possible, allowing users from different locations to work on the same virtual world.  Preliminary tests on the gesture recognition performance are presented given several  different input modalities and setups. An experimental application is also  described, showing the flexibility and extensibility features of the software  framework.</description><creator>Rioux, François, 1980-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Software framework for parsing and interpreting gestures in a multimodal virtual environment context</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gn72j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk36k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f400t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present work aims to assess the ductile behaviour of porous  Inconel 625 nickel-based superalloys, produced by Metal Injection Moulding (MIM). A  qualitative study of the local behaviour was conducted through a series of simple  finite element models. Obtained results have been analyzed and compared to more  common materials. The following study focuses on the strain localization phenomenon  leading to ligament failure between 2 pores relative to their dimensions, their  orientation, the distance separating them and the triaxiality ratio. Obtained  results demonstrated that the dimensions of the plastic zone in the neighbourhood of  pores proportionally increase with pore diameter. Hence, it has been shown that in  the case of Inconel 625, the localization was more pronounced between 2 pores whose  relative orientation is 0º. Furthermore, it was possible to observe that the  critical far-field strain corresponding to the onset of flow localisation between  two pores was decreasing as the distance between them was diminishing. By comparing  the behaviour of Inconel 625 with that of aluminium 7075-T6, it has been shown that  the amplification of the plastic strains was lower in the case of Inconel 625 and  consequently the onset of strain localisation (i.e.ligament failure) was found to be  delayed in comparison with aluminium. Hence, the high work hardening coefficient of  Inconel 625 reduces its sensitivity to the presence of pores. It has thus been shown  that Inconel 625 MIM has mechanical properties superior to the equivalent cast  material.</description><creator>Després, Mélissa</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>On the evaluation of ductile behaviour of porous nickel-based superalloys using finite element method</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf27h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f400t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nr50s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the potential for pre-service teacher  training of video portfolios of elementary students doing school tasks. Study 1  investigates pre-service teachers' use of such records to assess student progress.  Ten undergraduate education students each viewed two video portfolios, one for  mathematics and one for reading. Each portfolio consisted of four video records.  Participants watched the four records in an incorrect order and attempted to put  them in their original order. Their orders by-and-large were correct. Most ordered  the records according to task characteristics and provided detail interpretations  and justifications for their ordering. Since the usefulness of video portfolios in  teacher training rests on their ability to highlight characteristics of student  learning, Study 2 further analyzes eleven mathematics video records selected from  Study 1 to investigate whether the task condition constructed in the adult-student  interaction allows sufficient presentations of student achievement. Potential  threats in task administrator's instructional behaviors to video quality were  discussed.</description><creator>Zhou, Wenyan, 1980-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Teachers -- Training of.</subject><subject>Students -- Rating of.</subject><subject>Portfolios in education.</subject><subject>Educational tests and measurements</subject><title>Video portfolios as a tool in primary grade student evaluation and their potential in pre-service teacher training</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc54n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr50s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hc719</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the role of Armenian community centres, in  relation to the local dwelling place of Montreal, the distant homeland, and the rest  of the Armenian diaspora. Due to the staggering increase in migration and to the  proliferation of transnational flows throughout the globe, our conception of home  has substantially changed. Thus, what motivates immigrants to build and attend  "diasporic dwellings" representative of their ethnicity in their new  dwelling places? By describing the characteristics of the two largest Armenian  community centres in Montreal, (the Armenian Community Centre and the ABGU Centre),  I analyse how these mediated social spaces embody elements that represent a distant  home, a diaspora, and the local dwelling place---complete with organizations,  symbols, imagery, iconography, and language. Utilizing the methodology of  participant observation and through conducting interviews, I demonstrate how members  of the Armenian community living in Montreal, negotiate their multiple cultural  identities through their involvement with Armenian community centres. Moreover, I  discuss how the community centres articulate a collective memory in the present  within Montreal's public sphere.</description><creator>Manjikian, Lalai</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Community centers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Armenians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Collective memory and diasporic articulations of imagined homes : Armenian community centres in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074v683.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hc719</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k595</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thermoforming process is subject to a lot of variability  with regard to the viscoelastic properties of the material, and the level of  residual stresses caused by the manufacturing (extrusion and calandering) process of  a plastic sheet. A robust control system must be able to identify and adjust to  these perturbations in real time during the thermoforming process. The research project proposes two process sub-models, which  predict the behavior of the elastic modulus and the level of frozen-in stresses.  These two sub-models will be used in a model based control system, consisting of a  number of process submodels encompassing different material properties and machine  characteristics. A series of experiments was conducted using an industrial  thermoforming machine to measure the elasticity and the level of frozen-in stresses  in the material. A bubble inflation technique was used to determine the behavior of  the elastic modulus in the transition state between solid and liquid. Additionally,  a simulation of the sag that occurs during plastic sheet heating was developed to  identify the level of frozen-in stresses.</description><creator>Rezazadeh-Bahadoran, Iman</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Online characterization of viscoelastic and stress-relaxation behavior in thermoforming</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wq69v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k595</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128b45p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The application of visible/near-infrared hyper-spectral analysis  to monitor the quality of frying oil and fried breaded chicken nuggets was  investigated. Partial least squares (PLS) calibration models were developed to  predict the acid value, total polar components and viscosity of heated oils with  different ratios of hydrogenation. Coefficient of determination (R2) and root mean  square error (RMSE) were calculated to assess the performance of each model. Results  of the study demonstrated good prediction ability of the calibration models for the  quality parameters with R2 values of over 0.92. The second study was based on developing calibration models for  prediction of moisture and fat contents of fried breaded chicken nuggets with  different levels of moisture and fat contents. Performing the same procedure for  evaluation of the PLS calibration models, results of the study demonstrated that  moisture and fat contents of fried breaded chicken nuggets could be predicted with  R2 values of 0.92.</description><creator>Kazemi Sangdehi, Samira</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Cookery (Chicken)</subject><subject>Convenience foods.</subject><subject>Near infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Deep frying.</subject><title>Quality evaluation of frying oil and chicken nuggets using visiblenear-infrared hyper-spectral analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w524d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128b45p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q446v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Zinc cluster proteins are a major class of transcriptional  regulators in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. This protein family includes Uga3 and Dal81,  which are both required for the activation of genes involved in the catabolism of  gamma-aminobutyrate (GABA). We discovered that the region of Uga3 encompassing amino  acids 130 to 300 likely corresponds to the regulatory domain of the protein. We also  determined that both the region encompassing amino acids 300 to 350 and the  C-terminus of Uga3 are required for activation. Additionally, activation by Uga3 can  occur in strains unable to completely degrade GABA or lacking the GABA permease  Uga4. Uga3 can form homodimers in vivo, both in the presence and in the absence of  GABA. However, it seems that Da181 cannot form heterodimers with Uga3 nor interact  with the UGA1 promoter. Furthermore, Dal81 is no longer required for activation if  Uga3 is overexpressed or mutated to a constitutively active form.</description><creator>Sylvain, Marc-André</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Functional analysis of Uga3 and Dal81, regulators of gamma-aminobutyrate catabolism in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jb958.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q446v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v363n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance of hypertension as a risk factor for the  development of AF is well recognized. Despite this leading importance, the role of  essential hypertension in providing a substrate for AF is incompletely understood.  The present study was undertaken to investigate the possibility of having rats as an  adequate animal model for the relationship between hypertension and AF in man and to  elucidate the role of hypertension as a risk factor for AF. The results of this  study show that structural remodeling especially in the form of increased amount of  interstitial fibrosis seems to be the major contributing factor to the AF  sustainability. Although it can be concluded that hypertension could accelerate the  accumulation of fibrosis which occurs during the normal process of aging, a clear  relationship between hypertension and AF in this rat model was not found. Further  work in the other animal models of hypertension would be  interesting.</description><creator>Andalib, Ali</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Relationship between a trial fibrillation and hypertension in rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dw097.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v363n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mq209</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The numerical analysis of electromagnetic devices can generate  large volumes of data describing the performance of the device. To date, this  information has been provided to the user either as sets of numeric data or in  graphical form. However, modern personal computers are actually capable of producing  other forms of output such as sound. Although an essential component in computer  gaming, sound has not been explored in any depth in scientific results  evaluation. This thesis describes the implementation of software designed to  investigate outputting data obtained from the simulation of an electromagnetic  system in the form of sound using readily available hardware components. Results  from surveys conducted suggest that the use of such a complementary output system  could enhance the understanding of the results of an analysis.</description><creator>Ahmad, Yasmin</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>The use of sound in enhancing the reality of computer simulations of electromagnetic devices /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246s58w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mq209</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687h962</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We review basic results in the field of finding extremal metrics  for spectral invariants of the Laplacian on both graphs and manifolds. Special  attention is given to the special case of the Klein bottle. The nececery theory is  developed to produce the result of Jakobson et all [J-N-P] regarding lambda 1 on the  Klein bottle. Using similar techniques, a new result is established in proving that  there is only one extremal metric of a certain kind for lambda 2 on the Klein  bottle.</description><creator>Bacle, Sébastien</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Extremal metrics on graphs and manifolds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn009z284.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687h962</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w66344235</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tyrosine phosphorylation is one of the most important  post-translational modifications used by cells to respond to external stimuli. Two  different sets of enzymes control the tyrosine phosphorylation levels of proteins:  the protein tyrosine kinases and the protein tyrosine phosphatases. The  identification of the cellular function of these enzymes is a key step in the  understanding of many biological processes, such as proliferation, differentiation  and apoptosis. We used a mouse model deficient in the protein tyrosine phosphatase  TC-PTP to identify its biological and biochemical functions. Analysis of the  phenotype of murine embryonic fibroblasts from TC-PTP-/- embryos revealed that  TC-PTP-/- cells have an impaired proliferation due to a slow progression during the  early G1-phase of the cell cycle. In these cells, there is a delayed expression of  cyclin D1 through a defective IKK/NF-kappaB signaling pathway. These data confirmed  that TC-PTP plays a positive role in cell proliferation. In the second part of this thesis, I studied the putative role  of TC-PTP in response to DNA damage. I demonstrated that mice and cells lacking  TC-PTP have a high sensitivity to genotoxic stress, which seems to be associated  with an increased stability and elevated phosphorylation of serine-15 of the tumor  suppressor p53. We found that the p53 inhibitor, Mdm2 is highly tyrosine  phosphorylated in TC-PTP-/- cells. High tyrosine phosphorylation levels on Mdm2 are  associated with more stability of p53. Although, it was not possible to show that  Mdm2 is a direct substrate for TC-PTP, this seems to be the most likely mechanism  used by TC-PTP to control p53. Interestingly, I also showed that double deficient  mice for both TC-PTP and p53 live longer and display a normal spleen compared with  the TC-PTP single knockout. However, another phenotype like the anemia is not  rescued in the double knockout mice. Murine embryonic fibroblasts from TC-PTP-/-  p53-/- embryos also have a better survival after genotoxic stress when compared with  the TC-PTP-/- cells. Thus, we propose that TC-PTP plays a role in response to DNA  damage by affecting the tyrosine phosphorylation levels of Mdm2, and its associated  increased stability of the tumor suppressor p53 In the last part of my thesis, I tested the genetic interaction  between the protein kinase c-Abl and the protein tyrosine phosphatase TC-PTP. Taking  in account the knockout phenotypes of both enzymes, we generated double deficient  mice for both TC-PTP and cAbl. TC-PTP-/- c-Abl-/- mice are viable, but there was no  difference in the time of survival of these animals when compared with the single  knockouts. However, data obtained with primary fibroblasts indicated that indeed  there is a genetic interaction between TC-PTP and c-Abl. Double deficient primary  fibroblasts proliferate better than TC-PTP-/- cells, and also present a better  survival in response to genotoxic stress. The induction of p53 is also reduced in  comparison with TC-PTP-/- cells. These results indicate that a genetic interaction  between both enzymes exists and that this phenomenon is likely to be resulting from  the existence of at least one common substrate.</description><creator>Ibarra-Sánchez, Maria</creator><contributor>Tremblay, Michel L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Biochemical and cellular function of t-cell protein tyrosine phosphatase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q449p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66344235</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407x843</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation presents solid-state NMR studies of the chain  conformation, dynamics and morphology of three adsorbed polymer systems: two random  semi-crystalline copolymers, poly(ethylene-co-acrylic acid) (PEA) and  poly(propylene-co-acrylic acid) (PPA), and an amorphous homopolymer, poly(n-butyl  methacrylate) (PnBMA). Zirconia (ZrO2) was chosen as the substrate for all three  polymers since the binding of carboxylic acids to this metal oxide is well  understood. The choice of polymers was based on their particular bulk conformational  and dynamic properties as well as their common use in polymer coatings. These  studies are motivated by the general lack of a microscopic picture of adsorbed  polymers, which can be provided by NMR, and the relevance of chain conformation and  dynamics to important polymer film properties such as adhesion. First the chain conformation and surface binding of adsorbed PEA  as a function of acrylic acid content are characterized by 13C cross polarization -  magic angle spinning (CP-MAS), 2D 1H- 13C wideline separation (WISE) and 1H spin  diffusion NMR experiments and FTIR-PAS (Fourier transform infrared photoacoustic  spectroscopy) measurements. The most important finding is that the chain  conformation of adsorbed PEA is determined primarily by the sticker group density  rather than the surface coverage. The second study of PEA concerns the chain  dynamics in the bulk and adsorbed states. Variable temperature NMR experiments  provide evidence that ethylene segments of adsorbed PEA form partially folded loops  rather than flat extended trains. Finally 129Xe NMR studies, used to probe the  morphology of adsorbed PEA, show a bulk-like signal only for the highest  loadings. The second system investigated, PPA, is another semi-crystalline  random copolymer which binds to zirconia via carboxylate linkages. The 13 C CP-MAS  NMR spectra of adsorbed PPAC unexpectedly show splittings normally associated with  chain-chain packing in the crystalline regions of bulk polypropylene (PP). The  splittings in the spectra of adsorbed PPAC, which are more resolved than in bulk  PPA, are proposed to arise from recrystallization of the PP segments between sticker  groups. Finally the interfacial properties of an amorphous homopolymer,  PnBMA were studied using 13C and 129Xe NMR to characterize adsorbed and filled  samples. PnBMA binds to zirconia via the partial hydrolysis of the ester side  chains. The remaining ester chains of adsorbed PnBMA are found to segregate to the  polymer/air interface. Both adsorbed and ZrO 2-filled PnBMA show enhanced local  segmental mobility. However, the 129Xe NMR measurements of the filled samples are  consistent with restricted motion on a larger length scale which may be due to  particle bridging.</description><creator>Nasreddine, Victor Fuad</creator><contributor>Reven, Linda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Solid state nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy of polymer thin films : chain conformation, dynamics, and morphology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt407.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x843</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z8302</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mammalian prosomatostatin (PSST) yields two bioactive peptides  SST-14 and SST-28 through C-terminal cleavage at basic residues by protein  convertases (PCs). Additionally, a second cleavage, mediated by an unknown enzyme at  a putative Lys13 residue at the NH2-termius generates PSST[1--10] (antrin). The  function of the PSST prosegment is unknown, but its high degree of sequence homology  throughout vertebrate evolution argues that it may harbor information for directing  PSST towards the regulated secretory pathway (RSP). Therefore, the PSST NH2-terminal  region has been extensively analyzed with the following questions asked: Does the  NH2-terminus play a role in targeting of PSST to the RSP? Is PSST cleaved at the  Lys13 site resulting in antrin production, and by the action of which enzyme? What  is the identity of the putative receptor in the trans-Golgi involved in properly  targeting PSST? To test the role of antrin in sorting function, alanine scanning and  deletional mutagenesis were constructed and stably expressed in AtT-20 cells. The  region Pro5 to Gln12 which constitutes an alpha-helix was identified as being  important in precursor targeting with Leu7 and Leu11 being critical. Earlier  morphological studies have implicated immature secretory granules as the site of  prohormone processing however, blockade of PSST targeting through disruption of the  helix did not hinder the ability of PSST to be processed at its C-terminus.  Furthermore, I find that PSST NH2-terminal cleavage does not take place at a basic  site but, most likely at the -R6-L 7-R8-Q9-F 10-L11↓ recognition motif.  Overexpression experiments in COS-1 and HEK-293 cells implicate the recently cloned  subtilase-kexin-isozyme 1 (SKI-1) in antrin production. Additionally, as proteins  function exclusively by means of interaction with other molecules, using the PSST  NH2-terminus as a bait in yeast two-hybrid screening assay I attempted to find  specific components in the trans-Golgi for</description><creator>Mouchantaf, Rania</creator><contributor>Patel, Y. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Processing and intracellular targeting of somatostatin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nf28j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z8302</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50ts20n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In primary rat hepatocytes, we found that activation of the  Pl3-kinase pathway is both necessary and sufficient to account for EGF-induced DNA  synthesis. To identify the mechanism of EGF-induced Pl3-kinase activation, we  demonstrated that three distinct p85-associated complexes were formed following EGF:  ErbB3-p85, Shc-p85 and a large complex Gab2-Grb2-SHP2-p85. The latter accounted for  &gt;80% of total Pl3-kinase activity. Further experiments showed that these  complexes are differentially localized in rat liver following EGF treatment.  ErbB3-p85 and Shc-p85 complexes were localized to PM and Endosomes; whereas the  multimeric Gab2-Grb2-SHP2-p85 complex was formed rapidly and exclusively in cytosol.  A central role for Gab2 in EGF-induced Pl3-kinase activation and DNA synthesis was  established when we observed that over-expression of wild-type Gab2 augmented these  EGF actions, whereas a Gab2 mutant lacking p85 binding sites did not effect such  augmentation. Over-expression of the PH-domain of Gab2 did not affect EGF-induced  Gab2 phosphorylation, Pl3-kinase activation and DNA synthesis, whereas  over-expressed Gab2 lacking the PH-domain was comparable to wild-type Gab2 in  respect to these EGF-induced signals. These data demonstrated that Gab2 is  phosphorylated and mediates EGF signaling in a PH-domain independent manner. We then  explored the mechanism of Gab2 phosphorylation by EGF; our results demonstrated that  PP1, a selective inhibitor of Src family kinases, blocked EGF-induced Gab2 tyrosine  phosphorylation and downstream events. Moreover, Gab2 phosphorylation was increased  in Csk knock-out cells in which Src family kinases are constitutively activated. A  constitutive association between Gab2 and Src via proline rich sequences on Gab2 was  demonstrated since deletion of proline rich sequences in Gab2 prevented EGF-induced  association of Src with Gab2, Gab2 phosphorylation, Pl3-kinase/Akt activation, and  DNA synthesis. The role of SHP2 was defin</description><creator>Kong, Mei, 1972-</creator><contributor>Posner, Barry I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Epidermal growth factor-induced DNA synthesis : key roles for phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase and the adaptor protein Gab2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9997234.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts20n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v404</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has recently been recognized that adult  Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) is a valid disorder (Gadow &amp;  Weiss, 2001). Much less is known, however, about the assessment of ADHD, and about  the functional impairments associated with ADHD, in adults compared to children. The  objective of the present study was to characterize the functional impairments in  DSM-IV diagnosed ADHD adults compared to community control adults and  clinic-referred adults reporting symptoms of inattention, hyperactivity and/or  impulsivity who did not meet symptom thresholds for the disorder. Method. The sample  for this study consisted of 120 adults: 47 adults with ADHD, 43 clinic-referred  adults who did not meet criteria for ADHD, and 30 community control adults. All were  assessed with a comprehensive battery assessing psychiatric, cognitive, school, and  driving impairment. Results. ADHD adults showed significantly more impairment than  community control adults on all outcome measures. ADHD adults had subtle cognitive  deficits, and higher rates of lifetime conduct problems compared to  clinic-comparison adults. ADHD adults did not differ reliably from clinic-comparison  adults on measures of internalizing disorders, school problems, or driving  impairment. Clinic-comparison adults showed significantly more impairment than  community control adults on measures of psychiatric functioning and school  impairment. Conclusions. DSM-IV diagnosed ADHD adults show a pattern of clinical  features that mirrors well-documented findings among children with the disorder, and  show significantly greater impairment than do community control adults. Adults  meeting some, but not all, criteria for ADHD fall in between ADHD adults and  community control adults, and may warrant treatment. Our results highlight the  importance of assessing ADHD in adults in a manner that attends to the potential  reduced sensitivity of the DSM-IV diagnostic criteria for use in adult populations  (Faraon</description><creator>Krane, Erica A.</creator><contributor>Koestner, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hechtman, Lily (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Cognition disorders.</subject><subject>Attention-deficit disorder in adults.</subject><title>Functional impairments associated with DSM-IV diagnosed adult attention-deficithyperactivity disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945r34g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v404</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526c834</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Up until recently, the development and generalization of h-type  and hp-type refinement techniques and strategies for the efficient and effective  adaptive finite element analysis of continuum problems has been limited by the  widespread use of geometrically conforming mesh discretizations, designed to  maintain the continuity of the field model. These limits have retarded the growth,  and restricted the potential, of modern adaptive finite element methods for  engineering electromagnetic systems modeling, analysis and simulation. A new  generalized theory and family of techniques which alleviate the need for conforming  meshes is presented. The method is based on the concept of generalized irregular  meshes and the formulation of a corresponding system of generalized constraint  equations. Both theoretical and numerical investigations indicate that the new  formulation can facilitate a very significant improvement in stable h-type and  hp-type refinement flexibility, as well as, a strong potential for increased  modeling efficiency and reduced computational costs. The new techniques have been implemented and tested for 1D, 2D  and 3D applications, for both scalar and vector finite element formulations in  engineering electromagnetics. In addition, the new theory has been used to develop  formulations for overlapping elements and layered meshes for adaptive error  estimation; semi-full-domain elements for parallel and distributed processing domain  decomposition methods; and, a new class of truly local and fully generalized hp  -type finite elements for adaption.</description><creator>Ma, Donglin, 1960-</creator><contributor>McFee, Steve (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Irregular finite elements : constraint theory and techniques</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw61w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526c834</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17ct45p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sample size determination is one of the most important  statistical issues in the early stages of any investigation that anticipates  statistical analyses. In this thesis, we examine Bayesian sample size determination  methodology for interval estimation. Four major epidemiological study designs,  cohort, case-control, cross-sectional and matched pair are the focus. We study three  Bayesian sample size criteria: the average length criterion (ALC), the average  coverage criterion ( ACC) and the worst outcome criterion (WOC ) as well as various  extensions of these criteria. In addition, a simple cost function is included as  part of our sample size calculations for cohort and case-controls studies. We also  examine the important design issue of the choice of the optimal ratio of controls  per case in case-control settings or non-exposed to exposed in cohort  settings. The main difficulties with Bayesian sample size calculation  problems are often at the computational level. Thus, this thesis is concerned, to a  considerable extent, with presenting sample size methods that are computationally  efficient.</description><creator>M'lan, Cyr Emile</creator><contributor>Joseph, Lawrence (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Wolfson, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Bayesian sample size calculations for cohort and case-control studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s298d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct45p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000000531</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:26:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first decades of the twentieth-century featured a full-scale  assault on prostitution and Red Light Districts in cities across North America. The  Committee of Sixteen's efforts to erase 'commercialized vice' from Montreal reflect  moral regulation projects as they have been recently theorized. The Committee's  members represented a range of commercial, feminist, social and religious  institutions with various agendas. This thesis considers how prostitution is  constructed to mobilize a diverse range of social actors at specific times.  Examining the press of the time, as well as reports and speeches produced by the  Committee over its seven-year history reveals how members constructed prostitution  as a symbol and scapegoat for multiple, sometimes contradictory, contemporary  concerns and anxieties in the years following World War I. This discourse served to  further marginalize the very women the Committee ostensibly sought to  'rescue'.</description><creator>Herland, Karen</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Committee of Sixteen (Montréal, Québec)</subject><subject>Social problems -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 20th century</subject><subject>Prostitution -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>Organized righteousness against organized viciousness : constructing prostitution in post World War I Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qs51w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000000531</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43950</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>