<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:41:51Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39700" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p37t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mafic volcanic sequences of tholeiitic basalt and associated komatiite are common to many Precambrian shields of the world. Recently discovered remnants of Archean greenstone belts in the northern Superior Province of Canada exhibit characteristics similar to larger belts of the southern Superior Province. Three of the best preserved belts are trapped in ca. 2.77--2.88 Ga tonalitic intrusives of the Faribault-Thury amphibolitic Complex (FTC), and provide direct evidence for the nature of the mantle prior to the major volcanic events of the late Archean (ca. 2.7 Ga). These belts consist of amphibolite facies rocks of volcanic and sedimentary origin, in one of which a wide variety of cumulates are preserved. The association of the lavas with meta-pelites, iron formations, marbles, and the lack of conglomerate and clearly crustally contaminated lavas suggest that the FTC lavas were erupted in an oceanic environment. The three belts are separated by over 100 km, but exhibit similar chemical characteristics and may represent the base of an extensive early mafic crust. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Maurice, Charles, 1976-</creator><contributor>Francis, Don (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Archean mafic volcanism of the Eastern Ungava peninsula, Northern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs56c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p37t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt01h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Organochlorine (OC) compounds that include several pesticides as well as an array of industrial chemicals were very efficacious for their intended use but were also characterized by deleterious environmental impacts when released either intentionally or inadvertently. Their lipophilic nature, long persistence in the environment and threat to human health caused all the developed countries to ban the production of these chemicals as well as restricted the use of formulations containing these material for food production. A number of scientists have become involved in the development of intentional degradation methods/techniques for these compounds using zero-valent metals or bimetallic mixtures. To date, there is no single, simple and continuous procedure available to completely dechlorinate lindane or pentachlorophenol (PCP). This work describes the complete dechlorination of lindane and pentachlorophenol by zero-valent Zn, Fe and Fe/Ag bimetallic mixture as well as a supercritical fluid extraction technique for a more efficient mass transfer of the substrates to the surfaces of the metal catalyst. The dechlorination reaction occurs on the surface of metal particles with the removal of all the chlorine atoms from lindane and PCP in a matter of minute, and yields completely dechlorinated hydrocarbon molecules and chloride as products. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kabir, Anwar.</creator><contributor>Marshall, William D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Pentachlorophenol -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Lindane -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Solvent extraction.</subject><title>Dechlorination of chlorinated organic compounds by zero-valent and bimetallic mixture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860874v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt01h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb283</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reforestation is being considered as a mitigation option to help combat the climate change predicted to result from atmospheric carbon dioxide pollution. Forestry-based carbon storage projects are being introduced in many tropical countries, and assessment of species-specific carbon storage potentials is made difficult by a lack of species-level information. This study focuses on teak (Tectona grandis), to measure many of the characteristics affecting the carbon storage potential both of the trees themselves and of the plantations they are in. Root-to-shoot ratio, above- and belowground biomass, as well as tissue carbon content were measured in 20-year-old teak trees in Panamanian plantations. A regression relating diameter at breast height (DBH) to total tree carbon storage for trees of various sizes was developed. To scale up to the plantation level, this regression was used to estimate the carbon storage of the trees of four plantations. Litter, undergrowth, and soil were studied to estimate carbon storage in these compartments. These estimates were collated to form a global estimate of carbon storage in Panamanian harvest age teak plantations. Various methods of calculation of carbon storage in short-rotation plantations are discussed. This work will allow greater precision in the assessment of carbon storage in individual plantations.</description><creator>Kraenzel, Margaret.</creator><contributor>Potvin, Catherine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Carbon dioxide mitigation -- Panama.</subject><subject>Tree farms -- Panama.</subject><subject>Teak -- Panama.</subject><subject>Carbon sequestration -- Panama.</subject><title>Carbon storage of Panamanian harvest-age teak (Tectona grandis) plantations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw98w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb283</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b5211</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Septic patients produce increased nitric oxide (NO). We postulated increased exhaled nitric oxide (exNO) in SIRS after cardiopulmonary bypass surgery (CPB). Methods. Forty-two intubated patients were studied postoperatively and at two-hour intervals for eight hours or until extubated. Hemodynamic indices, including indexed systemic vascular resistance (SVRi) and cardiac index (CI) were measured. ExNO was analyzed by ozone chemiluminescence. Results. Six patients (14%) Manifested SIRS, defined as SVRI &lt;1800 dynes·sec/cm5/m2. ExNO indexed by expired volume of minute ventilation and body surface area (exNO· V˙Ei) was less in SIRS patients at each interval. Overall, normal exNO·V˙Ei was 4.3 +/- 0.4 nL/min/m2 with a Cl of 2.56 +/- 0.05 L/min/m 2 and an SVRI of 2488 +/- 62 dynes·sec/cm5/m 2, whereas in SIRS exNO·V˙Ei was 0.7 +/- 0.3 (p &lt; 0.001) with a Cl of 2.97 +/- 0.09 (p &lt; 0.001) and an SVRi of 1826 +/- 86 (p &lt; 0.001). Conclusions. Pulmonary production of NO in post-CPB SIRS differs from sepsis and may not be reflective of systemic levels. Increased pulmonary blood flow may scavenge lung production of NO thereby decreasing exhaled levels.</description><creator>Keyser, Eric J.</creator><contributor>Goldberg, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Exhaled nitric oxide and the Systemic Inflammatory Response Syndrome (SIRS) after cardiac surgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172010x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b5211</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r21c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This multi-centered study examined the prevalence of outcome measure use in physiotherapy practice for low back pain, the frequency and timing of use and the factors associated with their use. A review of 265 charts of clients who had received treatment for low back pain from 53 physiotherapists was completed to identify outcome measure use. Review of the charts identified seven standardized and thirteen non-standardized outcome measures that were used in clinical practice. Of these, all were measures of impairment except for two that measured disability. Standardized and non-standardized measures were mainly used at the initial evaluation. 27% and 66%. Thirty-four percent (95% CI, 14--50) of the physiotherapists were identified as users of standardized measures. The users of standardized measures provided more treatments (p = 0.0018), and the treatments were over a longer period of time (p = 0.0029) than non-users and the source of payment for the physiotherapy service was from Worker's Compensation, motor vehicle and hospitals rather than from private insurance (p = 0.0000035).</description><creator>Kirkness, Carmen Stephanie.</creator><contributor>Korner-Bitensky, Nicole (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Prevalence of outcome measure use by physiotherapists in the management of low back pain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td93j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r21c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s34f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The scope of these studies was two-fold: to evaluate high pressure homogenized slurries as a rapid means of screening wood pulps for their Cu, Mn and Fe content and to evaluate the high pressure homogenization in combination with chelating agents or enzymatic digestion for the liberation/extraction of metal ions from this matrix. Cu, Mn and Fe were determined successfully in pulp samples using high-pressure homogenization prior to slurry introduction-GF-AAS. The analysis time of the method from sample acquisition to determination was of the order of a few minutes per sample. Different cellulose swelling/dissolution agents were evaluated for the generation of quasi-stable pulp suspensions, rich in cellulose. High-pressure homogenization alone or in combination with chelating agents or enzymatic digestion was also investigated as a means of quantitatively releasing these metal ions into the liquid phases. A new model of homogenizer equipped with ceramic homogenizing valve with a few modifications was evaluated in terms of metal contamination levels within the final sample dispersion. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ehsan, Sadia.</creator><contributor>Marshall, W. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Trace elements -- Analysis.</subject><subject>High pressure (Technology)</subject><subject>Furnace atomic absorption spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Metals -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Wood-pulp -- Analysis.</subject><title>High pressure homogenization of wood pulp samples prior to slurry introduction for the determination of Cu, Mn and Fe by graphite furnace atomic absorption spectrometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k95c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s34f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236396n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A Sinorhizobium meliloti (S. meliloti ) mutant, Rm30O49, deficient in malate dehydrogenase (MDH) activity was isolated via random Tn5tac1 mutagenesis. DNA sequence analyses revealed 60 the inaction is within the mdh gene. Rm30049 lacks MDH activity under all growth conditions, but shows increased or decreased activities of the TCA cycle enzymes 2-oxoglutarate dehydrogenase and succinate dehydrogenase in the presence or absence, respectively, of IPTG (isopropyl beta-D-thiogalactoside). The symbiotic phenotype of the mutant is an inability to fix nitrogen. Alfalfa seedlings inoculated with Rm30049 produced small white root nodules, but were chlorotic and failed to reach a wild-type shoot dry weight. Cosmid clone pDS15 was isolated by heterologous complementation of a Rhizobium leguminosarum sucD mutant by the S. meliloti pLAFR1 clone bank. This cosmid also restored MDH activity to Rm30049, and complemented the mutant growth and symbiotic phenotypes. Three Tn5 insertions isolated in pDS15 within sucA failed to complement Rm30049. DNA sequence analyses indicate that the mdh gene is part of the TCA cycle operon with sucCD, and that downstream and upstream of this, are operons encoding sucAB and sdhCDAB, respectively.</description><creator>Dymov, Sergiy.</creator><contributor>Driscoll, B. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Malate dehydrogenase.</subject><subject>Rhizobium meliloti -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>Isolation and characterization of malate dehydrogenase mutant of Sinorhizobium meliloti</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h143.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236396n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tw995</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction. Defects in ion channels and kinase phosphorylation have been reported in streptozotocin (STZ) models of diabetic neuropathy. We hypothesise that changes in phosphorylation may underlie changes in the excitability in the peripheral nerves. Objective. To examine the effect of pharmacological modulation of electrophysiological parameters in STZ-diabetic mice. Methods. Electrophysiological measurements were done in sciatic nerves of mice made diabetic with Streptozotocin. Results. We report that sucrose gap measurements on sciatic nerves of compound action potential conduction velocity, area and refractory period was affected in STZ mice. Treatment with 4-Aminopyridine increased the delayed depolarization area in diabetic more than in control, which could reveal problems with fast potassium channels and/or slow sodium channels. Pharmacological tools showed that regulation of PKC and tyrosine phosphorylation in diabetic mice was disturbed. Conclusion. These results strongly suggest that aberrant phosphorylation could contribute to the pathological symptoms observed in diabetic neuropathy.</description><creator>Dupont, Michel, 1976-</creator><contributor>Padjen, A. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Electrophysiological evidence of altered excitability in ion channels due to phosphorylation change in STZ-induced diabetic mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr1720116.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw995</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws124</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>English-style crumpets (pH 6--8, aw 0.97--0.99) are a popular baked product enjoyed by consumers worldwide. However, over the past few years, outbreaks of food poisoning have been caused by the growth of Bacillus cereus in crumpets. This spore forming microorganism, which originates in flour, can easily survive the baking process and grow to &gt;106 CFU/g within 3--5 days at ambient storage temperature. Therefore, control of this pathogen is essential to ensure the safety and marketability of English-style crumpets. Initial studies were done to determine the effect of water activity ( aw), pH, modified atmosphere packaging (MAP), UV-light, bacteriocins, organic acids and esters, alone and in conjunction with each other, on the growth of B. cereus in model broth/agar systems. B. cereus is a difficult microorganism to control in food using conventional preservation methods. Further studies are now under way to investigate novel methods to control the growth of this pathogen, particularly in high pH crumpets. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>El-Khoury, Wassim.</creator><contributor>Smith, J. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Bacillus cereus -- Control.</subject><subject>Baked products -- Preservation.</subject><title>Control of Bacillus cereus in English-style crumpets</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj999.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws124</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g685w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Measles virus (MV) infects up to 40 million individuals each year, leading to one million deaths. MV can infect a wide variety of cell types including cells of the immune system. Although vitamin A (retinal) supplements can significantly reduce measles-associated mortality, the mechanism(s) remains unknown. We adopted a three-pronged approach to investigate vitamin A modulation of measles infection of human immune cells. We found that, at 1muM, both retinoic acid and retinol (ROH) with or without retinol binding protein (RBP) decreased MV production by 33% +/- 24% (p &lt; 0.001), 37% +/- 20% (p &lt; 0.001), and 23% +/- 17% (p &lt; 0.04) respectively and peak inhibition with ROH:RBP occurred at 10-6 muM. Also, ROH:RBP treatment of U937 cells increased the viral fusion:nucleocapsid mRNA ratio by 1.6 +/- 0.3-fold (p &lt; 0.05) thus altering optimal transcript ratios. Finally, MV-infection of U937 cells increases retinoic acid receptor alpha and retinoid X receptor alpha mRNA expression (2.0 +/- 0.74-fold and 2.1 +/- 0.33-fold; p &lt; 0.05, respectively) while simultaneous treatment with ROH:RBP maintained or decreased levels of these two receptors compared to control, respectively. These data demonstrate that vitamin A can have substantial impact on MV replication and viral protein expression in human immune cells in vitro. These data also suggest that MV may have its profound impact on the immune system by manipulation of the retinoid signaling pathway and that supplemental retinoids may interfere with this action.</description><creator>Chatterjee, Avijit.</creator><contributor>Ward, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Vitamin A and measles : cellular and molecular analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd315.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g685w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk76v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A dual stable isotope approach (delta13C and delta15N) was used to assess the importance of pelagic organic carbon in littoral secondary production and explore its predictability. Forty-seven sites were sampled in Lake Memphremagog (Quebec--Vermont) to characterize the isotopic position of the primary producers and filter-feeding freshwater mussels, as well as macrophyte biomass, chlorophyll-a concentration, and site exposure. The different sites spanned a wide range in the three environmental variables. For each site, littoral, terrestrial, and pelagic contributions to the diet of the mussels were calculated from mussel isotopic position, corrected for trophic enrichment. The mean contributions were: littoral---8%, terrestrial---27%, and pelagic---65%. However, the magnitude of the pelagic contribution was not related to macrophyte biomass, site exposure or chlorophyll-a concentration. The finding that the unionid mussels, a major littoral zone filter-feeder, obtain about two-thirds of their nutrition from pelagic zone particles washed into the littoral zone provides evidence for a close coupling in carbon flow of the littoral and pelagic zone. This study represents an important step towards a better understanding of carbon flow in aquatic food webs.</description><creator>Chagnon, Guillaume.</creator><contributor>Kalff, Jacob (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Lake ecology -- Memphremagog, Lake (Québec and Vt.)</subject><subject>Food chains (Ecology) -- Memphremagog, Lake (Québec and Vt.)</subject><title>The relative contribution of pelagic primary production to the littoral food web of lakes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z966n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk76v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p217p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Troilus gold-copper deposit lies within the northeastern part of the Archaean Frotet-Evans greenstone belt, in the Opatica sub-province of the Superior Province, northern Quebec, and contains total reserves of 51 Mt at 1.08 g/t gold, 0.11% copper, and 1.4 g/t silver. The largest orebody, Zone 87, has been mined by open pit methods since 1993. Rocks of the Troilus domain include a coarse- to medium-grained metadiorite, a finer-grained amphibolite, a rock with a brecciated texture and felsic dykes, which crosscut the metadioritic pluton, the amphibolite and the breccia. The amphibolite, breccia, and felsic dykes all locally host ore. Previous researchers have proposed a porphyry-type model for the genesis of the Troilus deposit. However, evidence that the breccia unit is not hydrothermal but a product of magma mixing, that the felsic dykes predate mineralization, and that mineralization and associated alteration occurred as two discrete events separated by a major episode of regional metamorphism (amphibolite facies), requires that alternative genetic models for the deposit be considered, such as orogenic gold model. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Carles, Patricia, 1975-</creator><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Goodman, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Constraints on the genesis of the Archaean Troilus gold-copper deposit, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2363986.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p217p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3013226</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We used decision analysis to determine the factors that influence the decision of whether or not to extubate and to evaluate the usefulness of testing with the RR/Vt ratio. A questionnaire was also distributed to experienced critical care specialists. We showed that the rate of improvement in the patient condition had the greatest influence on the decision to extubate. When the rate of improvement was high, the best decision was to continue with mechanical ventilation unless the probability of tolerating extubation was greater than 0.95. However, when there was little or no chance of further improvement with ongoing mechanical ventilation, the best decision was always to extubate. These results appeared to be counter-intuitive to experienced clinicians who were more likely to extubate when patients were improving and less likely when patients were stable. Testing with the RR/Vt ratio was of little benefit when deciding to extubate.</description><creator>Cardinal, Pierre.</creator><contributor>Hutchinson, Thomas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>The role of the respiratory rate over tidal volume ratio and other clinical variables in the decision to extubate : a decision analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj25c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3013226</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq535</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Due to a rising interest in natural fibres for textiles as well as environmental concerns, the demand for fibre flax has increased in recent decades. It was, therefore, with great enthusiasm that Canadian farmers welcomed, in 1997, the opening of a flaxprocessing unit in the region of Salaberry-de-Valleyfield, Quebec. The purpose of this study was to investigate the economic viability of fibre flax contracting as an alternative activity for field-crop producers in Quebec. A risk-programming model called minimization of total absolute deviation (MOTAD) was developed to better approach this issue. The MOTAD takes into account the variability in income that stems from uncertainty in commodity-market prices and yields. In addition, five different marketing strategies for pricing grain corn and soybeans were included in the model. These pricing techniques combined the use of futures and options markets. In a global agricultural system, where international commitments force governments to cut subsidies, reducing income variability for risk-averse farmers becomes a critical challenge. This study offered to assess the contribution of both contracting and futures markets as alternative market instruments for risk management. Five portfolio farm plans were identified for 200- and 300-hectare farm sizes. The results showed that gains through fibre flax contracting, in terms of risk reduction, exist only for the farm plans with lower levels of income and risk. Moreover, simulations demonstrated that the use of futures and options markets can help maximize overall net farm return.</description><creator>Amrouk, El Mamoun.</creator><contributor>Gunjal, Kisan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Flax -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Flax industry -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>The economic implications of combining fibre flax contracting along with futures and options to control for farm revenue instability in Quebec /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838235v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq535</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw30k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Let S be a data set of n points in Rd, and m&amp;d4; be a point in Rd which "best" describes S. Since the term "best" is subjective, there exist several definitions for finding m&amp;d4; . However, it is generally agreed that such a definition, or estimator of location, should have certain statistical properties which make it robust. Most estimators of location assign a depth value to any point in Rd and define m&amp;d4; to be a point with maximum depth. Here, new results are presented concerning the computational complexity of estimators of location. We prove that in R2 the computation of simplicial and halfspace depth of a point requires O (n log n) time, which matches the upper bound complexities of algorithms by Rousseeuw and Ruts. Our lower bounds also apply to two sign tests, that of Hodges and that of Oja and Nyblom. In addition, we propose algorithms which reduce the time complexity of calculating the points with greatest Oja and simplicial depth. Our fastest algorithms use O(n3 log n) and O(n4) time respectively, compared to the algorithms of Rousseeuw and Ruts which use O(n5 log n) time. One of our algorithms may also be used to find a point with minimum weighted sum of distances to a set of n lines in O( n2) time. This point is called the Fermat-Torricelli point of n lines by Roy Barbara, whose algorithm uses O( n3) time. Finally, we propose a new estimator which arises from the notion of hyperplane depth recently defined by Rousseeuw and Hubert.</description><creator>Aloupis, Greg.</creator><contributor>Toussaint, Godfried T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>On computing geometric estimators of location</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j465.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw30k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w0324825</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nitric oxide (NO) has been shown to be lethal for a variety of intracellular pathogens including Leishmania. In murine models, the inducible nitric oxide synthase gene (iNOS) is expressed in activated macrophages and is involved in the synthesis of NO. Because the role of NO and iNOS in human leishmaniasis was less clear, we examined the expression of the iNOS gene in human macrophages infected with Leishmania in vitro and in biopsy tissue from subjects with cutaneous leishmaniasis. Pentavalent antimony (Sb5+) in the form of Pentostam(TM) or Glucantime(TM) is still the treatment of choice despite its toxicity. Aldara(TM) (5% imiquimod) is an immune-response modifying agent that has been approved by the Food and Drug Administration in the USA for treating genital warts caused by papillomaviruses. We conducted an open-label, prospective study of combined Glucantime(TM) + Aldara(TM) therapy in subjects with CL who had previously failed a complete course of Glucantime(TM) treatment at regular doses. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Arevalo, Iracema.</creator><contributor>Matlashewski, Greg (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Ward, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Leishmaniasis, Cutaneous -- Immunotherapy.</subject><subject>Antimony -- Therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Antimony Sodium Gluconate.</subject><subject>Leishmaniasis, Cutaneous -- Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>Aminoquinolines.</subject><subject>Quinoline.</subject><title>Cutaneous leishmaniasis : iNOS gene expression and a novel immunomodulatory therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f309d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0324825</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0969065</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several epidemiological studies have evaluated whether an association exists between hypertension and cancer with inconclusive results because of several design biases. Using the Saskatchewan Health Databases, a cohort of subjects with incident treated hypertension between 1980 and 1987 was assembled and followed until 1996 to identify all incident cancer hospitalizations. Age and sex-standardized incidence ratios for all cause and for site-specific cancers were estimated using provincial cancer rates. A small increased risk of all-cause cancer was found mainly among females (RR: 1.12, 95 percent CI 1.06--1.17). Site-specific analyses revealed increased risks for uterine, breast, bladder, kidney, and several less common cancers. Re-analyses to control for reverse causality and detection bias did not alter the findings. While this study suggests a weak association between hypertension and cancer, the inability to control for information bias and for certain confounders does not allow for a definitive conclusion on causality.</description><creator>Assimes, Themistocles.</creator><contributor>Suissa, Samy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Hypertension and the risk of cancer : a population study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h365n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0969065</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gj27x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recognised as an excellent tool for competition in the current liberalised framework of international air transport, code-sharing is becoming a common practice, as an integral part of the activity of an airline, with obvious implications for both airlines and passengers. This thesis presents two predominant legal implications of such a practice, involving two carriers for a single flight: the contracting carrier and the operating carrier. First, this study aims at examining the relationship between users/passengers and code-share partners, more particularly identifying the practice as misleading due to the non-disclosure of the actual operator of the flight, which is magnified by the inaccuracy and shortcomings of computerised reservation systems (CRS). The regulatory framework in this regard is described and the legal obligation to disclose the identity of the actual carrier is given top priority. The delimitation of operational responsibilities will also be addressed (inadmissible passengers, overbooking and baggage concerns). The private agreement between the code-share partners will be given importance in ascertaining the liability issues. Second, the current international liability regime is analysed with a view to consider the code-sharing scenario. The potential conflict between the different international legal regimes governing air carriers' liability is highlighted in order that this aspect be taken into account by the code-share partners in their contractual agreement. Last but not least, some provisions of the new Montreal Convention of 28 May 1999 will be examined. A closer look will be given specifically to those provisions of Chapter V that are particularly applicable to a code-sharing situation.</description><creator>Guelfi, Audrey.</creator><contributor>Van Fenema, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Liability for aircraft accidents.</subject><subject>Competition, International.</subject><subject>Airlines -- Reservation systems.</subject><title>Implications of code-sharing agreements on air carriers' liability</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm27s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj27x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x576r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) issued on 27 March 1997 a recommendation concerning cryptography policy guidelines in an attempt to foster international co-operation and harmonization. Information is becoming increasingly valuable in society. Globalization of markets, improvements in information and communication technology and the shift to a knowledge-based economy has, furthermore, created an enormous potential for electronic commerce. Conservative estimates predict electronic commerce will have a turnover of more than US $400 billion by 2002. The increasing importance of information and communications has, however, made the information society vulnerable. Cryptography plays an important part in securing transactions in electronic commerce and moreover, in establishing a secure electronic environment in the information society. Fear of privacy infringements and lack of secure methods for electronic transactions has until now been holding electronic commerce back. Cryptographic methods are an essential part in securing electronic commerce. Law enforcement agencies and national security organizations fear, however, that widespread use of strong encryption will impede their work substantially. This thesis analyzes the advantages and disadvantages of strong encryption and how the balance of the conflicting interests has been dealt with in the OECD Cryptography Policy Guidelines. Moreover, shows the thesis how the OECD Cryptography Policy Guidelines have been implemented and makes suggestions on how the guidelines should be implemented.</description><creator>Jeppson, Jonas.</creator><contributor>Glenn, H. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Data encryption (Computer science) -- Law and legislation -- OECD countries.</subject><subject>Cryptography -- OECD countries.</subject><subject>Privacy, Right of -- OECD countries.</subject><title>The OECD cryptography policy guidelines and their implementation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s4284.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x576r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd32f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study deals with the prerogatives associated with work distribution in copyright law. The first part is devoted to the droit de destination and the exhaustion doctrine. We will illustrate each one with legislative and jurisprudential examples. While these theories are often regarded as opposite, they in fact are dissimilar juridical solutions. The exhaustion doctrine derives from an economic conception of copyright law whereas the droit de destination originates from natural law focussed on the interests of the author. The second part is concerned with the fact that a coherent theory on work distribution in Canadian copyright law has yet to be established. It will be shown how the legislator and the jurisprudence have developed means to assure that, after the first distribution of the work, the copyright holder is still in the position to control some of its use. Finally, I will proceed to analyse the regime that deals specifically with parallel imports allowing the copyright holder to supervise imported works.</description><creator>Hickey, Jonathan L.</creator><contributor>Gendreau, Yeolde (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Copyright.</subject><subject>Intellectual property.</subject><title>La distribution des oeuvres du point de vue du droit de destination, de l'épuisement du droit et des importations parallèles /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182n06s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd32f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623f47x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When should a commander be held responsible for the crimes of those under his control? Must a commander have known, or is it enough that he should have known, that his subordinates had committed or were about to commit a crime before we impose criminal responsibility on him for failing to prevent or punish those crimes? In attempting to answer these questions, the very foundations of criminal responsibility are set out and form the normative framework within which our examination of the command responsibility doctrine is undertaken. The historical evolution and modern-day application of the command responsibility doctrine are also set out and draws upon two themes; whether there is any justification for the distinction between the responsibility of military and civilian commanders and which mens rea standard should be adopted for the doctrine of command responsibility.</description><creator>Hood, Andrew, 1976-</creator><contributor>Provost, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>International offenses.</subject><subject>Command of troops.</subject><subject>International Criminal Court.</subject><title>The doctrine of command responsibility and the International Criminal Court : development, regression or compromise?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pj197.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f47x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j70g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This present study examined parent and teacher treatment integrity during conjoint behavioral consultation (CBC) in the remediation of behavioral problems in children at home and at school. A primary purpose of the study examined the relationship between treatment integrity and treatment outcome. A second purpose was to investigate the association between the integrity with which interventions were implemented and treatment acceptability. More specifically, the relationships between parent and teacher treatment integrity and (a) time to effectiveness; and (b) intervention difficulty were examined. An A/B design was used and participants included 12 children, their parents, and their teachers. Results indicate that parent and teacher treatment integrity was moderately related to the effectiveness of interventions. Results also indicate that treatment integrity and parent and teacher perceptions of treatment acceptability were minimally related. However, strong relationships were found between treatment integrity and parent and teacher perceptions of time to effectiveness and a moderate relationship was found with treatment integrity and parent ratings of program difficulty. Moreover, the directions of the treatment integrity relationships with treatment acceptability and intervention difficulty factors were in the direction hypothesized with the exception of teacher perceptions of treatment acceptability. The theoretical and practical implications of these findings, limitations of this study, and future research directions are discussed.</description><creator>Steinbach, Lisa.</creator><contributor>Sladeczek, I. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Family psychotherapy.</subject><subject>Behavior disorders in children.</subject><title>Parent and teacher treatment integrity and conjoint behavioral consultation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268700j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j70g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq54f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the effects of hyperbaric oxygen (HBO) therapy on acute ankle injuries and determined if HBO therapy shortened time to recovery, decreased edema and pain, and increased range of motion and strength of the ankle. Subjects were randomly assigned to either an experimental (HBO) group (n = 4) or a control group (n = 4). All subjects received the same standardized physical therapy for lateral ankle sprains at the McGill Sport Medicine Clinic. The HBO group received 5 consecutive HBO treatments at 2.5 ATA for 90 minutes starting within 24 hours post injury. The control group received no HBO treatments. All subjects were evaluated by a physician within 24 hours of injury. All subjects suffered a second-degree lateral ankle sprain. Pain, range of motion, strength, volume displacement, and function were evaluated on the day of injury (Day 1), on Day 6 post injury, and on the day of return to play (Day RTP). There was no significant difference in time to return to play. However, the HBO group (25.5 +/- 11.6 days) did return 31% faster than the control group (36.8 +/- 19.4 days). There were no differences found between groups on the variables. There was a decrease in pain found over time (Day 1 was 57 mm, Day 6 was 18.5 mm, and Day RTP was 7 mm). The results of this study suggest that with treatment of HBO there is no effect on ankle sprains for return to play or improved function.</description><creator>Skelton, Deborah.</creator><contributor>Montgomery, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Ankle -- Wounds and injuries -- Treatment.</subject><subject>Hyperbaric oxygenation.</subject><subject>Sprains -- Treatment.</subject><title>The effects of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on acute ankle sprains /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t59f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq54f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb210</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates, through primary research, the role of traditional knowledge in regional, national, and international political activities of Canadian Inuit. The links between an increasingly postmodern West, global environmental discourse, and the role of traditional knowledge in Inuit self-identity and self-government issues are outlined and set in relation to anthropological theory on globalization. The research indicates that Inuit engagement in competition over resources and power is complemented by a competitive cultural imagery, which draws on and contributes to a discourse on global cultural exchange. Subordinate groups' uses of such imageries have been discussed in anthropology, and are discussed further in the thesis. It is argued that deconstructive critiques of these imageries are problematic, but the need for research about cultural imageries is acknowledged as well. It is suggested that analyses of the politicization of cultural imageries should include political and philosophical contexts in order to lessen their potentially harmful consequences.</description><creator>Sjunner, Roger.</creator><contributor>Scott, Colin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Inuit -- Commerce.</subject><subject>Inuit -- Intellectual life.</subject><subject>Inuit -- Politics and government.</subject><title>Traditional knowledge and global politics : the promotion of Inuit culture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qn878.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb210</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v7361</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary purpose of this study is the exploration of the theoretical and critical framework of media education. The major paradigms used as rationale for the study of media embody views of media as agents of cultural decline that stress discriminating against the media; media as popular arts, stressing discriminating within the media; media as agents of communication, featuring the behavioral models of media studies; studying the media as representational or symbolic systems; and an exploration of the interaction between the self and the media and the question of whether and how media empower or oppress. Developments in the fields of structuralism, semiotics, theories of ideology and the social context of media production are discussed as the contributing factors to a view of media as representational systems. The study is concluded with a discussion of the significance of the context of meaning and a brief discussion of the educational implications of the field of cultural studies.</description><creator>Taebi, Shala.</creator><contributor>McDonnough, Kevin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Mass media -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>Mass media -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Theoretical foundations of media education : a critical analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv476.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7361</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39725</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>