<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:29:36Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m833b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The above-ground part of a plant has an important contribution to plant development and yield production. Physiological activities of a plant canopy highly correlate to morphology of plant vegetation. Obviously, leaf area index is a good indicator for leaf area, but does not provide any information about the spatial architecture of plant canopy. With the development of fractal theory, a quantitative toot is now available for the investigation of complex objects and shapes such as plant structure. Vegetation structure of corn ( Zea mays L.) and soybean (Glycine max. (L.) Merr.] plants might be affected by the plant population density (low, normal, high) of each crop and corn-soybean intercropping. Skeletonized leaf-off images provided acceptable information to estimate the fractal dimension of the soybean plant 2-dimensionally, using the box-counting method. Fractal dimension varied among soybean treatments, with rankings: low &gt; normal &gt; intercrop &gt; high, in the overall mean and normal ≈ intercrop ≈ low &gt; high, in the slope of time plots. An adjustment of field corn plants to treatments, by changing the orientation of the plane of developed leaves with respect to the row, was observed. Thus, the fractal dimension of corn plant skeletal images from each of two sides, side I (parallel to row) and side 2 (perpendicular to row), was analyzed. On the basis of overall means of fractal dimension, treatments were ranked as: high &gt; normal ≈ intercrop ≈ low for side 1 and intercrop &gt; low ≈ normal &gt; high for side 2. In both cases of soybean and corn plants, leaf area index, plant height and number of leaves (only in case of soybean plant) increased over the experiment for all the treatments, indicating a positive correlation with fractal dimension. In contrast, light penetration decreased during crop development, indicating a negative correlation with fractal dimension. Furthermore, a modified version of the Beer-Lambert equation, in which fractal dimension mu</description><creator>Foroutan-pour, Kayhan.</creator><contributor>Dutilleul, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Soybean -- Morphology.</subject><subject>Companion planting.</subject><subject>Fractals.</subject><subject>Corn -- Morphology.</subject><title>Fractal geometry concepts applied to the morphology of crop plants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b278v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m833b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171z89q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possible involvement of spinal metabotropic glutamate receptors (mGluRs) were examined in animal models of persistent and chronic pain. In Study 1, it was shown that spinal administration of relatively selective group I mGluR antagonists, or a selective group III mGluR agonist, but not a non-selective mGluR antagonist, slightly, but significantly reduced nociceptive scores in the rat formalin test Also, spinal administration of a non-selective mGluR agonist, or a selective group I mGluR agonist, but not a relatively selective group II agonist, enhanced formalin-induced nociception. The pro-nociceptive effects of these agents were reversed by a non-selective mGluR antagonist or by an N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor (NMDAR) antagonist. In Study 2, it was shown that intrathecal administration of two non-selective mGluR agonists or a selective group I mGluR agonist, but not a selective group II or group III mGluR agonist, produced spontaneous nociceptive behaviours, (SNBs) in rats. Also, the SNBs induced by these agents were reduced by a non-selective mGluR antagonist or by an NMDAR antagonist. In Study 3, it was shown that intrathecal administration of a selective group I mGluR agonist produced persistent mechanical allodynia, mechanical hyperalgesia and heat hyperalgesia in rats. In Study 4, it was shown that early, but not late intrathecal administration of a relatively selective group I mGluR antagonist reduced nociceptive behaviours, in a model of neuropathic pain. In Study 5, it was shown that intrathecal administration of a selective group I mGluR antagonist reduced mechanical allodynia and cold hyperalgesia, while a selective group II mGluR agonist and a selective group III mGluR agonist only reduced mechanical allodynia and cold hyperalgesia, respectively, in the neuropathic pain model. Results from these studies first suggest that spinal group I mGluRs may be more critically involved in the development of chronic nociceptive behaviours, compared to persis</description><creator>Fisher, Kim Nöel.</creator><contributor>Coderre, Terence (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chronic pain -- Animal models.</subject><subject>Nociceptors -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>The contribution of metabotropic glutamate receptors to models of persistent and chronic pain /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q7965.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z89q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g194b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation is devoted to an exploration of Baudelaire's correspondence from the sociopoetic perspective. Elements of form or style in the poet's letters, their unique pragmatics and social dimensions, are primary targets of inquiry. For Baudelaire, as for any epistolier, the writing of letters rests on the author's specific education, the traditions of his time, his philosophy, imagination and economic situation. As it is only through these different "filters" that Baudelaire's particular letter writing can be understood, the first part of this dissertation summarizes the main aspects of the socio-cultural history of epistolary practice in the nineteenth century. The second part focuses on the commerce of letters, what can be called the "economy" of Baudelaire's correspondence, wherein the letter is considered as an object of discourse. This section, which aims throughout to study how Baudelaire understood, considered and managed his own correspondence, also permits a close examination of the characteristic brevity of many of his letters. Without the self-indulgence of a diary, Baudelaire's correspondence is nevertheless related to this genre by the level of introspection it contains. Throughout his letters, for himself and the "Other", Baudelaire was preoccupied with defining his identity; increasingly this effort was concentrated on the creation of a persona, that of the Poet. The third and last part of this dissertation explores the staging and textualization of this ideal self.</description><creator>Fisher, Martine.</creator><contributor>Everett, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Baudelaire, Charles, 1821-1867. Correspondence.</subject><title>Du commerce épistolaire : Baudelaire et ses correspondants, 1832-1866</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66345533.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g194b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fj80w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The studies included in this thesis were aimed at identifying the mechanisms that lead to aberrant expression of the PTHRP gene in cancer. We have used the hepatocyte growth factor receptor oncogene, Tpr-Met, as a model and examined the effect of this oncogene on PTHRP expression. When transfected into Fisher rat 313 (Fr3T3) fibroblasts, Tpr-Met increased the transcription of PTHRP mRNA and secretion of the protein. To identify the signaling pathways involved we analyzed a mutant of Tpr-Met, Tyr489, that was impaired in activating a number of downstream effectors, including Phosphatidylinositol-3 kinase, Grb2 and Shc. The ability of Tpr-Met/Tyr 489 mutant to induce PTHRP expression was significantly reduced. Furthermore, inhibiting Ras using lovastatin, in wild-type Tpr-Met transfected cells, Completely Suppressed PTHRP levels, suggesting that the mechanism was Ras-dependent. We next directly investigated the effect of Ras on PTHRP expression in vitro, and on hypercalcemia of malignancy in vivo. When transfected PTHRP cells the activated mutant of Ras (RasV12) potently increased PTHRP mRNA and protein levels. When RasV12 expressing cells were subcutaneously injected into BALB/c/nu/ nu mice, the tumors developed rapidly, and signs of hypercalcemia were detected within 2 weeks. Inhibiting Ras using a specific inhibitor, B-1096, completely blocked expression of PTHRP, in vitro, and suppressed the sips of hypercalcemia in vivo. These results show that inhibiting Ras was sufficient to block tumor expression of PTHRP and development of hypercalcemia. Using rat Leydig tumor H-500 cells, we next investigated effector pathways downstream of Ras that mediate serum stimulated PTHRP expression. PTHRP mRNA was decreased by a dominant negative mutant of Raf (Raf C4B) and by a MEK inhibitor (PD 098059), implicating the involvement of Ras-Raf-MEK pathway in the serum response. In addition, stimulation with UV light or expression of an activated form of Rac (Rac V12) was sufficient to increase PTHRP mRNA. Furthermore, a dominant negative mutant Of Rac (Rac N17) also blocked serum induced expression of mRNA. This suggests that the stress-activated pathways may provide alternative mechanisms that can regulate the PTHRP gene. These pathways also appear to be important in the serum induced response. Collectively, the results from these studies contribute to our limited knowledge of the mechanisms governing PTHRP expression in cancer. The findings also provide novel targets to explore for improved therapy of hypercalcemia.</description><creator>Aklilu, Fasika.</creator><contributor>Rabbani, S. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>The regulation of parathyroid hormone-related protein (PTHRP) gene expression in hypercalcemia of malignancy /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t52h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj80w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t71n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the more frequently utilized and popular informal sector financial institutions is the Rotating Savings and Credit Association (ROSCA). Despite the popularity of the institution, it has not been subjected to rigorous analysis within the field of economics. ROSCAs allow members to pool savings, and get access to credit without collateral. ROSCAs encourage members to save, and they also increase interaction between members. The main issues that ROSCAs raise are: how is credit allocated, what are the welfare implications of the various allocation schemes, and how does the ROSCA address moral hazard and adverse selection issues? And finally, how does the ROSCA encourage savings even amongst low income groups? These questions are addressed in detail in the thesis. ROSCA members are strictly better off compared to saving under autarky, and under some reasonable assumptions, even better off compared to saving through a bank. Random allocation of the pot is Pareto optimal when members are homogeneous, but the result does not hold for heterogeneous members. Bidding ROSCAs are quite complicated since a 'jointly owned' asset is auctioned, and the auction is repeated over many periods. This auction requires explicit modeling of the auction environment, and the information structure of the individual members. We study different auctions, bidding strategies and information environments, and provide equilibria under specific conditions. The standard auction results are shown not to hold under certain conditions. ROSCAs face moral hazard and adverse selection issues like any other financial institution. But, given that the institution is embedded in a community and social context, ROSCA members deal with the problem utilizing community networks, and the threat of ostracization. We study the selection and monitoring process, and then characterize an equilibrium under which a ROSCA can deter default successfully, and sustain itself over time. Empirical literature on ROSCAs also points out that members view ROSCAs as 'commitment mechanisms' that facilitate saving. This observation sits uneasily with the neoclassical assumption of a utility maximizing agent. We study various possible explanations of the phenomena, and show how a ROSCA can act as such a mechanism.</description><creator>Bari, Faisal.</creator><contributor>Cairns, R. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Whitmore, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Rotating credit associations.</subject><title>Essays on modeling innovative and flexible credit arrangements : the case of Rotating Savings and Credit Associations (ROSCAs)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763875w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t71n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t085s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis focuses on the effects of development assistance (ODA), private foreign commercial capital (PFX), domestic savings (SAV), the openness of the economy and producer prices on agricultural output, and on export and domestic shares of agricultural output in sub-Saharan Africa (SSA). This study uses panel data spanning 27 countries and the period 1970 to 1993. The production function is a Cobb-Douglas type. Static export and domestic share equations are derived from a specification of the agricultural gross domestic product function. Transformed auto-regressive distributed-lag versions of the static share models are used to investigate long-run dynamics, persistence and implementation lags in the share response model. Agricultural output is affected as follows. ODA, PFX and SAV have small positive or negative impact depending on agricultural region or economic policy environment. The impact of openness of the economy is negative in all agricultural regions, however, there is evidence of positive effect of openness within improved policy environment. None of these effects are statistically significant. Export share is affected as follows. ODA, PFX and SAV have small positive impact in some agricultural regions and policy environments, both in the short-run and in the long-run. PFX is not significant anywhere. ODA is significant only when countries are grouped by policy environment in the short-run. SAV is significant in the short-run only in some regions, and significant in the long-run only in others. Openness has positive impact in the short-run. This is significant in many regions. Its long-run impact is mostly positive but not significant anywhere. The impact of producer price is mostly positive but not significant. Efforts to encourage economic activities in rural communities such as improvements in domestic terms of trade in favor of agriculture, together with the provision of infrastructure are likely to stimulate output. Strategies to diversify and process agricultural exports in the face of falling agricultural commodity prices should be pursued.</description><creator>Aboagye, Anthony Q. Q.</creator><contributor>Whitmore, Alex (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gunjal, Kisan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Econometric models.</subject><subject>Agricultural assistance -- Africa, Sub-Saharan -- Econometric models.</subject><title>Financial flows, macroeconomic policy and the agricultural sector in Sub-Saharan Africa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z094.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t085s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s4152</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three experiments investigated the hypothesis that high doses of methylphenidate (MPH) are particularly effective in enabling boys with Attention-Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) to regulate the allocafion of effort and persistence under high information processing demands. In Experiment 1, the performance of boys with ADHD, ages 7 to 13, was investigated on placebo and three dosages of MPH, on a visual-memory search (VMS) task across a wide range of processing loads. Accuracy increased with dosage in a linear fashion. Findings on reaction times (RTs) revealed, however, that MPH dosage had a differential effect depending on processing load. All doses of MPH improved accuracy on low loads without a concomitant increase in processing times. When both processing load and (MPH) dosage were high, however, the ADHD boys shifted to a more cautious, time comsuming strategy, apparently in order to achieve continuing gains in accuracy. Experiment 2 compared the performance of ADHD and control boys on the VMS. It established that the ADHD group had difficulty meeting the processing demands of the VMS across all of the information loads studied, as revealed by higher error rates and slower RTs. The ADHD-control comparison also established that the effects of high doses of MPH at high loads in Experiment 1 constituted a further slowing of the ADHD boys' already slow RTs. A third, normal developmental study of boys ages 7 to 13 showed that both error rates and RTs on the VMS task decreased with age. This study also revealed considerable similarity between the performance patterns of ADHD boys and those of younger control boys on the VMS.</description><creator>Berman, Tamara.</creator><contributor>Douglas, Virginia I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>Effects of methylphenidate on complex cognitive : processing in attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c62j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s4152</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655j333</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Urokinase (uPA), a member of the serine protease family, and its cell surface receptor (uPAR) have been implicated in promoting the progression of various human malignancies including hormone dependent malignancies such as breast and prostate cancer. However, the underlying molecular mechanisms regulating uPA production in breast and prostate cancer progression are poorly understood. In the current studies, we have examined the role of uPAR in breast cancer progression by developing a homologous model of uPAR overexpression by a rat breast cancer cell line Mat B III. Overexpression of uPAR resulted in increased breast cancer growth, invasion and metastasis in vitro and in vivo. Development of this syngeneic breast cancer model allowed me to examine the ability of the anti-estrogen, tamoxifen (TAM) and a synthetic active site inhibitor of uPA, 4-iodo benzo[b]thiophene-2-carboxamidine (B-428), to prevent breast cancer progression. TAM and B-428 treatment alone or in combination effectively prevented breast tumor growth, invasion and metastasis in vitro and in vivo. Morever, TAM and B-428 treatments caused a decrease in uPAR gene expression and protein production. These results underscore the utility of anti-proteolytic agents (B-428) in addition to standard hormone therapy (TAM) in advanced breast cancer patients where the uPA/uPAR system plays a key role in tumor progression. Regulation of uPA production by androgens in prostate cancer was then examined in the androgen insensitive PC-3 cells transfected with the functional human androgen receptor cDNA (PC-3T). Androgens down regulate uPA gene expression and protein production in androgen sensitive PC-3T cells. Furthermore, restoration of androgen responsiveness in PC-3T cells caused a dramatic decrease in tumor growth, invasion and metastasis in vitro and in vivo. Due to the ability of sex steroids to inhibit uPA gene expression, I have also examined the correlation between hormone sensitivity and uPA expression in several hormone responsive (HR) and hormone insensitive (HI) breast and prostate cancer cell lines. uPA mRNA was expressed only in the highly invasive, HI breast (MDA-231) and prostate (PC-3) cell lines. Failure of uPA mRNA expression in the minimally invasive, HR breast (MCF-7) and prostate (LnCAP) cells was due to transcriptional suppression of uPA gene. Southern blot analysis using methylation sensitive
enzymes revealed that CpG islands of uPA gene are hypermethylated in HR, MCf-7 and
Ln-CAP cells whereas they are hypomethylated in HI. MDA-231 and PC-3 cells.
Treatment of MCf-7 cells with cytosine DNA methyltransferase inhibitor 5' azacytidine
caused a dose-dependent induction of uPA mRNA due to demethylation of the epG
islands of uPA gene which led to increased invasive ability ofthese HR cancer cells. These
results demonstrate that DNA methylation can regulate the transcription of uPA gene to
alter the invasive behaviour ofthese HR breast and prostate cancer cells.</description><creator>Xing, Rosie Hongmei, 1968-</creator><contributor>Rabbani, S. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Studies on the role of urokinase (uPA) and its cell surface receptor (uPAR) in the invasion and metastasis of hormone dependent malignancies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634555n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j333</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182m92n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis I investigate the relationship between 'I' as principle of transcendental philosophy and its ordinary use as first-personal pronoun. This relationship is a central issue in the philosophy of J. G. Fichte. Fichte was concerned to secure the gains made by Kant's Critique against what he called the 'dogmatism of the so-called Kantians' as well as against the attack of the skeptics, by grounding philosophy in a first principle which he called 'I'. To say what Fichte means by 'I' is to give an account of his philosophy, for, according to him, nothing is to be assumed outside of this 'I'. For Fichte the dogmatism of the 'so-called Kantians' consists in the idea that even when the formal conditions of experience have been established, a non-conceptualized content needs to be given to the mind from outside in order to produce empirical knowledge. This way of conceiving empirical constraints of thought, according to Fichte, threatens the results of Kant's critical philosophy, because it is inconsistent with the theoretical spontaneity and the practical autonomy that are crucial to Kant's conception of reason. Fichte argues that adequate empirical constraints can only be deduced from within the 'I'. To do this we must radically rethink our received concept of an 'I', a rethinking which in essence has already been effectuated by Kant, and which Fichte merely wants to make explicit and bring to fruition. Adequate constraints can be seen to be generated internally, once we realize that the standpoint of the 'theoretical I' is derivative from the standpoint of the 'practical I'. A result of Fichte's emphasis on the practical aspect of reason is a heightened awareness of the concept of the individual person and its status vis-a-vis the 'I' as philosophical principle. To be consistent with his principle, and indeed to prove his point, Fichte must 'deduce' the 'I' as individual. Fichte's repudiation of dogmatism bears striking resemblances to a contemporary reading of Kant associated with the works of P. F. Strawson and John McDowell. The crucial difference is that for these philosophers the concept of a person is taken as primitive, and hence as the starting point of philosophy. At Fichte's time this position was defended by Fichte's critic, F. H. Jacobi. In the thesis I develop a position in contrast with Fichte's idealism which I call a 'naturalism of second nature' and which I use as a conceptual foil to explicate Fichte's thinking. I argue that ultimately Fichte's project fails by his own standards, in that it fails to save what we normally mean by a moral individual. I argue that in order to conceive of adequate constraints on freedom, we need to make the concept of a person as a natural individual our point of departure.</description><creator>Wilhelm, Hans-Jakob.</creator><contributor>di Giovanni, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Self (Philosophy) -- History.</subject><subject>Liberty -- Philosophy -- History.</subject><subject>Fichte, Johann Gottlieb, 1762-1814 -- Contributions in philosophy of the self.</subject><subject>Philosophy of nature -- History.</subject><title>The 'I' and the individual : the problem of nature in Fichte's philosophy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw171.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182m92n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj87r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coping behaviour, perceived control, and the self concept of elementary school children with learning disabilities educated in regular and special education classrooms was examined using a comparative design. In addition, the influence of teachers' classroom management orientation on children's self-perceptions and coping behaviour was investigated. Children attending a special school for students with learning disabilities were found to be more adaptive copers than children in special education classes in regular schools, children receiving resource room assistance, and children mainstreamed in regular classes. Children with learning disabilities were found to have positive perceptions of their global self-worth regardless of the type of class they were in, although they indicated less confidence in their academic abilities compared to their self-perceptions of physical appearance and athletic competence. In general, most children believed that they were responsible for their academic successes and at the same time perceived academic failure as unavoidable. The students who coped most effectively demonstrated the most realistic appraisals of their academic situation. They recognized that they could not control academic failure, however, they believed that the best way to succeed in school was by continuing to exert effort. Additionally, successful copers held high expectations for future academic success and believed that they possessed the capacities needed to achieve this success. Children who coped most effectively strongly endorsed beliefs in their capacity to have a positive relationship with their teachers. Children who were rated as effective copers had teachers whose instructional orientation promoted autonomous functioning in their students.</description><creator>Weintraub, Gerald A.</creator><contributor>Derevensky, Jeffrey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Adjustment (Psychology) in children.</subject><subject>Learning disabled children -- Education.</subject><title>Perception of control and coping mechanisms of children with learning disabilities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq47t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj87r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j060h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The contagious sound of Congo-Zaire's distinctive popular dance music has made it a kind of 'musica franca' of sub-Saharan Africa. Despite the music's influence outside of its country of origin, virtually no research has been done to explore the history, production and meaning of the musical style. In addition to being a privileged feature of Congo-Kinshasa's cultural landscape, this 'musique moderne' also constitutes a valuable source of information of the way that 'modernity' is ordered and understood in an African context. 'Modernity', I want to argue, is driven by 'tradition', and 'audition' pulls 'modernity' back into its sphere of utility, resulting in a never-ending, forever-changing, cultural and political spiral. 'Modernism', on the other hand, as a stance or 'way of being' in the world, is used as a means of gaining mastery over the paradoxes and pleasures of 'modernity's' condition. Findings are based on fourteen months of intensive fieldwork (1995--1996) in Brazzaville (Peoples' Republic of Congo) and Kinshasa (Democratic Republic of Congo). I conducted research on three basic units of study relative to Congolese popular dance music: the music industry, the musical style and the audience. By comparing information from these three domains of knowledge, I have attempted to show not only how music in Kinshasa is performed, but how it is produced and understood. The 'modern' idiom through which music expresses itself is interesting in itself, but it also highlights the importance of culture and history to the study of popular culture and politics.</description><creator>White, Bob Whitman.</creator><contributor>Galaty, John G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Popular music -- Zaire -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Music trade -- Zaire.</subject><title>Modernity's spiral : popular culture, mastery, and the politics of dance music in Congo-Kinshasa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f00s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j060h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418p939</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For many years, the fact that the primary transcript of human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) is inefficiently spliced was largely taken for granted and the underlying mechanism remained unexplored. We set out to define the cis-acting elements involved in splicing regulation of the HIV-1 tat/rev intron. This task was facilitated by the use of a plasmid designed for transient expression in COS-7 cells of a synthetic gene that contained the first intron of human beta-globin. By exchanging either the 5' splice site (5' ss) or the 3' splice site (3' ss) of beta-globin with various portions of the HIV-1 genome spanning the tat/ rev splice sites, we could draw several conclusions. By trimming away flanking sequences, we demonstrated that the tat/rev 3' ss is intrinsically inefficient. Mutagenesis studies revealed that both the branchpoint and polypyrimidine tract elements were suboptimal. The tat/rev 5' ss, on the other hand, was shown to be utilized efficiently. The efficiency of the tat/rev 5' ss was not affected by inclusion of the tat/ rev intron sequences. Therefore, we concluded that the only requirement for inefficient splicing of the tat/rev intron is the suboptimal nature of the branchpoint and polypyrimidine tract elements. Deletion studies revealed that two cis-acting elements within the downstream exon modulate splicing of the tat/ rev intron. These elements include a positive element, the exon splicing enhancer (ESE), and an adjacent negative element, the exon splicing silencer (ESS). The ESE was mapped to a 10 nt purine-rich element that is functionally interchangeable with other purine-rich ESEs. The ESS exhibited context dependence in that its extent of splicing inhibition was sensitive to mutations that improve the branchpoint or polypyrimidine tract. During the course of our investigation of the HIV-1 ESS in a heterologous context, we made the unexpected discovery of novel splicing regulatory elements within the EDA exon of the human fibronectin gene. As in HIV-1, these elements include adjacent positive and negative elements. Although the fibronectin ESE is not purine-rich, we demonstrated that it is functionally analogous to the ESE of HIV-1. The fibronectin ESS is relatively large. Evolutionary alignment and mutagenesis studies implicate secondary structures as determinants of splicing inhibition. Finally, using chimeric beta-globin/HIV-1 introns as above, we tested a model for nuclear retention of unspliced pre-mRNA which proposes that the RNA becomes trapped in "handicapped" splicing complexes as a consequence of the pairing of a strong splice site with a weak one. We present evidence that the inefficient tat/rev 3' ss is insufficient to cause nuclear retention; additional tat/rev intron sequences are required to prevent the cytoplasmic accumulation of unspliced RNA.</description><creator>Staffa, Alfredo.</creator><contributor>Acheson, Nicholas H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Post-transcriptional regulation in HIV-1 and human fibronectin : multiple CIS-acting elements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999838z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418p939</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj84p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My study is an investigation of the discourse of madness in Timothy Findley's fiction, where madness is defined as a discursive element that is both structural and thematic. The work encompasses Findley's short stories, novels, a work of non-fiction, and personal archival material. I argue that what has been called a diverse body of work (Hunter) is, in fact, solidly cohesive in its use of the discourse of madness that systematically subverts patterns of authority. My purpose is to reveal a discursive structure that both supports and subverts narrative coherence, locating its degree of disruption within a psychodynamic exchange. My theoretical model situates the reader as the recipient of and participant in the initiating text's psychodynamic discourse, and so implicates the reader in the subversion of authority. The study amalgamates psychocriticism and reader response theory to demonstrate that Findley's writing actively engages the reader in a visceral exchange that I liken to that encountered within the psychoanalytic interview (Bollas). With the addition of the psychoanalytic component, my research moves substantially beyond the position taken by Wolfgang Iser on reader response and by Norman Holland, both of whom acknowledge the value of psychocriticism but maintain a dualistic (reader/text) model. While Iser and Holland assign the status of co-production of the text to the activity of reading, both neglect to address specific production value to the activity of writing which, in effect, leaves the reader as lone producer. By introducing the "idiom" of the author my theoretical model becomes triadic so that my reading can move beyond the simple oscillation between text and reader to engage the author in a way that amplifies important questions of status raised by the psychodynamic model, such as: "Who is reading whom?" "Who is the analyst and who the analysand? Who is maintaining or manipulating authority?" These, in turn, raise further questions regarding subject/object relations and the ways in which transference-countertransference between selves and others, subjects and objects, conscious and unconscious states take place. In addressing these questions in terms of the triadic process of reading, which re-instates the initiating author, the value and originality of this study becomes apparent in its investigation of biographical material to literary production.</description><creator>Steinson, Elizabeth Hay.</creator><contributor>Cooke, Nathalie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Findley, Timothy -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Mental illness in literature.</subject><title>The discourse of madness as structure and theme in the work of Timothy Findley /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b2794.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj84p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666628v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The conclusion of the Cold War has had contradictory effects on on-going conflicts in the former superpower client states of Ethiopia, Somalia and Angola. The argument proposed in this dissertation seeks to explain these variations in conflict. Two conditions, distribution of power and governing agreement, are considered to be fundamental to this explanation. In many cases, disputants have had access to arms in the past and their ability to pursue violent means to their objectives in the future is contingent on their continued access to weapons or other resources. These patterns are reflected in the distribution of power. The second condition, governing agreement, reflects the fact that in the immediate post-Cold War era, disputants have frequently sought to resolve their differences through negotiations. What is relevant here is whether any subsequent political pact exists between disputants and whether it involves power-sharing or a winner-take-all process. These two conditions, military viability and governing agreement, are combined in a matrix to suggest how their interaction leads to divergent outcomes. Depending on the mix of conditions, the outcomes range from "stable peace" to "tense peace or low-level conflict" to "civil war." The argument is applied to the three cases from 1985 to 1995. The author concludes that winner-take-all elections, though often the preference of African leaders, can be a recipe for disaster in tightly contested states with a history of violent conflict. On the other hand, while power-sharing agreements are difficult to arrive at (and even more difficult to implement), agreements leading to governments which are inclusive of the main disputants are an important step in the mitigation of conflict. By building security and creating the sense that both parties have a stake in the continued functioning of a political system, armed movements may be more willing to relinquish their weapons and embrace peace.</description><creator>Spears, Ian S.</creator><contributor>Brynen, Rex (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Political stability -- Ethiopia.</subject><subject>Cold War -- Influence.</subject><subject>Political stability -- Angola.</subject><subject>Political violence -- Angola.</subject><subject>Political violence -- Somalia.</subject><subject>Political stability -- Somalia.</subject><subject>Political violence -- Ethiopia.</subject><title>Evolutions in African conflict : the impact and aftermath of the Cold War, 1985-1995</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c56f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666628v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m835w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The investigations contained within this thesis were performed to gain a more comprehensive understanding of pursed-lips breathing (PLB). The first study compared the load compensatory responses of expiratory resistive loading (ERL) and volitional pursed-lips breathing (PLB) in healthy individuals. Although ERL and PLB promoted similar respiratory muscle recruitment responses, ERL did not fully simulate the breathing pattern and end-expiratory lung volume (EELV) changes induced by PLB. PLB promoted a slower and deeper breathing pattern during both rest and exercise. It had no effect on resting inspiratory muscle recruitment patterns, but modestly increased the contribution of the rib cage/accessory muscles and abdominal muscle relaxation during exercise. Greater expiratory muscle recruitment was promoted by PLB during rest and exercise. In the second study, volitional PLB produced a slower and deeper breathing pattern in patients with COPD at rest and during exercise. Inspiratory muscle recruitment patterns were not altered by PLB in either condition. Expiratory muscle recruitment was increased at rest. Because such muscles were markedly recruited during exercise alone, PLB produced no further effect. PLB had an inconsistent effect on dyspnea across patients. This effect was related to the changes it concurrently promoted to EELV and tidal volume and the impact of such on ventilatory muscle force generating capacity and performance. The third study endeavoured to determine the prevalence of spontaneous PLB in 57 patients with COPD during conditions of rest, exercise and recovery. Patients who spontaneously performed PLB at rest, invariably continued during exercise and recovery, whereas patients who commenced PLB during exercise continued during recovery. In our patients, 11% used PLB at rest, 42% during exercise, 54% during recovery, 35% did not perform PLB at any time, and 11% performed such other maneuvers as grunting or hissing. Factors distinguishing patient</description><creator>Spahija, Jadranka.</creator><contributor>Grassino, Alejandro (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Pursed-lips breathing in health and disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq03j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m835w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r484v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The retention of process colloids in the paper web is essential for papermaking process efficiency and product quality. Fines (fibre fragments) and fillers strongly affect the optical, surface and mechanical properties of paper. A very efficient flocculation aid system to deposit fine material (colloids) on fibres (collectors) consists of a polymer used in conjunction with anionic microparticles. The objective of this thesis is to elucidate the mechanism of fines retention with poly(electrolyte)-montmorillonite flocculant systems. Two main subjects are addressed. Firstly, polymer transfer between colloidal particles and collectors was characterised and modelled, and the influence on the papermaking process was evaluated. Secondly, the role of anionic microparticles in a dual flocculation aid was investigated. The influence on the flocculation kinetics and the adsorption behaviour of dissolved and colloidal compounds were studied. The hetero-flocculation of wood fibres and fines induced by polymer and microparticles was analysed in a stirred tank reactor. The deposition of fines on fibres in the presence of polymer is transient. This is attributed to polymer transfer between surfaces upon particle detachment, which leads to the formation of an electro-steric barrier. The resulting polymer layers have limited bridging abilities. A mathematical model describing the simultaneous particle deposition and polymer transfer was developed and validated. The kinetics is determined by three rate constants: a deposition rate constant (k1), a detachment rate constant (k2) and a polymer transfer coefficient (beta). The influence of shear, salt concentration and polymer chemistry on the kinetics was quantified. Microparticles act as bridging agents between adsorbed polymer layers. They provide a stronger bond than single polymer layers. Bond strengthening occurs irrespective of the bridging ability of the adsorbed layers towards cellulosic surfaces. The mechanism is explained in terms of charge densities and polymer layer conformations. The de-layering of montmorillonite is crucial for its efficiency. Finally, the efficiency of montmorillonites as white water scavengers was quantified using model wood colloids and polymers. Dissolved and colloidal substances adsorb on montmorillonites following a low-affinity Langmuir isotherm. Dissolved polymers form molecular monolayers, while colloids adsorb as particles. Montmorillonite was found an efficient scavenger for colloidal material. Montmorillonite used in conjunction with a poly(electrolyte) has three effects in improving fines retention. It augments the bond strength as a bridging agent between adsorbed polymer layers, it allows the retention of colloids coated with inactive polymer layers and finally it scavenges the dissolved and colloidal substances, which would otherwise decrease the poly(electrolyte) efficiency.</description><creator>Asselman, Tom.</creator><contributor>Garhier, Gil (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Hetero-flocculation of wood fibres and fines induced by polymers and microparticles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj85z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r484v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj45r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nerve growth factor family of neurotrophins play multiple roles in both the developing and mature mammalian nervous systems. During development, neurotrophins are typically thought to act as retrogradely-derived signals that mediate the survival of innervating neurons. However, recent studies have highlighted different mechanisms of delivery and multiple functions for certain neurotrophins, extending their scope of biological activity beyond that suggested by the neurotrophic hypothesis. This thesis highlights two novel roles for the neurotrophin, brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF), in the mammalian nervous system, and the mechanisms by which these events are mediated. First, we show that BDNF is anterogradely transported in central noradrenergic neurons to regulate the development of target neuron populations such as the neocortex, and to mediate the survival of injured motor neurons. This provides the first evidence of a functional role for anterogradely-derived BDNF during the survival and development of target neuron populations. Two transgenic mouse constructs were used to determine the role of anterogradely-derived BDNF; the previously characterized dopamine beta-hydroxylase (DBH):BDNF transgenic mice, and Talpha1:nlacZ transgenic mice which have been extensively characterized within the scope of this thesis. Second, we show that BDNF mediates apoptosis via the p75NTR in neurons lacking TrkB. Indeed, BDNF-mediated p75NTR activation results in increased sympathetic neuron death in vitro, and ablation of BDNF and p75 in vivo, (BDNF-/- or p75-/- mice), results in an increased number of SCG neurons following the period of naturally occurring cell death. Together, these data indicate that p75NTR can mediate apoptosis, and that this mechanism is essential for naturally-occurring cell death. We also show that the tumor suppressor protein, p53, is essential during naturally-occurring sympathetic neuron death, and that p53 protein levels are increased following both BDNF-mediated activation of p75, and NGF withdrawal. Moreover, we postulate that both the p75-mediated and NGF withdrawal-induced upregulation of p53 is mediated by the MEKK-JNK pathway. The p53 tumor suppressor protein has been shown to play an apoptotic role in several cell types, including in neurons exposed to external stressors, such as excitotoxicity and DNA damage. This is the first time p53 has been demonstrated to play an apoptotic role during the development of the mammalian nervous system.</description><creator>Bamji, Shernaz Xerxes.</creator><contributor>Miller, Freda D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The role of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) in development and survival in the mammalian nervous system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks17s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj45r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r38z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments were conducted in 1997, 1998 and 1999 to determine the effects of mulch/mini-tunnel and thermal-water tube combinations on daily carbon dioxide (CO2) concentration, air, soil temperatures and early growth of muskmelons (var. Earligold) during the vegetative phase. Treatments consisted of mulched plot covered with a clear perforated, a clear non-perforated or a non-perforated infrared polyethylene mini-tunnel with the absence or the presence of a thermal-water tube compared with control treatments. Additional treatments consisting of the ventilation non-perforated clear and infrared tunnels containing no tube were used in 1998 and 1999. The non-perforated tunnels significantly increased CO2 concentrations, air and soil temperatures compared with those of perforated tunnels and controls. Inclusion of a thermal-water tube reduced air temperature fluctuations in the tunnels. Ventilating the non-perforated tunnels significantly decreased CO2 concentrations and air temperatures. During the first 10--15 days after transplanting, muskmelons grown in the non-perforated tunnels had higher relative growth rate (RGR), net assimilation rate (NAR), and dry weight than those of grown under perforated tunnels and in the control plots. However, during the later period, 11--16 days after transplanting to anthesis, the effects of mulch/mini-tunnels on the RGR, NAR and dry weight of muskmelons were inconsistent. Muskmelons grown in the mulch/tunnels had significantly higher RGR, but generally lower NAR, than those of grown without tunnel. The use of mulch/mini-tunnels significantly increased dry weight at anthesis in 1997, but not in 1998 and 1999. The presence of thermal-water tube in the tunnels and ventilating the non-perforated tunnels generally increased RGR, NAR, and dry weight of muskmelons. The use of mulch/mini-tunnels reduced time for muskmelon to reach anthesis by 9 to 11 days. The leaves of muskmelons grown in mulch/mini-tunnels had significantly lower ratios of variable to maximum fluorescence (Fv/Fm) than control plants throughout the experiments, except at 10 and 20 days after transplanting in 1997. Leaves of muskmelons grown in non-perforated tunnels had significantly higher levels of chlorophyll than all other treatments during first 15 days after transplanting. However, chlorophyll values in these treatments decreased as muskmelons reached anthesis. The presence of a thermal-water tube in the mulch/mini-tunnels and ventilating the non-perforated tunnels generally increased both Fv/Fm ratios and chlorophyll levels of muskmelon leaves.</description><creator>Aziz, Fahrurrozi.</creator><contributor>Stewart, K. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Plastics in agriculture -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Mulching -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Muskmelon -- Québec (Province) -- Growth.</subject><title>Effects of mulchmini-tunnel and thermal-water tube combinations on daily carbon dioxide concentration and early growth of muskmelons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z710n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r38z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wm004</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The application of haptic devices to surgery simulation presents many exciting opportunities. For example, medical students could practise surgery without using animals and surgeons could evaluate and plan surgical procedures before making a single real incision. An integral component of these surgical simulator systems is haptic feedback. There are many engineering challenges that must be addressed in order to successfully integrate haptics with the environmental characteristics found in surgery. The most fundamental of these challenges is to achieve update rates of solid nonlinear deformable objects that are acceptable to the human haptic system. This thesis presents a software architecture that is designed to meet these challenges by analysing the task, the haptic, and the hardware constraints of surgery simulation. A new hierarchical finite element mesh structure is introduced that uses an equivalent impedance method to specify parent-child relationships, an idea inspired by Thevenin equivalents in circuits. The mesh hierarchy achieves several important objectives, including mixed-mode simulations, multi-frequency operation, and explicit accuracy-time tradeoffs. After an analysis of the problem constraints, the theoretical framework of the hierarchical mesh structure is presented. Implementation issues and results are presented for three cases: a linear, dynamic, and linear-nonlinear system. These results show that the hierarchical mesh structure can provide low force latency even for nonlinear systems.</description><creator>Astley, Oliver Richard.</creator><contributor>Hayward, Vincent (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A software architecture for surgical simulation using haptics /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js906.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm004</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw250</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Empirical Orthogonal Function (EOF) analysis technique has proven to be one of the most powerful methods to analyze data in meteorology and many other fields. However, this method is statistical only and has no physical basis. Brunet (1994) has introduced Held's (1985) concept of conservation of wave activity and orthogonal functions into the EOF analysis and called it the "Empirical Normal Mode" (ENM) analysis technique. This new method uses both statistical concepts from the classical EOF analysis method and a dynamical constraint from the generalized Eliassen-Palm theorem to ensure that the functions that we obtained are orthogonal to each other and are the solutions of linearized dynamical equations. In this thesis, we use the ENM analysis to analyze data from both a (2D) shallow water model integration and from 3-D atmospheric observations, with an emphasis on stratospheric sudden warming events. For the shallow water model case, the results of the ENM analysis are evaluated by testing against the theoretical (numerical) normal mode solutions provided by Longuet-Higgins (1968). It is shown that the ENM analysis can recover the spatial structures and the frequencies of the normal modes with a great degree of accuracy if the temporal record is sufficiently long. The average errors in the periods for 2000 and 100 day time series are found to be 1% and 4.6%, respectively. From the eigenvalues (percentage of the total variance) and sharp frequency peaks associated with normal modes, the ENM analysis shows that the model generates only a few modes with monochromatic frequencies. The method can be used to test a new or modified shallow water model integration or to study other Hough modes generated by different kinds of forcings. Having shown the value of the ENM technique in a barotropic context, we advance further by performing an ENM analysis on an 11 year atmospheric data set. In this study, we focus on stratospheric warming events. The winter (DJF) data set is partitioned into warming and non-warming periods in order to characterize the flow differences between the regimes. The stratospheric quasi-potential vorticity or wave activity structure in the warming period is found to be much stronger, as expected, than in the non-warming periods. The ENM analysis clearly shows the tropospheric difference between the two periods, e.g., a higher wave activity in the main tropospheric structure as well as in the tropospheric polar regions in the warming periods. The analysis also reveals that there is a higher level of stratospheric wave activity during the warming periods in the second normal mode of zonal wave number 1 but the tropospheric structures of the quasi-potential vorticity are the same as during non-warming periods. This suggests that there is/are (a) mechanism(s) associated with the stratospheric warming other than the upward wave propagation. All the common features of the stratospheric warming event are captured by the first two normal modes of zonal wave numbers 1 and 2, such as wave-mean flow interaction leading to the deceleration of the zonal mean wind, the polar vortex being displaced by the northward movement of the Aleutian High, as well as wave amplitude enhancement/reduction during the growing/decaying stages.</description><creator>Tran, Dinh Hai, 1966-</creator><contributor>Brunet, Gilbert (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Derome, Jacques (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Atmospheric model and data analysis in terms of empirical normal modes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d1679.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw250</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm64z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The normal isoform of the prion protein (PrPC) is a small cell-surface glycoprotein that is expressed predominantly in the brain as well as a wide variety of peripheral tissues. Although the involvement of an abnormal, protease-resistant isoform of the protein (PrPSc) in certain neurodegenerative diseases is clear, its normal function remains unknown. We investigated several aspects of prion protein biology to improve our understanding of the role it may play in both health and disease. We characterized the expression pattern of PrPC during human leukocyte maturation. We observed that prion protein is present on bone marrow stem cells and that it is downregulated upon differentiation along the granulocyte lineage in vivo. This observation was replicated using an in vitro system of granulocyte differentiation. These data suggest that bone marrow stem cells may support prion agent replication in disease, since this process is dependent on availability of PrP C. Additionally, our studies provide a novel in vitro system to study prion gene regulation. We developed soluble, tagged versions of the prion protein to determine the existence of a cognate cell-surface receptor. A prion-human placental alkaline phosphatase fusion protein was found to bind specifically to the surface of many cell lines, implicating the existence of such a receptor. We further investigated the nature of this interaction and determined that it was not only specific, but saturable and high-affinity, as expected for a ligand-receptor interaction. We determined that the N-terminal region of the prion protein is essential for binding to the receptor and mapped the precise location of the binding site using peptide inhibition studies. It was found that the N-terminal region will interact with the receptor only when bound by copper ions, suggesting that PrPC and its receptor may play a role in copper regulation. We developed a novel expression cloning methodology using Xenopus oocytes to identify the receptor for PrP. Protocadherin 2 was isolated as a positive clone and is therefore proposed as a prion receptor candidate.</description><creator>Dodelet, Vincent C.</creator><contributor>Cashman, Neil R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Distribution and function of the normal cellular isoform of the prion protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c240.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm64z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sb99h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Steffen, Thomas, 1958-</creator><contributor>Aebi, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Three-dimensional spine biomechanics : a combined in-vivo and ex-vivo approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784n41j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sb99h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Orthopaedic Research Laboratory</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj10r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Michaud, Denis, 1970-</creator><contributor>Burgess, C. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Neutrinos and fluctuating matter : going beyond MSW</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r9486.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj10r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429b96r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of integrability of scalar partial differential equations in two independent variables is investigated from a geometric viewpoint. The structure of "equations describing pseudo-spherical surfaces" introduced by S. S. Chern and Keti Tenenblat is taken as the starting point, and the fact that every equation which describes pseudo-spherical surfaces is the integrability condition of a sl(2, R)--linear problem is exploited throughout. A classification of evolution equations of the form ut = F(x, t, u, ..., uxm) which describe one-parameter families of pseudo-spherical surfaces ("kinematic integrability") is performed, under a natural a priori assumption on the form of the associated family of linear problems. The relationship between the class of equations which results, and the class of equations which are formally integrable in the sense of Mikhailov, Shabat and Sokolov, is studied. It is shown that every second order formally integrable evolution equation is kinematically integrable, and it is also shown that this result cannot be extended as proven to third order formally integrable evolution equations. A special case is proven, however, and moreover, the Harry-Dym, cylindrical KdV, and a family of equations solved by inverse scattering by Calogero and Degasperis, are shown to be kinematically integrable. The theory of coverings due to Krasil'shchik and Vinogradov is introduced, and (local, nonlocal) conservation laws and (generalized, nonlocal) symmetries of kinematically integrable equations are investigated within this framework: theorems on the existence of generalized and/or nonlocal symmetries are proven, and several sequences of local and/or nonlocal conservation laws are constructed. The relationship between the Cavalcante, Chern, and Tenenblat approach (conservation laws from pseudo-spherical structure) and the more familiar "Riccati equation" approach (conservation laws from the associated linear problem) is analysed. An appendix on nonlocal Hamiltonians for evolution equations is also included. The relationship between Chern and Tenenblat "intrinsic" point of view, and the "extrinsic" approach due to Sym is studied, and more conservation laws for equations describing pseudo-spherical surfaces are found. It is also shown that within the "extrinsic" framework, a new class of equations, interpretable as two-parameter deformations of the equations in the Chern-Tenenblat class, can be introduced. It is pointed out that these deformations are themselves the integrability condition of sl(2, R)--linear problems, and conservation laws for them are briefly considered.</description><creator>Reyes, Enrique G.</creator><contributor>Kamran, Niky (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>On the integrability of scalar partial differential equations in two independent variables : some geometric aspects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t0862.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429b96r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr37f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:49:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this research program were to provide evidence of the distinction between global and specific relational models and to assess their relative contributions in the experience of significant life events and daily social interactions. Relationship-specific models were operationalized in two ways: in terms of significant role relationships and in terms of salience (i.e., frequency of interactions). The association between global relational models and specific models, selected on the basis of the other's role (Study 1) or salience (Study 2), was examined. Results indicate that these constructs were correlated, but not redundant. Moderate stabitily of global and specific models was found over 4 months. Analyses examining the extent to which change in this network of models operated through top-down or bottom-up processes suggested that change occurred mainly as a bottom-up process. Models of self and other for established relationships were generalized to the global models, but the global models did not contribute much to shaping changes in specific models. Adjustment to two different life events was examined to distinguish between the contributions of global and distinct relationship-specific models in the experience of events eliciting different relational needs. Adjustment to university, anticipated to induce secure base needs, was in part explained by the global model of self and also by the model of other for father. In contrast, adjustment to a romantic breakup, expected to arouse safe haven needs, was associated with the model of self with a close friend, but not parental or global models. Finally, global and specific models of self and other contributed to explaining the experience of daily interactions within relationships. Relationship-specific models of other were most strongly associated with the quality and intimacy of interactions. The global model of other made modest, but significant additional contributions to explain these ratings. The global model of self moderated the association between specific models of self and ratings of interactions to explain a significant, yet small proportion of the variance. In sum, this research demonstrated that attachment or relational models can be considered both global and specific representational structures, reflecting relational as well as individual differences.</description><creator>Pierce, Tamarha.</creator><contributor>Lydon, John E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Attachment behavior.</subject><subject>Interpersonal relations.</subject><title>Global and specific relational models in the experience of social interactions and significant life events</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj815.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr37f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>