<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:43:33Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40125" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354h118</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This arts-informed inquiry uses auto-photography, rephotography,                interviews, memory work and writing about the photograph as tools to draw out of the                archive an understanding of the self-in-place. I focus on memory and photography in                an autotopographical (following Heddon) exploration of topographical intimacy as it                relates to childhood and current landscapes, known and unknown spaces. Using place as                common ground, I interview my siblings to excavate our shared childhood place                memories. I then photograph/rephotograph these remembered childhood places, looking                to identify the influence of place on childhood identity. This research with siblings                was a rich and storied resource. I also enter two public spaces with my camera, the                Architectural Garden of the Canadian Centre for Architecture in Montreal and the Jim                Everett Memorial Park in Vancouver, to map both the place and my relationship with/in                it, and in so doing, to engage with photography itself. By creating what one might                call place photo albums, I attempt to create an involvement with previously unknown                spaces, hoping to link past and present places. I explore the evidential and embodied                usefulness of photography in establishing topographical intimacy with/in place and                confirm the importance of using place as a means of exploring identity. Photography's                use as an active device of memory and its value in documenting place for inquiry is                made explicit.</description><description>Cette recherche faite en connaissance des arts utilise                l'auto-photographie, la rephotographie, des entrevues et un travail de mémoire et                d'écrit sur la photo en tant qu'outil permettant de soutirer des archives une                compréhension du soi dans l'espace. Je porte attention à la mémoire et à la                photographie d'une manière auto-topographique (selon Heddon), tout en explorant                l'intimité topographique liée aux paysages de l'enfance et de la vie actuelle, aux                espaces connus et inconnus. Utilisant le lieu comme cadre conceptuel commun, j'ai                interviewé ma sœur et mes frères afin de fouiller nos mémoires partagées des lieux                communs à notre enfance. J'ai par la suite photographié/rephotographié ces lieux de                souvenirs d'enfance tout en essayant d'identifier l'influence que porte le lieu sur                l'identité de l'enfance. Cette recherche avec ma sœur et mes frères fût une ressource                riche en récits. De plus, j'ai visité deux lieux publics avec mon appareil                photographique, le Jardin architectural du Centre canadien d'architecture de Montréal                et le Jim Everett Memorial Park de Vancouver afin de représenter le lieu et le                rapport que j'entretiens avec/dans ces lieux, ceci me permettant de m'investir                directement à la photographie. En créant ce que l'on pourrait appeler des albums de                photos de lieux, j'essaie de créer une participation avec les espaces auparavant                inconnus tout en espérant pouvoir relier les lieux du passé à ceux du present.                J'explore l'utilité évidente et incarnée de la photographie dans la création de                l'intimité topographique avec/dans un lieu tout en confirmant l'importance de                l'utilisation d'un lieu afin d'explorer l'identité. L'utilisation$</description><creator>Allnutt, Susann</creator><contributor>Claudia A Mitchell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Social Sciences</subject><title>Knowing my place: learning through memory and photography</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k461.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h118</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd52n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Products excreted or secreted (ES) by parasitic nematodes may contribute                to the processes of infection and tissue migration of the parasite, modulating the                host immune response and host physiology. These ES products allow the parasite to                persist and survive in conditions that would otherwise bar or destroy them. cDNAs                encoding three known secreted proteins of Brugia malayi was cloned for expression in                E. coli and subsequent protein purification. These proteins were chosen because they                have been reported to be secreted and to play roles in immune evasion. These proteins                include: macrophage inhibitory factor 1 (MIF-1), a tumor protein homologue (TPH-1)                and a cysteine protease inhibitor (CPI-2). Antibodies were raised to all of these                secreted proteins. The secreted protein CPI-2 was localized to a specific region of                microfilariae of B. malayi and the basic anatomy of this parasitic stage was observed                by means of confocal microscopy. The protein was found to be localized to the                secretory pore, which appears to be regulated by musculature. Biotinylated Sandwich                ELISAS were developed to detect these secreted proteins in cultures of two stages and                both sexes of B. malayi.</description><description>Les produits sécrétés ou excrétés de nématodes                parasitiques pourraient contribuer aux processus d`infection et de migration dans les                tissues, tout en modulant le système immunitoire et la physiologie de l`hôte. Ces                produits permettent au parasite de survivre dans des conditions infavorables. Trois                protéines sécrétées du nématode parasitique Brugia malayi ont été clonées et                produites dans du E.coli. Celles-ci ont ensuite été purifiées. Ces protéines se                trouvent à être: la macrophage inhibitory factor 1 (MIF-1), la tumor protein                homologue (TPH-1) et la cysteine protease inhibitor (CPI-2). CPI-2 a été localisée                dans une région délimitée de la microfilaria du B.malayi et l`anatomie de ce stage                parasitaire a été observé à l`aide de la microscopie confocale. La région délimitée                où cette protéine est sécrétée se trouve à être le pore sécrétoire. Le pouvoir                sécrétoire de ce pore semble être contrôlé par la musculature du nématode. Des ELISAs                Sandwich Biotinylés ont été développés pour détecter la présence de MIF-1, TPH-1 et                CPI-2 dans les différents stages de développement du B.malayi et dans les deux sexes                de ce nématode.</description><creator>Solomon, Jonathan</creator><contributor>Timothy Geary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>The localization and «in vitro» detection of «Brugia malayi» secreted proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp86m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd52n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644t375</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine la viabilité d'une approche récente,                dite des Dimensions Supplémentaires Larges Supersymétriques (Supersymmetric Large                Extra Dimensions, or SLED), qui propose une solution au problème de la constante                cosmologique et à celui de la hiérarchie. Un aspect central de cette approche est                l'existence de deux dimensions supplémentaires de grande taille r_c ~ 10 micromètres,                et la faible valeur de l'échelle de gravité, M_* ~ 10 TeV. Afin d'éviter un conflit                immédiat avec l'expérience, tous les champs du Modèle Standard sont supposés être                confinés dans les quatre dimensions observées (i.e. sur une brane). Une                implémentation de cette idée de SLED est realisée par le biais de la supergravité 6D                de Nishino et Sezgin (NS), dont on sait qu'elle a des compactifications 4D-plates. Un                certain nombre de questions, laissées ouvertes lorsque cette thèse à débutée, sont à                présent partiellement ou complètement résolues. En particulier, nous étendons les                solutions connues de la supergravité NS; elle incluent à present: compactifications                déformées ayant la symétrie de Sitter ou anti-de Sitter 4D, solutions statiques avec                invariance de Lorentz 4D brisée, et solutions d'échelle ("scaling'') dépendentes du                temps. La relation entre les propriétés des branes et la forme asymptotique des                champs de bulk lorsqu'ils approchent la brane est mise en lumière et expliquée. La                stabilité marginale des solutions 4D-plate est démontrée pour une large classe de                conditions de bord. Etant donné que les solutions déformées de la supergravité NS que                l'on considère sont singulières à l'emplacement de la brane, une procédure explicite                de rég</description><description>In this thesis we examine the viability of a recent proposal, known as                Supersymmetric Large Extra Dimensions (SLED), for solving both the cosmological                constant and the hierarchy problems. Central to this proposal is the requirement of                two large extra dimensions of size r_c ~ 10 micrometres together with a low value for                the higher-dimensional scale of gravity, M_* ~ 10 TeV. In order not to run into                immediate conflict with experiment, it is presumed that all fields of the Standard                Model are confined to a four-dimensional domain wall (brane). A realization of the                SLED idea is achieved by relying on the 6D supergravity of Nishino and Sezgin (NS),                which is known to have 4D-flat compactifications. When work on this thesis first                began, there were many open questions which are now answered either partially or                completely. In particular, we expand on the known solutions of NS supergravity, which                now include: warped compactifications having either 4D de Sitter or 4D anti-de Sitter                symmetry, static solutions with broken 4D Lorentz invariance, and time-dependent                "scaling'' solutions. We elucidate the connection between brane properties and the                asymptotic form of bulk fields as they approach the brane. Marginal stability of the                4D-flat solutions is demonstrated for a broad range of boundary conditions. Given                that the warped solutions of NS supergravity which we consider are singular at the                brane locations, we present an explicit regularization procedure for dealing with                these singularities. Finally, we derive general formulae for the one-loop quantum                corrections for both massless and massive field in arbitrary dimensions, with an eye                towards applying these results to NS supergravity</description><creator>Hoover, Douglas Allan</creator><contributor>Clifford Peter Burgess (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</subject><title>Supersymmetric large extra dimensions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b0676.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t375</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2686965</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> Peripheral muscle stretch reflexes at the calf muscles have been shown                to be important in postural control, by opposing forward sway. They are task                dependent, and vary based on the conditions at the joint and associated muscle                activation levels. Also, dynamic changes in stability, such as those induced by upper                body movements, are preceded by anticipatory postural adjustments (APAs) in the rest                of the body. To date, nobody has studied how stretch reflexes in the postural muscles                change during these APAs. For forward oriented upper body movements (e.g. arm raise,                arm reach, forward bend), the APA is typically characterized by an inhibition of the                calf muscle before the activation of the shoulder muscle, and a recovery of calf                muscle activity just before the onset of the arm movement. Biomechanically, this                muscle pattern results in anticipatory forward sway, with the body then held at the                new position. Hence during this period, one might expect the reflexes in the calf to                be initially inhibited (since they oppose forward sway), and then rebound close to                movement onset (to assist the slowing down of forward sway). However, to date, this                has not been demonstrated. Therefore, we devised a novel paradigm, where we measured                the excitability of the stretch reflex at the calf at different times during the APA                associated with unilateral right arm raises in standing humans. Our results showed                that in this period, as hypothesized, reflexes followed a general pattern similar to                the calf muscle activity. However, the reflex and muscle activity changes showed                temporal differences- reflexes were inhibited after the inhibition in muscle                activity, and rebounded just before the correspo</description><description> Il a déjà été démontré que les réflexes d'extension                périphériques que l'on retrouve dans les muscles du mollet ont un rôle important dans                le contrôle de la posture en s'opposant à l'oscillation avant. Ces réflexes dépendent                de la tâche accomplie. Ils varient selon la position des articulations et le niveau                d'efforts du muscle auquel ils sont associés. D'autre part, les changements                dynamiques provoquant un déséquilibre sont causés en partie par les mouvements du                torse et sont souvent précédés d'ajustements anticipatoires de la posture (AAP). Les                changements causés par les AAP sur les réflexes d'extensions n'ont cependant jamais                été étudiés. Pour les mouvements avant du torse (ex. levé ou extension du bras, se                pencher par en avant), les AAP sont habituellement caractérisés par une suppression                de l'activité du muscle du mollet avant l'activation du muscle de l'épaule et un                rétablissement de l'activité musculaire du mollet à l'amorcement du mouvement du                bras. Ceci résulte biomécaniquement par une oscillation anticipatoire avant gardant                le corps dans une nouvelle position. Donc, durant cette période, on peut s'attendre à                ce que le réflexe d'extension au niveau du mollet soit initialement inhibé (pour                opposer l'oscillation avant) et puis réactivé au début du mouvement (afin d'aider le                ralentissement de l'oscillation). Jusqu'à présent, ceci n'a jamais été démontré. Nous                avons donc conçu un nouveau paradigme qui nous permet de mesurer la réactivité du                réflexe du mollet à différent moment au courant d'un AAP causé par l'action de lever                le bras droit en position debout. Nos résultats démontrent comme supposé par                l'hyp</description><creator>Vedula, Siddharth</creator><contributor>Robert E Kearney (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Paul Stapley (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Ankle stretch reflexes during anticipatory postural adjustments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s199q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2686965</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fq714</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les points quantiques (PQs) sont des nanoparticules                inorganiques ayant des propriétés optiques exceptionnelles. À ce jour, les PQs n'ont                pas atteint leur plein potentiel en tant que marqueurs fluorescents dans les cellules                vivantes à cause des difficultés liées à l'interface biologique. L'objectif de cette                thèse est d'étudier les problèmes techniques reliés à la synthèse reproductible des                PQs, les stratégies de marquage spécifique des cellules biologiques par des PQs,                ainsi que la compréhension et l'exploitation des propriétés optiques de ceux-ci. Des                PQs de grande qualité avec diverses compositions (CdSe, CdTe et noyau/coquille                CdSe/ZnS) ont été synthétisés avec une méthode organométallique. Pour les rendre                biocompatibles, trois stratégies furent appliquées. Avec la plus simple, nous avons                utilisé de petites acides mercaptocarboxyliques et avons amélioré la performance avec                des peptides spécialement préparés et des couches de lipide micelle. Pour le marquage                biologique spécifique des PQs, nous avons développé des stratégies de conjugaison                pour l'attachement des biomolécules ainsi que des méthodes de caractérisation                spectroscopique pour évaluer l'efficacité de la conjugaison. Pour cibler les                bactéries Gram négatives, une méthode d'auto-assemblage électrostatique a été                utilisée afin d'attacher un antibiotique sélectif à cette classe de bactéries,                polymyxin B. Pour cibler les récepteurs du neurotransmetteur dopamine, une méthode de                conjugaison covalente a été utilisée pour l'attachement de la dopamine. Il a ainsi                été démontré que la molécule de dopamine permet le transfert d'électron aux PQs, et                la photophysi</description><description>Quantum dots (QDs) are inorganic nanoparticles that have exceptional                optical properties. Currently, QDs have failed to reach their potential as                fluorescent probes in live cells, due to the nontrivial requirements for biological                interfacing. The goal of this thesis is to address technical hurdles related to the                reproducible synthesis of QDs, strategies for the specific targeting of QDs to                biological cells and to understanding and exploitation of the photophysical                properties. High quality QDs of varying composition (CdSe, CdTe and core/shell                CdSe/ZnS) were synthesized with an organometallic method. To prepare biocompatible                QDs, three strategies were used. The simplest strategy used small mercaptocarboxylic                acids, while performance improvements were realized with engineered-peptide and                lipid-micelle coatings. For specific biological targeting of the QDs, conjugation                strategies were devised to attach biomolecules, while spectroscopic characterization                methods were developed to assess conjugation efficiencies. To target gram-negative                bacterial cells, an electrostatic self-assembly method was used to attach an                antibiotic selective for this class of bacteria, polymyxin B. To target dopamine                neurotransmitter receptor, a covalent conjugation method was used to attach dopamine,                the endogenous ligand for that receptor. It was shown that dopamine molecule enabled                electron transfer to QDs and the photophysics was studied in detail. A novel                conjugation and targeting strategy was explored to enable the selective binding of                QDs to polyhistidine epitopes on membrane proteins. Epifluorescence microscopy was                used to evaluate the biological activity of the three QD probes. Combined, they a</description><creator>Clarke, Samuel</creator><contributor>Jay Nadeau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Synthesis, biological targeting and photophysics of quantum dots</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw36h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq714</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm72n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the forests of Wemindji Cree Territory on the eastern shores of James                Bay, north-western Quebec, forest fires burn frequently, human interventions are                rare, and fire is the key agent of forest transformation. This thesis examines Cree                perceptions of spatial and temporal post-fire ecosystem processes, more specifically,                the interactions of plants, animals, people and the physical landscape. Western                scientific studies have focused on the complex actions of fire in shaping these                ecosystems. I interviewed Cree forest experts in Wemindji and reviewed the literature                on forest fire in this area. The knowledge that both hunters and scientists have                acquired is often nearly parallel. I suggest some ways in which the different                perspectives of Cree and western scientists might complement each other and                contribute to new knowledge of postfire ecology.</description><description>Sur le territoire des Cris de Wemindji, sur la rive est de                la Baie James au Nord-Ouest du Québec, les incendies de forêt surviennent                fréquemment, les interventions humaines sont rares et le feu est l'acteur clef des                transformations touchant la forêt. Ce mémoire examine les conceptions des Cris face                aux processus spatio-temporels affectant l'écosystème après un feu et, plus                spécifiquement, les interactions entre plantes, animaux, humains et contexte                physique. Les études scientifiques occidentales se focalisent sur les rôles complexes                du feu dans le façonnement des écosystèmes. J'ai interrogé à Wemindji des experts                cris de la forêt et revu la littérature sur les incendies de la région. Un parallèle                net peut être établi à plusieurs égards entre les connaissances des chasseurs et                celles des scientifiques. Je suggère des moyens pour rendre les perspectives                respectives des Cris et des scientifiques occidentaux complémentaires et contribuer à                l'acquisition de nouvelles connaissances concernant l'impact écologique des feux de                forêt.</description><creator>Scott, Katherine</creator><contributor>Colin Hartley Scott (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Anthropology - Cultural</subject><title>Fire, plants and people: exploring environmental relations through local knowledge of postfire ecology at Wemindji, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t817f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm72n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn60f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electronic circuits have evolved into multifunctional and highly                integrated systems that often require ultra-high-speed and wideband data                transmission. Due to the miniaturization trend in CMOS devices, digital processors                can now achieve these extreme specifications and enable operation with                multi-gigahertz clock frequencies. However, fundamental interconnect limitations                prevent from full accomplishment of multi-Gigabit per second data rates. Most                importantly, increased conductor and dielectric losses at high frequencies can                significantly reduce the channel bandwidth. In addition, crosstalk and                electromagnetic interference further deteriorate the link performance, especially in                compact routing networks. Therefore, alternative interconnects that enable                ultra-high-speed/high-frequency signaling while maintaining signal integrity are                needed. This thesis proposes a new method of high-speed data transfer by utilizing                waveguide-type interconnects, which offer efficient and confined data transmission                due to their low-loss and excellent isolation properties. The electromagnetic bandgap                concept is employed for a systematic design of the waveguide sidewalls in order to                yield negligible signal leakage in straight and meandered interconnect paths. The                performance of the suggested waveguide interconnects is fully investigated from the                signal integrity point of view. Due to the three-dimensional nature of the waveguide                and its incompatibility with planar structures, a few transition structures are                investigated, and important design parameters are identified. Models for transition                structures used in 3-D integration, i.e., the via and aperture transitions, are                proposed i</description><description>Les circuits électroniques ont évolué pour devenir des                systèmes multifonctionnels hautement intégrés requérant une transmission à très haute                vitesse et de large bande. Du à la tendance de miniaturisation des composantes CMOS,                les processeurs digitaux peuvent maintenant atteindre ces spécifications extrêmes et                permettent par le même fait une opération à plusieurs gigahertz. Cependant, des                limitations fondamentales par rapport aux interconnections empêchent une transmission                de plusieurs Gigabits par seconde. Plus précisément, la croissance des pertes de                conductions et diélectriques aux hautes fréquences peuvent réduire la bande de                transmission de façon significative. De plus, la diaphonie et l'interférence                électromagnétique contribuent également à détériorer la performance de lien, plus                spécialement dans des réseaux de routage compacts. Par conséquent, une alternative                aux interconnections standards est nécessaire qui permit une transmission à des                fréquences ultra-rapide tout en maintenant l'intégrité des signaux. Cette thèse                propose une méthode nouvelle de transmission de données à haute vitesse utilisant des                interconnections à guide d'ondes permettant ainsi une transmission de données                efficace grâce aux pertes relativement basses et excellentes propriétés d'isolation.                Le concept de bande électromagnétique interdite est utilisé pour un design                systématique des parois du guide d'ondes afin de procurer une fuite de signal                négligeable dans des interconnections droites ou courbées. La performance de                l'interconnexion à guide d'ondes suggérée est complètement investiguée du point de                vue de l'intégrité du signal. Du fait</description><creator>Suntives, Asanee</creator><contributor>Ramesh Abhari (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>High-speed data transmission using substrate integrated waveguide-type interconnects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w419x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn60f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj96q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Germline mutations in the genes, BRCA1 and BRCA2 have been implicated in                hereditary breast cancer (HBC) and hereditary breast and ovarian cancers (HBOC). A                large-scale multi-center genetic linkage analysis revealed that while linkage to                BRCA1 and BRCA2 was evident in the majority of HBOC families, the large proportion of                HBC families remained unaccounted for by either of these genes. These findings                supported the hypothesis that other novel breast cancer susceptibility genes could                account for the unexplained clustering of female breast cancer cases in the HBC                families. Previous studies have identified common BRCA1 and BRCA2 mutations in the                French Canadian (FC) population. The objective of this thesis was to establish the                contribution of BRCA1 and BRCA2 mutations to the HBC and HBOC families in the FC                population of Quebec. Mutations were identified in 96 of 224 (43%) families that met                our inclusion criteria of at least three verified cases of breast cancer diagnosed                below 65 years of age or ovarian cancer. An additional 13 novel mutations were added                to the FC mutation spectrum including the BRCA2:3398delAAAAG mutation which was                identified in eight independent families. Haplotype sharing of closely related                alleles in the carriers of this novel BRCA2 mutation suggested that the mutation was                introduced by a common ancestor. Although the FC population was more heterogeneous                than originally expected five common mutations accounted for 84% of the mutation                carrier families. The BRCA1/BRCA2 phenotype was further defined to include                metachronous bilateral breast cancer. In addition, 38 mutation-negative families were                identified that were phenotypically indiscernible from the BRCA</description><description>Les mutations germinales dans les gènes BRCA1 et BRCA2 ont                été impliquées dans la prédisposition aux syndromes du Cancer Héréditaire du Sein                (CHS) et des Cancers Héréditaires du Sein et de l'Ovaire (CHSO). Une grande étude                multi-centres a révélé que bien que la ségrégation associée à BRCA1 et BRCA2 soit                évidente dans la majorité des familles avec le CHSO, une grande proportion des                familles avec le CHS ne sont pas visiblement associées à ces gènes. Cette observation                supporte l'hypothèse que des gènes de prédisposition au cancer du sein inconnus                pourraient être responsables de l'excès de cancer du sein féminin dans ces familles                CHS. Des études précédentes ont identifié des mutations communes dans BRCA1 et BRCA2                dans la population canadienne française (CF). L'objectif de cette thèse portait à                déterminer la contribution des mutations dans BRCA1 et BRCA2 chez les familles avec                le CHS et le CHSO dans la population canadienne française du Québec. Des mutations                furent identifiées dans 96 des 224 (43%) familles rencontrant nos critères                d'inclusion, soit au moins 3 cas vérifiés de cancer du sein (diagnostiqués avant                l'âge de 65 ans) ou de cancer de l'ovaire dans la famille. Treize mutations                additionnelles furent ajoutées à la gamme de mutations CF, dont la mutation                BRCA2:3398delAAAAG identifiée dans 8 familles indépendantes. Les porteurs partagent                un haplotype d'allèles très similaires ce qui suggère que la mutation fut introduite                dans la population par un ancêtre commun à tous les porteurs. En dépit de                l'observation que la population CF semble plus hétérogène qu'originalement anticipé,                5 mutations communes sont responsab</description><creator>Oros Klein, Kathleen</creator><contributor>Patricia N Tonin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>A genetic analysis of the French Canadian population in search of evidence in favour of novel breast cancer susceptibility genes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289k854.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj96q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268697f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse propose une analyse des techniques de                modélisation informatique des instruments de musique de la famille des bois à perce                et trous arbitraires. Le modèle d'une structure acoustique simple implémenté avec                Matlab est vérifié par des mesures expérimentales de la directivité du rayonnement.                Les méthodes de calcul de l'impédance acoustique à l'entrée ainsi que de la pression                acoustique à n'importe quelle position le long de l'instrument sont présentées. La                procedure de calcul de la pression de radiation est détaillée pour le cas d'un tuyau                cylindrique ouvert avec deux trous latéraux. Les formules de calcul du rayonnement en                champ lointain et en champ proche sont données. Un système de mesure de la réponse                impulsionnelle est utilisé pour mesurer la directivité de la radiation sur un                prototype d'instrument ayant les caractéristiques de la famille des bois. La mesure                et le traitement des données sont simulés en utilisant un modèle de guide d'ondes                numérique pour tester la validité du système de mesure. Les mesures finales sont                effectuées pour les cinq doigts de l'objet mesuré. Les résultats sont comparés aux                valeurs théoriques pour évaluer la qualité du modèle. Des suggestions pour                l'amélioration de la mesure et du modèle sont données. </description><description>This thesis provides a review of a computational modeling technique for                woodwind-like musical instruments with arbitrarily shaped bore and finger holes. The                model of a simple acoustic structure implemented in Matlab is verified through                experimental measurements in terms of radiation directivity. The methods of                calculating the acoustical impedance at the input end and the internal sound pressure                at any position along the principle axis of the bore are presented. The procedure for                calculating the radiation pressure is detailed in an example featuring a main bore                with two open holes. The far-field and near-field formulas of radiation distances and                angles are given. A modified pulse reflectometry system is used to measure the                radiation directivity of the sample woodwind-like instrument. The measurement and                data processing are simulated using a digital waveguide model to test the validity of                the measurement system. The final measurements are performed with five fingerings for                the measured object. The measurement results are compared with the theoretically                predicted values to evaluate the fitness of the model. Suggestions for further                improvement of both the measurement and the model are given.</description><creator>Yong, Shi</creator><contributor>Gary Scavone (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Acoustics</subject><title>Comparing theory and measurements of woodwind-like instrument acoustic radiation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn50v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268697f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9031792</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer du sein est connue pour être une maladie très                hétérogène, composé d'un nombre de différents sous-types avec différents niveaux de                l'agressivité et distinctes, mais indéfini, profils moléculaires. Ici, nous avons                analysé plusieurs nouveaux modèles de souris pour le cancer du sein, dans le cadre                des sous-types, et nous avons trouver des parallèles à un certain nombre de niveaux                pertinents biologiques. En outre, nous avons développé une méthodologie statistique                pour aider à élucider les différents composants moléculaires qui sont à jouer dans un                groupe de tumours de sein d'humains ou mammaires murins. Nos résultats indiquent que,                même si aucun modèle de souris capte tous les aspects de la maladie chez l'homme,                chacun contiennent des composants qui sont partagées par un sous-ensemble de tumeurs                mammaires humaines. En outre, notre outil statistique offre de nombreux avantages par                rapport aux précédentes méthodes, pour aider à révéler les voies moléculaires qui                composent la biologie des tumeurs.</description><description>Human breast cancer is an extremely heterogeneous disease, consisting of                a number of different subtypes with varying levels of aggressiveness reflected by                distinct, but largely undefined, molecular profiles. Here we have analyzed several                novel mouse models for breast cancer in the context of the human subtypes, and have                shown parallels between the mice and humans at numerous biologically relevant levels.                In addition, we have developed a statistical framework to help elucidate the                individual molecular components that are at play across a panel of human breast or                murine mammary tumors. Our results indicate that, while no mouse model captures all                aspects of the human disease, they each contain components that are shared by a                subset of human breast tumors. Furthermore, our statistical framework provides                numerous advantages over previous methodologies, in helping to reveal the individual                molecular pathways that make up the biology of the tumors.</description><creator>Lesurf, Robert</creator><contributor>Michael Trevor Hallett (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Bioinformatics</subject><title>Molecular pathway analysis of mouse models for breast cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm73x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9031792</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pf789</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse analyse la question concernent le rôle des                professeurs anglophones et non anglophones de TOEFL dans le système coréen. Dans ce                système, les examens ont beaucoup d'impact sur l'enseignement et l'apprentissage. Le                but de cette étude est d'examiner les perceptions des parties concernées : les                professeurs anglophones et non anglophones ainsi que les étudiants dans les écoles                secondaires en Corée. Les données ont été collectées à travers des entretiens avec                des professeurs et des étudiants, des bulletins de classe et des conversations                informelles; et ce pendant une période de deux mois. Les professeurs et les étudiants                s'entendent que le rôle des professeurs coréens est beaucoup plus important que celui                des professeurs non coréens, notamment en tout ce qui a trait à la discipline, la                facilité de l'apprentissage et les cours de TOEFL. Pendant les entretiens et les                observations, d'autres problèmes tels que les devoirs à la maison, l'implication des                étudiants et leur attitude en classe, ont émergé. Ces problèmes sont à même                d'entraver les enseignants à aller au delà de leur objectif dans les classes de                TOEFL. L'étude révèle que les professeurs anglophones et non anglophones doivent                améliorer leurs potentiels de communication et de collaboration afin de mieux                accomplir leur rôle dans les classes de TOEFL et aider les étudiants à atteindre un                bon niveau de compétence en anglais, non seulement pour le TOEFL, mais aussi pour la                vie courante.</description><description>This exploratory qualitative study explores issues related to native and                nonnative English teachers about their roles in test-preparation courses (TPCs) in                the context of Korean English education where tests have an enormous impact on                learning and teaching. My goal is to examine the perceptions of native and nonnative                English teachers, and Korean junior-high school students of teachers' roles in the                context of recently adapted TOEFL courses. I collected data for a two-month period in                Korea in 2008 through open-ended interviews with students and teachers, field notes                of class observations, informal conversations, and school documents such as student                report cards. These major stakeholders seem to perceive that Korean English teachers                play a major role and native English teachers play a minor role as disciplinarians,                facilitators and language experts in TPCs. Through the interviews and observations,                other issues emerged, such as teachers' and students' dilemmas, a role of homework                and students' investment in learning and teacher's classroom management which                influenced students' attitudes toward learning English. These emerged issues may                prevent teachers from performing beyond the expected major and minor roles in TPCs.                The data suggest that both native and non-native teachers are required to develop                their strengths through communication and collaboration in order to perform confident                roles in TPCs. Data also suggest that teachers need to support students in TPCs to                achieve high- English competence not only on high stakes tests but also in the                context of real world communication and situations.</description><creator>Kim, Jung-Ok</creator><contributor>Joan C Russell (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Mary H Maguire (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Social Sciences</subject><title>Roles of native and non-native teachers in test-preparation courses in Korea: teachers' and students' perceptions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p893x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pf789</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw32w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des essais visant à évaluer la faisabilité d'utiliser la                spectroscopie de réflectance dans le visible et le proche infrarouge (VIS/PIR) pour                déterminer certaines caractéristiques contribuant à la qualité de la tomate                (Lycopersicon esculentum Mill. cv. 'DRK 453' et 'Trust') ont été menés. Une analyse                de régression partielle par les moindres carrés a servi à bâtir des modèles de                prédiction. D'excellentes prédictions ont été obtenues pour la teneur en lycopène                (TL), la valeur chromatique a*/b*, l'indice de couleur de la tomate (ICT), et la                fermeté. Les coefficients de détermination (R2) pour chacun de ces paramètres ont été                de 0.96, 0.99, 0.99 et 0.97. Tous ces R2 ont été significatifs à un niveau de 1%.                L'erreur-type de prédiction (ETP) a été petite pour tous ces paramètres, indiquant un                très bon degré d'ajustement des modèles. Des valeurs d'ETP de 2.15, 0.06, 1.52 et                1.44 ont respectivement été obtenues pour le TL, le rapport a*/b*, l'ICT, et la                fermeté. Cependant, les modèles visant à prédire l'acidité totale, la teneur en                solides solubles et le rapport acide-Brix se sont montrés peu fiables avec des                valeurs respectives de R2 de 0.49, 0.03 et 0.65 et de ETP de 0.43, 0.15 et 0.08. De                plus, un modèle multivariable bâti par une méthode de régression partielle par des                moindres carrés (PLS2) s'est montrée très performant pour la prédiction simultanée du                rapport a*/b*, de l'ICT, de la fermeté et de la TL avec des valeurs respectives de R2                de 0.99, 0.99, 0.97 et 0.92 et de ETP de 0.06, 1.75, 1.44 et 3.03. Comme auparavant                toutes les valeurs de R2 ont été significatives à un niveau de 1%.</description><description>Experiments were conducted to assess the feasibility of determining the                quality attributes of tomato (Lycopersicon esculentum Mill cv 'DRK 453' and 'Trust')                based upon visible/near-infrared reflectance (VIS/NIR) spectroscopy. A partial least                squares regression (PLS) method was used to build prediction models. Excellent                prediction performance was achieved for lycopene content (LC), colour value a*/b*                ratio, tomato colour index (TCI), and firmness. Coefficient of determination (R2) for                each of the parameters was respectively 0.96, 0.99, 0.99, and 0.97. All these R2 were                significant at 1% level. The root mean square errors of prediction (RMSEP) for all                the parameters were low indicating the high quality of the fit of the prediction                models. The values were 2.15, 0.06, 1.52, and 1.44 for LC, a*/b* ratio, TCI, and                firmness, respectively. However, the models for prediction of titratable acidity,                soluble solids content (SSC) and acid-Brix ratio showed relatively poor reliability,                with R2 value of 0.49, 0.03 and 0.65, and RMSEP of 0.43, 0.15 and 0.08, respectively.                Further, a model built by the PLS2 method showed good performance in simultaneously                predicting a*/b* ratio, TCI, firmness, and LC of tomato, with R2 values of 0.99,                0.99, 0.97, and 0.92, and RMSEP of 0.06, 1.75, 1.44, and 3.03, respectively. Once                again here all the R2 values were significant at 1% level.</description><creator>Chen, Limei</creator><contributor>Clement Vigneault (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>G S Vijaya Raghavan (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</subject><title>Non-destructive measurement of tomato quality using visible and near-infrared reflectance spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s658p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw32w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xd51s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Little is known about clouds during drought. In 1999-2005 the Canadian                Prairies experienced one of the most severe and prolonged droughts in its                climatological record. The objective of this study is to characterize and better                understand clouds and their associated radiative properties during drought in the                Canadian Prairie Provinces with a particular focus on this recent drought. Drought                severity was determined using the Standardized Precipitation Index. Cloud properties                from NASA/GEWEX's Surface Radiation Budget data base were used to examine overall                cloud amount, optical thickness, and top-of-the-atmosphere albedo. It was found that,                although cloud amounts differ slightly from dry to wet conditions (approximately a                10% increase in cloud cover fraction from 63% when severely dry to 73% when severely                wet), the correlation with precipitation is weak. The occurrence of thin clouds                increased as drought severity increased, whereas medium thickness clouds and thick                clouds decreased. Similar trends were found to pertain at smaller scales.</description><description>Très peu est connu a propos des nuages durant une                sècheresse. Entre 1999 et 2005, les Prairies canadiennes ont vécu une des sècheresses                les plus sévères et les plus longues dans ses registres climatologiques. L'objectif                de cette étude est de caractériser et de mieux comprendre les nuages et leurs                propriétés radiatives durant les sècheresses dans les provinces des Prairies                canadiennes. Une attention particulière a été donnée à cette récente sècheresse. La                sévérité de la sècheresse a été déterminée avec l'index standardise de                précipitations. Les propriétés des nuages obtenues de la base de données du Budget                Radiatif de Surface de NASA/GEWEX ont été utilisées pour examiner l'ensemble de la                quantité de nuage, l'épaisseur optique et l'albédo du haut de l'atmosphère. Les                résultats ont démontré que malgré une légère différence dans la quantité de nuage                entre des périodes sèches et humide (une augmentation d'environ 10% dans la                couverture nuageuse de 63% durant des conditions extrêmement sèches a 73% pendant des                périodes extrêmement humide), la corrélation avec la précipitation est faible. Les                nuages minces augmentent lorsque la sévérité de la sècheresse augmente, alors que les                nuages d'épaisseur moyenne ou épaisse diminuent. Les résultats ont aussi démontré que                des tendances similaires se rapportent à plus petite échelle. </description><creator>Greene, Heather</creator><contributor>Ronald Stewart (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Henry Leighton (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>Drought and associated cloud fields over the Canadian Prairies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n0501.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd51s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q808r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En 2007, Babaioff, Immorlica, et Kleinberg formulèrent la                version matroïdale du problème du secrétaire (matroid secretary problem), liant de                façon élégante la théorie des matroïdes à des généralisations du problème du                secrétaire. Dans cette thèse, nous introduisons le lecteur aux matroïdes et au                problème du secrétaire, avant de nous lancer dans la définition de Babaioff et al. et                dans une étude de résultats récents. En suite nous nous concentrons sur l'important                cas spécial du transversal matroid secretary problem. Nous formulons une classe de                matroïdes transversales qui n'a pas été defini auparavant, et présentons un                algorithme c-compétitif (c une constante) pour cette classe. Nous fournissons aussi                l'analyse la plus rigoureuse que l'on connaisse de l'algorithme récent (2008) de                Plaxton et Dimitrov pour le transversal matroid secretary problem, ainsi donnant le                meilleur rapport de compétitivité que l'on connaisse pour ce problème. </description><description>In 2007 Babaioff, Immorlica, and Kleinberg formulated the matroid                secretary problem, elegantly tying together the field of matroid theory with                generalizations of the secretary problem. In this thesis, we introduce the reader to                matroids and the secretary problem, before diving into Babaioff et al's definition                and a survey of recent results. We then focus on the important special case of the                transversal matroid secretary problem. We formulate a previously undefined class of                transversal matroids and give a constant competitive algorithm for them. We also                provide the tightest known analysis of Plaxton and Dimitrov's recent 2008 algorithm                for the transversal matroid secretary problem and thereby give the tightest known                competitive ratio for this problem.</description><creator>Thain, Nithum</creator><contributor>Adrian Roshan Vetta (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</subject><title>On the transversal matroid secretary problem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8382321.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q808r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tr12b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Massively multiplayer online games (MMOG) have become an extremely                popular genre of gaming boasting millions of subscribers. Focusing on cheating, game                designers often implement client-server network models which ensure that authority                over the gamestate is retained by the game providers. Due to scalability limitations                of such architecture the transition to the more scalable, yet less secure, peer to                peer (P2P) models has become a more attractive option. Concentrating on cheat                detection, the IRS hybrid network model is proposed. It combines positive features                from both network designs and represents a reasonable trade-off between security and                network efficiency. The IRS model's centralized server acts as the authority over the                game-state, managing peer to peer matching and monitoring client behaviour. This                allows for a reduced computational load by enabling clients to resolve messages for                others. Intermittent peer auditing which compares two client's computation of the                same request message also allows for the discovery and elimination of cheating                behaviour. By simulating the proposed hybrid model in an abstract game environment                designed to incorporate parameters of actual gameplay it is shown that malicious                clients are purged extremely quickly and with minimal impact on non-cheating clients,                while still ensuring continued benefit and scalability from distributed computation.                Since cheating has a very serious impact on gaming it is essential that any study                into the improvement of MMOG network models strives to preserve security.</description><description>Les jeux en ligne massivement multi-joueur (MMOG) sont un                genre de jeu devenu extrêmement populaire, avec des millions d'abonnés. Pour éviter                les situations de tricherie, les concepteurs de jeux favorisent le modèle réseau                client/serveur (C/S) parce qu'il garantie que l'autorité sur l'état du jeu est                conservée par le fournisseur du jeu. Cependant, l'évolution de tel modèle est limité.                Malgré leur lacune au niveau de la sécurité, les modèles pair-à-pair (P2P) sont une                alternative intéressante. Nous proposons un modèle de réseau hybride, l'IRS, qui se                spécialise dans la détection des cas de tricherie. Ce modèle exploite les aspects                positifs des deux types de modèle réseau (C/S et P2P), tout en proposant un compromis                raisonnable entre la sécurité et l'efficacité. Dans le modèle IRS, un serveur                centralisé possède l'autorité absolue sur l'état du jeu, tout en assurant la gestion                des communications pair-à-pair et la surveillance du comportement des participants.                En permettant aux participants d'exécuter des messages pour d'autres participants, la                charge d'exécution sur le serveur est réduite. Les cas de tricherie peuvent être                découverts et éliminés à l'aide d'audits intermittentes qui comparent les résultats                d'exécution d'un même message par deux participants. Des simulations du modèle                hybride proposé ont été effectuées dans un environnement jeu visant à reproduire des                situations de jeux réelles. Les résultats démontrent le modèle expulse les                participants malveillants très rapidement du jeu avec des impacts minimaux aux autres                participants, tout en conservant les avantages d'extensibilité des modèles                distribués. Puisq</description><creator>Goodman, Joshua</creator><contributor>Clark Verbrugge (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>A hybrid design for cheat detection in massively multiplayer online games</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx29p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr12b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1618115</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main theme of this thesis is the study of compatible systems of                $\ell$-adic Galois representations provided by the étale cohomology of arithmetic                varieties with a large group of symmetries. A canonical decomposition of these                systems into isotypic components is proven (Section 3.1). The isotypic components are                realized as the cohomology of the quotient with values in a certain sheaf, thus                providing a geometrical interpretation for the rationality of the corresponding                $L$-functions. A particular family of singular hypersurfaces $W_\ell^{m,n}$ of degree                $\ell$ and dimension $m + n - 3$, admitting an action by a product of symmetric                groups $S_m \times S_n$, arises naturally when considering the average moments of                certain exponential sums (Chapter 4); asymptotics for these moments are obtained by                relating them to the trace of the Frobenius morphism on the cohomology of the                desingularization of the corresponding varieties, following the approach of Livné.                Two other closely related classes of smooth hypersurfaces admitting an $S_n$-action                are introduced in Chapter 3, and the character of the representation of the symmetric                group on their primitive cohomology is computed. In particular, a certain smooth                cubic hypersurface of dimension 4 is shown to carry a compatible system of                2-dimensional Galois representations. A variant of the Faltings-Serre method is                developed in Chapter 5 in order to explicitly determine the corresponding modular                form, whose existence is predicted by Serre's conjecture. We provide a systematic                treatment of the Faltings-Serre method in a form amenable to generalization to Galois                representations of other fields and to other groups besides $\GL_2$.</description><description>Le thème principal de cette thèse est l'étude des systèmes                compatibles de représentations galoisiennes $\ell$-adiques provenant de la                cohomologie étale de variétés arithmétiques admettant beaucoup de symétries. Une                décomposition canonique de ces systèmes en composantes isotypiques est obtenue                (section 3.1). Les composantes isotypiques sont décrites comme la cohomologie du                quotient à valeurs dans un certain faisceau, fournissant ainsi une interprétation                géométrique de la rationalité des fonctions $L$ correspondantes. Une famille                spécifique d'hypersurfaces $W_\ell^{m,n}$ de degré $\ell$ et dimension $m+n-3$,                admettant une action du produit de groupes symétriques $S_m \times S_n$, apparaît                naturellement en lien avec les moments moyens de certaines sommes exponentielles                (chapitre 4); le comportement limite de ces moments est obtenu en considérant la                trace du morphisme de Frobenius sur la cohomologie de la désingularisation des                variétés correspondantes, suivant l'approche développée par Livné. Deux autres                classes apparentées d'hypersurfaces lisses admettant une action du groupe symétrique                sont introduites au chapitre 3, et le caractère de la représentation de $S_n$ sur                leur cohomologie primitive est calculé. En particulier, dans le cas d'une certaine                hypersurface cubique de dimension 4, un système compatible de représentations                galoisiennes de dimension 2 est obtenu. Une variante de la méthode de Faltings-Serre                est développée dans le chapitre 5 afin de déterminer explicitement la forme modulaire                correspondante, dont l'existence est prédite par la conjecture de Serre. Nous                proposons un traitement systématique de la méthode de Falting</description><creator>Chênevert, Gabriel</creator><contributor>Eyal Z Goren (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</subject><title>Exponential sums, hypersurfaces with many symmetries and Galois representations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g925g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1618115</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt866</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Paleo-evidence suggests that the mean state of the atmosphere in the               early Holocene resembles the positive phase of the modern North Atlantic/Arctic               Oscillation (NAO). To test this theory we use a coupled ice-ocean model to study the               effects of atmospheric and ocean forcing from the positive phase of the NAO and               altered surface radiation on sea-ice concentration and thickness in the Arctic during               the early Holocene. The resulting sea-ice concentrations are compatible with               reconstructions based on dinoflagellate cysts assemblages. Sensitivity studies show               that local winds dominate the changes in sea-ice concentration from the East Siberian               Sea, whereas ocean currents and sea surface and air temperatures all contribute               significantly to anomalous sea-ice concentrations in the Barents Sea. Patterns in               sea-ice thickness anomalies show similar results but are spread out over larger               areas. The net radiation is shown to have little effect on the Arctic sea-ice cover               during the early Holocene.</description><description>Les données paléocéanographiques suggèrent un régime               atmosphérique semblable à la phase positive de l'oscillation de l'Arctique/Atlantique               Nord (NAO) moderne durant l'Holocène inférieur (9.5 ka). Pour examiner cette               hypothèse, on utilise un modèle dynamique-thermodynamique de la glace de mer, couplé               avec un modèle de circulation de l'océan, afin d'analyser les effets atmosphériques               et océaniques de la phase positive de la NAO et du bilan radiatif modifié sur la               concentration et l'épaisseur de la glace de mer durant l'Holocène inférieur dans               l'Arctique. La concentration de la glace de mer simulée est compatible avec les               reconstructions de glace de mer derivée des assemblages des kystes de dinoflagellés.               Des analyses de sensibilité montrent que les vents locaux dominent les changements de               glace dans la mer de Sibérie Orientale mais les courants marins et les températures               de surface océaniques et atmosphériques contribuent aux anomalies dans la mer de               Barents. Le patron des anomalies d'épaisseur de la glace de mer sont semblables, mais               plus étalés dans l'espace. La rayonement net est un facteur négligeable dans les               changements de la couverture de la glace de mer durant l'Holocène inférieur.</description><creator>Dyck, Sarah</creator><contributor>Anne de Vernal (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Bruno Tremblay (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Atmospheric Science</subject><title>Modeling the Arctic sea-ice cover from the early Holocene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk731.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt866</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655j422</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the design and implementation of an SQL front end                for a relational database programming system JRelix. The purpose of this thesis is to                lay a strong basis for the full SQL support by JRelix. The SQL language is the de                facto standard in Relational Databases which motivates its integration into JRelix.                Through the SQLSTMT and SQLEXP commands the user can use SQL to perform operations on                a JRelix database. These operations are translated into Aldat (the native programming                language of JRelix) and can interactively perform updates, deletions and selections                on the distinct relations of the database. The SQLSTMT command allows us to execute                full SQL commands on the system whereas the SQLEXP command returns a relational                expression to the system that can interact with other elements of the commands                written in Aldat in the same statement.</description><description>La présente thèse traite de la conception et de la mise en                oeuvre d'une interface SQL pour le système de programmation de bases de données                relationnelles JRelix. Cette thèse a pour but de poser les fondements d'une                couverture exhaustive de SQL par JRelix. Le Language SQL est le standard en bases de                données relationnelles ce qui est à l'origine de son intégration dans JRelix. A                l'aide des commandes SQLSTMT et SQLEXP l'utilisateur peut effectuer des requêtes sur                la base de données JRelix en SQL. Ces requêtes sont traduites en Aldat (le language                natif de programmation de JRelix) et peut, de façon interactive, effectuer mises à                jour, suppressions et sélections sur les différentes relations. La commande SQLSTMT                permet d'exécuter des requêtes entièrement exprimées en SQL alors que la commande                SQLEXP retourne au système une expression relationnelle qui peut interagir avec                d'autres expressions relationnelles exprimées en Aldat dans la même requête.</description><creator>Khaya, Ibrahima</creator><contributor>Timothy Merrett (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>SQL front-end for the JRelix relational-programming system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x532.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j422</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj970</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La méthode des éléments finis (FEM) est utilisée pour                résoudre les problèmes de diffusion et de rayonnement électromagnétiques en trois                dimensions. Les solutions obtenues par la méthode des éléments finis contiennent deux                types d'erreur principaux: l'erreur de discrétisation et l'erreur de frontière.                L'erreur de discrétisation dépend du nombre de paramètres libres utilisés pour                modéliser le problème, et sur l'efficacité de la distribution de ces paramètres dans                le domaine du problème. Pour réduire l'erreur de discrétisation, l'ordre du polynôme                des éléments est augmenté, soit uniformément dans le domaine ou sélectivement dans                les régions où la solution a une qualité basse. L'erreur de la frontière est produite                par la condition appliquée à la frontière qui est utilisée pour tronquer le domaine                de calcul. Pour réduire l'erreur de la frontière, une condition absorptive de                frontière itératif (IABC) est implémentée. L'IABC commence avec une condition de                frontière pas dispendieuse dont la qualité est améliorée progressivement avec                l'augmentation du nombre d'itérations. Un mécanisme automatique pour contrôler                l'erreur (AEC) est implémenté pour équilibrer les deux types d'erreur. Avec l'AEC, la                condition à la frontière est améliorée lorsque l'erreur de discrétisation est réduite                à un niveau suffisamment bas pour faire ce qui mérite d'être fait. L'AEC a les                caractéristiques suivantes: (i) d'abord il utilise une méthode de troncature pas                dispendieuse (ii) il permet que la frontière de troncature soit très proche du                diffuseur/radiateur, (iii) il met davantage l'effort de calcul sur les parties du                problème où il$</description><description>The finite element method (FEM) is used to solve three-dimensional                electromagnetic scattering and radiation problems. Finite element (FE) solutions of                this kind contain two main types of error: discretization error and boundary error.                Discretization error depends on the number of free parameters used to model the                problem, and on how effectively these parameters are distributed throughout the                problem space. To reduce the discretization error, the polynomial order of the finite                elements is increased, either uniformly over the problem domain or selectively in                those areas with the poorest solution quality. Boundary error arises from the                condition applied to the boundary that is used to truncate the computational domain.                To reduce the boundary error, an iterative absorbing boundary condition (IABC) is                implemented. The IABC starts with an inexpensive boundary condition and gradually                improves the quality of the boundary condition as the iteration continues. An                automatic error control (AEC) is implemented to balance the two types of error. With                the AEC, the boundary condition is improved when the discretization error has fallen                to a low enough level to make this worth doing. The AEC has these characteristics:                (i) it uses a very inexpensive truncation method initially; (ii) it allows the                truncation boundary to be very close to the scatterer/radiator; (iii) it puts more                computational effort on the parts of the problem domain where it is most needed; and                (iv) it can provide as accurate a solution as needed depending on the computational                price one is willing to pay. To further reduce the computational cost, disjoint                scatterers and radiators that are relatively far from each other</description><creator>Paul, Prakash</creator><contributor>Jonathan P Webb (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>An iterative truncation method for unbounded electromagnetic problems using varying order finite elements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx21q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj970</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k905r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Saccharomyces cerevisiae has become a model for studying various                biological processes in eukaryotic cells, including human cancer cells and fungal                pathogens. Here we endeavoured to study a class of transcriptional regulators, the                zinc cluster proteins, and their roles in mediating pleiotropic drug resistance.                Because of the presence of functional redundancy within the yeast genome, the role of                these proteins has been difficult to unmask. In this study, double knockouts of genes                encoding regulators believed to play a role in multidrug resistance were made and                assayed using a panel of drugs in order to gain further insight into the functional                relationships among these transcriptional regulators. Our phenotypic analysis allowed                us to infer new possible functional relationships among zinc cluster transcription                factors, as well as confirm and dispute the existence of previously described                relationships.</description><description>Saccharomyces cerevisiae est maintenant un organisme                modèle pour l'étude de la multi-résistance aux médicaments chez les cellules                eucaryotes, incluant les cellules de cancer chez les humains et les levures                pathogéniques. Au cours de ce projet, nous avons étudié un groupe de régulateurs de                transcription, les protéines du type Zn(II)2Cys6, et leur rôle dans la                multi-résistance aux médicaments. La redondance fonctionnelle est commune dans la                séquence génétique de S. cerevisiae, ce qui rend l'étude de ces protéines difficile.                En raison de cette redondance fonctionnelle, nous avons généré des souches comportant                des double deletions pour les gènes codant pour les protéines Zn(II)2Cys6                responsables pour la multi-résistance aux médicaments. Ces déletions ont été étudiées                phénotypiquement en les exposants à différents médicaments. Ces expériences nous ont                aidé à obtenir davantage d'informations sur les relations fonctionnelles entre les                membres de ce groupe de protéines et à confirmer ou infirmer l'existence de relations                décrites auparavant.</description><creator>Patel, Reena</creator><contributor>Bernard Turcotte (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Mediation of pleiotropic drug resistance by zinc cluster transcriptional regulators in «Saccharomyces cerevisiae»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dh60m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k905r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sr83p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines images of martial women as they were produced in                the biography column of the late Qing journal Nüzi shijie (NZSJ; 1904-1907). By                examining the historiographic implications of revised women's biographies, I will                show the extent to which martial women were written as ideal citizens at the dawn of                the twentieth-century. In the first chapter I place NZSJ in its historical context by                examining the journal's goals as seen in two editorials from the inaugural issue. The                second and third chapters focus on biographies of individual women warriors which                will be read against their original stories in verse and prose. Through these                comparisons, I aim to demonstrate how these "transgressive women" were written as                normative ideals of martial citizens that would appeal to men and women alike.</description><description>Cette thèse examine les images de femmes martiales                reproduites dans la rubrique biographique du journal Nüzi shijie (NZSJ; 1904-1907)                publiée à la fin de la dynastie Qing. En examinant les implications                historiographiques des biographies révisées des femmes, j'essai de démontrer                l'importance de la façon dont les femmes martiales étaient décrites come citoyennes                idéales à l'aube du vingtième siècle. A travers une exploration des objectifs posés                par le journal et mis en évidence dans deux éditoriaux extraits du premier numéro du                journal, mon premier chapitre essaie de placer le NZSJ dans sa propre contexte                historique. Le deuxième et le troisième chapitres se concentrent sur les biographies                individuelles des femmes guerrières, lesquelles sont juxtaposés aux histories                originales écrites sous forme de vers et prose. A travers ces juxtapositions, mon                projet démontre la façon dont ces "femmes transgressives" illustraient l'idéal                normatif du citoyen martiale, lequel attirait les hommes ainsi que les femmes.</description><creator>Cully, Eavan</creator><contributor>Grace S Fong (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>History - Asia, Australia and Oceania</subject><title>Nationalism, feminism, and martial valor: rewriting biographies of women in «Nüzi shijie» (1904-1907)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp203.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr83p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j38608729</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The bifurcation diagram of a model nonlinear Langevin equation with                delay is obtained. A finite delay implies non-Markovian behavior, and is the subject                of current interest as such equations model delayed feedback loops in many settings,                including the study of cell regulation. We show that the bifurcation remains sharp,                both in the ranges of direct and oscillatory instabilities. Below threshold, the                stationary distribution function is a delta function at the trivial state x = 0                despite the delay. At threshold, the stationary distribution function becomes a power                law p(x) ∼ x ^a with −1 &lt; a &lt; 0, where a = −1 at threshold and                monotonously increases with increasing value of the control parameter. Unlike the                case without delay, the bifurcation threshold is shifted by fluctuations, and the                shift scales linearly with the noise intensity D.</description><description>Le diagramme de bifurcation d' une équation de Langevin                non linéaire retardée est obtenu. Un retard fini implique un processus non markovien.                De telles équations permettent de modéliser des boucles d'autorégulation retardées                dans de nombreux systèmes, incluant la régulation cellulaire. Nous démontrons que la                bifurcation demeure aigüe dans les cas d'instabilités stationnaires et oscillatoires.                Sous le seuil de bifurcation, la fonction de distribution de probabilité stationnaire                est une fonction delta à la solution triviale x = 0, malgré la presence du retard. Au                seuil de bifurcation, la distribution stationnaire devient une loi de puissance p(x)                ∼ x ^a avec −1 &lt; a &lt; 0, où a = −1 au seuil and croît de facon monotone                avec le paramètre de contrôle. Contrairement au cas non-retardé, le seuil de                bifurcation est déplacé par les fluctuations, et ce déplacement augmente linéairement                avec l'intensité du bruit D.</description><creator>Lepine, Francoise</creator><contributor>Jorge Vinals (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</subject><title>Pitchfork and Hopf bifurcation threshold in stochastic equations with delayed feedback</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn514.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38608729</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft23s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse tente d'apporter réponse à la question                suivante: est-ce que la motoneige électrique peut faire partie des solutions afin                d'aider à diminuer les émissions et la consommation d'énergie des motoneiges? Afin de                répondre à cette question, un questionnement sur les performances des prototypes de                motoneiges électriques actuelles est entrepris et il en ressort qu'à moins qu'une                énorme percée technologique ne vienne changer la donne, la densité d'énergie des                technologies de piles présentement disponibles fait en sorte qu'une motoneige                électrique ne peux pas envisager performer de façon similaire à une motoneige                conventionnelle à essence sur le plan de l'autonomie et de la performance de façon                simultanée. Ceci étant dit, il existe tout de même des applications de niche pour                lesquelles une motoneige électrique est parfaitement apte à accomplir le travail                requis. Cette thèse suggère que l'utilisation de la modélisation et de la simulation                peut s'avérer un outil précieux afin de surmonter certains obstacles à l'implantation                de motoneiges électriques. Un modèle virtuel de motoneige électrique est assemblé et                une simulation virtuelle est complétée et ensuite validée en utilisant des données                obtenues lors d'essais sur neige avec une vraie motoneige électrique. Une simulation                est faite et permet de démontrer que sur la totalité de son cycle de carburant, une                motoneige électrique canadienne émet généralement moins d'émissions et consomme moins                d'énergie qu'une motoneige conventionnelle à essence, et ce, de façon substantielle.                Cependant, puisque ce résultat est fortement lié aux méthodes de production d'énergie                il ne peu</description><description>This thesis addresses the question: can an electric snowmobile be one of                the solutions to help lower snowmobile emissions and energy consumption? In                addressing this question the performance limitations of current electric snowmobile                prototypes are investigated and it is shown that, unless a huge leap is seen in                current battery technology energy density, electric snowmobiles cannot perform on par                with gasoline snowmobile on both range and performance simultaneously. Despite this,                electric snowmobiles do have a certain number of niche applications where they can be                useful. This thesis suggests that electric snowmobile powetrain modeling and                simulation for these niche applications can potentially help overcome some of the                challenges that exist in implanting such a vehicle for regular use. A complete,                virtual electric snowmobile model was built and validated using actual electric                snowmobile on-snow test data. Snowmobile emission and energy consumption simulation                was performed and demonstrated that Canadian electric snowmobile fuel cycle emissions                and energy consumptions were, in general, substantially lower than gasoline                snowmobiles. However, this is closely linked with electricity generation techniques                and should not be extrapolated to say that this is the case for all potential                electric snowmobiles worldwide.</description><creator>Ouellette, Simon</creator><contributor>Peter Henry Radziszewski (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Investigating the development of a zero emission electric utility snowmobile</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr40r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft23s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zs553</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis has three primary objectives and is organized into two                separate but related manuscripts: In the first manuscript, entitled A Review of                Client Involvement in Psychotherapy, the goal is to provide a thorough review of the                involvement literature and to present a theoretical conceptualization of client                involvement that could clarify our understanding of involvement. Specifically, it is                argued that client involvement is composed of two facets, the internal and external                processes which guide whether a client will participate in therapy. The goal of the                second manuscript, which is entitled Factor Analysis and Construct Validity of a                Measure of Client Involvement, is to evaluate a factor model of client involvement                based on empirical data. The client involvement measure is the Comprehensive Scale of                Psychotherapy Session Constructs Client Involvement subscale (CSPSC-CI; Eugster                &amp; Wampold, 1996), and it has not previously been independently evaluated. The                psychometric properties of this measure were examined. Factor analysis of the                CSPSC-CI revealed three interpretable factors: a Client factor, an Active Therapist                factor, and a Disengaged Therapist factor. Discriminant and convergent construct                validity was also evaluated; the results of the study provide preliminary support for                the construct validity of the measure.</description><description>Cette these a trois objectifs principaux et se divise en                deux manuscrits distincts mais liés: Dans le premier manuscrit, intitulé A Review of                Client Involvement in Psychotherapy, le but est de fournir un examen approfondi de la                littérature de la participation et d'avancer une conceptualisation de la                participation qui clarifiera notre compréhension de la participation. Précisément,                nous maintenons que la conceptualisation de la participation est composée de deux                facettes, le processus interne et le processus externe, qui indiquent si un client                participera à la thérapie. Le but du deuxième manuscrit, intitulé Factor Analysis and                Construct Validity of a Measure of Client Involvement, est d'évaluer un modèle des                facteurs de la participation des clients basé sur les données empiriques. La mesure                de la participation des clients est l'Echelle exhaustive des concepts des séances de                psychothérapie, sous-échelle Participation des Clients (Comprehensive Scale of                Psychotherapy Session Constructs – Client Involvement subscale [CSPSC-CI; Eugster                &amp; Wampold, 1996]), qui n'a jamais été évaluée de façon indépendente. Nous                avons examiné les propriétés psychométriques de cette mesure. L'analyse des facteurs                de la sous-échelle CSPSC-CI a révélé trois facteurs distincts: un facteur de Client,                un facteur de Thérapeute Actif, et un facteur de Thérapeute Inattentif. Nous avons                également évalué la validité de concept de la mesure, et les résultats de l'étude                fournissent un appui préliminaire de la validité de concept de la sous-échelle.</description><creator>Morris, Eric</creator><contributor>Marilyn R Fitzpatrick (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>Client involvement in psychotherapy: a literature review and evaluation of an involvement measure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4627265.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zs553</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956h74p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La chenille de Spodoptera exigua est capable de nourrir                sur les plantes malgré ses défenses anti-herbivores, grâce à des enzymes salivaires.                Un de ces enzymes salivaires capable de combattre les defenses, glucose oxidase                (GOX), est aussi régulé par la diète avec laquelle la chenille se nourrit. Il est                donc important d'identifier la réglementation des produits salivaires comme GOX. Ce                projet vise à déterminer les tendances de transcription et d'activité enzymatique de                trois gènes salivaires (Se1H, Se2J et SeGox) en réponse de différentes diètes. De                plus, les régions en amont des gènes salivaires ont tentées être séquencer afin de                trouver des promoteurs putatives. Les résultats ont démontré que les trois gènes ne                sont pas régulées transcriptionellement, mais que l'activité enzymatique de GOX                dépend de la qualité nutritive des diètes. Cependant, les régions en amont des trois                gènes n'ont pas pu être séquencé à cause de raisons de contaminations et                d'amplification imprécises.</description><description>The beet armyworm, Spodoptera exigua, has evolved numerous mechanisms to                circumvent plant defense responses. One of these mechanisms is believed to involve                the activity of labial salivary glucose oxidase (GOX) which, through the production                of hydrogen peroxide, interferes with plant induced defenses. The activity of GOX is                diet-dependent. The expression of SeGox and another salivary gene, Se1H, are                differentially regulated in response to diet (plant or transfer from plant to                wheat-germ based artificial diet for 4 hours), but not in response to chemically                defined artificial diets varying in protein to digestible carbohydrate ratios.                However, GOX enzyme activity is dependent on the nutrient quality of the chemically                defined artificial diets. This suggests that nutritional quality controls enzyme                activity through post-transcriptional regulation. To simulate natural plant diets,                Medicago truncatula plants were grown under ambient (440 ppm) or elevated (880 ppm)                carbon dioxide conditions to alter their C:N ratio. When caterpillars were fed these                plants, labial salivary GOX activity was undetectable regardless of the plant                treatment. Finally, 5' upstream regions of salivary genes Se1H, Se2J and SeGox were                amplified to determine potential upstream promoter elements, but were unable to be                sequenced due to amplicon contamination.</description><creator>Afshar, Khashayar</creator><contributor>Jacqueline Bede (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - General</subject><title>Diet-dependent regulation of labial salivary genes in the beet armyworm, «Spodoptera exigua»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333423k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h74p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40150</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>