<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:03:03Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3400" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032525r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a Battery Energy Storage Systems simulation and study platform. Its purpose is specifically to perform energy storage system asset sizing with the objective of rate of return maximization. The simulation platform contains the models for the main components, the controller of the Battery Energy Storage Systems as well as a Return on Investment calculation model.Based on the simulation platform, methodologies for finding the optimal asset sizes are proposed to provide peak shaving service for both front-of-meter and behind-the-meter Battery Energy Storage Systems installations. In the front-of-meter case, the Hydro-Quebec Hemmingford substation peak shaving project is studied by applying the methodology, while in the behind-the-meter case, the methodology is applied in the study of two industrial customers.</description><description>Cette  thèse présente premièrement une plateforme de simulation et analyse des systèmes de stockage de l'énergie électrique par batteries. Celle-ci a pour but de bien dimensionner de tels systèmes afin d'obtenir le meilleur retour sur investissement pour la durée de vie complète de l'équipement. Cette plateforme contient des modèles des composants principaux qui se trouvent dans un système de stockage de l'énergie électrique par batteries, et aussi un modèle de calcul de retour sur investissement.Ensuite, en s'appuyant sur la plateforme, des méthodologies sont suggérées pour trouver les meilleurs dimensionnements dans les planifications des systèmes de stockage de l'énergie électrique aux batteries pour la réduction des pointes installés soit en amont ou en aval des compteurs. Dans le cas de systèmes installés en amont du compteur, la méthodologie est appliquée pour l'étude du cas du poste Hemmingford d'Hydro-Québec. Tandis que dans le cas de systèmes installés en aval de compteur, deux cas sont étudiés pour deux clients industriels en appliquant la méthodologie.</description><creator>Shi, Ruigao</creator><contributor>François Bouffard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>A simulation platform and methodology for optimal sizing of battery energy storage systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k7376.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032525r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n5564</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Critical processes, including seed bank persistence, seedling establishment, and interspecific interference govern agricultural annual weed population dynamics. Agronomic practices alter weed populations and limit the weed pressure via those key processes. Among them, biofumigation is an innovative technique to control soilborne pests and weeds. Biofumigation is a mass release of volatile chemicals following Brassicaceae tissue disruption when myrosinase enzymes hydrolyze glucosinolates (GSLs). The most common volatile produced following this reaction are isothiocyanates (ITCs). The project focused on assessment of weed species susceptibility, surviving weed responses, and key population dynamic process changes in response to allelochemicals generated during biofumigation. First, a laboratory experiment examined relationships amongst seed dormancy, seed morphology, and weed seed susceptibility to biofumigation. A novel Petri dish biofumigation methodology exposed seeds of eight different weed species to allelochemicals released by increasing rates of Indian mustard (Brassica juncea L.) biomass. The first experiment demonstrated that the dormancy state was an important factor related to seed germination, seed mortality and changes in seed dormancy. Weed species expressed specific dose responses, estimated ED50, LD50, and maximal mortality. Among species in the experiment, hairy galinsoga (Galinsoga quadriradiata Cav.) and wild carrot (Daucus carota L.) were the most affected by biofumigation, where maximal mortality reached 97 and 95%, ED50 values for germination were 2.30 and 3.23 mg cm-2, and LD50 were 3.99 and 4.44 mg cm-2 of mustard tissue, respectively. Second, laboratory and greenhouse experiments assessed the impact of biofumigation on common ragweed (Ambrosia artemisiifolia L.) and velvetleaf (Abutilon theophrasti Medik.) fitness components of surviving plants. Potential alterations of fitness components of the second and third generations were also examined. The second project research outlined that biofumigation modifies weed fitness components by reducing seed germination and survival, promoting seedling mortality, deferring emergence and flowering, and in some cases, decreasing number of seeds produced. However, following generations of surviving weeds may improve their tolerance to biofumigation by an increased number of dormant seeds, greater survival of seedlings, possible increased seed production, and increased relative weight of the embryo, and testa thickness. Finally, a three-year field experiment assessed seasonal variation and impact of biofumigation on weed community and population dynamics. Indian mustard cover crops sown in the spring and fall, once or twice a year were compared to an oat (Avena sativa L.) cover crop and weedy check plots. At full flowering of mustard, all cover crops were finely chopped and incorporated into the soil. Weed emergence, establishment and weed community data were recorded during the cover crop growth and after biomass incorporation. Indian mustard cover crop impacts on weeds were associated to biofumigant potential. As the amount of ITC detected increased in 2015 and 2016, Indian mustard reduced weed establishment within the cover crop growth, and post incorporation weed spring emergence. Allelopathic interference of Indian mustard increased above the corresponding GSL level in tissues generating more than 600 µg of allyl-ITC g-1. Biofumigation technique realized in good conditions may lead in lower weed species richness and diversity and contribute to altering community structure, according to biofumigant potential of mustard, weed community and sites. This project exposes the potential of biofumigation for weed control, allows a better recognition of allelopathy as a defining factor of population dynamics Overall, the project provides a comprehensive understanding of mechanisms of weed population and community responses to Indian mustard biofumigation. </description><description>La biofumigation est une technique novatrice permettant de lutter contre les pathogènes du sol, les nématodes et les mauvaises herbes. La biofumigation est une diffusion dans le sol de molécules toxiques durant la décomposition des tissus végétaux de la famille des Brassicacées, notamment les isothiocyanates (ITCs) produits lorsque les glucosinolates (GSLs) sont hydrolysés par l'enzyme myrosinase. Le projet vise à approfondir les connaissances sur la sensibilité des mauvaises herbes à la biofumigation, sur les réponses des individus survivant à ce procédé et sur les changements des processus clés de la dynamique des populations suite à une exposition aux composés allélopathiques générés durant la biofumigation. Une première expérience en laboratoire a été réalisée pour évaluer les relations entre la dormance, la morphologie et la sensibilité des graines de mauvaises herbes à la biofumigation. Une nouvelle méthode de biofumigation en vase de Pétri a été développée et a permis d'exposer les graines de huit espèces de mauvaises herbes aux composées allélochimiques libérés lors de l'utilisation de taux croissants de biomasse de moutarde brune (Brassica juncea L.). Cette première expérience a souligné l'importance de la dormance des graines pour expliquer la germination, la mortalité et les changements dans l'état de dormance. Les différentes espèces à l'étude ont montré une réponse spécifique à des taux croissants de biofumigation. Parmi ces espèces, le galinsoga cilié (Galinsoga quadriradiata Cav.) et la carotte sauvage (Daucus carota L.) étaient les plus affectés par la biofumigation, où les valeurs de LD50 étaient de 3,99 et 4,44 mg cm-2 de moutarde sèche broyée, respectivement. Une deuxième expérience, menée en laboratoire et en serre, a permis évaluer l'impact de la biofumigation sur les composantes de la valeur adaptative de la petite herbe à poux (Ambrosia artemisiifolia L.) et l'abutilon (Abutilon theophrasti Medik.). Cette étude a permis d'établir que le biofumigation modifie la valeur adaptative des mauvaises herbes principalement en réduisant la germination et la survie des graines et en provoquant une mortalité accrue des plantules en émergence. Les générations subséquentes de mauvaises herbes exposées de nouveau à la biofumigation pourraient avoir une tolérance accrue avec un plus grand nombre de graines dormantes et un taux de survie de plantules plus élevé. Finalement, une expérience en champ de trois ans a permis d'évaluer l'impact de la variation saisonnière et l'effet de la biofumigation sur la dynamique des populations et des communautés de mauvaises herbes. Une culture de couverture de moutarde brune semée au printemps et/ou à l'automne a été comparée à une culture de couverture d'avoine (Avena sativa L.) et à un témoin enherbé. La levée des mauvaises herbes, l'établissement des plantules et les communautés de mauvaises herbes ont été évalués pendant la croissance des cultures de couverture et suite à leur incorporation au sol. Comme les quantités d'ITCs détectées étaient plus élevées en 2015 et 2016, la moutarde brune a permis de réduire l'établissement des mauvaises herbes et la levée printanière suite à son incorporation. La composante allélopathique de l'interférence de la moutarde brune était importante lorsque les plants contenaient plus de 600 µg d'allyl-ITC g-1 de plante. La biofumigation réalisée dans des conditions adéquates peut mener à une richesse spécifique et une biodiversité des mauvaises herbes plus faible et ainsi contribuer à changer la structure des communautés de mauvaises herbes. Globalement, les observations réalisées dans ce projet nous permettent de croire qu'une utilisation efficace et raisonnée de la biofumigation peut dans certaines conditions réduire la pression des mauvaises herbes. De façon générale, le projet a permis de comprendre les mécanismes qui influencent la réponse des populations et des communautés de mauvaises herbes à la biofumigation.</description><creator>Lefebvre, Maxime</creator><contributor>Alan K Watson (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Maryse Leblanc (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Plant Science</subject><title>Impact of «Brassica juncae L.» biofumigation on annual weed ecology and population dynamic in organic soil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv39b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n5564</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806219k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Software projects capture information in artifacts that include production code, test suites, and documentation. Because different artifacts serve different purposes, the information they encode can be redundant. We present an approach to mitigate this redundancy by allowing developers to encode in unit tests information that is used to automatically generate documentation fragments. The result is a set of documentation fragments injected in the reference documentation of the methods under test. We implemented this approach in the form of an Eclipse plug-in. The ability to regenerate the documentation fragments allows documentation to be automatically updated when unit tests are modified. This approach is part of the larger idea of embedding information in source code through the use of meaningful constructs, a concept we termed constructural documentation. We report on a multi-case study that provides insights on the pertinence of constructural information in real world systems. This study highlighted several practices that favor or prevent embedding constructural information in tests, such as the use of standardized local variable names to encode recurring concerns of a test, thus acting as anchors for constructural documentation. Combined with the detailed description of a working tool, the study shows constructural documentation to be a promising way to increase automation in software documentation practices.</description><description>L'exercice de programmation nécessite de la part des développeurs d'encoder beaucoup d'information. Cependant, il est commun dans des projets de développement de logiciel de recoder cette information dans un format différent pour documenter le code, dans l'intérêt des lecteurs humains. De plus, d'autres artéfacts de code, comme les tests unitaires, requièrent que les développeur encode à nouveau la même information dans un format différent.Dans cette thèse, nous présentons une approche exploitant ce parallèle entre l'information encodée dans les tests unitaires et la documentation, dans le but de générer automatiquement la documentation. Cette approche génère des fragments de documentation, insérés directement dans le code de production, dans les commentaires d'en-tête de chaque méthode testée. La possibilité de régénérer facilement ces fragments de documentation lorsque les tests unitaires sont modifiés permet à la documentation d'être constamment mise à jour. Cette approche fait partie de l'idée plus générale d'intégrer de l'information dans du code source grâce à des structures sémantiques. Nous appelons ce concept « information constructurale ».Nous présentons une étude de cas ayant pour but d'évaluer la pertinence de l'information constructurale dans des systèmes logiciels réels. Cette étude a permis de mettre en valeur certaines pratiques favorisant or entravant l'incorporation d'information constructurale dans les tests unitaires, comme l'utilisation de noms de variable génériques, plutôt que spécifiques au contexte du test, permettant ainsi d'encoder de façon constante les éléments récurrents des tests unitaires, favorisant donc l'information constructurale.</description><creator>Nassif, Mathieu</creator><contributor>Martin Robillard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Embedding constructural documentation in unit tests</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t820.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806219k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng98f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA has gained great attention both as a biological molecule and structural building block due to its well-defined structure, molecular recognition properties and programmability. The marriage of DNA with synthetic polymers, creating DNA-polymer hybrids, has allowed the realization of novel materials with added functionalities, that could not be achieved otherwise. To date, different synthetic routes have been proposed for the generation of DNA block copolymers. However, the generation of monodisperse DNA-polymer conjugates with control over the sequence of monomer and length of strand has been a challenge. These limitations have impacted the potential applications of DNA-polymer conjugates, where structural polydispersity has limited their use in drug delivery and materials science. Recently, a new class of monodisperse sequence-defined DNA-polymers has been reported. This thesis examines this new class of DNA-polymer hybrids in the context of drug delivery and supramolecular assembly. Using this DNA-polymer platform, different strategies that address key challenges of self-assembled materials in drug delivery are investigated. Firstly, the examination of DNA nanoparticles as a structurally monodisperse drug delivery platform is described. Detailed investigation of the stability of structures, cellular uptake, and in vitro activity demonstrates the high efficacy of drug-loaded structures. Additionally, in vivo studies of this system show full-body biodistribution, long circulation times and tumor accumulation in mouse models. The great potential of these DNA-polymer vehicles as a general platform for chemotherapeutic drug delivery is highlighted. Secondly, different approaches to tackle limitations of nanocarrier-based delivery systems are investigated. Through a range of optimization studies to our first-generation DNA nanoparticle system, we show progress towards creating a highly functional "smart" delivery platform for biomedical applications. Thirdly, an application of sequence-defined DNA polymers in supramolecular assembly in described. A discovery is reported where the site-specific introduction of a single cyanine dye into DNA-polymer conjugates causes a complete morphological shift from spheres to 1D nanofibers with controlled length and dimensionality. DNA fibers are formed through a seeded growth mechanism and can also be used as bioanalytical tools due to changes in their optical properties upon assembly. These structures also form complex hierarchical hybrid structures when combined with other nanomaterials. Overall, this thesis provides a critical evaluation of the exciting applications of this new class of DNA-polymers, highlighting approaches to tackle the challenges of nanomaterials at the interface of biomedicine and materials science. </description><description>L'ADN éveille la curiosité des scientifiques au-delà de ses propriétés biologiques : des groupes de recherches utilisent la molécule d'ADN comme un matériau de construction moléculaire.  En effet, l'information contenue dans sa structure lui confère des propriétés de reconnaissance moléculaire et une très grande programmabilité. L'ajout de polymères synthétiques sur des brins d'ADN a permis la création de nouveaux matériaux et de structures auto-assemblées aux propriétés uniques. Jusqu'à aujourd'hui, différentes voies ont été développées pour la synthèses de ces matériaux hybrides. Cependant, il reste encore difficile de contrôler précisément, lors de la synthèse, la séquence et la longueur du copolymère. La polydispersité du produit obtenu a ainsi limité l'utilisation de ces conjugués en chimie des matériaux ou pour des applications thérapeutiques. Récemment, nous avons développé une méthode de synthèse de polymères hybrides qui permet de contrôler précisément la séquence à l'échelle moléculaire. Ces polymères forment des structures monodisperses. Dans cette thèse, nous proposons d'examiner les propriétés d'auto-assemblage de ces matériaux hybrides à la séquence connue et définie, ainsi que leur utilisation comme système d'administration de médicaments. Dans le premier chapitre, nous présentons une méthode pour encapsuler un agent anti-cancéreux dans des structures micellaires. Nous avons étudié la stabilité de ces nanoparticules en milieu biologique ainsi que leur internalisation dans les cellules. Les résultats in vitro ont montré que les particules pouvaient détruire les cellules cancéreuses en libérant le principe actif. Enfin, des expériences sur des modèles de souris ont révélées que la particule circulait à travers tout le corps, possédait une grande stabilité et s'accumulait dans les tissus cancéreux. Dans une deuxième partie, nous avons cherché à améliorer les propriétés du système d'encapsulation développé précédemment, afin de créer une particule intelligente. Les expériences ont révélé le potentiel de ces véhicules de seconde-génération dans l'administration de médicaments. Enfin, nous avons étudié les propriétés d'assemblage de polymères à séquence contrôlée. Nous avons introduit une molécule de cyanine dans le conjugué ADN-polymère causant un changement de morphologie. L'insertion de la molécule dans la séquence conduit à la formation de nanofibres, au lieu de sphères, dont on peut contrôler la longueur et la dimension. Une étude mécanistique a révélé que ces fibres d'ADN se formaient à partir d'un noyau moléculaire (mécanisme par nucléation). Lors de l'assemblage, les propriétés optiques de la structure changent, ce qui rend ces matériaux intéressants pour des applications bio-analytiques. Finalement, nous avons utilisé ces structures en combinaison avec d'autres nanomatériaux afin de créer des structures hybrides d'une très grande complexité. En conclusion, cette thèse propose d'étudier différentes applications des conjugués ADN-polymères, en apportant de nouvelles solutions aux défis actuels dans le développement de nanomatériaux utilisés en biomédecine et en chimie des matériaux. </description><creator>Bousmail, Danny</creator><contributor>Hanadi Sleiman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Sequence-defined DNA polymers: Applications in drug delivery and supramolecular assembly</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc665.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng98f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f360c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hepatitis C virus (HCV) recruits two molecules of the liver-specific microRNA-122 (miR-122) to two adjacent sites (S1 and S2) located at the 5′ end of the viral RNA genome. This interaction promotes viral RNA accumulation, but the precise mechanism(s) remain incompletely understood. Previous studies suggest that miR-122 is able to protect the HCV genome from 5′ exonucleases (Xrn1/2), but this protection is not sufficient to account for the effect of miR-122 on HCV RNA accumulation. Results also suggest that sequences in the 3′ tail of miR-122 may mediate important interactions that are involved in HCV RNA accumulation, but are not required for canonical miRNA activities. In addition to S1 and S2, the HCV genome contains several other putative miR-122 binding sites, one in the internal ribosomal entry site (IRES), three in the NS5B coding region, and one in the 3′ untranslated region (UTR). Herein, we: i) investigated a protective role for miR-122 against recognition of the HCV genome by innate sensors of RNA or cellular pyrophosphatases; ii) determined whether additional miR-122 binding sites within the HCV genome play a role in the viral life cycle; and iii) developed tools to identify host and/or viral proteins involved in miR-122-mediated viral RNA accumulation during HCV infection. First, we investigated whether miR-122 could prevent recognition of the viral 5′ triphosphate from cellular sensors of RNA, including PKR, the RIG-I-like receptors RIG-I, MDA5 and LGP2, and IFITs 1 and 5. Using luciferase reporter HCV RNAs, we found that although PKR and IFIT1 were able to limit HCV RNA accumulation, their recognition was not modified in the presence or absence of miR-122. Therefore, miR-122 does not play a protective role against recognition by the innate sensors PKR, RIG-I-like receptors, or IFITs 1 and 5. In contrast, we found that knockdown of two cellular pyrophosphatases, DOM3Z and DUSP11, was able to increase viral RNA accumulation of a full-length HCV RNA in the absence of miR-122. However, although pyrophosphatase knockdown stabilized the viral RNA, it could not restore HCV replication in the absence of miR-122, suggesting that miR-122 likely plays an additional role(s) in the HCV life cycle, beyond 5′ end protection. In addition, investigation of additional putative miR-122 binding sites in the HCV genome revealed that mutations predicted to alter miR-122 binding at the IRES and NS5B sites lead to reductions in HCV core protein expression and viral RNA accumulation; with a concomitant decrease in viral particle production for the NS5B.2 mutant. However, supplementation of miR- 122 molecules with compensatory mutations did not rescue these site mutants to wild-type levels, suggesting that mutation of these sequences likely disrupts an additional interaction important to the HCV life cycle, beyond direct interactions with miR-122.Previous studies suggested that the 3′ terminal nucleotides of miR-122 are important for maintaining HCV RNA abundance, while being dispensable for canonical miRNA activities. Therefore, we hypothesized that miR-122 molecule binding to the 5′ end of the HCV genome are part of a non-canonical miRNA complex. We developed an approach based on the λN-BoxB affinity system followed by proximity-dependent biotinylation (BioID) to identify host and/or viral proteins in miR-122:HCV complexes located at the 5′ end of the HCV genome. Overall, our results support a model in which binding of miR-122 to S1 and S2 stabilizes the HCV genome by shielding its 5′ terminus from cellular pyrophosphatase activity and subsequent turnover by exonucleases. We also demonstrated that S1 and S2 play a predominant role in viral RNA accumulation, while the additional putative miR-122 binding sites in the IRES, NS5B and 3′ UTR regions have negligible contributions to viral protein expression, viral RNA accumulation, and infectious particle production. Thus, we further elucidated the role of miR-122 in HCV infection.</description><description>Le virus de l'hépatite C (VHC) recrute deux molécules du microARN-122 (miR-122) spécifique au foie à deux sites adjacents (S1 et S2) situés à l'extrémité 5′ du génome ARN viral. Cette interaction favorise l'accumulation d'ARN viral, mais le ou les mécanisme(s) précis restent incomplètement compris. Des études antérieures suggèrent que le miR-122 est capable de protéger le génome du VHC des exonucléases 5′ Xrn1 et Xrn2, mais cette protection n'est pas suffisante pour expliquer entièrement l'effet du miR-122. Les résultats suggèrent également que les séquences de l'extrémité 3′ du miR-122 peuvent médier des interactions importantes impliquées dans l'accumulation de l'ARN du VHC. En plus des S1 et S2, le génome du VHC contient plusieurs autres sites potentiels de liaison au miR-122; un dans le site d'entrée interne des ribosomes (IRES), trois dans la région codante NS5B et un dans la région 3′ non codante (UTR). Ici, nous avons: i) étudié le rôle protecteur du miR-122 contre la reconnaissance du génome du VHC par des récepteurs de l'immunité innée ou par des pyrophosphatases cellulaires; ii) déterminé si d'autres sites de liaison au miR-122 dans le génome du VHC jouent un rôle dans le cycle de vie viral; et iii) développé des outils pour identifier les protéines hôtes et/ou virales impliquées dans l'accumulation d'ARN viral médiée par le miR-122 au cours de l'infection par le VHC.Premièrement, nous avons cherché à savoir si le miR-122 pourrait empêcher la reconnaissance du triphosphate 5′ viral par les récepteurs de l'immunité innée PKR, les récepteurs de type RIG-I (RIG-I, MDA5, LGP2) et IFITs 1 et 5. En utilisant un ARN du VHC contenant le gène rapporteur de la luciférase, nous avons démontré que miR-122 ne joue pas de rôle protecteur contre la reconnaissance du génome viral par ces récepteurs. Par contre, nous avons constaté que l'inhibition de deux pyrophosphatases cellulaires, DOM3Z et DUSP11, permet d'augmenter l'accumulation d'ARN viral en l'absence du miR-122. De plus, l'étude des sites potentiels de liaison au miR-122 dans le génome du VHC a révélé que des mutations devant altérer la liaison du miR-122 aux sites situés dans l'IRES et la région NS5B entraînaient une réduction de l'expression des protéines du VHC et de l'accumulation d'ARN viral; avec une diminution concomitante de la production de particules virales pour le mutant NS5B.2. Cependant, la supplémentation des cellules avec des molécules du miR-122 contenant des mutations compensatoires n'a pas permis à ces mutants de récapituler le phénotype du virus de type sauvage, suggérant que la mutation de ces séquences perturbe probablement une interaction supplémentaire importante pour le cycle de vie du VHC, au-delà des interactions directes avec le miR-122. Finalement, nous avons émis l'hypothèse que le miR-122 se liant à l'extrémité 5′ du génome du VHC fait partie d'un complexe microARN non canonique. Nous avons développé une approche basée sur le système d'affinité λN-BoxB suivie d'une biotinylation dépendante de la proximité (BioID) afin d'identifier les protéines hôtes et/ou virales présentes dans les complexes miR-122:VHC situés à l'extrémité 5′ du génome du viral. Dans l'ensemble, nos résultats supportent un modèle dans lequel la liaison du miR-122 aux S1 et S2 stabilise le génome du VHC en protégeant son extrémité 5′ terminale de l'activité de deux pyrophosphatases cellulaires et de la dégradation subséquente médiée par les exonucléases Xrn1 et Xrn2. Nous avons également démontré que les S1 et S2 jouent un rôle prépondérant dans l'accumulation de l'ARN viral, tandis que les sites potentiels de liaison supplémentaires ont une contribution négligeable dans le cycle de vie du virus. Ainsi, nous avons élucidé davantage le rôle du miR-122 dans l'infection par le VHC.</description><creator>Bernier, Annie</creator><contributor>Selena Sagan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Microbiology &amp; Immunology</subject><title>MiR-122 interactions at the 5' terminus of the hepatitis C virus genome prevent recognition of the viral RNA by cellular pyrophosphatases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx64h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f360c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x95t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Osteoporosis is a common, aging-related disease diagnosed primarily by measuring bone mineral density (BMD). We performed two genome-wide association studies (GWAS) to identify human genetic determinants of BMD estimated from the heel calcaneus (eBMD), leveraging the UK Biobank's interim release (142,487 individuals) and full release (426,824 individuals). We identified a total of 518 (454 novel) genome-wide significant loci, an approximate 7x increase of what was previously known. We also explained up to 20% of its trait variance, with the previous most recent estimate at approximately 6%. We then identified target genes for all loci using a combination of statistical fine-mapping and functional genomics data for SNP annotation. Skeletal phenotyping in mice of novel top candidate genes GPC6, DAAM2, CBX1, DSCC1, RGCC, WAC, and YWHAE confirmed their role in bone biology. We performed further validation of DAAM2 through CRISPR/Cas9 mediated knockouts in a human bone cell line, SaOS-2, and observed a mineralization phenotype for this crucial bone forming cell. Following our GWAS, we performed an epigenome-wide association study (EWAS) to identify human epigenetic determinants of BMD measured at the femoral neck and lumbar spine. We used site-specific CpG DNA methylation assessed in whole blood with the Illumina Infinium HumanMethylation450 array. We studied 4,614 individuals for our discovery analysis but failed to identify any consistently associated findings upon meta-analysis with a validation cohort of 901 individuals. We therefore present the findings in this thesis as novel contributions to the genetic determinants of osteoporosis, and a cautionary tale for the study of the epigenetic determinants of osteoporosis.</description><description>L'ostéoporose est une maladie courante ayant un lien étroit avec le vieillissement. Cette maladie est principalement diagnostiquée en mesurant la densité de la masse osseuse (BMD). Nous avons effectué deux études d'association pan-génomique (GWAS) afin d'identifier les déterminants génétiques humains de la BMD estimés à partir du talon calcanéum (eBMD). En tirant en premier lieu de la libération provisoire de la cohorte de l'UK Biobank (142,487 individus) et, subséquemment, de sa libération complète (426,824 individus). Nous avons identifié un total de 518 locus (incluant 454 nouveaux) étant statistiquement significatifs locus significatifs à l'échelle du génome. Représentant ainsi une augmentation d'environ 7 fois le total de locus précédemment connus. Suite à ces résultats, nous pouvons maintenant expliqué jusqu'à 20% de la variance phenotypique de la BMD comparé à l'estimer d'environ 6% établi précédemment. Nous avons ensuite identifié des gènes cibles pour tous les loci à l'aide d'une combinaison de données statistiques de fine-mapping et de génomique fonctionnelle pour l'annotation de SNPs. Une analyse du phénotypes squelettiques liées aux nouveaux gènes candidats GPC6, DAAM2, CBX1, DSCC1, RGCC, WAC et YWHAE chez les souris, nous a permis de confirmer leurs rôles dans la biologie osseuse. Nous avons effectué une validation supplémentaire pour DAAM2 à travers des knockouts médiés par CRISPR/Cas9 dans une lignée de cellules osseuses humaines (SaOS-2) et, avons observé un phénotype de minéralisation pour cette cellule de formation osseuse cruciale. À la suite de notre GWAS, nous avons réalisé une étude d'association pan-épigénomique (EWAS) pour identifier les déterminants épigénétiques humaines de la BMD mesurés au niveau du cou fémoral et de la colonne lombaire. Nous nous sommes concentrés sur la méthylation de l'ADN dans la sang aux sites CpG compris sur la matrice d'Illumina Infinium HumanMethylation450. Nous avons interrogé 4,614 individus dans une cohorte initiale suivi par une méta-analyse avec une cohorte de validation de 901 individus et avons constaté aucun résultats systématiquement associés au phénotype de la BMD. Nous présentons donc les conclusions de cette thèse en tant que nouvelles contributions aux déterminants génétiques de l'ostéoporose, et un conte de prudence pour l'étude des déterminants épigénétiques liés l'ostéoporose.</description><creator>Morris, John</creator><contributor>John Brent Richards (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>The genetic and epigenetic determinants of osteoporosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c4957.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x95t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b563j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DICER1 is an endoribonuclease central to the generation of microRNAs (miRNAs), small RNA molecules that are predicted to silence the expression of ~30% of protein-coding genes.  DICER1 utilizes its RNase IIIa and IIIb endonuclease domains to cleave pre-miRNA stemloops to release the mature single-strand miRNA, coded within either the 5' (5p) or 3' (3p) arms. DICER1 mutations have been identified in patients with pleiotropic tumour predisposition syndrome (DICER1 syndrome).  Most DICER1 syndrome lesions/tumours have one loss of function (LOF) DICER1 mutation and an in trans RNase IIIb "5p miRNA altering" DICER1 mutation.  DICER1 syndrome usually manifests in childhood and includes multinodular goiter, pleuropulmonary blastoma, and cystic nephroma.  While biallelic DICER1 mutations (LOF + "5p miRNA altering") are observed in the tumours/lesions of DICER1 syndrome, still other rare tumours could be DICER1-associated, and it remains a mystery how these paired DICER1 mutations initiate tumourigenesis.  It is hypothesized that DICER1 syndrome and DICER1-associated tumours/lesions originate from a multipotent cell whose miRNome/transcriptome is altered due the presence of only an RNase IIIb-mutated DICER1 that has acquired other genetic mutations.  An in vitro cleavage assay was developed to assess the ability of 38 different disease-relevant DICER1 variants to cleave a pre-miRNA.  The very rare anaplastic sarcoma of the kidney was often shown to have LOF + "5p miRNA altering" DICER1 mutations and are therefore DICER1-associated.  Mouse mesenchymal stromal/stem cells (MSCs) lacking Dicer1 and rescued with various human variants of DICER1 were generated to model the cell of origin of DICER1 syndrome.  Analysis of these cell lines identified potential early disease biomarkers, candidates for therapeutic intervention, and genes potentially involved in tumour priming. Introduction of ErbB2 and subsequent evaluation of transformation potential suggests that relative over-abundance of 3p miRNAs may be key to transformation.  In vivo experiments suggest that MSCs may have chemo attractive potential.  The data for this thesis support the hypothesis that DICER1 syndrome/DICER1-associated entities have LOF + "5p miRNA altering" mutations. In addition, many tools for the DICER1 syndrome research field have been generated including the in vitro cleavage assay and multiple cell isogenic cell lines with different DICER1 variants.  </description><description>DICER1 est une endoribonucléase essentielle pour la génération de microARNs (miARNs), de petites molécules d'ARN qui devraient réduire l'expression de ~30% des gènes codant pour des protéines. DICER1 utilise ses domaines d'endonucléase ARNase IIIa et IIIb pour couper les tiges-boucles de pré-miARNs pour relâcher le miARN simple brin mature, codé soit par la branche 5' (5p) ou 3' (3p). Des mutations DICER1 ont été identifiées chez les patients avec le syndrome de prédisposition tumorale pléiotropique (syndrome DICER1).  La plupart des lésions/tumeurs du syndrome DICER1 ont une mutation DICER1 occasionnant une perte de fonction (LOF) et une mutation « 5p miRNA altering » en trans de l'ARNase IIIb  de DICER1.  Le syndrome DICER1 se manifeste habituellement pendant l'enfance et inclus le goitre multinodulaire, le blastome pleuropulmonaire et le néphrome kystique.  Tandis que des mutations bi-alléliques de DICER1 (LOF + "5p miRNA altering") sont observées dans les tumeurs/lésions du syndrome DICER1, d'autres tumeurs rares peuvent aussi être associées à DICER1; le mystère demeure quant à savoir comment ces mutations appariées de DICER1 initient la tumorigénèse.  Une hypothèse avancée est que le syndrome DICER1 et les tumeurs/lésions associées à DICER1 proviennent d'une cellule multipotente dans laquelle le miRNome/transcriptome est altéré dû à la seule présence l'ARNase IIIb muté de DICER1 et à l'acquisition d'autres mutations génétiques. Un test de clivage in vitro a été développé pour évaluer l'habilité de 38 différents variants de DICER1 pertinents à la maladie à cliver un pré-miARN.  Il a souvent été montré que le très rare sarcome anaplasique du rein présentait des mutations  DICER1 LOF + "5p miRNA altering", était donc associées à DICER1.  Les cellules stromales / souches mésenchymateuses de souris dépourvues de  Dicer (-/-) et secourues avec divers variants humains de DICER1 ont été générées pour modéliser les cellules à l'origine du syndrome DICER1.  L'analyse de ces lignées cellulaires a identifié des biomarqueurs potentiels de la maladie au stade précoce, candidats pour des interventions thérapeutiques et des gènes potentiellement impliqués dans l'initiation de la tumorigénèse. L'introduction d'ErbB2 et l'évaluation subséquente du potentiel de transformation suggèrent que la surabondance relative de miARNs 3p peut être la clé de la transformation.  Les expériences in vivo suggèrent que les cellules souches mésenchymateuses peuvent avoir un potentiel chimio-attractif.  Les résultats présentés dans cette thèse appuient l'hypothèse que le syndrome DICER1/ les entités associées à DICER1 ont des mutations LOF + "5p miRNA altering". De plus, pour la recherche sur le syndrome de DICER1, plusieurs outils ont été générés incluant le test de clivage in vitro et  les lignées cellulaires isogéniques à cellules multiples avec différents variants de DICER1.</description><creator>Wu, Mona</creator><contributor>William Foulkes (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Marc Fabian (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>DICER1 syndrome: assays, associations and models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw85f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b563j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p73m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During nervous system development, gradients of molecular cues guide axons to their targets. In the developing spinal cord, Sonic hedgehog (Shh) has dual function as a morphogen and as an axon guidance cue. However, signaling of the Shh-mediated axon guidance is poorly understood. In this thesis, we aim to understand the molecular mechanism in how Shh navigates axons. Axon guidance cues act by changing the cytoskeleton of the growth cone, which is the motile structure at the tip of axons. In Chapter 4, we aim to uncover how Shh regulates the cytoskeletal remodelling that underlies growth cone turning, focusing on guanine nucleotide exchange factors (GEFs), which switch on the Rho GTPase cytoskeletal regulators. First, we showed that Dock GEF activity is required for Shh-induced Rac1 activation and axon turning. We further identified Dock3/4, expressed in commissural neurons, as the responsible GEF working downstream of Shh. We further found that ELMO1/2, binding regulators for Dock3/4, are expressed in the commissural neurons and required for the Shh-induced axon attraction. Mechanistically, we demonstrated that the protein complex of Dock3/4 and ELMO1/2 interacts with Boc, the axon guidance receptor for Shh. The Dock/ELMO complex is released from Boc in response to Shh, and relocalizes to the growth cone periphery. We found that polarized Dock activity is sufficient to induce axon turning. Lastly, we demonstrated that either Dock3/4 or Elmo1/2 knockdown leads to misguidance of commissural axons in vivo.In the classical model of the commissural axon guidance in the spinal cord, Netrin1 is a long-range attractive cue. A Netrin1 gradient generated by secretion from the floorplate attracts commissural axons. Recent studies debate whether Netrin in the floorplate is dispensable for commissural axon guidance in the spinal cord. Varadarajan et. al. demonstrated that commissural axons can still cross the midline by genetically deleting netrin1 at the floorplate.  However, the detailed analysis with commissural axon marker remains to be performed. In Chapter 5, we aim to answer this question firstly by investigating axon guidance defect in the embryo in which netrin1 is deleted at the floorplate. While most commissural axons reached the floorplate in those embryos, we found an abnormal morphology in the commissural axonal tract and axon invasion into motor column. We further demonstrated that the axonal invasion was enhanced with Boc-/- background which has Shh signaling defect. These results indicate that Netrin1 in the floorplate is important for commissural axon guidance and that Shh collaborates this long-range axon guidance. </description><description>Au cours du développement du système nerveux, les prolongements des neurones (ou axones) sont guidés vers leur cible par des gradients de signaux moléculaires. Lors du développement de la moelle épinière, la protéine Sonic Hedgehog (Shh) a une double fonction : elle agit en tant que morphogène et en tant que signal de guidage axonal. Cependant, la signalisation du guidage axonal médié par Shh reste mal comprise. Dans cette thèse, nous visons à comprendre le mécanisme moléculaire responsable du rôle de Shh en tant que qu'agent chimioattractif dans le tube neural.Les molécules de guidage axonal agissent en modifiant le cytosquelette du cône de croissance, qui est la structure motile à l'extrémité des axones. Dans le chapitre 4, nous cherchons à découvrir comment Shh régule le remodelage du cytosquelette au niveau du cône de croissance, en se concentrant sur les facteurs d'échange des nucléotides guanine (GEF), qui activent les régulateurs du cytosquelette Rho GTPase. Premièrement, nous avons montré que l'activité du GEF Dock est requise pour l'activation de Rac1 induite par Shh et pour l'attraction des axones par un gradient de Shh in vitro. Nous avons également identifié Dock3/4, exprimé dans les neurones commissuraux, comme le GEF essentiel pour la signalisation en aval de Shh. Nous avons également trouvé que ELMO1/2, régulateurs de liaison pour Dock3/4, sont exprimés dans les neurones commissuraux et sont requis pour l'attraction des cônes de croissance induite par Shh. Mécanistiquement, nous avons démontré que le complexe protéique de Dock3/4 et ELMO1/2 interagit avec Boc, un récepteur de guidage axonal pour Shh. Le complexe Dock/ELMO est libéré de Boc en réponse à Shh et se relocalise à la périphérie du cône de croissance. Nous avons trouvé que l'activité polarisée de Dock est suffisante pour induire l'attraction des axones. Enfin, nous avons démontré que la perte de fonction de Dock3/4 ou de Elmo1/2 conduit à des erreurs de guidage des axones commissuraux in vivo.Dans le modèle classique du guidage axonal commissural dans la moelle épinière, la Nétrine 1 est un agent chemoattractif qui agit à longue distance. Un gradient de Nétrine 1 est généré par la sécrétion des cellules de la plaque du plancher et attire les axones commissuraux provenant de la partie dorsale du tube neural. Des études récentes débattent afin de savoir si la Nétrine provenant de la plaque du plancher est dispensable pour le guidage des axones commissuraux dans la moelle épinière. Varadarajan et al. a démontré que les axones commissuraux peuvent encore traverser la ligne médiane en supprimant génétiquement la Nétrine 1 à la plaque du plancher. Cependant, l'analyse détaillée des projections avec des marqueurs spécifiques des axones commissuraux reste à effectuer. Au chapitre 5, nous cherchons d'abord à répondre à cette question en examinant le défaut de guidage axonal chez des embryons dans lequel la Nétrine 1 est éliminée au niveau de la plaque du plancher. Alors que la plupart des axones commissuraux atteignaient la ligne médiane, nous avons observé une morphologie anormale du tractus axonal et une invasion de la colonne motrice par les axones commissuraux. Nous avons en outre démontré que l'invasion axonale était encore plus importante dans un fond génétique Boc-/-, déficient pour la signalisation Shh. Ces résultats indiquent que la Nétrine 1 issue de la plaque du plancher est importante pour le guidage axonal des neurones commissuraux et que Shh collabore à ce guidage axonal à longue portée.</description><creator>Makihara, Shirin</creator><contributor>Frederic Charron (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Sonic hedgehog signaling in axon guidance of spinal commissural neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139426x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p73m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763924m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The overarching objective of this thesis is to develop novel methods for dynamic in vivo carbon-13 (13C) Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy (MRS) for rodent brain imaging. Dynamic 13C MRS is a powerful technique that provides non-invasive means to quantify neurotransmitter cycling rates and cell-specific neuroenergetics in the brain, following the infusion of a 13C labeled substrate. Proton observed carbon edited (POCE) MRS is a popularly used indirect 13C MRS technique, typically implemented with a surface coil transceiver on the proton channel to benefit from surface coil sensitivity gains. POCE MRS implementations for a surface coil transceiver benefit from the use of relatively long and power intensive adiabatic radiofrequency (RF) pulses to minimize nutation angle errors, signal losses, and artifacts due to the spatially varying magnetic field (B1+). The first goal of this work was thus to develop an RF coil platform with homogeneous B1+, in addition to providing receive sensitivity gains of a surface coil. This was achieved by combining a proton volumetric resonator, and detunable surface coil for proton signal reception, in addition to a surface coil on the 13C channel. A point resolved spectroscopy (PRESS) localized POCE MRS sequence with a 12.6-ms echo time (TE) was implemented with short conventional pulses, enabling uniform nutation, two-shot edited POCE MRS, combined with a short TE; a feat that cannot be achieved with all-surface coil based approaches described in the literature.An extension to the above goal was to improve the PRESS-POCE sequence by reducing the sequence TE and minimize T2 and homonuclear J-evolution related losses. To that end, a novel PRESS localized POCE sequence that utilizes simultaneous editing and localization pulses (SEAL-PRESS) allowing the TE to be reduced to a theoretically optimal value of 8.1-ms was implemented. The SEAL-PRESS sequence was validated in phantom and in an in vivo rat preparation. Carbon editing efficiency of the SEAL-PRESS sequence was &gt;95%, and provided a &gt;17% improvement of 13C labeled metabolites relative to the previously described PRESS-POCE sequence. The final goal of this thesis was to investigate the feasibility of sequentially acquiring indirect and direct 13C MRS during a dynamic in vivo 13C MRS session, to harvest the benefits of indirect and direct 13C methods, with the ultimate goal of improving metabolic modeling. Modifications to the RF chain were necessary to extend the developed coil platform to be capable of both direct and indirect 13C MRS. A PRESS-localized semi-adiabatic distortionless enhancement by polarization transfer (DEPT) sequence was designed and evaluated in phantom, and the SEAL-PRESS sequence was used for indirect 13C MRS. Phantom data showed that measurements made with the two sequences were in reasonable agreement. Finally a dynamic in vivo 13C MRS study in rat brain was conducted while sequentially acquiring data with both sequences. Time-resolved indirect 13C spectra were obtained as expected, however due to much poorer sensitivity of direct 13C signal acquisition; no meaningful time-resolved spectra were recorded. Avenues for SNR degradation along the RF chain were investigated, and considerations for the next iteration coil setup are discussed. </description><description>L'objectif global de cette thèse est de développer de nouvelles méthodes dynamiques de spectroscopie par résonance magnétique (SRM) du carbone-13 (13C) pour l'imagerie du cerveau des rongeurs in vivo. La SRM-13C est une technique puissante qui fournit des moyens non-invasifs pour quantifier les taux de cyclage de neurotransmetteurs et de neuroénergétiques spécifiques aux cellules du cerveau, suite à la perfusion d'un substrat marqué au 13C. La SRM par l'observation du proton, édité par le carbone (Proton Observed Carbon Edited - POCE), est une technique de SRM-13C indirecte communément utilisée avec une antenne de surface  émetteur-récepteur pour protons puisque c'est une construction relativement facile, et bénéficie de gains de sensibilité typiques aux antennes de surfaces. Les implémentations SRM-POCE pour une antenne de surface émetteur-récepteur bénéficient d'autant plus d'impulsions de radiofréquences (RF) adiabatiques relativement longues et puissantes pour minimiser les erreurs d'angle de nutation, les pertes de signaux et les artefacts dûs aux variations spatiales du champ magnétique (B1+). Le premier objectif de ce travail était donc de développer une antenne de RF avec un B1+ homogène, en plus de fournir des gains de sensibilité avec l'utilisation d'une antenne de surface. Ceci a été réalisé en combinant un résonateur volumétrique pour des impulsions de transmission de protons, une antenne de surface pour la réception de signaux de protons, en plus d'une antenne de transmission de surface pour le 13C. Une séquence SRM-POCE localisée par spectroscopie résolu ponctuelle (Point Resolved SpectroScopy - PRESS) avec un temps d'écho de 12,6 ms (TE) a été implémentée avec de courtes impulsions conventionnelles permettant une nutation uniforme, une SMR-POCE édité en deux coups, et un TE court; une prouesse qui ne peut être atteinte avec des approches à base d'antennes de surface décrites dans la littérature.Une extension à l'objectif ci-dessus était d'étudier les améliorations apportées à la séquence PRESS-POCE en réduisant le TE et donc minimisant les pertes liées à l'évolution de T2 et des couplages-J homonucléaires. A cette fin, une nouvelle séquence POCE localisée PRESS utilisant des impulsions d'édition et de localisation simultanées (SEAL-PRESS) permettant de réduire le TE à une valeur théoriquement optimale de 8,1 ms a été mise en œuvre. La séquence SEAL-PRESS a été validée avec un fantôme et in vivo chez le rat. L'efficacité d'édition du carbone de la séquence SEAL-PRESS était &gt;95% avec une amélioration de &gt;17% des métabolites marqués au 13C par rapport à la séquence PRESS-POCE précédente. Le but final de cette thèse était d'étudier la faisabilité d'acquisition séquentielle de SRM-13C indirects et directs au cours d'une seule session, in vivo, afin de récolter les bénéfices des méthodes indirectes et directes du 13C dans le but ultime d'améliorer la modélisation métabolique. Des modifications de la chaîne radiofréquence ont été nécessaires pour effectuer une SRM-13C directe. Une séquence localisé PRESS semi-adiabatique d'augmentation par transfert de polarisation sans distortions (DEPT) a été conçue et évaluée avec un fantôme, et la séquence SEAL-PRESS a été utilisée pour le SRM-13C indirect. Les données obtenues avec le fantôme ont démontré que les mesures faites avec ces deux séquences étaient raisonnablement en accord. Finalement, une étude dynamique SRM-13C dans le cerveau de rats in vivo a été menée en acquérant séquentiellement des données avec ces deux dites séquences. Les spectres indirects 13C résolus dans le temps ont été obtenus comme prévu, cependant en raison d'une sensibilité beaucoup plus faible de l'acquisition directe du signal 13C, aucun spectre significatif résolu dans le temps n'a été enregistré. Les avenues pour la dégradation du ratio signal:bruit le long de la chaîne RF ont été étudiées, et des considérations pour une nouvelle itération de l'antenne y sont discutées.</description><creator>Kumaragamage, Chathura</creator><contributor>James Patrick Near (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Richard Hoge (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Biomedical Engineering</subject><title>Development of dynamic «in vivo» carbon-13 magnetic resonance spectroscopy for rat brain imaging at 7-Tesla</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860914m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763924m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t99d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis seeks to study the essays of Serge Bouchard by focusing on two components: metonymy and irony, both constitutive of the genre of essay and which application in Serge Bouchard's texts is notably speaking. This thesis provides an exploration of the relation to cultural objects seen as "lieux communs" in the first three collections of essays (Le moineau domestique, L'homme descend de l'ourse and Les corneilles ne sont pas les épouses des corbeaux). The two elements that inform Serge Bouchard's poetic of the essay, i.e. metonymy and irony, are the objects of the second and third chapters. The two chapters attempt to present how the single objects Serge Bouchard reflects on in his essays are given a new meaning and a general implication. The metonymic and ironic writing supports the idea of an expanded community which underlies Serge Bouchard's essays. Firstly, this thesis demonstrates that the metonymic structure undertakes a transfer from singular to common, from particular to general and from local to universal. Secondly, this thesis explains that Serge Bouchard's irony rests on both the distance from the context of reference and the sense of community it seeks to strengthen. From there, it allows for the values of togetherness and solidarity to be given to each "lieu commun". In conclusion, this thesis reveals the idealistic and utopic vision that determines Serge Bouchard's essayistic writing.</description><description>L'objectif de ce mémoire est d'étudier les essais de Serge Bouchard en privilégiant deux volets : la métonymie et l'ironie, procédés propres au genre de l'essai qui trouvent ici une application riche. À partir d'une lecture attentive des trois premiers recueils, soit Le moineau domestique, L'homme descend de l'ourse et Les corneilles ne sont pas les épouses des corbeaux, ce mémoire examine le rapport à des objets culturels considérés comme des « lieux communs ». Les deux procédés qui caractérisent la poétique de l'essai chez Serge Bouchard, à savoir la métonymie et l'ironie, font l'un et l'autre l'objet d'un chapitre distinct dans ce mémoire. Dans les deux cas, il s'agit de présenter de quelle façon les objets singuliers sur lesquels portent les essais de Serge Bouchard sont chargés d'un sens nouveau et acquièrent une valeur générale. L'écriture métonymique et ironique soutient l'idée de communauté élargie qui se trouve à l'origine de la pensée essayistique de Serge Bouchard. Ce mémoire montre dans un premier temps que la structure métonymique opère un transfert du singulier au commun, du particulier au général, du local à l'universel. Ce mémoire explique dans un deuxième temps que l'écriture ironique se fonde à la fois sur la distance par rapport au contexte de référence et sur le sentiment de communauté qu'elle cherche à renforcer. De là, la valorisation du lieu commun comme facteur de rapprochement et de solidarité. En conclusion, ce mémoire souligne la vision idéaliste et utopique qui sous-tend l'écriture essayistique de Serge Bouchard.</description><creator>Savard-Gratton, Blanche Ophélie</creator><contributor>Michel Biron (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>French Language and Literature</subject><title>L'Universalité du lieu commun: la métonymie et l'ironie dans les essais de Serge Bouchard</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk88n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t99d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pq26c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction : Le rétablissement est un élément central des services de santé mentale. Il s'avère néanmoins que les interventions traditionnellement utilisées à l'égard de personnes judiciarisées et atteintes de problèmes de santé mentale s'inscrivent plutôt dans une approche punitive propre au système de justice criminelle et pénale. Or, l'utilisation d'un cadre axé sur le rétablissement avec ces personnes revêt une grande importance, puisque l'intégration communautaire suite à des périodes répétées de détention, de peines purgées en communauté ou d'hospitalisations est souvent marquée par des difficultés d'intégration sociale, professionnelle et résidentielle. Objectif : Dans ce contexte, la présente thèse explore le concept du rétablissement chez les personnes judiciarisées. La démarche de recherche se décline en quatre volets imbriqués les uns dans les autres. Méthodologie : Pour la première étude, nous avons mené un examen de la portée tandis que les trois études suivantes suivent une approche empirique. Compte tenu des taux élevés de judiciarisation chez les personnes vivant des situations d'itinérance, l'échantillon du projet At Home/Chez Soi a été sélectionné pour effectuer les analyses. Le projet At Home/Chez soi est un projet de recherche et de démonstration pancanadien portant sur l'approche Logement d'abord et financé par la Commission de la Santé Mentale du Canada et Santé Canada. Au total, 2 298 hommes et femmes aux prises avec des troubles de santé mentale et se trouvant en situation d'itinérance ont été recrutés à Montréal, Toronto, Vancouver, Winnipeg, et Moncton. Résultats : La première étude examine les études quantitatives et qualitatives portant sur le rétablissement en santé mentale chez les personnes judiciarisées. Suite à un examen approfondi de la littérature, un cadre théorique axé sur le rétablissement, présenté en six dimensions, a été établi en adaptant le modèle de Whitley et Drake (2010) afin de tenir compte de préoccupations criminogènes. La deuxième étude examine la concordance entre les propos auto-rapportés et les données administratives en fait d'implication judiciaire. Les résultats ont révélé que les personnes en situation d'itinérance qui ont un problème de santé mentale rapportent avec précision leur implication judiciaire. La troisième étude a identifié cinq profils d'implication judiciaire distincts grâce à une analyse de profils latents : non-délinquants ou délinquants de faible intensité, délinquants modérés, délinquants violents/antisociaux, délinquants polyvalents et de subsistance, et délinquants en lien avec les substances. Ces profils illustrent l'hétérogénéité en termes de besoins et de caractéristiques des délinquants ayant des problèmes de santé mentale. Enfin, la quatrième étude a exploré l'influence du profil d'implication judiciaire sur l'efficacité de l'approche Logement d'abord sur les trajectoires de rétablissement, en utilisant le modèle à six dimensions. Le profil d'implication judiciaire semble influencer l'efficacité du Logement d'abord en termes de problèmes d'utilisation de substance, de stabilité résidentielle et de nombre d'arrestations. Conclusions : Ensemble, ces résultats démontrent l'importance d'utiliser un modèle multidimensionnel du rétablissement afin d'évaluer de manière flexible ses différentes facettes individuellement, puisque toutes les initiatives axées sur le rétablissement ne cibleront pas les mêmes dimensions. De plus, il est essentiel d'intégrer les facteurs criminogènes dans un modèle du rétablissement lorsqu'il s'agit d'intervenir auprès des populations qui ont des taux élevés d'implication judiciaire, telles que les personnes en situation d'itinérance, puisque ces aspects peuvent influencer les trajectoires de rétablissement. Enfin, utiliser un cadre théorique axé sur le rétablissement avec les délinquants atteints de troubles mentaux contribuera à mieux arrimer les politiques en matière judiciaire avec celles en matière de santé mentale</description><description>Introduction. Recovery is a defining value of mental health services. Conversely, interventions used with criminally involved persons with mental illness are at times discordant with recovery values, as they are often inscribed within a punitive approach to justice policy. However, using a recovery framework with these persons is pivotal, as repeated experiences of detention, community sentences or forensic hospitalizations pose additional barriers to recovery in terms of social, vocational and housing integration. Aims. As such, the purpose of this dissertation is to explore the concept of recovery in criminally involved persons with mental illness through four studies that build upon each other. Methods: The first study consists of a scoping review, while studies 2, 3, and 4 use an empirical approach. Given the high rates of criminal justice involvement among persons who experience homelessness, analyses were conducted using a sample of the At Home/Chez Soi project, a Mental Health Commission of Canada/Health Canada-funded randomized control trial of 2,298 homeless and mentally ill individuals in Montreal, Toronto, Vancouver, Winnipeg and Moncton. Results: Study 1 examines quantitative and qualitative studies of recovery in criminally involved populations. Following a thorough review of the literature, a six-dimensional theoretical framework of recovery is proposed, adapting Whitley and Drake's (2010) five-dimensional model to add criminogenic concerns. We propose that for justice involved individuals, recovery should include clinical, existential, functional, social, physical, and criminological dimensions. Study 2 explores the concordance between self-reported and administrative justice involvement. Results show that mentally ill individuals who experience homelessness are accurate reporters of their justice involvement, indicating that it is possible to obtain valid responses from populations with multiple vulnerabilities. Using latent profile analysis, study 3 circumscribes five distinct profiles of criminal justice involvement among individuals with mental illness who experience homelessness: Non/infrequent offenders, Moderate offenders, Violent/antisocial offenders, Versatile subsistence offenders, and Substance offenders. These profiles illustrate the heterogeneity of this population in terms of needs and characteristics. Study 4 explores the influence of criminal justice profile on the effectiveness of Housing First on recovery trajectories, as conceptualized by the six-dimensional model. The effectiveness of the Housing First intervention on substance abuse, housing stability and number of arrests was found to be influenced by criminal justice involvement profile. Implications: Together, these findings underline the importance of using a multi-dimensional recovery framework to flexibly assess the different facets of recovery individually, as not all recovery-oriented endeavours will target the same dimensions. Moreover, criminogenic concerns should be integrated to recovery models and interventions when working with populations that have high rates of criminal justice involvement, such as homeless individuals, as these may influence recovery outcomes. Finally, using a recovery framework with criminal justice involved persons with mental illness could contribute to better-informed justice policy decisions by aligning them with current mental health policies.</description><creator>Lemieux, Ashley</creator><contributor>Anne Crocker (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Robert Whitley (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Psychiatry</subject><title>Expanding the concept of recovery for criminally involved persons: New meaning to the dignity of risk</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nb06d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq26c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x3643</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le virus de l'immunodéficience humaine (VIH) touche de 30,8 à 42,9 millions de personnes et demeure l'une des 10 principales causes de décès dans le monde. Bien que l'utilisation des traitements antirétroviraux ait amélioré l'espérance de vie des personnes infectées par le VIH, elle ne permet pas de guérir complètement de l'infection par le VIH. De plus, le coût élevé ainsi que les effets indésirables bien caractérisés reliés à la thérapie antirétrovirale soulignent la nécessité de trouver une thérapie alternative ou même un traitement de guérison contre le VIH. Une approche envisagée pour guérir l'infection par le VIH est l'utilisation de la thérapie génique pour rendre toutes les cellules cibles du VIH résistantes à la réplication virale. Plusieurs ARN anti-VIH ont été proposés à cet effet, notamment les ARN courts en épingle à cheveux, les ARN leurres, les ribozymes et les ARN interférents U1 (ARN U1i). De la même façon que la thérapie antirétrovirale actuelle, la thérapie génique antivirale nécessitera probablement une approche combinatoire multiple pour réduire la probabilité de résistance virale et éviter la saturation de toute voie cellulaire. Par conséquent, il existe un besoin constant d'identifier et de caractériser de nouveaux ARN antiviraux. L'ARN U1i est un candidat très prometteur pour une utilisation en thérapie génique contre le VIH-1 et plusieurs ont été conçus pour cibler l'ARN du VIH-1 via l'augmentation de l'épissage ou l'inhibition de la polyadénylation de l'ARNm. Cependant, il y a un manque de données de comparaison des ARN U1i qui augmentent l'épissage de l'ARN viral à ceux qui inhibent la polyadénylation. Dans le but d'identifier les candidats ARN U1i antiviraux optimaux, nous avons construit et comparé l'efficacité antivirale des principaux ARN U1i identifiés dans des études précédentes agissant par l'intermédiaire de l'un ou l'autre de ces mécanismes. En plus, nous avons conçu et construit de nouveaux ARN U1i ciblant le cadre de lecture ouvert de Gag. Pour la première fois, nous avons montré que les ARNs U1i ciblant des régions en amont du premier site accepteur d'épissage ont le potentiel d'inhiber la réplication du VIH-1 par un mécanisme non caractérisé auparavant. Par ailleurs, les ARN U1i qui augmentent l'épissage de l'ARN du VIH-1 sont des inhibiteurs plus efficaces de la réplication virale que ceux qui inhibent la polyadénylation. Des études de toxicité préliminaires indiquent que les ARN U1i n'induisent pas de toxicité à fortes doses dans les cellules en culture. Enfin, nous avons constaté que le domaine de reconnaissance des ARN U1i pouvait être augmenté de 6 nucléotides, avec la même capacité à inhiber la réplication du VIH-1. Dans l'ensemble, nos résultats suggèrent que les ARN U1i peuvent être ajoutés à l'armée croissante d'ARN antiviraux ciblant le VIH-1.</description><description>Human Immunodeficiency virus (HIV) affects 30.8 to 42.9 million people and remains one of the top 10 causes of death worldwide. Although the use of antiretrovirals has improved the life expectancy of those infected with HIV, it is likely never to be curative due to its inability to eliminate the virus. Furthermore, the high cost of antiretroviral therapy and well-characterized side effects highlights the need for an alternative therapy or even a cure for HIV. One approach being considered to cure HIV infection is the use of gene therapy to make all HIV target cells resistant to HIV replication. Several anti-HIV RNAs have been proposed for use in gene therapy including short hairpin RNAs, decoy RNAs, ribozymes and U1 interfering RNAs (U1i RNAs). Similar to current antiretroviral therapy, antiviral gene therapy will likely require a combinatorial and multiplexing approach to reduce the likelihood of viral resistance and avoid the saturation of any cellular processing pathways. Therefore, there is a constant need to identify and characterize novel antiviral RNAs.U1i RNA represent attractive candidate for use in HIV-1 gene therapy and several have been designed to target HIV-1 RNA through splicing enhancement or inhibition of mRNA polyadenylation. However, there is a lack of data comparing U1i RNAs that enhance splicing of viral RNA to those that inhibit polyadenylation. To identify optimal U1i RNA antiviral candidates, we constructed and compared the antiviral efficacy of top U1i RNAs identified in previous studies and acting through either mechanism. We also designed and constructed new U1i RNAs targeting the Gag open reading frame of HIV-1 RNA. Here, we show for the first time that U1i RNAs targeting regions upstream of the first splice acceptor site have the potential to inhibit HIV-1 replication through a previously uncharacterized mechanism. We also demonstrate that U1i RNAs that enhance HIV-1 RNA splicing are more effective inhibitors of viral replication when compared to those that inhibit polyadenylation. Preliminary toxicity studies indicate that U1i RNAs do not induce toxicity at high doses in cultured cells. Lastly, we found that the recognition domain of U1i RNAs can be increased by 6 nucleotides with little effect on their ability to inhibit HIV-1 replication. Overall, our results suggest that U1i RNAs that act through mechanisms other than inhibition of polyadenylation are competitive candidates for use in combination gene therapy with antiviral RNAs targeting HIV-1.</description><creator>Del Corpo, Olivier</creator><contributor>Anne Gatignol (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The characterization and optimization of U1i RNAs for use in gene therapy for HIV</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd73p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3643</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1071211</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Categorical Perception (CP) occurs when our categories influence our perception, making members of the same category look more alike (compression) and members of different categories look more different (separation). It is known that CP occurs innately for colors, phonemes and facial expressions, and it is now emerging that categorical perception can also be induced by category learning. In this thesis, we report a series of experiments in which we induced CP effects by training human participants to sort multifeatured visual stimuli into two categories by trial and error. To measure CP, we compared subjects' dissimilarity judgements before and after the categorization training. The categorization tasks and stimuli varied in degree of difficulty, defined a-priori as the proportion of stimuli features that co-varied with category membership (the smaller the proportion of co-varying features, the harder the task). The visual stimuli used in the first and second manuscripts were black and white squared shaped textures, composed of distributed features; in our third manuscript, we used line-drawings of fish with local, shape-based features. Overall, the results of the reported experiments show positive evidence for changes in perception after having learned a visual category. The mechanisms behind these changes were assessed with analyses of underlying brain activity (Event Related Potentials) and cognitive modeling with Artificial Neural Networks. The first manuscript reports behavioral indices of category learning and learned CP effects -separation and compression- in three separate experiments with human subjects and sketches a simple neural network model for category learning that showed similar CP effects. While the nets showed a strong negative correlation between the proportion of covariant features and the task difficulty, this correlation was not evident in the human participants. We concluded that, unlike the nets, the human visual system does not treat the visual features equally, some of them being more salient than others. The second manuscript reports changes in early and late components of the visual ERP after having learned to categorize the stimuli: A decrease in the occipital N1, related to selective attention and feature extraction, and an increase in the parietal Late Positive Component (LPC), associated with memory-related judgements, decision accuracy and response confidence. We also report two significant correlations: one between the amplitude of the N1 after having learned the categories and the degree of separation and another one between the amplitude of the LPC and the response accuracy during the categorization task. We interpret the changes on the N1 as related to the mechanisms behind the perceptual change after learning a category, while the changes on the LPC would account for later-stage cognitive processing affected by category learning. Finally, our third manuscript reports learned CP effects and its electrophysiological correlates for a different kind of stimuli: fish with shape-based local features. After learning, we observed both compression and separation and also changes in early and late components of the visual ERP. While the LPC showed the same pattern as in Manuscript 2 (an increase in amplitude after category learning), the effects on the N1 were less robust; the early changes were observed in another ERP component, the P1, related to selective attention for pre-cued spatial locations. These results suggest that the early brain processes through which we extract localized and distributed features during categorization differ, while the later higher-stage cognitive processes associated with categorical decision making remain the same. Taken together, the results of these three studies provide further evidence that learning to categorize unfamiliar stimuli induces Learned CP effects while providing behavioural, neural and computational evidence to explain the mechanisms that generate it</description><description>La perception catégorielle (PC) se produit lorsque nos catégories influencent notre perception, ce qui rend les membres d'une même catégorie plus semblables (compression) et les membres appartenant à différentes catégories plus différents (séparation). On sait que la PC est présente de façon innée pour les couleurs, les phonèmes et les expressions faciales. Récemment, les évidences qui montrent que la perception catégorielle peut également être induite par l'apprentissage des catégories s'accumulent. Dans cette thèse, nous rapportons une série d'expériences dans lesquelles nous avons induit des effets de PC en entraînant, par essais et erreurs, des participants humains à trier des stimuli visuels avec plusieurs attributs qui co-varient (ou pas) avec l'appartenance à la catégorie. Pour mesurer la PC, nous avons comparé les jugements de similarité faits par les sujets avant et après l'entraînement. Les tâches de catégorisation et les stimuli variaient en degré de difficulté. La difficulté était définie à priori comme la proportion d'attributs covariants avec l'appartenance à une catégorie (plus la proportion de caractéristiques qui co-varie était faible, plus la tâche était difficile). Les stimuli visuels utilisés dans le premier et la deuxième étude étaient des textures carrées en noir et blanc, composées de micro-composantes distribuées dans l'espace. Dans notre troisième étude, nous avons utilisé des dessins de poisson avec des propriétés locales. En général, les résultats, des expériences rapportées, montrent des changements de perception après avoir appris une nouvelle catégorie visuelle. Les mécanismes à l'origine de ces changements ont été évalués à l'aide d'analyses de l'activité cérébrale sous-jacente (EEG/Potentiels évoqués cognitifs) et de la modélisation cognitive avec des réseaux de neurones artificiels.La première étude présente des indices comportementaux de l'effet d'apprentissage de nouvelles catégories et des effets de PC apprise (séparation et compression) à partir de trois expériences distinctes et propose un modèle de réseau neuronal simple pour l'apprentissage des catégories qui a montré des effets de PC similaires. Bien que les réseaux aient montré une forte corrélation négative entre la proportion d'attributs covariantes et la difficulté de la tâche, cette corrélation n'était pas évidente chez les participants humains. Nous avons conclu que, contrairement aux réseaux, le système visuel humain ne traite pas également les attributs visuelles, certaines d'entre elles étant plus saillantes que d'autres. La deuxième étude rapporte des changements dans les composantes précoces et tardives des potentiels évoqués (ERP) après avoir appris à classer les stimuli: une diminution de la composante N1 occipitale qui serait liée à l'attention sélective et à l'extraction des attributs ainsi qu'une augmentation de la composante LPC (Late Positive Component) frontopariétale qui serait associée à des jugements liés à la mémoire, au choix de stratégie et à la certitude de réponse. De plus, l'étude présente deux corrélations significatives. Une première entre l'amplitude de la N1 après avoir appris les catégories et le degré de séparation observé et une deuxième entre l'amplitude de la LPC et la précision de la réponse pendant la tâche de catégorisation. Nous interprétons les changements de la N1 comme étant liés aux mécanismes à l'origine du changement de perception, tandis que les changements de la LPC tiennent compte du traitement cognitif à un stade ultérieur affecté par l'apprentissage explicite. Enfin, la troisième étude rapporte les effets de la PC et ses corrélats électrophysiologiques avec un autre type de stimuli (...) Pris ensemble, les résultats de ces trois études fournissent des preuves que l'apprentissage des catégories visuelles induit des effets de PC apprise tout en fournissant des évidences comportementales, physiologiques et computationnels pour expliquer les mécanismes qui les génèrent.</description><creator>Pérez Gay Juarez, Fernanda</creator><contributor>Victor Frak (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Stevan Harnad (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>How and why does category learning cause categorical perception? Behavioural, neural and computational aspects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt538.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1071211</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj55t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction     La résistance au traitement à base de platine se développe chez la plupart des patients traités pour le cancer de l'ovaire séreux de haut grade (HGSOC), un fait qui explique en grande partie la mortalité élevée de cette maladie. Cooke et ses collègues (Oncogene, 2010) ont montré précédemment que la résistance au platine (Pt) résulte de l'expansion des populations sous-clonales de cellules résistantes présentes avant le traitement. Les modèles en-vitro actuels de résistance au Pt peuvent être confondus par un manque de fidélité à la signature génétique du HGSOC ou par les méthodes utilisées pour provoquer l'apparition d'une résistance pouvant être dépourvue de pertinence clinique. Ce projet vise à déterminer si la résistance aux Pt peut être développée à partir d'une population de cellules sensibles au Pt exposées au cisplatine (CDDP) d'une manière cliniquement pertinente en utilisant des lignes cellulaires dérivées de patients telles que PEO1. L'objectif central était de découvrir quelle hétérogénéité pourrait exister dans cette lignée cellulaire et de déterminer si la résistance à la Pt dérivée en-vitro pouvait résulter de la sélection d'une fraction de cellules préexistants, comme cela se produit en-vivo. Méthodes     La sensibilité au platine des lignes cellulaires utilisées a été établie en exposant les cellules en culture au CDDP pendant 1 heure. Le nombre de cellules vivantes et le pourcentage de viabilité ont été évalués 72 heures après le retrait de la drogue en utilisant une microcytométre Guava Muse. L'évaluation à long terme de la toxicité du Pt a été réalisée avec l'aide du test de survie clonogénique. Pour atteindre la résistance au Pt en-vitro, une culture de PEO1 a été exposée à 10 µM de CDDP pendant 1 heure et laissée se repeupler. Ces cellules ont été passé en culture et utilisées pour établir une nouvelle ligne cellulaire (PEO1X) avec une sensibilité à la Pt diminuée de 20 fois, ce qui a été confirmée par le test de survie clonogénique. Les cellules PEO1X ont été testées pour les marqueurs histopathologiques et de l'état EMT par l'immunohistochimie et comparées à PEO1. La capacité de migration a été évaluée par la méthode de la chambre Boyden, tandis que le statut du cycle-cellulaire 72 heures après l'exposition au CDDP a été interrogé en utilisant une coloration à l'iodure de propidium. Le temps de doublage a également été déterminé et une signature génétique partielle a été établie en séquençant un panel de 33 gènes liés au cancer. Résultats      PEO1 exige une asymétrie morphologique, avec une dichotomie entre les phénotypes épithéliaux et mésenchymateux. Ceci est encore démontré par l'expression hétérogène de marqueurs tels que E-Cadherin, Vimentin et CA125. Bien que similaires au taux de prolifération de PEO1, les cellules PEO1X présentent des différences de morphologie évidentes, étant plus petites et ayant un aspect plus homogène avec une expression modifiée de marqueurs tels que E-Cadhérine, Vimentine, CA125 et CD133. Contrairement à le PEO1, le cycle cellulaire de PEO1X est à peine modifié 72 heures après l'exposition au CDDP, même à 10 µM. PEO1X possède également un phénotype plus migrateur que le PEO1 avec beaucoup plus de cellules transitant la membrane de la chambre Boyden après 30 heures. Le séquençage a révélé une hétérogénéité dans l'état de P53 dans le PEO1, avec le PEO1X étant légèrement enrichi dans les cellules exprimant P53 WT. Il est intéressant de noter que le gène NF1, codant pour la protéine Neurofibromine (un suppresseur de tumeur), contient une mutation indel dans PEO1 et PEO1X tout en contenant une mutation de point différente de PEO4 et en étant WT dans PEO6. Conclusion     La ligne cellulaire PEO1 contient une sous-population de cellules résistantes au Pt qui peuvent être sélectionnées en-vitro par un traitement avec CDDP aux paramètres pertinents cliniquement. Ces cellules sont distinctes de celles ayant émergé cliniquement chez le patient d'origine.</description><description>Introduction     Resistance to platinum-based therapy develops in most patients treated for High Grade Serous Ovarian Cancer (HGSOC), a fact that largely accounts for this disease's elevated mortality. It was previously shown by Cooke and colleagues (Oncogene, 2010) that platinum (Pt) resistance results from the expansion of sub-clonal populations of resistant cells present prior to treatment. Current in vitro models of Pt-resistance may be confounded by a lack of fidelity to the genetic signature of HGSOC, or by the methods used to elicit the onset of resistance which may lack clinical relevance. This project aims to address whether Pt-resistance can be evolved from a population of Pt-sensitive cells exposed to cisplatin (CDDP) in a clinically relevant manner using patient-derived cell lines such as PEO1. The central aim was to uncover what heterogeneity might exist within this cell line and to determine if in vitro derived Pt-resistance can result from the selection of pre-existent subsets of cells as occurs in vivo. Methods     The Pt-sensitivity of the cell lines used, was established by exposing cells in culture to CDDP for 1 hr. Live cell number and percent viability were assessed 72 hours after drug removal using Guava microcytometry. Long-term assessment of Pt toxicity was provided by use of the clonogenic survival assay. To achieve Pt-resistance in vitro, a culture of PEO1 was exposed to 10 µM CDDP for 1 hour and allowed to repopulate. These cells were passaged and used to establish a novel cell line (PEO1X) with 20-fold diminished Pt-sensitivity confirmed via the clonogenic survival assay. PEO1X cells were assayed for histopathological and cell-fate markers by immunohistochemistry and compared to PEO1. Migratory capacity was assessed via the Boyden chamber method, while cell cycle status 72 hours after CDDP exposure was interrogated using propidium iodide staining. Doubling time was also determined, and a partial genetic signature was established by sequencing a panel of 33 cancer-related genes. Results     PEO1 exhibits morphological asymmetry, with a dichotomy between epithelial and mesenchymal phenotypes. This is further evidenced by the heterogeneous expression of markers such as E-Cadherin, Vimentin and CA125. Although similar to PEO1 in proliferation rate, PEO1X cells possess obvious differences in morphology, being smaller and more homogenously rounded in appearance with altered expression of markers such as E-Cadherin, Vimentin, CA125 and CD133. Unlike PEO1, the cell cycle status of PEO1X is barely altered 72 hrs following CDDP exposure even at 10 µM. PEO1X also possesses a more migratory phenotype than PEO1 with significantly more cells transiting through the pores of the Boyden chamber membrane in 30 hrs. Sequencing revealed heterogeneity in the status of P53 in PEO1 with PEO1X being slightly enriched in P53 WT expressing cells. Interestingly, the gene NF1, encoding the tumor-suppressor neurofibromin was found to contain an indel mutation in PEO1 and PEO1X while containing a different loss-of-function point mutation in PEO4 and being WT in PEO6 despite all being established from the same patient. Conclusion     The cell line PEO1 contains a sub-population of Pt-resistant cells that can be selected for, in vitro, by clinically relevant CDDP treatment. These cells are distinct from those having emerged clinically in the original patient.</description><creator>Lisio, Michael-Anthony</creator><contributor>Carlos Telleria (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Pathology</subject><title>Evaluation of platinum-sensitivity in a cell line model of high grade serous ovarian cancer and the induction of re- sistance from a chemo-sensitive cell line through the re- population of cells following short-term cisplatin treatment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935522n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj55t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p0478</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human cryptosporidiosis caused by Cryptosporidium hominis and C. parvum is an important disease causing severe diarrheal symptoms in infants and adults around the world.  To date, no curative therapeutics or prophylactic vaccines against cryptosporidiosis exist.  A recombinant Gp45 vaccine, developed in our laboratory, has shown to be partially protective against C.parvum in mice.  However, to develop a more effective vaccine, we propose to use an attenuated Salmonella typhimurium model as an oral vaccine delivery vector for the Gp45 recombinant protein.  We hypothesize that mucosal immunity, i.e. IgA levels, will be greater following the use of an oral YS1646 vaccine in addition to the intramuscular Gp45 vaccine in comparison with the intramuscular Gp45 vaccine alone. The overall goal of this M.Sc. was to produce various vaccine candidates against C.parvum, assess the expression of Gp45 of each candidate and evaluate the immunogenicity of our vaccine candidates in mice. Three constructs were constructed to express Gp45 in S. typhimurium and were transformed in an attenuated strain of S.typhimurium. We were successful in creating various plasmid constructs for expression of recombinant Gp45 in S.typhimurium. Unfortunately, we did not succeed in demonstrating expression of the recombinant Gp45 in any of our expression constructs. Despite failure to express Gp45 from Salmonella in vitro, two of our vaccine candidates were used in a preliminary study in mice. Following an IM/oral vaccination regimen and a 6-week study period, one of our vaccine candidates showed a statistically significant response compared to a negative control and no vaccine candidate produced greater serum IgG or intestinal IgA compared to a single dose of intramuscular Gp45. However, our YS1646 vaccine elicited a strong S.typhimurium specific serum IgG and intestinal IgA response suggesting the vaccine vector, and not the protein of interest, was the target of the murine immune system.  Further optimization of our constructs is needed to obtain detectable levels of protein expression in vitro and enhance humoral immunity by our oral YS1646 vaccine in vivo. This investigation provides a first insight regarding the use of a vaccine vector against cryptosporidiosis.</description><description>La cryptosporidiose humaine causée par Cryptosporidium hominis et Cryptosporidium parvum est une maladie importante causant une diarrhée importante chez les enfants ainsi que chez les adultes.  À ce jour, il n'existe aucun traitement curatif ou prophylactique contre la cryptosporidiose. Par conséquent, étant donné la forte morbidité reliée à la crypstosporidiose, nous avons cherché à développer un vaccin prophylactique. Un vaccin recombinant Gp45 adjuvé, développé dans notre laboratoire, s'est révélé partiellement protecteur contre C.parvum chez la souris. Cependant, pour développer un vaccin plus efficace, nous proposons d'utiliser un modèle atténué de Salmonella typhimurium comme vecteur d'administration de vaccin oral pour la protéine recombinante Gp45. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que l'immunité de la muqueuse, c'est-à-dire les taux d'IgA intestinaux, sera supérieure suite à l'utilisation d'un vaccin oral YS1646 en plus du vaccin intramusculaire Gp45. L'objectif global de cette Maitrise était de produire divers candidats de vaccins contre C.parvum, évaluer l'expression de Gp45 de chaque candidat et évaluer l'immunogénicité de nos vaccins candidats chez la souris. Trois plasmides ont été clonés pour exprimer Gp45 dans S. typhimurium et ont été transformés dans une souche atténuée de S. typhimurium. Nous avons réussi à créer diverses constructions plasmidiques pour l'expression de Gp45 recombinant dans S.typhimurium. Malheureusement, nous n'avons pas pu démontrer l'expression de la protéine Gp45 recombinante dans aucun de nos plasmides. Malgré l'impossibilité d'exprimer Gp45 à partir de S.typhimurium in vitro, deux de nos candidats de vaccins ont été utilisés dans une étude préliminaire chez la souris. Après un régime de vaccination IM / orale et une période d'étude de 6 semaines, un candidat-vaccin a montré une réponse statistiquement significative comparée à un contrôle négatif et aucun vaccin n'a produit une IgG sérique ou une IgA intestinale supérieure à une dose unique de Gp45 intramusculaire. Cependant, notre candidate de vaccin YS1646 a induit une forte réponse IgG sérique spécifique de S.typhimurium et une réponse IgA intestinale suggérant que le vecteur, et non la protéine d'intérêt, était la cible du système immunitaire murin. Une optimisation supplémentaire de nos constructions est nécessaire pour obtenir des niveaux détectables d'expression des protéines in vitro et améliorer l'immunité humorale par notre vaccin oral YS1646 in vivo. Ce projet de recherche fournit un premier aperçu concernant l'utilisation d'un vecteur de vaccin contre la cryptosporidiose.</description><creator>Lemieux, Maxime</creator><contributor>Momar Ndao (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Developing an experimental vaccine against Cryptosporidiosis using an attenuated «Salmonella typhimurium» delivery vector</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913s131.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p0478</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935523x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La spectroscopie par perte d'énergie des électrons (EELS) est une technique de caractérisation sensible aux éléments de faible masse. L'analyse EELS requiert des spectres de références pour valider les résultats obtenus. Les simulations de spectres offrent une faon d'obtenir des références pour des nouveaux matériaux. Bien que les simulations soient utiles, ellesrequièrent des ajustements de paramètres. Un de ces paramètre est la façon de gérer un trou d'état de cœur. Une nouvelle technique pour calculée l'intensité de masquage des trous d'électrons est proposée, ce qui a pour effet d'augmenter la précision des spectres EELS des matériaux contenant du lithium. La méthode est appliquée pour vérifier la pertinence deconduire des expériences EELS à 30 keV, ce qui a pour effet de minimiser l'endommagement des échantillons induits par de le faisceau d'électron. La méthode est basée sur la théorie de la réponse linéaire, qui relie la densité des électrons aux effets de masquage. Ces effets sont par la suite représentés par un trou partiel dans les calculs par la théorie de la fonctionnellede la densité d'états d'électrons. En utilisant la technique proposée dans ce travaille, les spectres EELS calculées pour le Li2O, le LiF et le lithium métallique sont en meilleur accordance avec les résultats expérimentaux de ces matériaux. Ces résultats ouvrent la porte à des méthode quantitatives basée sur la spectroscopie EELS.</description><description>Electron energy loss spectroscopy (EELS) is an electron microscopy technique ideal for analyzing lightweight elements. The technique relies on using reference spectra to fingerprint and analyze results. These references can be obtained either through experiments on standards or through simulation. Simulations provide the ability to produce spectra for previously unstudied or sensitive materials, but rely on numerous approximations. Central to the simulation of EELS are the approximations treating core holes and shielding. In this work, a new method of calculating the magnitude of core hole screening in the case of lithium materials is developed and implemented in density functional theory calculations. The method is used to verify the validity of performing electron energy loss spectroscopy at 30 keV to reduce beam damage. EELS fine structure are calculated for metallic lithium, Li2O, and LiF and marked improvements in agreement between calculation and experiment are observed. The technique uses linear response theory to relate the electron density to the core hole shielding contribution. This contribution is then implemented via a non integer core hole in final state rule density functional theory calculations. The improvements enabled by the technique open the possibility of conducting increasingly quantitative EELS  analysis.</description><creator>Stoyel, Quentin</creator><contributor>Raynald Gauvin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>George Demopoulos (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Density functional theory techniques for electron energy loss analysis of lithium materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408040m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935523x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw792</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:00:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La glace massive au sol est une caractéristique des environnements périglaciaires à travers Sibérie, Alaska, le nord du Canada, l'Antarctique et Mars. L'occurrence de la glace massive au sol produit des questions par rapport à : i) son origine, ii) son importance à travers le paysage et iii) sa réaction aux changements climatiques. Dans l'archipel de la haute arctique canadienne, on se trouve de la glace au tabulaire massive partout dans les basses terres des îles Ellesmere et Axel Heiberg. Des recherches précédentes par W.H. Pollard ont interprété la glace à avoir une origine intra-sédimentaire reliée à la déglaciation et régression marin pendant l'Holocène. Cette étude a utilisé une approche géochimique (isotopes stables d'eau, ions majeurs) pour expliquer la source d'eau et l'histoire de congélation des exposés de glace massive au sol dans les basses terres du Eureka Sound. Sédiments de la couche active et carottes de pergélisol ont été pris des masses de glace au sol à travers un gradient d'élévation – de le niveau de mer moderne jusqu'à la limite marine de l'Holocene (143 m a.s.l.). Nos résultats démontrent que la glace massive au sol de Eureka Sound est provenue d'un système ouvert durant l'Holocene, pendant que des sédiments marins élevés gelaient lentement de la surface vers le bas. La glace massive a formé quand la contribution de eaux souterraines appauvries en isotopes était beaucoup plus grand que la vitesse de congélation en direction vers le bas. L'ampleur du mixage géochimique et du processus de ségrégation de glace sont des résultats de la vitesse de congélation – donc on peut reconstruire la rapidité d'aggradation du pergélisol à travers un gradient de 143 m, ce qui représente un espace d'environ 8,000 ans après déglaciation. </description><description>Massive ground ice is a feature of periglacial environments throughout Siberia, Alaska, northern Canada, Antarctica and Mars. The occurrence of massive ground ice raises questions about: i) its origin, ii) its extent across the landscape and iii) its response to climatic change. In the Canadian High Arctic Archipelago, tabular massive ground ice is found extensively throughout the Eureka Sound Lowlands (ESL) on Ellesmere and Axel Heiberg islands. Previous research by W.H. Pollard interpreted the ice as having a segregated origin related to deglaciation and Holocene marine regression. This study used a geochemical approach (stable water isotopes, major ions) to further explain the water source and freezing history of massive ground ice exposures in the ESL. Active layer sediments and permafrost cores from massive ice bodies were collected along an elevation gradient, from modern sea level to Holocene marine limit (~143 m a.s.l.). Results show that ESL ground ice formed during the Holocene in an open-system as raised marine sediments slowly froze from the ground surface downwards. Massive ice formed where the input rate of isotopically-depleted groundwater (from an underlying aquifer fed by the disintegration of the Innuitian Ice Sheet) was much greater than the downwards freezing rate. The extent of geochemical mixing and of the ice segregation process are reflections of the freezing rate – thus we can reconstruct permafrost aggradation along an elevation gradient of 143 m, which represents a span of ~8,000 years since deglaciation.</description><creator>Roy, Cameron</creator><contributor>Wayne H Pollard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Geography</subject><title>The origin of massive ground ice in raised marine sediments along the Eureka Sound Lowlands, Nunavut, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw69j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw792</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q884</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transcriptional regulators that play crucial roles in cancer progression have gained prominence as anticancer drug targets.  Inhibitors of positive transcription elongation factor b (P TEFb), a factor essential for promoter proximal pause release, have proven effective against a number of cancer types, including mixed lineage leukemia driven by translocations of the histone methyltransferase MLL. These translocations result in chimeric proteins that have been implicated in P-TEFb recruitment to target cancer-driving genes. P-TEFb is a kinase with multiple targets, including RNA polymerase II as well as two factors associated with the paused polymerase, negative elongation factor (NELF) and DRB sensitivity-inducing factor (DSIF). To determine the functional significance of P-TEFb-dependent pathways and elucidate the mechanisms underlying sensitivity to P-TEFb inhibitors in MLL-rearrangement associated leukemias, I characterized the responses to transcriptional inhibitor treatment of two cancer cell lines, THP-1, which has a MLL-rearrangement, and K562, which has unaltered MLL. I found that THP-1 exhibits reduced viability and greater loss of P-TEFb activity upon inhibition of P TEFb. While consistent with the idea that MLL-rearrangement associated leukemias have increased dependency on P-TEFb, this work also raises the possibility that MLL-fusion proteins might globally impair P TEFb, contrary to current models. I also took steps towards creating cell lines with phosphoacceptor site mutations in the P-TEFb target Spt5 using CRISPR/Cas9. My efforts revealed that double-stranded repair templates, which are commonly used in CRISPR/Cas9-mediated gene replacement, are non-specifically inserted into the genome at a high frequency. Overall, this work advances our understanding of the importance of P TEFb dependent pathways in cancer biology.</description><description>Les régulateurs de la transcription jouent un rôle crucial dans la progression du cancer et sont, par conséquent, devenus des cibles de médicaments anticancéreux intéressantes. Les inhibiteurs du facteur positif d'élongation de la transcription (P-TEFb), un facteur essentiel pour la sortie de la pause proximale au promoteur, se sont révélés efficaces contre plusieurs types de cancers, incluant la leucémie aiguë de phénotype mixte entraînée par des translocations de la méthyltransférase MLL. Ces translocations forment des protéines chimériques qui sont impliquées dans le recrutement de P-TEFb aux gènes affectant ce cancer. P-TEFb est une kinase avec plusieurs cibles, incluant l'ARN polymérase II et deux facteurs associés à la polymérase en pause, soit le facteur négatif d'élongation (NELF) et le facteur inductible à la sensibilité au DRB (DSIF). Pour déterminer l'importance fonctionnelle des mécanismes régulés par P-TEFb et élucider les mécanismes sous-jacents à la sensibilité aux inhibiteurs de P-TEFb dans les leucémies avec réarrangement de MLL, j'ai caractérisé les réponses aux inhibiteurs transcriptionnels de deux lignées cellulaires cancéreuses, soit THP-1, qui possède un réarrangement de MLL, et K562, qui ne possède pas de réarrangement. J'ai découvert que THP 1 présente une viabilité réduite et une perte plus importante de l'activité de P-TEFb lors de traitement avec les inhibiteurs de P-TEFb. Bien qu'ils conforment à l'idée que les leucémies avec réarrangement de MLL dépendent davantage sur le P-TEFb, mes résultats soulèvent également la possibilité que les protéines de fusion MLL pourraient globalement altérer P-TEFb, contrairement aux modèles actuels. J'ai aussi tenté de créer des lignées cellulaires avec des mutations aux sites phosphoaccepteurs de Spt5, une cible de P-TEFb, en utilisant la technique CRISPR/Cas9. Mes efforts ont révélé que les molécules d'ADN à double brin, qui sont couramment utilisés comme modèles de réparation lors de l'essai CRISPR/Cas9, sont insérés dans le génome de manière non-spécifique à une fréquence élevée. Pris ensemble, mes résultats améliorent notre compréhension de l'importance des mécanismes régulés par P-TEFb dans la biologie du cancer.</description><creator>Zhu, Xinwen</creator><contributor>Terence Hebert (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jason Tanny (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</subject><title>P-TEFb-dependent pathways in cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h46w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q884</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jr08b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RNA structures possess multiple levels of structural organization. A secondary structure, made of Watson-Crick helices connected by loops, forms a scaffold for the tertiary structure. The 3D structures adopted by these loops are therefore critical determinants shaping the global 3D architecture. Earlier studies showed that these local 3D structures can be described as conserved sets of ordered non-Watson-Crick base pairs called RNA structural modules. Unfortunately, the computational efficiency and scope of the current 3D module prediction methods are too limited to benefit from all the knowledge accumulated in the module databases. We present BayesPairing, an automated, efficient and customizable tool for (i) building Bayesian networks representing RNA 3D modules, and (ii) rapid de novo predictions of 3D modules in sequences. BayesPairing uses a flexible definition of RNA 3D modules which allows it to predict a broader range of modules than current alternatives such as multi-branched loops, and features running time improvements that open the door to a broad range of large-scale applications.</description><description>La structure d'une molécule d'ARN est répartie en plusieurs niveaux d'organisation. La structure secondaire, constituée d'hélices Watson-Crick connectées par des boucles, forme un échafaudage pour la structure tertiaire. La structure tertiaire adoptée par ces boucles est donc critique dans la détermination de l'architecture 3D globale. Plusieurs études ont démontré que ces structures 3D locales peuvent être décrites comme des ensembles conservés de paires de bases non-Watson-Crick. Malheureusement, l'efficacité computationnelle et la portée des approches actuelles pour la prédiction des modules 3D sont trop limitées pour bénéficier de toutes les connaissances accumulées dans les bases de données de modules.Nous présentons BayesPairing, un outil logiciel automatisé, efficace et flexible pour (i) la modélisation de modules 3D sous forme de réseaux bayésiens, et (ii) la prédiction rapide de modules 3D à partir de séquences. BayesPairing utilise une définition flexible de module 3D d'ARN qui lui permet de prédire un éventail plus vaste de modules que ses concurrents, comme les boucles multi-branches et ce, plus rapidement. Ces améliorations en flexibilité et en efficacité ouvrent la porte à un vaste champ d'applications à grande échelle.</description><creator>Sarrazin Gendron, Roman</creator><contributor>Jérôme Waldispuhl (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Automated, customizable and efficient identification of RNA 3D base pair modules from sequence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf01s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jr08b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720g18x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les éléments des terres rares (ETR) sont utilisés dans de nombreuses domaines innovatives. Le Bastnaésite, un minéral des terres rares (MTR) fluorocarboné, est l'une des sources principales de production des ETR. La flottation par mousse est l'une des techniques les plus communément utilisées dans le traitement des MTR ainsi que dans l'industrie minéralurgique en général. Une liquide ionique (LI), le tetraethylammonium mono-(2-ethylhexyl)2-ethylhexyl phosphonate ([N2222][EHEHP]), a été étudiée auparavant pour l'extraction par solvant des ETR et s'est démontrée comme étant sélectif et efficace. Ce projet étudie l'utilisation du [N2222][EHEHP] comme collecteur pour la flottation des MTR.  Les résultats sont comparés au quartz et à l'hématite (deux minéraux de la gangue couramment associés aux dépôts MTR). Des mesures du potentiel zêta et la spectroscopie infrarouge à transformée de Fourier (IRTF) ont été utilisées pour étudier la chimie de surface des minéraux. Ces résultats ont été utilisés pour supporter des données de microflottation obtenus auparavant. Les résultats de microflottation suggèrent que la capacité de collecte du LI est plus élevée pour le quartz et l'hématite que pour le bastnaésite, qui n'a montré qu'une récupération appréciable à un pH de 5 avec 500 g/t de LI. Les résultats du potentiel zêta et de l'IRTF suggèrent une adsorption du groupe phosphonate sur le bastnaésite et l'hématite, probablement par le mécanisme de chimisorption, tandis que pour le quartz, la récupération élevée de la flottation est possiblement due au groupe de l'ammonium faiblement lié. Pour prouver l'efficacité de la séparation, trois dépresseurs ont été testés, soit le silicate de sodium, le NorligH (un dépresseur commercial contenant du lignine sulfonate de calcium) et le chlorure de manganèse. Les résultats des tests de microflottation montrent que les dépresseurs peuvent réduire considérablement le bastnaésite dans toutes les conditions testées, avec peu d'impact sur l'hématite et le quartz. Un mélange synthétique de trois minéraux a été testé par flottation en laboratoire à un pH de 5 avec le silicate de sodium. Les résultats montrent que le bastnaésite a été sélectivement diminué tandis que la récupération de l'hématite et du quartz est restée considérablement stable. Une meilleure séparation pourrait être obtenue en utilisant la méthode de la flottation inverse avec une dose de collecteur plus élevée et un dépresseur plus efficace. Une étape de prétraitement est proposée pour rejeter certains minéraux de la gangue avant la flottation afin d'améliorer l'efficacité de la séparation.</description><description>Rare earth elements (REE) have been utilized in many cutting-edge applications. Bastnäsite, a flurocarbonate rare earth mineral (REM), is one of the primary sources in REE production. Froth flotation is one of the most commonly applied techniques in REM processing, as well as for the mineral processing industry in general. A type of ionic liquid (IL), tetraethylammonium mono-(2-ethylhexyl)2-ethylhexyl phosphonate ([N2222][EHEHP]), has been investigated previously for REE solvent extraction, and was proven selective and effective. In this work, [N2222][EHEHP] has been investigated as a collector for REM flotation for the first time, with the results compared to quartz and hematite (two gangue minerals commonly associated with REM deposits). Zeta potential measurements and Fourier transfer infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) were used to investigate the surface chemistry of the minerals, the results of which were used to explain microflotation responses. Microflotation results suggest higher collecting ability of IL for quartz and hematite than for bastnäsite, which only showed appreciable recovery at pH 5 with 500 g/t IL. FTIR and zeta potential results suggest adsorption of the phosphonate group onto bastnäsite and hematite, likely through chemisorption; whereas for quartz, the high flotation recovery is likely due to weakly bonded ammonium moiety. To improve the separation efficiency, three depressants, sodium silicate, NorligH (a commercial depressant contains calcium lignin sulfonate), and manganese chloride were tested. Microflotation tests show that the tested depressants can significantly depress bastnäsite at all tested conditions, with limited impact on hematite and quartz. A synthetic mixture of three minerals was tested in bench scale flotation at pH 5 with sodium silicate. Results show that bastnäsite was selectively depressed, with the recovery of hematite and quartz remaining almost unchanged. A better separation could be achieved following such reverse flotation route, possibly with a higher collector dose and a more effective depressant. A pretreatment stage is suggested to reject some of the gangue minerals before flotation in order to improve separation efficiency.</description><creator>Li, Ronghao</creator><contributor>Kristian Waters (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>An investigation into using ionic liquids for rare earth mineral flotation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rr035.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g18x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c9594</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human FOXP3+ regulatory T (Treg) cells play an essential role in the maintenance of immune homeostasis by controlling self-tolerance while maintaining immune responses to non-self antigens. Treg cells constitutively express the master regulator transcription factor FOXP3, are hyporesponsive to in vitro TCR-induced proliferation, express low levels of inflammatory cytokines and inhibit the activation, maturation and effector functions of a variety of innate and adoptive immune cells. Mutation of the foxp3 locus and consequential abrogation of Treg cell function lead to the development of multi-organ autoimmunity in mice and in humans. Some have reported that Treg cell numbers and function are abrogated in patient with autoimmune disease while others claim there are no differences in Treg cells in these inflammatory environments. The inconsistency in the literature on this topic is due to the lack of cell surface markers that would allow for the specific identification and isolation of Treg cells in health and disease conditions. The main markers currently used to identify human Treg cells are CD25hiCD127loFOXP3+, however, these markers are also T effector (Teff) cell activation markers, rendering the Treg cell population indistinguishable in inflammatory settings. Our lab sought to identify novel Treg cell-specific surface markers by developing a novel single cell strategy to evaluate epigenetic, transcriptional signature, phenotype and function of CD4+ T cell subsets. These studies led to the identification of three T cell populations: FOXP3- non-suppressive (FNSN), FOXP3+ suppressive (FPSP or TregFunc) and FOXP3+ non-suppressive (FPSN or TregDys). Upon further evaluation of these subsets, Helios, TIGIT and FCRL3 were found to be preferentially expressed in the TregFunc cells, and could be used to accurately identify the functional and stable Treg cells. Conversely, the IL-6-family receptor gp130 was found to be preferentially expressed on the TregDys cells. We further evaluated the role IL-6 and IL-27-mediated gp130-signals play on Treg cell phenotype and function. We demonstrate that IL-6 and IL-27 decrease FOXP3 and Helios expression in the TregFunc and TregDys cells, and that gp130+ Treg cells are more susceptible to phenotypic modulation by IL-6 and IL-27. We also show that TregDys cells produce IL-17 and that IL-17 expression is increased in these Treg cells in IL-6-mediated Th17 conditions. Lastly, we show that IL-6 and IL-27 cause Treg cells to lose their suppressive capacity, which can be rescued by inhibiting the gp130 receptor with a small molecule inhibitor. The effects observed by IL-6 and IL-27 on Treg cells could be in part responsible for autoimmune disease pathogenesis. </description><description>Les lymphocytes FOXP3+ T régulateurs (Treg) humains jouent un rôle essentiel dans le maintien de l'homéostase immunitaire en promouvant la tolérance au soi tout en permettant les réponses immunitaires face aux pathogènes. Les Treg expriment le facteur de transcription FOXP3 de manière constitutive. Les mutations du locus foxp3 qui perturbent la fonction des cellules Treg causent le développement d'une auto-immunité qui affecte plusieurs organes, aussi bien chez la souris que chez l'homme. Toutefois, le rôle des Treg lors de maladies auto-immunes demeure largement débattu. Certains groupes ont rapporté que la fonction et l'accumulation des Treg sont affectés chez les patients atteints d'une maladie auto-immune alors que d'autres ne perçoivent pas ces différences. Le débat qui persiste sur ce sujet est notamment dû à l'absence de biomarqueurs de surface qui permettrait une identification précise et spécifique des cellules Treg humaines. Les principaux marqueurs actuellement utilisés pour identifier les Treg humaines sont la combinaison de CD25, CD127 et FOXP3 (CD25hiCD127loFOXP3+), mais ce profil d'expression est également observés chez les cellules T effectrices (Teff) lors de leur activation; ce qui rend la population de Treg indiscernable des Teff dans un contexte inflammatoire. Nous avons cherché à identifier de nouveaux marqueurs de surface spécifiques aux Treg en développant une stratégie monocellulaire pour évaluer le profil épigénétique, la signature transcriptionnelle, le phénotype et la fonction des populations de cellules T CD4+. Ces études ont conduit à l'identification de trois populations de cellules: (1) FOXP3- non suppressive (FNSN), (2) FOXP3+ suppressive (FPSP ou TregFunc) et (3) FOXP3+ non-suppressive ou dysfonctionnelles (FPSN ou TregDys). Une évaluation approfondie de ces groupes nous a permis d'identifier les marqueurs Helios, TIGIT et FCRL3 exprimés spécifiquement par les TregFunc alors que gp130, membre de la famille des récepteurs de l'IL-6, s'est avéré préférentiellement exprimé sur les TregDys. Nous avons donc évalué le rôle de gp130 à travers son activation par les cytokines IL-6 et IL-27 sur le phénotype et la fonction des Treg. Nous démontrons ici que l'IL-6 et l'IL-27 diminuent l'expression de FOXP3 et Helios dans les Treg, et que les Treg gp130+ sont celles sensibles à la modulation par l'IL-6 et l'IL-27. Nous montrons également que les TregDys produisent de l'IL-17 et que cette production est modulée par l'IL-6. Enfin, l'IL-6 et l'IL-27 diminuent la capacité suppressive des Treg, ce qui peut être rétabli en bloquant le récepteur gp130 avec un inhibiteur spécifique. Les effets observés de l'IL-6 et l'IL-27 sur les Treg pourraient être responsables de la pathogenèse des maladies auto-immunes.</description><creator>Bartolucci, Sabrina</creator><contributor>Ciriaco Piccirillo (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The role of gp130-related cytokines in the modulation of human regulatory T cell function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000232p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c9594</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj553</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous présentons une architecture générique en électrodynamique quantique en cavité (en anglais: QED), capable de cultiver différents types d'intrication quantique à plusieurs corps. Ce système, présentement accessible au niveau expérimental dans diverses architectures, nécessite seulement une interaction faible entre un ensemble de spins et une cavité soumise à un processus paramétrique à deux photons. Le premier protocole d'intrication que nous proposons, soit le protocole assisté par un état noir quantique (en anglais: DMAP), consiste à transférer la compression du champ intra-cavité vers l'ensemble de spins. L'état comprimé de spin résultant de ce procédé (avec un paramètre de Kitawaga sur l'ordre de 10-2) présente un enchevêtrement fort dans les différentes paires de spins, ce qui s'avère très utile dans le contexte de la métrologie quantique. Dans un temps de préparation relativement court (inversement proportionnel à la magnitude du couplage collectif), notre protocole permet d'atteindre pratiquement la limite quantique d'Heisenberg (avec un paramètre de Wineland près de 2/N), et ce même pour un faible échantillon de spins. Si la limite de compression générée par la torsion à un axe ou deux axes est contrainte par la taille de l'échantillon, notre protocole ne l'est pas en plus d'être plus rapide et de ne pas souffrir de la dynamique oscillatoire de la torsion à un axe. Nous allons aussi démontrer comment le DMAP se compare à une évolution adiabatique même si l'adiabaticité semble impraticable dans ce contexte. Dans des travaux précédents nous avons démontré qu'un processus paramétrique à deux photons peut être utilisé pour simuler un couplage très fort dans un system QED en cavity standard à interaction faible. Nous allons élargir cette technique au système présent pour simuler le modèle de Dicke, qui est reconnu pour ses propriétés quantiques intéressantes telles que la possibilité d'un enchevêtrement quantique important et des transitions de phases superradiantes. Les autres protocoles d'intrication que nous proposerons utilisent la simulation du modèle de Dicke, soit la réalisation de la porte de Molmer-Sorenson, intimement reliée à la torsion à un axe, et la culture de grands états de chat enchevêtrés. Plus spécifiquement nous proposerons un protocole d'intrication délocalisée, un ingrédient clé pour l'informatique quantique, où un état de Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger sera préparé dans le système à interaction faible pour être ensuite transformé en un grand état de chat enchevêtré grâce au model simulé de Dicke. Finalement nous révèlerons notre système comme étant une plateforme intéressante pour étudier les transitions de phase superradiantes ainsi que leur dépendance sur le bruit quantique comprimé.</description><description>We present a generic cavity quantum electrodynamics (QED) set-up that can generate different types of strong multipartite entanglement. The proposed system is already accessible at the experimental level in different cavity QED architectures as it only involves a spin ensemble weakly coupled to a two-photon driven cavity. The first entangling scheme we propose, the dark-mode assisted protocol (DMAP), consists in transferring the squeezing from the cavity to the spin ensemble. The resulting spin squeezed state (with a Kitawaga spin squeezing parameter on the order of 10−2) has strong pairwise entanglement that is especially useful for quantum metrology. In a relatively short timescale (inversely proportional to the collective coupling strength), our scheme can almost reach the quantum Heisenberg limit (with a Wineland spin squeezing parameter close to 2/N), even for a few spins. Unlike one-axis twisting and two-axis countertwisting, the amount of spin squeezing generated by our scheme is not constrained by the number of spins. Our scheme is faster and doesn't suffer the oscillatory dynamics of one-axis twisting. We will also demonstrate how the DMAP can be analyzed as an adiabatic evolution even though achieving adiabaticity might seem impossible in our gapless system. In the second part of the thesis, we build on our previous work which showed that a two-photon drive can be used to simulate ultra-strong coupling in a standard cavity QED system where the cavity is weakly coupled to a single qubit. We extend this approach to a cavity weakly interacting with a spin ensemble and simulate the Dicke model, which is known to exhibit interesting quantum features such as strong entanglement and quantum phase transitions. The other entangling schemes we propose, make use of the simulated Dicke model: the realization of a Molmer-Sorenson gate, closely related to one-axis twisting, and the generation of large multipartite entangled cat-states. We demonstrate how our scheme can be used to prepare a remote entanglement protocol, a key ingredient in quantum information, where the weakly interacting Hamiltonian is used to grow a Greenberger–Horne–Zeilinger state which will then be transformed into an entangled-cat state by the simulated Dicke Hamiltonian. Finally we illustrate how our system can become an interesting platform to study superradiant phase transition and as well as the effects of squeezed input noise.</description><creator>Leroux, Catherine</creator><contributor>Clerk, Aashish (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Multi-qubit entanglement and spin squeezing in cavity QED via two-photon driving</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw04s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj553</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nt221</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, social work scholars have focused on financial capability to help individuals and families experiencing increasing disparities in wealth and income. Although a number of studies have examined the association between individuals' levels of financial knowledge and their financial behaviour and practices, we know little about how financial knowledge varies across individuals living in different social locations, including age, gender, and income statuses. In this dissertation, I used quantitative data from the 2009 and 2014 Canadian Financial Capability Survey and qualitative data collected from key informants to examine the disparity in financial knowledge and confidence and to identify groups that are disadvantaged. Findings suggest that older adults significantly overestimate their levels of financial knowledge, which implies vulnerability to financial fraud, exploitation, and abuse. Findings also suggest that individuals living in low-income have significantly lower levels of financial knowledge than their non-low-income counterparts. But no gender gap in financial knowledge was found within both low-income and non-low-income groups. The findings of the qualitative inquiry complemented the findings of the quantitative studies. In addition, the findings of the qualitative inquiry suggest that financial knowledge is contextual and driven by financial practices. Findings also suggest that financial knowledge alone is not sufficient to make informed financial decisions; individuals need financial confidence, access to financial products and services, and sufficient income to achieve financial wellbeing.Building financial knowledge among vulnerable groups such as older adults and those in poverty needs to be a policy and practice priority. Because social workers work closely with vulnerable and disadvantaged groups, they can help older adults, and individuals and families in poverty enhance financial wellbeing through building awareness, financial knowledge, and confidence and advocate for policies. </description><description>Au cours des dernières années, les spécialistes du travail social se sont concentrés sur la capacité financière afin d'aider les individus et les familles confrontés à des disparités croissantes en termes de richesse et de revenus. Bien qu'un certain nombre d'études aient examiné l'association entre le niveau de connaissances financières des individus et leurs comportements et pratiques au niveau financier, nous en savons peu sur la manière dont les connaissances financières varient selon la situation et les caractéristiques sociales des personnes, tel que le revenu, l'âge ou le genre. Dans cette thèse, j'ai utilisé des données quantitatives provenant de l'Enquête canadienne sur les capacités financières de 2009 et de 2014 ainsi que des données qualitatives recueillies auprès d'informateurs clés afin d'examiner la disparité des connaissances et de la confiance financière et pour identifier les groupes défavorisés.Les conclusions de cette thèse suggèrent que les personnes âgées surestiment significativement leur niveau de connaissances financières, ce qui implique une vulnérabilité à la fraude financière, à l'exploitation et aux abus. Les résultats suggèrent également que les personnes à faibles revenus ont des niveaux de connaissances financières nettement inférieurs à ceux des individus ayant de meilleurs revenus. Cependant, aucun écart entre les genres en matière de connaissances financières n'a été constaté à l'intérieur des groupes de revenu. Les résultats de l'enquête qualitative sont complémentaires aux conclusions des études quantitatives. Ces résultats ont mis de l'avant que les connaissances financières sont contextuelles et dictées par les pratiques financières. Les connaissances financières seules ne suffisent pas pour prendre des décisions financières éclairées; les individus ont besoin de confiance financière, d'avoir accès à des produits et services financiers, et de revenus suffisants pour atteindre le bien-être financier.Le développement de connaissances financières parmi les groupes vulnérables tels que les personnes âgées et les personnes vivant dans la pauvreté doit être une priorité au plan des politiques sociales et de la pratique du travail social. Puisque les travailleurs sociaux œuvrent auprès des personnes vulnérables et de groupes désavantagés, ils peuvent contribuer à améliorer le bien-être financier des personnes âgées et des personnes et familles pauvres en les sensibilisant, en les aidant à améliorer leurs confiance et connaissances financières et en soutenant des politiques sociales. </description><creator>Khan, Mohammad</creator><contributor>David Rothwell (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jill Hanley (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Social Work</subject><title>Understanding the disparity in financial capability across individuals' social locations: A new dimension of inequality</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v5119.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nt221</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p889</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Though widely recognized as a key figure of twentieth-century modernism, Gustav Mahler (1860–1911) frequently references classical compositional techniques in many of his symphonic works. In particular, countless authors have observed the prominent classical elements of Symphony No. 4, which are especially notable in its first movement. While a formal analysis of this opening movement does reveal similarities between Mahler's organization and classical structural norms, it also uncovers many compositional strategies that are more characteristic of late-romanticism. For instance, whereas many analyze this movement as a typical first-movement sonata form, its tonal and formal organization more closely resembles that of a sonata-rondo (though this form is typically reserved for finales and the occasional slow movement). Additionally, Mahler plays with his listeners' expectations by incorporating several formal ambiguities that call into question the passages' true functional roles. This thesis presents a form-functional analysis of the first movement from Mahler's Symphony No. 4 with the goal of revealing the similarities and dissimilarities between its formal organization and that of classical works. The theoretical work of William E. Caplin informs the analytical methodology of this project, which centers primarily on an examination of formal functions, allowing for the consideration of musical syntax on various hierarchical levels. Ultimately, this project relies on the comparison of typical form-functional organization in classical instrumental works to the events of Mahler's movement with the aim of uncovering his predecessors' influence on the symphony while also revealing the work's relationship to the music of its time.</description><description>Bien que généralement reconnu comme étant une figure clé du modernisme du vingtième siècle, Gustav Mahler (1860–1911) fait souvent usage de techniques compositionnelles classiques dans ses œuvres symphoniques. La Symphonie n°4 est particulièrement remarquable à cet égard et d'innombrables auteurs ont observé la forte présence d'éléments classiques, notamment dans son premier mouvement. Bien qu'une analyse formelle du mouvement d'ouverture de cette symphonie révèle de nombreuses similitudes entre l'organisation de Mahler et les normes structurelles classiques, elle dévoile également un ensemble de pratiques compositionnelles plus caractéristiques du style romantique tardif. Ainsi, alors que certains spécialistes analysent ce mouvement dans la perspective d'une forme sonate typique, l'organisation tonale et formelle relève plus d'une forme sonate-rondo (forme typiquement réservée aux finales et occasionnellement aux mouvements lents). Aussi, Mahler joue avec les attentes de ses auditeurs en incorporant dans son mouvement de nombreuses ambigüités formelles semant ainsi le doute sur la véritable nature fonctionnelle de ces passages. Cette thèse propose une analyse des fonctions formelles du premier mouvement de la Symphonie n°4 de Mahler. Une telle approche permet de mettre en lumière à la fois les similitudes et les différences entre l'organisation formelle de ce mouvement et celle des œuvres classiques. Prenant appui sur les travaux théoriques de William E. Caplin, la méthodologie analytique de ce projet se concentre essentiellement sur l'analyse des fonctions formelles, ce qui permet d'étudier la syntaxe musicale à différents niveaux hiérarchiques. En comparant l'organisation des fonctions formelles de ce mouvement avec celle typique des œuvres instrumentales classiques il devient alors possible de mesurer à la fois l'influence des prédécesseurs sur cette symphonie mais aussi de révéler la relation de l'œuvre avec son répertoire contemporain.</description><creator>Johnston, Erin</creator><contributor>Christoph Neidhofer (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>William Earl Caplin (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Music</subject><title>Form-functional manipulations, deviations, and re-contextualizations in the first movement of Mahler's fourth symphony</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fr09v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p889</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wz089</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse se base sur les données des archives de l'Albanie, de la Bosnie, du Kosovo, du Monténégro et de la Serbie et sur un grand éventail des sources historiques publiées, tant primaires que secondaires. On y emploie la méthode des cas étendus et plusieurs méthodes historico-comparatives afin d'étudier le développement de l'identité nationale albanaise et serbe au cours des deux siècles passés. Notamment, la thèse expose l'émergence et l'évolution des deux mythes nationaux fondamentaux: le conte de l'origine autochtone illyrienne des Albanais et la narration de la Bataille du Kosovo de 1389. L'étude se focalise sur les processus historiques des niveaux micro- et méso, le parcours de vie des créateurs des mythes et les situations historiques spécifiques. La thèse se compose de quatre articles. Dans le premier article, on découvre que le mythe du Kosovo qui est souvent traité comme le cas « crucial » supportant la théorie éthno-symboliste, est un construit idéologique moderne. Le deuxième article introduit la discussion sur la propagation globale du nationalisme qui se développe dans la littérature généraliste, celle consacrée aux études des diasporas et celle du nationalisme à longue distance. Cela suggère que les chercheurs doivent prêter plus d'attention à l'agentevité des membres de diaspora et des migrants à l'extension globale du nationalisme. Le troisième article expose que les archéologues impérialistes ont contribué significativement à la construction de l'identité nationale et à l'établissement de la tradition de la recherche nationaliste en Albanie. Ces conclusions mettent en question la dichotomie entre l'archéologie impérialiste et nationaliste existante dans l'étude critique en archéologie et, plus largement, l'opposition continuelle entre l'impérialisme et le nationalisme dans les sciences humaines générales. Finalement, le quatrième article révèle que l'émergence du contre-mythe albanais sur la Bataille du Kosovo de 1389 à la fin des années 1980 – aux années 1990 est expliquée le mieux par la réaction morale des « saveurs de la nation » autodéclarés en Albanie et Kosovo face à la politisation de l'histoire médiévale dans les milieux intellectuels serbes. L'étude de la mythologie du nationalisme et de l'identité nationale peut gagner, si on analyse soigneusement la dimension morale du nationalisme, l'histoire relativement récente des institutions de socialisation et l'évolution interactive des politiques de l'identité. De façon générale, la thèse propose une explication originale de la face historique et culturellement paroissial du nationalisme. En analysant le parcours de vie des créateurs des mythes nationalistes dans de certaines situations historiques, la thèse découvre que la position sociale des individus et des groupes aux croisements et aux réticules des influences étrangères et nationales, fait naître un nationalisme exclusionnaire. Les mécanismes de ce lien de causalité peuvent être divers: idéationnels, émotionnels, institutionnels et habituels. Plus largement, cette thèse contribue au développement des discussions scientifiques sur le rôle de l'ethnicité au nationalisme, sur l'extension globale du nationalisme, sur la nature du modèle des états-nation, sur les rapports entre l'impérialisme et le nationalisme et sur la nature interactive, processuelle et dynamique du concept de l'identité nationale.</description><description>The dissertation employs comparative historical methods to investigate the development of Albanian and Serbian national identity over the last two centuries. More narrowly, it traces the emergence and evolution of two foundational national myths: the story of the Illyrian origins of the Albanian nation and the narrative of the 1389 Kosovo battle. The study focuses on micro- and meso-level processes, the life course of mythmakers and specific historical situations. For this, it relies on archival data from Albania, Bosnia, Kosovo, Montenegro and Serbia and a wide body of published primary and secondary historical sources. The dissertation is composed of four separate articles. In the first article, I offer evidence that the Kosovo myth, which is often seen as a "crucial" supporting case for ethno-symbolist theory, is a modern ideological construct. The second article contributes to debates on the global spread of nationalism in the generalist, diaspora studies and long-distance nationalism literatures. The article observes that the idea of Illyrian origins was brought to Albania from outside by the early Albanian-speaking diaspora. This suggests that scholars need to pay more attention to the agency of diaspora members and migrants in the global spread of nationalism. The third article discovers that imperialist archaeologists significantly contributed to the construction of national identity and the establishment of the nationalist research tradition in Albania.  These conclusions question the existing dichotomy between imperialism and nationalism in the generalist scholarship. Finally, the fourth article explores the emergence of an Albanian counter-myth in the 1980s and 1990s to the 1389 Kosovo battle narrative. It offers evidence that the counter-myth emerged as a moral reaction of self-perceived "saviors of the nation."  Therefore, the literatures on nationalist mythology and national identity construction can benefit by focusing more on the moral dimension of nationalism, the relatively recent history of socialization institutions, and the interactive dynamics of identity politics. Overall, the dissertation highlights the historical and culturally parochial face of nationalism. Analyzing the life-course of nationalist mythmakers in specific historical situations, the dissertation finds that the social location of individuals and groups at the crossroads and crosshairs of alien and native influences breeds exclusionary nationalism. The mechanisms of this causal link can be diverse: ideational, emotional, institutional, and habitual. More broadly, the dissertation contributes to ongoing scholarly discussions on the role of ethnicity in nationalism, the worldwide spread of nationalism, the nature of the nation-state model, the relationship between imperialism and nationalism and the interactive, processual and dynamic character of nationhood.</description><creator>Lomonosov, Matvey</creator><contributor>Matthew Lange (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Sociology</subject><title>Nationalist crossroads and crosshairs:on external and internal sources of Albanian and Serbian national mythology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1071229.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wz089</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3425</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>