<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:13:06Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5875" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr40b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Individuals with specialized training provide a unique opportunity to investigate training-associated brain plasticity and brain-behaviour relationships. Expert dancers and musicians allow for the study of the brain and behavioural correlates of long-term, intensive practice of sensorimotor skills. This dissertation aims to investigate the behavioural and gray matter structural correlates of dance versus music. This was accomplished by comparing performance on dance- and music- related tasks as well as multiple measures of gray matter structure between expert dancers, expert musicians and untrained controls. Correlations between gray matter structure and task performance were also examined. In the first of three studies, performance on a battery of dance- and music-related tasks was compared between dancers, musicians and controls. Distinct enhancements in sensorimotor skills were observed in both dancers and musicians relative to controls. In the second study, local gray matter structure as measured by voxel- and surface-based morphometry was compared between these groups and correlated with task scores. Both dancers and musicians showed increased cortical thickness in overlapping superior temporal regions relative to controls, and gray matter structure in this area was related to performance on both dance- and music-related tasks. Gray matter concentration in inferior frontal regions was correlated with dance task performance. These results suggest that the superior temporal region may be similarly associated with both dance and music. In addition, dance may possess a unique association with structure in frontal regions. This relationship between dance and structure in frontal regions was furthered by the third study, in which structural covariance networks were investigated in dancers, musicians and controls as well as in correlation with task scores. A unique structural covariance network in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex was observed in dancers. A corresponding correlation between structural covariance in this area and dance task performance was also observed. These results suggest an influence of local training-related factors on structure in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in dancers. They also indicate that the effects of training-associated brain plasticity may include interregional structural relationships in addition to local structural changes. Taken together, these findings suggest that the characteristics that dance and music share (e.g., sensorimotor integration) may be similarly associated with gray matter structure in superior temporal regions. In addition, the characteristics in which dance and music differ (e.g., whole-body versus effector-specific movements, following versus producing sound) may have unique relationships with gray matter structure in frontal regions. These studies corroborate evidence that a multi-method approach increases comprehensiveness and detail of gray matter structural analysis relative to a single measure, as the different measures provided unique but complementary results. The studies in this dissertation were the first to investigate gray matter structure in dancers using multiple measures, correlate gray matter structure to dance ability, and compare the behavioural and gray matter structural correlates of dance versus music. The findings increase understanding of training-associated brain plasticity and brain-behaviour relationships, which can be applied to the development of dance- and music-based therapy programs for clinical populations.</description><description>Les individus ayant suivi une formation spécialisée représentent une opportunité unique pour étudier la plasticité cérébrale associée à l'entrainement, ainsi que les relations entre le comportement et le cerveau. Les danseurs et les musiciens professionnels permettent d'étudier les corrélats comportementaux et cérébraux de la pratique longue et intensive des capacités sensori-motrices. Cette thèse vise à examiner les corrélats comportementaux et structurels de la matière grise de la danse par rapport à ceux de la musique. Pour cela, les performances obtenues lors des tâches liées à la danse et à la musique ont été comparées, ainsi que plusieurs mesures de structure de la matière grise entre des danseurs, des musiciens et des sujets de contrôles non-initiés. Les corrélations entre la structure et la performance obtenue lors des tâches ont également été analysées. Dans la première des trois études, la performance dans une batterie de tâches liées à la danse et à la musique a été comparée entre danseurs, musiciens et sujets de contrôle. Des différentes améliorations des capacités sensori-motrices ont étés observées chez les danseurs et chez les musiciens par rapport au sujets de contrôle. Dans la deuxième étude, la structure locale de la matière grise a été comparée entre ces groupes et mise en corrélation avec la performance mesurée lors des tâches. Les danseurs et les musiciens ont montré une épaisseur corticale plus élevée par rapport aux sujets de contrôle dans des régions temporales supérieures ; la structure dans cette région était aussi en relation avec la performance dans les tâches de danse et de musique. La concentration de la matière grise dans les régions frontales inferieures était en relation avec la performance dans la tâche de danse. Ces résultats suggèrent que la région temporale supérieure peut être associée pareillement à la danse et à la musique. De plus, la danse pourrait être associée de manière unique aux structures frontales. Dans la troisième etude, les réseaux de la covariance structurelle ont étés examinées chez les danseurs, les musiciens et les sujets de contrôle. Un réseau de covariance structurelle spécifique dans le cortex préfrontal dorso-latéral a été observé chez les danseurs. Ces résultats suggèrent une influence, chez les danseurs, des facteurs locaux liés à l'entrainement sur la structure du cortex préfrontal dorso-latéral. Les résultats indiquent également que les effets de la plasticité cérébrale associés à l'entrainement pourraient impliquer des relations structurelles inter-régionales en plus des changements de la structure locale. L'ensemble de ces résultats suggère que les caractéristiques partagées entre la danse et la musique pourraient être associées de façon similaire avec la structure de la matière grise dans les régions temporales supérieures. De plus, les caractéristiques différentes entre danse et musique pourraient présenter des relations uniques avec la structure de la matière grise dans les régions frontales. Ces études, en outre, corroborent l'évidence qu'une approche multi-méthode augmente la compréhensibilité et le détail de l'analyse structurelle de la matière grise par rapport à une simple mesure, puisque les différentes mesures ont fourni des résultats distincts mais complémentaires. Les études présentées dans cette thèse sont les premières à examiner la structure de la matière grise chez les danseurs en utilisant plusieurs mesures, à corréler la structure de la matière grise avec les capacités en danse, et à comparer les corrélats comportementaux et structurels de la matière grise entre la danse et la musique. Les résultats permettent une meilleure compréhension de la plasticité cérébrale associée à l'entrainement et des relations entre comportement et cerveau. Cela peut être appliqué pour développer des programmes de thérapie basés sur la danse et sur la musique.</description><creator>Karpati, Falisha</creator><contributor>Krista Hyde (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>The brain structural and behavioural correlates of specialized training: Dance versus music</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt092.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr40b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451m157</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La Paralysie Cérébrale (PC) est un ensemble de troubles neurologiques le plus commun chez les enfants avec divers déficits sensorimoteurs. Ces déficits influencent les mouvements d'atteinte et la capacité fonctionnelle et la participation sociale. L'utilisation des principes d'apprentissage moteur (répétition, sensation, feedback extrinsèque) modifiant l'exécution du mouvement peut améliorer les capacités fonctionnelles. Le feedback extrinsèque, information additionnelle fournie à l'individu pendant ou après la tâche à diverses fréquences et modalités (ex. visuelle et auditive), est suggéré pour améliorer l'apprentissage moteur chez les enfants avec la PC. Cependant, il y a un manque d'évidence scientifique et une absence de standardisation dans les protocoles de recherche quant aux modalités et fréquences de feedback qui devraient être priorisées. Un projet de recherche robuste, dans lequel la manipulation et la standardisation du feedback extrinsèque sont possibles par le biais des systèmes de réalité virtuelle, est nécessaire. Le principal objectif de cette thèse est d'optimiser l'apprentissage moteur grâce à la manipulation du feedback extrinsèque chez les enfants avec la PC de type hémiplégique légère.  Cette thèse inclut 4 manuscrits: 3 études expérimentales et 1 revue. Le premier manuscrit est une analyse secondaire d'une étude déjà publiée qui évalue le rôle de la sensation pour l'apprentissage moteur du membre supérieur chez un total de 16 enfants avec une PC de type hémiplégique qui ont participé à une intervention (15 h). Les résultats démontrent une association entre le seuil tactile et la proprioception avec le maintien de l'amélioration de la vitesse durant une tâche d'atteinte. Le 2e manuscrit évalue le rôle du feedback extrinsèque sur l'apprentissage moteur du membre supérieur chez les enfants sains et ceux avec la PC qui ont besoin plus d'information sensorielle pour compenser leur sensation diminuée. Les résultats suggèrent un manque de cohérence dans l'utilisation du feedback extrinsèque pour améliorer l'apprentissage moteur. De plus, le feedback en fréquence continue est suggéré au début de l'apprentissage d'une tâche complexe car l'information en continue ne nécessite pas une grande charge cognitive. Cette revue souligne l'importance de développer un projet de recherche qui permet de manipuler diverses modalités et fréquences de feedback extrinsèque.   Le 3e manuscrit compare trois mouvements d'atteinte effectués dans deux environnements (virtuel et physique) chez les enfants sains et ceux avec une légère PC de type hémiplégique. Les mouvements d'atteinte effectués dans un environnement virtuel sont plus lents et nécessitent moins de flexion et rotation du tronc chez les enfants sains. Chez les enfants avec la PC, les trajectoires sont plus courbées et l'utilisation de la flexion et rotation du tronc est moins proéminente. Entre les groupes, le temps des mouvements est un peu plus lent chez les enfants sains.  Considérer ces différences est nécessaire  pour établir un nouveau protocole de recherche avec  objectif d'améliorer les mouvements d'atteinte avec un système de réalité virtuelle.  L'objectif du 4e manuscrit est de déterminer la faisabilité de fournir différentes fréquences de feedback extrinsèque et d'intégrer une courte intervention (7 jours) avec un système de réalité virtuelle chez 7 enfants avec une légère PC de type hémiplégique. Les enfants ont participé à toutes les étapes. Les changements ont été observés dans les tests cliniques et cinématiques. Cette étude pilote démontre la possibilité de manipuler et de standardiser le feedback extrinsèque chez les enfants avec la PC de type hémiplégique et de favoriser l'apprentissage moteur. Les résultats de cette thèse démontrent l'importance d'optimiser les principes d'apprentissage moteur chez les enfants avec une PC de type hémiplégique. L'utilisation des systèmes de réalité virtuelle est proposée pour livrer le feedback extrinsèque. </description><description>Cerebral Palsy (CP) is the most common pediatric neurological disorder with sensorimotor impairments. Collectively, these impairments could alter reaching movements, leading to limited functional activities and participation levels. The use of motor learning principles (e.g., practice intensity and extrinsic feedback) to change movement behaviour may increase functional activity and participation levels. Extrinsic feedback is defined as additional information provided to the individual whether during and/or after performance of a task via different frequencies and modalities (e.g., visual and auditory). Though the provision of extrinsic feedback can improve motor learning in children with CP, there is a lack of standardized research paradigms that examined which types of feedback frequencies and modalities to prioritize. Thus, a more robust research design is needed in which extrinsic feedback can be manipulated and standardized, possibly with the use of virtual reality systems. The global aim of this thesis is to optimize motor learning through the manipulation of extrinsic feedback in children with mild hemiplegic CP.This thesis includes four manuscripts: three experimental studies and one literature review. The first manuscript, consisting of a secondary analysis of an intervention trial, examines the role of sensation on upper limb motor learning in children with hemiplegic CP. Results from 16 children with hemiplegic CP who participated in a 15-hour intervention demonstrated that better tactile thresholds and proprioception were associated with retention of improvements in velocity during a reach-to-grasp task. The second manuscript describes the role of extrinsic feedback on upper limb motor learning in healthy children and in children with CP as the latter group may need additional sensory information to compensate for their reduced sensation. This review indicated that there is a lack of consistency in modalities and in frequencies of feedback delivery for the improvement of motor learning in healthy children and in children with CP. Moreover, the delivery of continuous extrinsic feedback, which requires less cognitive processing, appears to be beneficial when learning a complex task. The results highlighted the need for a research paradigm that directly compares combinations of modalities of and frequencies of extrinsic feedback.The third manuscript presents a comparison between reaching kinematics of three gestures in a virtual reality system to those made in a matched physical environment of healthy children and of children with mild hemiplegic CP. Reaching in the virtual environment was slower and required less trunk flexion and rotation in healthy children. Hand trajectories of children with CP were more curved and less trunk flexion and rotation was used. Between the two populations, the movement time was clinically insignificantly longer in healthy children.  When setting goals or designing protocols to improve reaching with a virtual reality system, movement variables should be considered. The fourth manuscript examines the feasibility of delivering different frequencies of extrinsic feedback and of implementing a short intensive intervention through a virtual reality system for children with mild hemiplegic CP. Seven children with CP participated in a 7-day intervention. Results showed that all participants completed all sessions. Changes were observed in clinical scores and kinematics. This pilot study demonstrated the possibility of manipulating and standardizing extrinsic feedback in children with mild hemiplegic CP to improve their upper limb motor learning. The findings of this thesis highlighted the use of principles to optimize motor learning in children with mild hemiplegic CP and more specifically, the possibility of using a virtual reality system to deliver extrinsic feedback. </description><creator>Robert, Maxime</creator><contributor>Mindy Levin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>The role of feedback on cognitive motor learning in children with Cerebral Palsy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g45t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451m157</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b3561</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this doctorate work I have explored the cortical mechanisms of binocular interactions under normal and imbalanced viewing conditions using a steady state visually evoked response protocol (SSVER) in magnetoencephalograpy (MEG). In order to achieve high localization precision, I used individualized fMRI retinotopic maps for each participants in order to localize the responses obtained in MEG. Using the SSVEP protocol allowed me to tag the response from each eye and investigate its interaction. For all the three studies, I used binary noise stimuli tagged at 4 and 6Hz presented dichoptically and monocularly under varying contrast and luminance conditions. In the first study, I explored the effects of dichoptic masking and monocularly reduced luminance in driving cortical responses in primary visual areas. I observed a monotonic increase in the magnitude of SSVERs with changes in contrast from 0 to 32%. For both eyes, dichoptic masking induced a decrease in SSVER signal power. Reducing mean luminance delayed monocular processing by approximately 38 ms in V1. The reduced luminance also decreased the masking ability of the eye that had the reduced mean luminance. The results demonstrate that the signals resulting from different contrast or luminance stimulation of the two eyes are combined in a way that can be explained by an interocular signal normalization model. In the second study, I recruited observers with amblyopia to assess the characteristics of their latent binocular function using the stimuli at the temporal rate known to bypass the amblyopic suppression. The amblyopia group was compared with a control group with normal binocular vision. I found a normal pattern of dichoptic interaction in the amblyopic visual system when suppressive effects are minimal. However, there was a small imbalance in dichoptic masking; amblyopic eye inhibited the fellow normal eye less than the fellow normal eye inhibited the amblyopic eye.  An interocular processing delay of approximately 20 ms was identified in the amblyopic group. Hence, when suppression is eliminated, the amblyopic visual system exhibits a relatively normal pattern of binocular interactions.  The two differences revealed by MEG were a small dichoptic imbalance favouring the fellow eye and a signal delay in the amblyopic response. In the third study, I investigated the ocular dominance changes following a short term monocular deprivation with an opaque and translucent patch in normal adults. The participants were assessed in MEG before and after the 150 minutes of monocular deprivation.  I show that patching an eye for 2.5 hours modulates dichoptic inhibitory interactions in a reciprocal fashion; the unpatched eye is inhibited, the patched eye is released from inhibition.  Based on the previous work in our lab and other published data, I hypothesized that this effect is due to the changes in contralateral inhibition that shapes the contrast gain of each eye's response before the binocular combination.Based on the results obtained from this work, I have pointed out some future research directions that would be a logical continuity of the presented results. I think future work could explore the use of MEG for personalizing therapy for amblyopia by taking into account not only signal attenuation but also signal delay from the amblyopic eye. </description><description>Dans ce travail de doctorat, j'ai étudié les mécanismes corticaux des interactions binoculaires dans des conditions d'observation normales ou déséquilibrées en utilisant un protocole de réponse visuelle évoquée à régime constant (SSVER) en magnéto-encéphalographie (MEG). Afin d'obtenir une haute précision de localisation, j'ai utilisé des cartes rétinotopiques individuelles d'IRMf pour tous les participants pour localiser les réponses obtenues en MEG. L'utilisation du protocole SSVER m'a permis d'identifier la réponse provenant de chaque œil et d'étudier ses interactions. Pour les trois études, j'ai utilisé des stimuli de bruit binaire marqués à 4 et 6Hz, présentés de façon dichoptique et monoculaire sous différentes conditions de contraste et de luminance. Dans la première étude, j'ai étudié les effets d'un masquage dichoptique et d'une réduction de luminance monoculaire sur la réponse corticale dans les aires visuelles primaires. J'ai observé un accroissement monotone de l'amplitude des SSVER suivant des changements de contraste de 0 à 32 %. Pour les deux yeux, le masquage dichoptique a généré une diminution de la puissance du signal SSVER. Une réduction de luminance a retardé le traitement monoculaire d'approximativement 38ms dans V1. La réduction de luminance a également diminué l'effet de masquage de l'œil dont la luminance a été réduite. Ces résultats démontrent que les signaux résultant de la stimulation à différents contrastes ou luminances des deux yeux sont combinés par un mécanisme qui peut être expliqué par un modèle de normalisation interoculaire.Dans la deuxième étude, j'ai recruté des participants souffrant d'amblyopie afin d'étudier les caractéristiques de leurs fonctions binoculaires latentes en utilisant des stimuli à une fréquence temporelle supposée outrepasser la suppression amblyopique. Le groupe amblyope a été comparé avec un groupe contrôle ayant une vision binoculaire normale. J'ai observé un schéma d'interaction dichoptique normal dans le système visuel amblyope lorsque les effets suppressifs sont minimaux. Cependant, il y avait un léger déséquilibre dans le masquage dichoptique. L'œil amblyope inhibait moins l'œil directeur que ce que l'œil directeur inhibait l'œil amblyope. Un délai de traitement interoculaire d'approximativement 20ms a été identifié dans le groupe amblyope. Ainsi, lorsque la suppression est éliminée, le système visuel amblyope présente un schéma d'interactions binoculaires quasi normal. Les deux différences révélées par la MEG ont été un léger déséquilibre dichoptique en faveur de l'œil directeur et un délai dans la réponse de l'œil amblyope. Dans la troisième étude, J'ai étudié les changements de dominance oculaire engendrés par une occlusion monoculaire à court terme avec un patch opaque ou translucide chez les adultes normaux. Les participants ont été enregistrés en MEG avant et après 150 minutes d'occlusion monoculaire. Je montre que l'occlusion d'un œil pendant 2.5 heures altère les interaction inhibitrices dichoptiques de façon réciproque ; l'œil non-patché est inhibé, l'œil patché est libéré de l'inhibition. En me basant sur des travaux antérieurs dans notre laboratoire et d'autres données de la littérature, je suggère que cet effet est dû à des changements dans l'inhibition controlatérale qui module le gain de la réponse au contraste de chaque œil avant la combinaison binoculaire. En me basant sur les résultats issus de ces travaux, J'ai identifié de futurs axes de recherche formant la suite logique des résultats présentés. Je pense qu'un travail futur pourrait porter sur l'utilisation de la MEG afin de personnaliser les thérapies pour traiter l'amblyopie en prenant en compte non seulement l'atténuation de l'information mais aussi le délai provenant de l'œil amblyope.</description><creator>Chadnova, Eva</creator><contributor>Robert F Hess (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Binocular interactions in normal and abnormal visual systems: MEG investigation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pz580.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b3561</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sg13f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif de cette thèse est d'élargir la classe de schémas à convergence prouvable pour les équations aux dérivées partielles (EDPs) elliptiques, et d'améliorer leur précision. Nous l'accomplissons en nous appuyant sur la théorie de Barles et Souganidis, et l'extension de celle-ci par Froese et Oberman pour construire des schémas monotones et filtrés. Le premier problème considéré est la classe largement étudiée des équations de Hamilton-Jacobi (HJ) du premier ordre. L'objectif est de construire des schémas précis et convergents avec un solveur efficace, en utilisant le grand nombre de discrétisations et de solveurs déjà disponibles. À cette fin, nous construisons des schémas filtrés, dont l'idée principale est de combiner un schéma monotone, convergent, et stable, et un schéma précis, tout en conservant les avantages des deux. On préserve la stabilité et la convergence du premier et la plus grande précision du deuxième. En effet, nous sommes en mesure de construire des schémas de deuxième, troisième et quatrième ordre précis en une dimension, ainsi que des schémas de deuxième ordre précis en deux dimensions. En outre, les schémas sont explicites, ce qui nous permet d'utiliser la méthode dite de "Fast Marching", qui est facile à mettre en oeuvre. En utilisant différents schémas précis (par exemple, à partir de différences centrées standard, de "upwinding" à ordre supérieur, et d'interpolation ENO), la précision des schémas filtrés est validée avec des résultats informatiques pour l'équation eikonal et d'autres équations de HJ (aussi bien en une qu'en deux dimensions). Le deuxième problème considéré est l'équation 2-Hessienne, une EDP entièrement non linéaire associée à la courbure intrinsèque sur des les variétés tridimensionnelles. L'objectif est de construire des méthodes numériques pour en calculer la solution sur un domaine borné, et avec les données à la frontière prescrites. Nous proposons deux méthodes distinctes. On prouve que la première converge à la solution de viscosité unique. Le seconde a une plus grande précision et converge en pratique, mais on manque d'une preuve formelle de convergence. L'EDP est elliptique sur un ensemble restreint de fonctions: une contrainte de type convexe est nécessaire pour l'ellipticité de l'opérateur PDE, ce qui pose des difficultés supplémentaires lors de la construction des méthodes numériques. Les solutions avec les deux discrétisations sont obtenues en utilisant la méthode de Newton. Des résultats numériques sont présentés sur un certain nombre de solutions exactes qui varient en régularité, de lisses à non différentiables, et en forme, de convexes à non convexes.Le troisième et dernier problème consiste à construire un schéma convergent pour l'EDP non linéaire régissant le mouvement des ensembles de niveau par courbure affine. Il est étroitement lié au problème de courbure moyenne, mais présente des instabilités non trouvées dans ce-dernier. Ces instabilités, ainsi que le manque de régularité de l'opérateur de courbure affine, posent des difficultés inattendues et supplémentaires dans la construction de schémas monotones. Un schéma aux différences finies standard est proposé, et on présente un exemple qui illustre son instabilité non linéaire. Nous construisons un schéma aux différences finies monotones, dont on prouve la convergence. Des essais numériques démontrent la précision et la stabilité de la discrétisation, ainsi que le fait que nos solutions approximatives captent l'invariance affine et les propriétés morphologiques de l'évolution.</description><description>The goal of this thesis is to widen the class of provably convergent schemes for elliptic partial differential equations (PDEs) and improve their accuracy. We accomplish this by building on the theory of Barles and Souganidis, and its extension by Froese and Oberman to build monotone and filtered schemes.The first problem considered is the widely studied class of first order Hamilton-Jacobi (HJ) equations. The goal is to construct provably convergent accurate schemes, together with an efficient solver, by making use of the large number of discretizations and solvers already available. To this end, we build filtered schemes, whose main idea is to blend a stable monotone convergent scheme with an accurate scheme while retaining the advantages of both: stability and convergence of the former, and higher accuracy of the latter. Indeed, we are able to build schemes which are second, third, and fourth order accurate in one dimension, as well as schemes that are second order accurate in two dimensions. Moreover, the schemes are explicit, allowing us to use the easy-to-implement fast sweeping method. Using different accurate schemes (e.g. from standard centred differences, higher order upwinding and ENO interpolation), the accuracy of the filtered schemes is validated with computational results for the eikonal equation, as well as other HJ equations (both in one and two dimensions).The second problem considered is the 2-Hessian equation, a fully nonlinear PDE related to the intrinsic curvature for three-dimensional manifolds. The goal is to build numerical methods to compute its solution on a bounded domain given prescribed boundary data. We propose two distinct methods. The first is provably convergent to the unique viscosity solution. The second has higher accuracy and converges in practice, but lacks a formal proof of convergence. The PDE is elliptic on a restricted set of functions: a convexity-type constraint is needed for the ellipticity of the PDE operator, which poses additional difficulties when building the numerical methods. Solutions with both discretizations are obtained using Newton's method. Computational results are presented on a number of exact solutions which range in regularity from smooth to non-differentiable, and in shape from convex to non-convex.The third and last problem is to build a provably convergent scheme for the nonlinear PDE that governs the motion of level sets by affine curvature. It is closely related to mean curvature but exhibits instabilities not found in the former. These instabilities and the lack of regularity of the affine curvature operator posed unexpected and additional difficulties in building monotone schemes. A standard finite difference scheme is proposed and an example that illustrates its nonlinear instability is given. We build provably convergent monotone finite difference schemes. Numerical experiments demonstrate the accuracy and stability of the discretization, as well as the fact that our approximate solutions capture the affine invariance and morphological properties of the evolution.</description><creator>Saldanha Salvador, Tiago Miguel</creator><contributor>Oberman, Adam (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Numerical methods for nonlinear elliptic partial differential equations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xv345.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sg13f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qf56v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La sclérose en plaques (SEP) est une maladie neuro-inflammatoire du système nerveux central (SNC) qui entraîne une destruction ciblée de la myéline et une dégénérescence des neurones. Les changements pathologiques subis au cours de la SEP peuvent entraîner une incapacité importante dans les performances motrices et cognitives, ainsi qu'un dysfonctionnement dans les activités de la vie quotidienne. Malgré les progrès, nous ne comprenons pas encore complètement les facteurs qui interviennent entre les lésions cérébrales et les résultats cliniques. La recherche moderne suggère que ces facteurs incluent la plasticité innée du cerveau et sa capacité à compenser fonctionnellement la neuropathologie liée à la SEP. Des preuves considérables indiquent une activité cérébrale atypique chez les personnes atteintes de SEP, mais sans comprendre le processus par lequel une telle activité est produite, notre compréhension des changements adaptatifs ou inadaptés dans l'activité cérébrale est limitée.Le but de cette dissertation était d'évaluer un mécanisme cérébral qui intégrait des indices liés à la performance pour l'adaptation à l'utilisation de la région atypique du cerveau pendant l'exécution de la tâche. La recherche de Botvinick et ses collègues sur la théorie du contrôle des conflits et modèle de contrôle cognitif ont été appliquées pour évaluer comment les régions impliquées dans la réponse au besoin d'adaptation (anterior cingulate cortex, ACC) et la mise en oeuvre des ressources adaptatives (dorsolateral prefrontal cortex, DLPFC) performance cognitive chez les personnes atteintes de SEP. Les modèles de régression évaluant l'intégrité structurale à l'aide de l'imagerie du taux de transfert de magnétisation provenant de l'ACC et du DLPFC étaient des prédicteurs significatifs de la performance cognitive. Cependant, seul le modèle dans le groupe témoin sain est demeuré significatif après correction pour les variables nuisibles. Aucune valeur additionnelle de comptabilisation de la MTR au sein de l'ACC et DLPFC n'a été trouvée en considérant la neuropathologie de l'ensemble du cerveau. La connectivité fonctionnelle entre l'ACC et le DLPFC était positivement liée à la performance cognitive. La prise en compte de la connectivité fonctionnelle s'est améliorée sur les méthodes existantes d'évaluation des performances cognitives uniquement dans le groupe MS. C'était une découverte robuste, en utilisant plusieurs mesures de neuroimagerie de la neuropathologie liée à la SEP et de la performance comportementale.Ensemble, les résultats suggèrent que la neuropathologie liée à la SEP ne module pas la connectivité fonctionnelle entre l'ACC et le DLPFC et n'est pas responsable des corrélations observées avec la performance cognitive. Au contraire, la présence de la neuropathologie peut créer les conditions d'une altération de la performance cognitive sous laquelle l'importance des mécanismes cérébraux inhérents à l'adaptation est mise en évidence. Des preuves sont avancées à l'appui de la prise en compte de la connectivité fonctionnelle entre ces régions définies par le conflit lorsqu'elles tentent de déterminer l'impact de la neuropathologie liée à la maladie sur le niveau de performance cognitive d'un patient. Les implications pour la recherche future et les soins cliniques des personnes atteintes de SEP sont discutées.</description><description>Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a neuroinflammatory disease of the central nervous system (CNS) that involves a targeted destruction of myelin and degeneration of neurons. The pathological changes sustained during MS can lead to substantial disability in motor and cognitive performance, as well as dysfunction in activities of daily living. Despite progress, we still do not fully understand the factors that intervene between brain injury and clinical outcomes. Modern research suggests that these factors include the brains' innate plasticity and its ability to functionally compensate for MS-related neuropathology.  Considerable evidence points to atypical brain activity in persons with MS, however without understanding the process through which such activity is produced, our understanding of adaptive- or maladaptive – changes in brain activity is limited. The aim of this dissertation was to evaluate a brain mechanism that integrated performance-related cues for adaptation with the use of atypical brain region during task performance. The theoretical tenets of Botvinick and colleagues theory of conflict monitoring and cognitive control model were applied to evaluate how brain regions implicated in responding to the need for adaptation (anterior cingulate cortex; ACC) and implementing adaptive resources (dorsolateral prefrontal cortex; DLPFC) relate to cognitive performance in persons with MS. Regression models evaluating structural integrity using Magnetization Transfer Ratio imaging from the ACC and DLPFC were significant predictors of cognitive performance. However, only the model in the healthy control group remained significant after correcting for nuisance variables. No additional value of accounting for MTR within the ACC and DLPFC was found when considering whole-brain neuropathology. Functional connectivity between the ACC and DLPFC was positively related with cognitive performance. Accounting for functional connectivity improved on existing methods of evaluating cognitive performance only in the MS group. This was a robust finding, using multiple neuroimaging measures of MS-related neuropathology and of behavioral performance. Together, findings suggest that MS-related neuropathology does not modulate the functional connectivity between the ACC and DLPFC and is not responsible for observed correlations with cognitive performance. Rather, the presence of neuropathology may create the conditions for impaired cognitive performance under which the importance of inherent brain mechanisms for adaptation are highlighted. Evidence is put forward in support of considering the functional connectivity between these conflict-defined regions when attempting to determine the impact of disease-related neuropathology on a patients' level of cognitive performance. Implications for future research and clinical care of persons with MS are discussed. </description><creator>Holmes, Scott</creator><contributor>Lisa Koski (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Adaptation to neuropathology in patients with multiple sclerosis: Evaluating a conflict-based mechanism of performance monitoring in the central nervous system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w7121.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qf56v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nt47w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The maturation of ecosystems can be associated with increased connectedness and destabilizing feedbacks from biogenic habitat modification. Over regional scales, resulting disturbances can translate into strong spatial fluxes of ecosystem resources. Using a mechanistic meta-ecosystem model of rocky shore mussel beds, I explore the implications of ecosystem engineering for spatial synchrony and regional matter circulation. At the local scale, I find that aggregated mussel recruitment and feedback from biodeposition and sedimentation can lead to rare and catastrophic fluctuations of population abundance and strong spatial fluxes of (in)organic matter. At the regional scale, I show that resulting dynamics can maintain spatial heterogeneity under strong biotic and abiotic regional connectivity. This is characterized by non-stationary time series and a modulation of spatial synchrony. By explicitly considering stocks and fluxes of engineered matter, I show that biogenic habitat modification interacts with spatial synchrony to determine the turnover and spatial distribution of (in)organic matter. These results suggest that resolving the implications of regional connectivity for population persistence, habitat structure, and resources availability requires considering how ecosystem engineering interacts with the stability and the connectivity of natural systems.</description><description>La maturation des écosystèmes peut être associée à l'augmentation du nombre et de l'intensité des interactions écologiques et à des retombées déstabilisantes des altérations biotiques de la structure des habitats. À l'échelle régionale, les perturbations associées à la maturité des écosystèmes peuvent se traduire par une redistribution spatiale des ressources écosystémiques. À l'aide d'un modèle méta-écosystémique décrivant les dynamiques de bancs de moules en milieux rocheux, j'examine l'impact des ingénieurs écosystémiques sur la synchronie spatiale et sur la circulation régionale de la matière. À l'échelle locale, je montre que les effets structuraux de la biodéposition et de la sédimentation ainsi que les processus d'agrégation qui gouvernent le recrutement au sein des bancs de moules peuvent entraîner des fluctuations importantes d'abondance. Ces perturbations ponctuelles résultent en des épisodes intenses de relâchement et de transport de la matière (in)organique. À l'échelle régionale, ces dynamiques génèrent une hétérogénéité spatiale robuste à la connectivité régionale. On observe alors des séries temporelles non stationnaires et une modulation de la synchronie spatiale. En examinant les stocks et les flux de matière (in)organique, je montre que l'ingénierie locale de la matière et la synchronie des flux régionaux interagissent afin de déterminer la rétention régionale de la matière. Ces résultats suggèrent que l'intégration du concept d'ingénieurs écosystémiques à la théorie des méta-écosystèmes pourrait apporter une meilleure compréhension des impacts du mouvement régional des organismes et de la matière sur la persistance des populations, sur la structure des habitats ainsi que sur la disponibilité des ressources à l'échelle régionale.</description><creator>Massé Jodoin, Julien</creator><contributor>Frederic Guichard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>Non-equilibrium dynamics in engineered meta-ecosystems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v44z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nt47w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb82q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metallic plasmonic nanostructures continue to fascinate scientists and draw efforts into their smart design and assembly owing to their ability to enhance light manipulation and confinement in small volumes. Plasmonic interactions may be exploited in light-based photonic devices, where the miniaturization of photonic structures is essential to increase their sensitivity and speed. Common dielectric waveguides are restricted by the diffraction limit of light, which, for visible light, is several hundreds of nanometres. For nanodevices, much smaller photonic elements are sought through extended planar structures capable of light guiding. The flux of surface plasmons can be tuned and acclimatized for a desired purpose by the controlled organization of metallic nanoparticles into higher order arrays and assemblies. The self-assembly of simple nanoparticle building blocks could provide an inexpensive means to achieve this goal. This thesis showcases the plasmon tuning of silver nanostructures via either their in-solution assembly into extended networks or shaping them into ring geometries.   In chapters three through five, we generate and examine, both experimentally and theoretically, extended anisotropic silver nanoparticle assemblies in solution using controlled amounts of one of three inexpensive, widely available, and environmentally benign short ditopic ligands: cysteamine, dithiothreitol and cysteine in aqueous solution. The self-assembly of the extended structures is enforced by hydrogen bonding. Varying the ligand concentration modulates the extent and density of these unprecedented anisotropic structures. Our results show a correlation between the chain nature of the assembly and the generation of spectral anisotropy. Deuterating the ligand further enhances the anisotropic signal by triggering more compact aggregates and reveals the importance of solvent interactions in assembly size and morphology. Spectroscopic measurements are compared to calculations of the absorption spectra of randomly assembled silver chains and aggregates based on the discrete dipole approximation. The models support the experimental findings and reveal the importance of aggregate size and shape as well as particle polarizability in the plasmon coupling between nanoparticles. In the fifth chapter, we present a more insightful data on the optical response of the silver nanoparticles assemblies via dark-field spectroscopic measurements on individual silver clusters of known morphologies and configuration. In the sixth chapter, we present our work on utilizing the tobacco mosaic virus coat protein as a command surface to grow and assemble silver nanoparticles into sub-30 nm rings. Plasmonic ring structures have stimulated rapid growth in the field of plasmonics due to their great impact on sensing, lasing, and nonlinear optics technologies. The fabrication of plasmonic nanorings remains of substantial interest by virtue of their enhanced electric and magnetic response to light fields which can be subsequently exploited in diverse applications. Scaling down the size of nanorings holds promise in creating artificial magnetism at wavelengths matching the solar spectrum. Nanosized bioscaffolds can be utilized to tackle the challenge of size reduction of metallic rings owing to their miniature features as well as their well-known biomineralization capacity. The versatility of TMV allows the formation of both solid rings and rings consisting of discrete nanoparticles that are characterized by UV–vis and TEM. The pH-dependent coulombic surface map along with the annular geometry of the protein aggregate allow the generation of rings with or without a central nanoparticle. Our silver rings are believed to be the smallest to date, and they can offer a test material for existing theories on metallic nanorings of this heretofore unreached size scale.</description><description>Les nanostructures métalliques continuent à fasciner les scientifiques et à attirer leurs efforts dans leur conception et leur assemblage intelligents en raison de leur guider la lumière et en restant compacte dans de petits volumes. Les interactions plasmiques peuvent être exploitées dans des dispositifs photoniques à base de lumière, où la miniaturisation des structures photoniques est essentielle pour augmenter leur sensibilité et leur rapidité. Les guides d'ondes diélectriques conventionels sont limités par d'une longueure d'onde de la lumière qui, pour la lumière visible, est dans l'ordre de plusieurs centaines de nanomètres. Pour les nanodispositifs, des éléments photoniques beaucoup plus petits sont recherchés à travers des structures planes étendues capables de guider la lumière. Le flux de plasmons de surface peut être ajusté et acclimaté dans un but souhaité par l'organisation contrôlée de nanoparticules métalliques dans des tableaux et ensembles d'ordre supérieur. L'auto-assemblage de blocs simples de nanoparticules pourrait constituer un moyen peu coûteux pour atteindre cet objectif. Cette thèse présente le modelage de plasmon des nanostructures d'argent via leur assemblage en solution dans des réseaux étendus ou en les façonnant dans des géométries en anneau. Dans les chapitres trois à cinq, nous générons et examinons, à la fois expérimentalement et théoriquement, des ensembles de nanoparticules d'argent anisotropes en solution en utilisant des quantités contrôlées d'un des trois ligands ditopiques courts peu coûteux, largement disponibles et respectueux de l'environnement: cysteamine, dithiothréitol et cystéine en solution aqueuse. L'auto-assemblage des structures est guidé par des liaisons d'hydrogene. La variation de la concentration de ligand modulant l'étendue et la densité de ces structures anisotropes sont sans précédent. Nos résultats montrent une corrélation entre la nature de la chaîne d'assemblage et la génération de l'anisotropie spectrale. Les mesures spectroscopiques sont comparées aux calculs des spectres d'absorption des chaînes et des agrégats d'argent assemblés de manière aléatoire sur la base de DDA. Les modèles soutiennent les résultats expérimentaux et révèlent l'importance de la taille et de la forme agrégées ainsi que de la polarisation des particules dans le couplage plasmon entre les nanoparticules. Dans le cinquième chapitre, nous présentons des données plus approfondies sur la réponse optique des assemblages de nanoparticules d'argent via des mesures spectroscopiques de « dark-field » sur des agglomérats d'argent individuelles de morphologies et de configurations connues. Dans le sixième chapitre, nous présentons notre travail sur l'utilisation de la protéine du TMV comme matrice pour assembler des nanoparticules d'argent dans des anneaux de moins de 30 nm. Les structures en anneaux plasmiques ont stimulé une croissance rapide dans le domaine de la plasmonique en raison de leur impact considérable sur les technologies optiques de détection, d'analyse laser et non linéaire. La fabrication d'anneaux plasmoniques reste d'un intérêt considérable en raison de leur réponse électrique et magnétique accrue aux champs légers qui peuvent ensuite être exploités dans diverses domains. La réduction de la taille d'anneaux est prometteuse dans la création d'un magnétisme artificiel à des longueurs d'ondes correspondant au spectre solaire. La polyvalence du TMV permet la fabrication d'anneaux solides et d'anneaux composés de nanoparticules caractérisées par UV-vis et TEM. Nos anneaux d'argent sont considérés comme les plus petits à ce jour, et ils peuvent offrir un matériel de test pour les théories existantes sur les anneaux microscopiques métalliques de cette échelle de taille jusqu'alors non atteinte.</description><creator>Bayram, Sirine</creator><contributor>Amy Blum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Solution-phase assemblies of silver nanoparticles for plasmon tuning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c83w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb82q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732dc38t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des études récentes ont indiqué que les trois domaines Cut de la protéine CUX1 interagissent avec la glycosylase du 8-oxoguanine (OGG1) et stimulent ses activités enzymatiques de glycosylase et de AP/lyase. Ces activité enzymatiques consistent dans l'enlèvement de la base oxydée, suivi d'une coupure simple brin afin d'initier la voie de réparation par l'excision des bases (« base excision repair, BER »). J'ai démontré que les fibroblastes d'embryon de souris Cux1-/- proliféraient à 3% d'oxygène, mais pas du tout à la concentration de 20% d'oxygène de l'atmosphère. J'ai montré que les domaines CUT sont rapidement recrutés aux sites de dommages à l'ADN et accélèrent la réparation de bases oxydées. J'ai aussi montré que le paralogue CUX2 interagit avec OGG1 et stimule ses activités enzymatiques. J'ai ensuite étudié la protéine SATB1 qui elle contient deux domaines CUT. La répression de SATB1 par shRNA cause un délai dans la réparation de l'ADN suite à l'exposition au H2O2, une augmentation du nombre de bases oxydées dans l'ADN génomique et une diminution de l'activité de l'OGG1 détectée dans les extraits cellulaires. J'ai aussi observé une augmentation des niveaux de CHK1 phosphorylé et de γ-H2AX ainsi qu'une diminution de la synthèse de l'ADN. À l'inverse, la surexpression de SATB1 accélère la réparation de l'ADN et réduit le nombre de bases oxydées dans l'ADN génomique. De plus, la protéine de fusion eGFP-SATB1 est rapidement recrutée aux dommages à l'ADN produits par la microirradiation au laser. Des manipulations avec des protéines purifiées ont établi que SATB1 interagit directement avec OGG1, augmente la liaison d'OGG1 avec l'ADN qui contient une base 8-oxoguanine, facilite la formation d'une base de Schiff et stimule les activités enzymatiques de glycosylase et de AP/lyase d'OGG1. Des tests de clivage in vitro avec des protéines purifiées ont révélé que les domaines CUT stimulent aussi l'activité du deuxième enzyme de la voie de réparation par l'excision des bases, APE1 ("apurinic/apyrimidinic endonuclease 1"). En accord avec ces résultats, répression de CUX1 par shRNA cause une augmentation des sites abasiques dans l'ADN génomique et une diminution de l'activité de l'APE1 détectée dans les extraits cellulaires. À l'inverse, la surexpression de CUX1 augmente l'activité de l'APE1 et diminue le nombre de sites abasiques dans l'ADN génomique. Le gène CUX1 se situe à 7q22.1, la région chromosomique la plus fréquemment et hautement amplifiée dans les glioblastomes. Des tests d'immunohistochimie sur une micropuce contenant 150 glioblastomes ont démontré que la protéine CUX1 est fortement exprimée dans ce type de tumeurs. Comme la résistance des glioblastomes au traitement avec l'agent mono-alkylant témozolomide est déterminée dans une certaine mesure par l'activité de l'APE1, j'ai décidé d'étudier les effets de la répression ou la surexpression de CUX1 sur la résistance des glioblastomes au témozolomide. Ces expériences ont établi que la répression de CUX1 diminue, alors que la surexpression de CUX1 augmente, la résistance des glioblastomes au témozolomide. De plus, une petite protéine recombinante ne contenant que deux domaines CUT, laquelle est active dans la réparation de l'DNA mais pas dans la régulation transcriptionnelle, est suffisante pour augmenter la résistance au témozolomide. Ces résultats démontrent que les niveaux d'expression de CUX1 ont un impact sur la résistance des glioblastomes au témozolomide et établissent que les domaines CUT représentent une cible thérapeutique potentielle. </description><description>The three CUT domains within CUX1 were shown to interact with the base excision repair (BER) enzyme, 8-oxoguanine DNA glycosylase (OGG1), and stimulate its glycosylase and AP/lyase enzymatic activities. These activities process the removal of the oxidized base lesion 8-oxoguanine and the subsequent strand incision step. We showed that Cux1-/- mouse embryonic fibroblasts proliferate poorly in hyperoxia (20% oxygen). In addition, we showed that CUT domains accelerate DNA repair of oxidized bases and are recruited to DNA damage sites in cells, underscoring the role of CUX1 in oxidative stress. We also showed that the CUX1 paralog CUX2 interacts with OGG1 and stimulates its enzymatic activities. We extended these findings to the protein SATB1, which contains two CUT domains. SATB1 knockdown caused a delay in DNA repair following exposure to H2O2, an increase in OGG1-sensitive oxidized bases within genomic DNA, and a decrease in OGG1 cleavage activity in cell extracts. In parallel, we observed an increase in phospho-CHK1 and γ-H2AX levels and a decrease in DNA synthesis. Conversely, ectopic expression of SATB1 accelerated DNA repair and reduced the levels of oxidized bases in genomic DNA. Moreover, an eGFP-SATB1 fusion protein was rapidly recruited to laser microirradiation-induced DNA damage. Using purified proteins, we showed that SATB1 interacts directly with OGG1, increases OGG1 binding to 8-oxoguanine containing DNA, promotes Schiff base formation and stimulates OGG1 glycosylase and AP/lyase enzymatic activities. Structure/function analysis demonstrated that CUT domains, but not the homeodomain, are responsible for the stimulation of OGG1 activity. Using in vitro incision assays with purified proteins, we established that the CUT domains also stimulate the activity of the second enzyme in the BER pathway, apurinic/apyrimidinic endonuclease 1 (APE1). In agreement with these findings, CUX1 knockdown causes an increase in the number of abasic sites in genomic DNA and a decrease in APE1 activity as measured in cell extracts. Conversely, ectopic CUX1 expression increases APE1 activity and lowers the number of abasic sites in genomic DNA. CUX1 resides on 7q22.1, the most frequently and highly amplified chromosomal region in glioblastomas. Using immunohistochemistry, we showed that CUX1 proteins are highly expressed in a tumor microarray of 150 glioblastoma samples. The resistance of glioblastoma cells to the mono-alkylating agent temozolomide is determined to some extent by the activity of APE1. The effect of CUX1 knockdown and overexpression on the resistance of glioblastoma cell lines to temozolomide was investigated. We found that CUX1 knockdown decreases, whereas CUX1 overexpression increases, the resistance of glioblastoma cells to temozolomide. Moreover, a short protein containing only two CUT domains, which is active in DNA repair but devoid of transcriptional activity, is still able to increase the resistance to temozolomide. These findings indicate that CUX1 expression level impacts on the response of glioblastoma cells to temozolomide treatment and identify the CUT domains as potential therapeutic targets.</description><creator>Kaur, Simran</creator><contributor>Alain Nepveu (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>The role of cut repeat proteins in DNA repair and resistance to treatments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268778f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732dc38t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m443k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le hockey sur glace impose un stress physiologique continu aux athlètes et laisse peu de temps pour la récupération ce qui peut causer de la fatigue et affecter la condition physique. Le suivi de la réponse physiologique à un effort sous-maximal et de la composition corporelle chez les joueurs de hockey universitaire peux refléter les changements de la condition physique.  L'évaluation de la condition physique durant la saison peut aider les joueurs, les entraîneurs et les préparateurs physiques à mieux adapter le programme d'entraînement pour optimiser la performance et le bien-être des joueurs. Deux différentes études ont pris place durant cette investigation. Le but de la première étude était d'identifier les changements de la réponse physiologique à l'effort et du profil de la composition corporelle durant la saison parmi des joueurs de hockey universitaire masculin et féminin. Aussi, le but était d'identifier les différences entre les sexes. Le but de la deuxième étude était de déterminer les changements de la perception de la charge interne durant un test d'effort sous-maximale de 4 minutes au cours de la saison.  Lors de la première étude, quarante-quatre joueurs, vingt-quatre hommes et vingt femmes, ont participé au test sous-maximal de 4 minutes ainsi qu'à l'évaluation de la composition corporelle à chacune des trois sessions (pré-saison, mi-saison et fin de la saison).  Les changements des paramètres physiologiques et de la composition corporelle ont été analysés à l'aide du test statistique ANCOVA à mesures répétés en contrôlant pour l'âge. Les hommes ont diminué leur taux de lactate dans le sang (p ≤ 0.05) à la mi-saison en comparaison avec la présaison, alors que les deux sexes l'ont augmenté (p ≤ 0.05) à la fin de la saison en comparaison avec la mi-saison.  La fréquence cardiaque a augmenté (p ≤ 0.05) après la 3ième et la 4ième minute du test chez les hommes et les femmes. Le pourcentage de gras a diminué (p ≤ 0.05) chez les hommes à la mi-saison, alors que les deux sexes ont augmenté (p ≤ 0.05) à la fin de la saison en comparaison avec la mi-saison. L'étude démontre que la réponse physiologique à l'effort ainsi que la composition corporelle des joueurs de hockey universitaire changent durant la saison de compétition. Une diminution de la condition physique a été observée chez les deux sexes lors de la 2ième moitié de la saison. Lors de la deuxième étude, des ratios de la charge interne était calculés à partir du test d'effort de la première étude. Aussi, les participants ont complété un questionnaire sur leur fatigue subjective au repos. Les changements des ratios de la charge interne et du questionnaire ont été analysés à l'aide du test statistique ANCOVA à mesures répétés en contrôlant pour l'âge et le sexe. Les ratios HR-RPE après la 1ière et la 2ième minute et le ratio BL-RPE étaient plus bas à la fin de la saison en comparant avec la pré-saison (p ≤ 0.05). Mettre une évaluation de l'effort subjective (RPE) en relation avec un paramètre physiologique (HR, BL) peut être une manière efficace d'évaluer la charge interne et la fatigue des joueurs de hockey universitaire. Les résultats de chacune de ces études peuvent avoir des utilités pour la performance des joueurs de hockey universitaire et peuvent aider à mieux adapter les programmes d'entraînement. Maintenir un niveau optimal de condition physique durant la saison de compétition pourrait aider les performances sportives des joueurs. </description><description>Ice hockey continually overloads the athletes with limited time for recovery, which may induce fatigue and affect the physical condition. The monitoring over time of collegiate hockey player's physiological responses to submaximal stress and body composition can reflect physical fitness fluctuations. In-season physical fitness assessments can help players, team coaches or strength and conditioning professional better tailor their training program to optimize performance and well-being among their players. Two separate studies took place in this investigation. The first study's purpose was to identify changes in physiological responses and body composition profiles over the competitive season in male and female collegiate ice hockey players and to identify between-sex differences. The second study's purpose was to determine the changes in internal load perception during a short 4-minute submaximal physiological assessment over a competitive season in collegiate ice hockey players. In the first study, forty-four players, twenty-four males, and twenty females participated in 4-minutes submaximal exercise tests and body composition assessment at pre-season, mid-season and end-season. Changes in physiological parameters and body composition were analyzed using repeated measures ANCOVA controlling for age and between-sex mean changes were analyzed using one-way ANOVA. Men's post-exercise blood lactate concentration decreased (p ≤ 0.05) from pre- to mid-season and both sexes increased (p ≤ 0.05) the concentration from mid- to end-season. Heart rate increased (p ≤ 0.05) after the 3rd and 4th minutes of the test in both sexes from pre- to end-season and from mid- to end-season. Males' body fat percentage decreased (p ≤ 0.05) from pre- to mid-season, while increases were observed (p ≤ 0.05) in both sexes from mid- to end-season. This study produced evidence that male and female collegiate hockey athletes' physiological responses and body composition profiles change over the season. Detraining was observed in both sexes in the second half of the season. In the second study, from the previous study, internal load ratios were created from the 4-minutes submaximal exercise and participants completed a subjective fatigue questionnaire before physical testing at pre-season, mid-season, and end-season. Changes in the internal load ratios and subjective fatigue scores at the three time-points were analyzed using repeated measures ANCOVA controlling for age and sex. HR-RPE ratio after the 1st and 2nd minute were lower at end-season compared to pre-season (F (1,41) =2.855, p ≤ 0.05). BL-RPE ratio was higher at mid-season compared to pre-season (F (1,41) =2.855, p ≤ 0.05), was lower at end-season compared to mid-season. A subjective rating (RPE) of effort in relation to physiological responses (HR, BL) might be an efficient way of assessing internal loading and fatigue in collegiate hockey players. The findings of each study can have important implications for the performance and well-being of collegiate athletes and help team coaches better tailor training programs. Maintaining an ideal level of physical fitness throughout the competitive university season would help the collegiate player maintain or improve both athletic and academic performance, increase their health, well-being, and reduce fatigue. </description><creator>Delisle-Houde, Patrick</creator><contributor>Ross Andersen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Seasonal changes of physical fitness attributes in collegiate ice hockey players</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b595t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m443k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x171c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse fait progresser la connaissance de deux transformations fondamentalement importantes en chimie organique : (1) la rupture des liaisons carbone-oxygène et (2) la formation de liaisons carbone-carbone. Une telle avancée repose sur quatre réactions hautement originales de réaction catalysées par des métaux de transition, à partir de matière première et de dérivés chimiques composés d'atome d'oxygène. Le développement de toutes ces méthodes de synthèse sera discuté chapitre par chapitre. Le chapitre 2 présente nos premières tentatives pour aborder un défi scientifique datant de 40 ans dans le domaine de la désoxygénation d'alcools: comment éliminer sélectivement et efficacement les groupes hydroxyles dans les molécules organiques. Pour résoudre ce problème, nous proposons un processus redox en une seule étape combinant l'oxydation déshydrogénante d'alcools suivie de la réduction de Wolff-Kishner. Le développement de la réaction catalysée par un complexe d'iridium et assistée par l'intermédiaire d'hydrazine dans de fortes conditions oxydantes, démontre la faisabilité de notre hypothèse. Ce protocole de désoxygénation s'avère efficace pour une large gamme de fonctions alcools activées, telles que les fonctions alcools benzyliques et allyliques. Le chapitre 3 décrit l'adaptation de la catalyse au ruthénium(II) pour la désoxygénation directe d'alcools primaires et aliphatiques. Il a été vital de développer un système catalytique robuste comprenant du [Ru(p-cymene)Cl2]2 et du dmpe. La combinaison de t-BuOK, DMSO et t-BuOH, est tout aussi importante. Par conséquent, cette méthode est nettement plus fonctionnelle, vis-à-vis du précédent protocole reposant sur la catalyse à l'iridium, en opérant dans des conditions thermiques nettement plus douces. Son utilité synthétique est démontrée avec élégance par la scission sélective des liaisons carbone-oxygène dans des molécules organiques simples et complexes telles que les stéroïdes et les alcaloïdes. Le chapitre 4 présente une nouvelle approche pour utiliser les composés carbonylés naturels en tant que source masquée de carbanion pour la formation de liaisons carbone-carbone, via des réactions d'addition sur des dérivés carbonylés. Traditionnellement, de telles transformations ne sont possibles qu'avec des réactifs organométalliques, composés de matières premières dérivées du pétrole et d'une quantité stœchiométrique de métal. En ajustant la basicité dans le système réactionnel, les dérivés d'hydrazones, préformés, s'additionnent à d'autres composés carbonylés pour former de nouvelles liaisons carbone-carbone. Cette addition est accomplie par l'intermédiaire d'un état de transition Zimmerman-Traxler, en forme chaise. Une large gamme d'alcools secondaires et tertiaires, possédant une grande valeur synthétique, est fournie dans des conditions réactionnelles très douces grâce à cette transformation unique. Parmi les autres points saillants, figurent une excellente compatibilité des groupes fonctionnels et un bon contrôle stéréochimique, contrôlé par des ligands chiraux amide et phosphine.Le chapitre 5 se concentre sur l'exploration plus approfondie de la réactivité 'umpolung' pour la formation de liaisons carbone-carbone, via des réactions d'addition conjuguées. Inspiré par la nature molle du pré-catalyseur au ruthénium(II), on suppose que le système catalytique à base de ruthénium(II) peut être plus efficace afin de mener des additions nucléophiles conjuguées. En effet, pour la première fois, des composés carbonylés aromatiques hautement fonctionnalisés sont utilisés en tant que carbanions benzyliques masqués pour s'additionner à des composés α, β-insaturés possédants des groupes déficients en électrons, comme des esters, des cétones, des sulfones, des phosphonates et des amides. Le chapitre 6 résume toutes les recherches présentées dans cette thèse et les contributions à l'avancement des connaissances.</description><description>This thesis advances the knowledge in two fundamentally important organic chemical transformations: (1) cleavage of carbon-oxygen bonds and (2) formation of carbon-carbon bonds. Such advancement consists of four late transition metal-catalyzed reactions based on the oxygenated chemical feedstock, which will be discussed on a chapter-by-chapter basis. Chapter 2 introduces our initial attempts to address a 40-year-old scientific challenge in the field of alcohol deoxygenation: how to selectively and efficiently remove hydroxyl groups in organic molecules without affecting other existing functional groups. We hypothesize a single-step, redox process to solve this problem, whereby the dehydrogenative oxidation of alcohols and the Wolff-Kishner reduction are combined. As a proof-of-concept discovery, the early development of this reaction is catalyzed by iridium complexes and mediated by hydrazine under forcing reaction conditions. This deoxygenation protocol proves effective for many simple activated substrates such as benzylic and allylic alcohols. The major limitation, however, is the poor reactivity and selectivity seen in aliphatic alcohol substrates. Chapter 3 describes the adaptation of ruthenium(II) catalysis for the direct deoxygenation of primary aliphatic alcohols in a completely chemo- and regio-selective manner. Such a robust catalytic system, comprising [Ru(p-cymene)Cl2]2 and 1,2-bis(dimethylphosphino)ethane, is vital to lower the activation energy barriers to the dehydrogenative oxidation of aliphatic alcohols, and makes this step more kinetically favorable. Equally important is the combination of KOt-Bu, DMSO and t-BuOH, which promotes the subsequent Wolff-Kishner reduction at low temperature. This method is thus more practical compared with the iridium-based protocol, proceeding under milder thermal conditions. Its synthetic utility is demonstrated by the selective cleavage of carbon-oxygen bonds in both simple and complex organic molecules such as steroids and alkaloids. Chapter 4 presents a synthetic approach to utilize naturally occurring carbonyl compounds (i.e. aldehydes and ketones) as more sustainable alkyl carbanion equivalents for formation of carbon-carbon bonds via carbonyl addition reactions. Traditionally, such transformations depend on organometallic reagents which are made from petroleum-derived chemical feedstocks and a stoichiometric quantity of metal. Accessing this new chemical reactivity of carbonyl compounds attributes to the ruthenium(II) catalytic system discovered in the early deoxygenation chemistry. By controlling the basicity, preformed carbonyl-derived hydrazones can intercept another carbonyl compounds to form new carbon-carbon bonds via a Zimmerman-Traxler chair-like transition state. This chemical transformation delivers a wide range of synthetically valuable secondary and tertiary alcohols. Additional highlights include excellent functional group compatibility and good stereochemical control governed by chiral amido and phosphine ligands. Chapter 5 focuses on the further exploration of such unique 'umpolung' reactivity for formation of carbon-carbon bonds via conjugate addition reactions. Inspired by the softness of ruthenium(II) pre-catalyst, which bears a resemblance to that of 'soft' transition metals in the classical 1,4-conjugate addition, we presume that this ruthenium(II)-based catalytic system may be more effective for conducting nucleophilic conjugate additions. Indeed, a variety of highly functionalized aromatic carbonyl compounds are used as latent benzyl carbanions, to couple with electron-deficient α,β-unsaturated compounds including esters, ketones, sulfones, phosphonates, and amides. Two bidentate phosphine ligands (dppp and dmpe) are found to facilitate this process in a complementary manner, largely depending on electronic profiles of the carbonyl compounds. Chapter 6 summarizes all research present in this thesis and contributions to knowledge advancement. </description><creator>Dai, Xi-Jie</creator><contributor>Chaojun Li (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Exploring oxygenated compounds for efficient transition metal-catalyzed molecular transformations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g956.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x171c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s0047</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Par rapport aux personnes en bonne santé, les patients atteints de la Fibrose Kystique (FK) subissent des exacerbations pulmonaires fréquentes et sont affectés par un volume expiratoire réduit de 1 seconde (FEV1), qui est la principale mesure pronostique de la fonction pulmonaire. Il a été démontré que l'activité physique atténue le taux de déclin de FEV1 chez les patients FK. Malgré le fait que les patients atteints de FK aient montré de l'activité physique d'intensité légère semblable à celle de leurs homologues en bonne santé, il a été démontré qu'ils passaient moins de temps à pratiquer de l'activité physique d'intensité modérée à vigoureuse. Ces résultats ont été soutenus grâce à la base de données recueillies pour la composante locale lors de l'essai international de contrôle aléatoire, ACTIVATE-CF, pour lequel les patients atteints de FK ont été quelque peu actifs, mais ont passé un temps minimal à être très actif. En utilisant des données recueillies à partir d'une étude réalisée par McIlwaine et al. (2013), nous avons visé à déterminer les prédicteurs de la fonction pulmonaire et de l'activité physique dans des patients atteints de FK. En utilisant le composant local de l'étude ACTIVATE-CF, nous avons aussi visé à déterminer si un programme d'exercice de 6-mois partiellement surveillé consistant d'un composant de motivation peut motiver des patients atteints de FK d'augmenter leurs niveaux d'activité physique et améliorer leur fonction pulmonaire. Nous formulons l'hypothèse que la saisonnalité et la fonction pulmonaire auront un impact sur les niveaux d'activités physique des patients atteints de FK. Nous formulons aussi l'hypothèse que le programme d'exercice motivera les patients atteints de FK d'augmenter leurs niveaux d'activité physique et améliorera leur fonction pulmonaire. Les résultats de l'analyse des données recueillies par l'étude de McIlwaine et al. (2013) ont déterminé que l'âge permet de prédire le temps passé comme plus ou moins actif alors que la fonction pulmonaire et les changements saisonniers permettent de prévoir le temps passé comme très actif chez les patients FK. D'ailleurs, le temps passé comme très actif, le type de technique de dégagement de voies aériennes, et l'âge permettent de prédire la fonction pulmonaire. Les résultats de cette étude démontrent que chez les patients atteints de FK, les changements saisonniers et la diminution de la fonction pulmonaire peuvent avoir une incidence sur leur participation à l'activité physique intense et que passer plus de temps comme très actif peut augment leur fonction pulmonaire. Après 3-mois d'entrainement, le programme d'exercice d'ACTIVATE-CF augmenté les niveaux d'activité physique pour les deux participants randomisés au groupe d'intervention. De plus, un des deux participants au groupe d'intervention a connu des améliorations au niveau de sa fonction pulmonaire et de sa composition corporelle. Ces résultats fournissent un soutien supplémentaire à la théorie que l'activité physique intense peut améliorer la fonction pulmonaire chez les patients atteints de FK.</description><description>Compared to healthy individuals, patients with Cystic Fibrosis (CF) experience frequent pulmonary exacerbations (PE) and are associated with a reduced forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1), the main prognostic measure of lung function in CF. Physical activity has been shown to attenuate the rate of decline in FEV1 in CF patients. Although CF patients have been shown to perform a similar amount of mild physical activity as their healthy counterparts, they have been shown to spend less time performing moderate to vigorous physical activity. These results were supported from baseline data collected for the local component of the international randomized control trial, ACTIVATE-CF, for which CF patients were shown to be somewhat active, but spent minimal time as very active. Using data collected from a study published by McIlwaine et al. (2013), we aimed to determine the predictors of lung function and physical activity in patients with CF. Using the local component of the ACTIVATE-CF study, we also aimed to determine if a 6-month partially supervised exercise-training program consisting of a motivational feedback component can motivate patients with CF to increase their physical activity levels and result in an improved lung function. We hypothesize that seasonality and lung function will have an impact on physical activity levels in patients with CF. We also hypothesize that the ACTIVATE-CF training program will motivate CF patients to increase their levels of physical activity and will improve their lung function. From the analysis of the McIlwaine et al. (2013) dataset, age was shown to predict time spent as somewhat active while lung function and seasonality were shown to predict time spent as very active in CF patients. Furthermore, time spent as very active, type of airway clearance technique, and age were shown to predict lung function. The results of this study suggest that in patients with CF, seasonal changes and lower lung function may be impacting their participation in intense physical activity and that spending more time as very active may increase their lung function. Following 3-months of training, the ACTIVATE-CF training program successfully increased physical activity levels for the two participants randomized to the intervention group. In addition, one of the two participants in the intervention group was associated with improvements in lung function and body composition. These results provide further support that intense physical activity may improve lung function in patients with CF.</description><creator>Aintabi, Daniel</creator><contributor>Larry Lands (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The impact of physical activity on lung function in patients with Cystic Fibrosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t175r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s0047</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k985p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La rugosité de la surface de glisse joue un rôle déterminant dans la résistance, la friction et le comportement dynamique des failles. Les modèles d'usure antérieurs et les observations sur le terrain suggèrent que la rugosité diminue avec le déplacement. Cependant, les mesures n'ont pas encore isolé l'effet du déplacement parmis d'autres contrôles geologique, tels que la lithologie ou le réglage tectonique. Pour mieux comprendre l'effet du déplacement sur les surfaces de glissement de failles, nous présentons une description qualitative et quantitative de l'évolution des failles dans le désert de San-Rafael, S.E. Utah, États-Unis. Ici, les failles ont accomodé de l'extension régionale à une profondeur de 1 à 3 km. Les failles sont preservées dans les grès poreux, bien triés et massifs Navajo et Entrada. Des profiles de rejet fournissent une contrainte maximale pour le déplacement à travers une zone de faille. Lorsque l'exposition en coupe transversale est bonne, et l'anignement des sties est évident, nous avons mesuré le déplacement exact en utilisant des décalages dans les horizons des marqueurs. Les contrôles de déplacement précis et l'uniformité de la lithologie et le context tectonique, nous ont permis d'isoler l'effet du déplacement, particulièrement pour les phases embryonnaires des failles (de 0 à 60 m en déplacement). Nos observations sur le terrain indiquent une nette progression de la composition et de la morphologie à partir de fracture de diaclase isolées ou de bandes de déformation vers des surfaces de glissement bien polie (miroir de faille) et continue avec un déplacement croissant. Pour quantifier ces observations, nous avons balayé des surfaces de glissement avec un interféromètre à lumière blanche, un scanner laser et un LiDAR au sol. Ensemble, ces instruments capturent plus de huit décennies de resolution (de moin de micrometres jusqu'à quelques metres en échelle). Dans cette étude, nous analysons plus de 120 balayages individuels des surfaces de glissement (d'après notre connaissance, cela représente plus de données que celles rapportées cumulativement dans les travaux antérieurs). Les résultats pour les surfaces avec les meilleures contraintes de déplacement indiquent que la rugosité telle que définie par la densité spectrale de puissance à une échelle de longueur donnée diminue avec le déplacement selon une loi de puissance avec une puissance de -1. Les mesures de rugosité associées uniquement aux contraintes maximales sur les déplacements corroborent ce résultat. En outre, la rugosité maximale pour un faille est délimitée par une rugosité primordiale correspondant à celle des surfaces des fracture de diaclase et des bords de bande de déformation. Nous proposons un modèle d'usure multi-échelle pour expliquer l'évolution des faille avec le déplacement. Nous suggérons qu'ensemble la brisure d'aspérités en tant que processus invariant à l'échelle, et la résistance stochastique des roches est compatible avec les contraintes d'observation qualitatives et quantitatives prises dans cette étude.</description><description>Fault slip surface roughness plays a determining role in the overall strength, friction, and dynamic behavior of fault systems. Previous wear models and field observations suggest that roughness decreases with increasing displacement. However, measurements have yet to isolate the effect of displacement from other possible controls, such as lithology or tectonic setting. In an effort to understand the effect of displacement, we present comprehensive qualitative and quantitative description of the evolution of fault slip surfaces in and around the San-Rafael Desert, S.E. Utah, United States. In the study area, faults accommodated regional extension at shallow (1 to 3 km) depth and are hosted in the massive, well-sorted, high-porosity Navajo and Entrada sandstones. Existing throw profiles provided a maximum constraint for displacement across an entire fault zone. Where cross-sectional exposure is good,  and slickenline lineations are evident, we measured exact displacement imparted on slip surfaces using offset in marker horizons. The tight displacement controls, combined with uniform lithology and tectonic history, allowed us to isolate the effect of displacement during the embryonic stages of faulting (0 to 60 m in displacement). Our field observations indicate a clear compositional and morphological progression from isolated joints or deformation bands towards smooth, continuous, and mirror-like fault slip surfaces with increasing displacement. To quantify these observations, we scanned pristine slip surfaces with a white light interferometer, a laser scanner, and a ground-based LiDAR. Together these instruments capture more than eight decades of spatial bandwidth (from less than microns to meters in scale). In this study, we report on more than 120 individual scans of fault slip surfaces (to the best of our knowledge, this represents more data than cumulatively reported in previous work). Results for the surfaces with the best displacement constraints indicate that roughness, as defined by the power spectral density at any given length scale decreases with displacement according to a power law with an exponent of -1. Roughness measurements associated with only maximum constraints on displacements corroborate this result. Moreover, maximum roughness for any given fault is bounded by a primordial roughness corresponding to that of joint surfaces and deformation band edges. Building upon these results, we propose a multi-scale wear model to explain the evolution of faults with displacement. We suggest that together, asperity failure as a scale invariant process, and the stochastic strength of host rocks are required to explain qualitative and quantitative observational constraints made in this study.</description><creator>Dascher-Cousineau, Kelian</creator><contributor>James Kirkpatrick (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Earth and Planetary Sciences</subject><title>The evolution of fault slip surfaces with displacement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz523.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k985p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333486v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: The NeuroVR virtual reality neurosurgical simulation platform has been used to analyze the bimanual psychomotor performance of neurosurgeons, residents and medical students. Previous metrics developed by our group have focused on safety, force use, and bimanual performance. A new metric, the force pyramid, was created to study the spatial distribution of forces applied during simulated tumor resections. Hypothesis: Hand ergonomics play an important role in the magnitude and spatial distribution of forces applied during simulated neurosurgical tumor resections. Objectives: First, to explore the role of the dominant, non-dominant and bimanual force pyramids in assessing the spatial distribution of forces applied during virtual reality tumor resections. Second to define the influence of hand ergonomics on the relationship between force applied, time expended, and tumor volume removed.  Methods: Data from trials in which neurosurgeon, resident and medical student groups resected simulated tumors were assessed. The force pyramid methodology was used to determine the spatial distribution of force applied, time expended, and tumor volume removed. To assess ergonomics, spatial information was partitioned into four tumor quadrants (Q1-Q4) each requiring a defined hand position to carry out the procedure. Results: The force pyramid analyses show that the highest forces form a crescent in Q4 for the dominant right hand and a peak at the center for the non-dominant left hand. The bimanual pyramids show an equal ratio of dominant and non-dominant forces for neurosurgeons and increased non-dominant forces for resident groups. Neurosurgeons distinctly adapt their performance to Q2 and Q4 and for each unit of force applied, neurosurgeons and residents remove more volume in Q2 and less in Q4. Conclusion: Hand ergonomics play a critical role in force application and tissue removal during surgical performance and help define expertise in the removal of simulated brain tumors. The new NeuroVR metrics assessed in this study allow for a more comprehensive evaluation of trainee psychomotor performance and provides detailed feedback on their technical skills.</description><description>Contexte : La plateforme de réalité virtuelle en neurochirurgie NeuroTouch/NeuroVR a été utilisée dans l'analyse de la performance psychomotrice bi-manuelle de neurochirurgiens, de résidents, et d'étudiants en médecine. Les indicateurs précédemment développés par notre groupe se sont principalement portés sur la sûreté, l'utilisation de la force, et la performance bi-manuelle. Un nouvel indicateur, la force pyramid, a été créé afin d'étudier la distribution spatiale des forces utilisées pendant la résection de tumeurs cérébrales virtuelles. Hypothèse : L'ergonomie de la main joue un rôle important dans l'ampleur et la distribution spatiale des forces utilisées pendant les résections de tumeurs cérébrales virtuelles. Objectifs : En premier, examiner le rôle des force pyramids dominantes, non-dominantes, et bi-manuelles dans l'évaluation de la distribution spatiale des forces utilisées pendant les résections de tumeurs cérébrales virtuelles. En second, définir l'influence de l'ergonomie de la main sur le rapport entre les forces utilisées, le temps dépensé, et le volume de tumeur retiré. Méthodes : Les données de neurochirurgiens, de résidents, et d'étudiants en médecine ayant réséqué des tumeurs cérébrales virtuelles ont été évaluées. La méthodologie de la force pyramid a été utilisée afin de déterminer la distribution spatiale des forces appliquées, du temps dépensé, et du volume de tumeur retiré. L'évaluation de l'ergonomie s'est faite en divisant l'information spatiale en quatre quadrants tumoraux (Q1- Q4), chacun exigeant une position de la main particulière pour effectuer la chirurgie. Résultats : Les force pyramids montrent que les forces les plus élevées forment un croissant à Q4 pour la main droite (dominante), et un pic au centre pour la main gauche (non-dominante). La pyramide bi-manuelle montre un rapport égal entre les forces dominantes et non-dominantes chez les neurochirurgiens, et des forces non-dominantes plus élevées chez les résidents. Les neurochirurgiens adaptent leur comportement à Q2 et Q4 et, pour chaque unité de force utilisée, les neurochirurgiens et les résidents retirent un plus grand volume tumoral à Q2 par rapport à Q4. Conclusion : L'ergonomie de la main joue un rôle crucial dans l'utilisation de la force et l'extraction de tissus pendant les opérations chirurgicales, et aide à définir le niveau d'expertise pour la résection de tumeurs cérébrales simulées. Les nouveaux indicateurs du NeuroVR évalués dans cette étude permettent une examination plus complète de la performance psychomotrice des résidents et fournissent des informations détaillées au sujet de leurs habiletés techniques.</description><creator>Sawaya, Robin</creator><contributor>Rolando Fausto Del Maestro (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Role of hand ergonomics in virtual reality brain tumor resections</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nx06r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333486v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jp042</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:51:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Whole body therapeutic hypothermia (TH) is the standard of care for infants with moderate or severe encephalopathy secondary to a hypoxic-ischemic insult. In infants with gestational age (GA) ≥ 36 weeks and birth weight (BW) ≥ 1800g a ladder approach is used to assess eligibility for the hypothermia treatment. This approach includes an initial identification of physiological criteria, followed by the presence of moderate or severe encephalopathy, which is classified according to the modified Sarnat exam. In our Institution this neurological evaluation should be performed by certified examiners using a standardized form at admission, and throughout the hypothermia treatment, including the day after rewarming. The Sarnat exam includes six categories, however, assessment of some of these categories are challenging. Specifically, evaluation of the autonomic nervous system (ANS) is subjective, can be affected by several variables, and therefore may not add much value to the final neonatal encephalopathy (NE) stage. Objectives: The objectives of the studies included in this thesis are: 1) assess the adherence to the use of a standardized neurological form, 2) evaluate the contribution of each category of the modified Sarnat exam to the overall assessment of NE and 3) investigate a more comprehensive analysis of ANS and its association with the final NE stage and clinical outcomes. Methods: All patients initiated on TH during the study periods were eligible. For the first two studies, data was retrospectively collected using a pre-defined data collection form to extract information related to completeness of the forms, as well as details of the neurological exam.  Specific methodology was used for each of the first two studies to achieve the pre-defined objectives. For the ongoing prospective study, new biological signals and technologies are being used to record data that will be analyzed when an adequate sample size is achieved. Results: Adherence to the use of the standardized neurological form was sub-optimal as it decreased significantly from admission to day 3 of TH, with critical information severely under-reported. The autonomic nervous system (ANS) was the only category that was not significantly associated with the final NE stage at all time points. A total of 8 infants have been enrolled in the prospective study and important issues related to the methodology have been identified. Conclusion: Although medical documentation is an important way to standardize care and audit practice, adherence to the use of a neurological form in infants with moderate or severe NE treated with TH was sub-optimal. Clearly, ongoing efforts need to be made to ensure a better adherence. Additionally, ANS evaluation using the modified Sarnat exam contributes poorly the final NE stage. Therefore, evaluation of the ANS may be rather imprecise and requires improvement, which is being investigated in the ongoing prospective study. Important limitations of the study design have been identified.  </description><description>Contexte: L'hypothermie thérapeutique du corps entier est la norme de soins pour les nourrissons présentant une encéphalopathie modérée ou grave secondaire à une insulte hypoxique-ischémique. Chez les nourrissons atteints d'âge gestationnel ≥ 36 semaines, et poids à la naissance ≥ 1800 g, une approche par étapes est utilisé pour évaluer l'admissibilité au traitement de l'hypothermie thérapeutique. Cette approche comprend une identification initiale des critères physiologiques, suivie de la présence d'une encéphalopathie modérée ou sévère, classée selon l'examen modifié de Sarnat. Dans notre institution, cette évaluation neurologique devrait être effectuée par des examinateurs certifiés, utilisant une forme standardisée à l'admission, et tout au long du traitement par l'hypothermie, y compris le lendemain du réchauffement. L'examen Sarnat comprend six catégories, mais l'évaluation de certaines de ces catégories est difficile. Plus précisément, l'évaluation du système nerveux autonome est subjective, peut être affectée par plusieurs variables et donc n'ajoute peut être pas beaucoup plus de valeur au stade final de l'encéphalopathie néonatale. Objectives: Les objectifs des études incluses dans cette thèse sont: 1) évaluer l'adhésion à l'utilisation d'une forme neurologique standardisée, 2) évaluer la contribution de chaque catégorie de l'examen Sarnat modifié à l'évaluation globale de l'encéphalopathie néonatale et 3) enquêter une analyse plus complète du système nerveux autonome et son association avec le stade final de l'encéphalopathie néonatale et les résultats cliniques. Méthodes: Tous les patients initiés sur l'hypothermie thérapeutique pendant les périodes d'étude étaient éligibles. Pour les deux premières études, les données ont été recueillies rétrospectivement à l'aide d'un formulaire de collecte de données prédéfini pour extraire l'information relative à l'exhaustivité des formulaires, ainsi que des détails sur l'examen neurologique. Une méthodologie spécifique a été utilisée pour chacune des deux premières études pour atteindre les objectifs prédéfinis. Pour l'étude prospective en cours, de nouveaux signaux et technologies biologiques sont utilisées pour enregistrer des données qui seront analysées lorsqu'une taille d'échantillon adéquate est atteinte.Résultats: L'adhésion à l'utilisation de la forme neurologique standardisée était sous-optimale car elle a diminué de manière significative de l'admission au jour 3 de l'hypothermie thérapeutique. De plus, les informations critiques étant gravement sous-déclarées. Le système nerveux autonome était la seule catégorie qui n'était pas significativement associée au stade final de l'encéphalopathie néonatale à tous les moments. Au total, 8 nourrissons ont été inscrits à l'étude prospective et des questions importantes liées à la méthodologie ont été identifiées.Conclusions: Bien que la documentation médicale soit un moyen important de normaliser les soins et la pratique de l'audit, l'adhérence à l'utilisation d'une forme neurologique chez les nourrissons atteints de l'encéphalopathie néonatale modérée ou sévère traité avec l'hypothermie thérapeutique était sous-optimale. De toute évidence, des efforts continus doivent être faits pour assurer une meilleure adhésion. En outre, l'évaluation du système nerveux autonome à l'aide de l'examen Sarnat modifié contribue de manière insuffisante au stade final de l'encéphalopathie néonatale. Par conséquent, l'évaluation du système nerveux autonome peut être plutôt imprécise et nécessite une amélioration, ce qui est étudiée dans l'étude prospective en cours. Des limites importantes liées à la conception de l'étude ont été identifiées.</description><creator>Sciortino, Cristina</creator><contributor>Guilherme Sant Anna (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Neurological evaluation of infants with evidence of a Hypoxic-Ischemic event treated with Therapeutic Hypothermia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n116x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jp042</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj863</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As sustainable practices become increasingly relevant in chemistry, and the realm of nanomaterial synthesis rapidly expands, efforts have been made to develop greener methods to access these valuable materials with fine control over size, monodispersity, shape and surface chemistry, while opening access to large-scale syntheses. While high-quality nanomaterials are presently accessed mostly by solution methods, these are not compatible with sustainable manufacturing due to large solvent and energy input. This thesis describes a unique, unprecedented synthesis of select metal-based nanoparticles (NPs) in the solid state through mechanically-activated spontaneous assembly, without requiring bulk solvents or heat. We first explore the possibility of accessing bismuth sulfide NPs and found that through this method of synthesis, highly monodisperse 2 nm nanoparticles formed systematically regardless of the grinding time, method of grinding, or amount of ligand present. These are the smallest NPs of bismuth sulfide ever reported, suggesting a distinct mechanism of nucleation and growth of NPs under solid-state conditions from that of solution-based methods, and therefore the possibility of accessing novel nanomaterials through this method. By varying the type of ligand, both organo- and water-suspendable products could be accessed, and the latter showed a significant radiodensity for their application as contrast agents in Computed Tomography imaging. We also show that PEGylation of these nanoparticles can be achieved in situ without additional steps post-synthesis. Next, we explore whether other metal-sulfide nanoparticles can be accessed via this route and turn to accessing nanoparticles of cadmium sulfide and zinc sulfide, which have numerous applications in optical-based devices and medical diagnostics. Once again, highly monodisperse nanoparticles were obtained in both cases (2.8-3.6 nm and 2.4-2.8 nm, respectively), and both showed fluorescent activity in the blue-range indicative of ultra-small quantum dots. In all cases, the reaction could be linearly scaled-up with ease in a planetary mill to achieve gram-scale quantities of product. Finally, given the increasing relevance of PEGylation in nanomedicine and drug development, we explored the possibility of accessing -functionalized derivatives in solid-state, eschewing the need for a solvent milieu. We find that –OTs, -Br, -SH, -NH2 and –COOH terminated PEG can be obtained rapidly and in good to quantitative yields with minimal mechanical input. With these results in mind, we hope that our promising results establish further research in accessing monodisperse nanomaterials through mechanochemistry as well as mechanistic elucidation of NP nucleation and growth under solid-state conditions.</description><description>Le développement de réactions chimiques dans le cadre de la chimie verte s'accélère, notamment pour la synthèse de nanomatériaux. En plus de l'aspect environnemental, une grande exigence au niveau de la taille, la monodispersité, la forme géométrique et la surface chimique de ces matériaux est requise. Tandis que les réactions en phase liquide permettent de produire des nanomatériaux de haute qualité, l'utilisation de grandes quantités de solvants et d'apport énergétique limitent leur utilisation dans les procédés de fabrication à grande échelle. Ainsi, nous avons choisi d'explorer la synthèse en phase solide de nanomatériaux.Ce mémoire décrit la synthèse unique et inédite de nanoparticules (NPs) à base de métaux en phase solide s'assemblant spontanément suite à un apport minimal d'énergie mécanique, cela sans utiliser de solvant ou de chaleur. Nous avons tout d'abord exploré la possibilité d'obtenir des NPs de sulfure de bismuth et nous avons obtenu des nanoparticules de 2 nm extrêmement monodispersées, indépendamment du temps ou des méthodes de broyage ou de la quantité de ligand présent. Ce sont les plus petites NPs de sulfure de bismuth reportées dans la littérature, et les résultats suggèrent un mécanisme de nucléation et de croissance des NPs qui soit distinct des méthodes en phase liquide. Cela ouvre par conséquent la possibilité d'obtenir de nouveaux nanomatériaux grâce à cette méthode. En modifiant le type de ligand, des produits dispersables dans des solvants organiques ou dans l'eau peuvent être obtenus, et ces derniers présentent une radiodensité significative dans leur application en tant qu'agents de contraste en imagerie tomographique. Nous avons aussi montré que la PEGylation de ces nanoparticules pouvait être réalisée in situ sans aucune étape supplémentaire. Par la suite, nous avons découvert que des nanoparticules de sulfure de cadmium ou de sulfure pouvaient être obtenues via cette méthode, qui ont de nombreuses applications en instrumentation optique et en diagnostic médical. Là aussi, des nanoparticules hautement monodispersées ont été obtenues dans les deux cas (2.8-3.6 et 2.4-2.8 nm respectivement) et les deux possèdent une activité fluorescente dans la gamme du bleu, ce qui est caractéristique des points quantiques de petite taille. Dans tous les cas, les particules peuvent être produites à l'échelle du gramme avec un broyeur planétaire à billes. Finalement, vu l'importance du PEGylation dans le développement pharmaceutique et nano-médecine, nous avons explore la possibilité d'accéder les dérivés -fonctionnalisés à l'état solide, ce qui évite le besoin d'un milieu liquide. Les PEG termines par –OTs, -Br, -SH, -NH2 et –COOH peuvent être synthétises sure une échelle de rendement allant de bon a quantitatif utilisant une force mécanique minimale. Nous espérons que nos résultats prometteurs inciteront à plus de recherches sur la synthèse mécanochimique de nanomatériaux monodispersés, ainsi qu'à l'élucidation du mécanisme de nucléation et de croissance en phase solide des NP.</description><creator>Malca, Michael</creator><contributor>Audrey Moores-François (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Tomislav Friscic (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Mechanically-activated assembly of monodisperse metal-based nanoparticles: a novel, simple and sustainable means to access chalcogenide nanoparticles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b5963.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj863</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mh999</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis includes separate research studies on atmospheric dust particles and viscous aerosol particles. In Chapters 2 and 3, the major source points of atmospheric dust particles in the Middle East are studied. We analyze daily images from a moderate resolution imaging spectroradiometer (MODIS) sensor as well as deep blue aerosol products to select dust events occurred between 2000-2012. Then, source point identification is performed on the images of dust events using an improved version of Middle East dust index (MEDI). Later, we classify the identified sources based on their intensity and frequency to better understand the contribution of each dust source point in generating dust storms. The findings show that Iraq and Syria have the highest active dust sites among all studied countries in the region. Furthermore, we investigate whether the observed intense and frequent dust activities are linked to desertification occurred over the past three decades. Analyzing Landsat TM images (1984 and 2012), it is found that 39% of identified sources in Iraq and its surrounding areas are located in newly desertified regions. Finally, these results are compared with other studies and the implication of the findings are discussed.   In Chapter 4, we describe a mathematical formulation of the water exchange diffusion problem and present analytical solutions for this problem for a spherical particle. Two different boundary conditions, constant and equilibrium concentration on the particle surface, are used to obtain solutions to the water exchange diffusion problem. Then, the effect of these boundary conditions is investigated in the context of isotope tracer experiments. Using dimensionless analysis, it is shown that the predicted sorption with fixed concentration on boundary is always greater than or equal to the model with the equilibrium boundary condition. These findings also suggest there are many physically relevant cases where the difference between these two solutions is inconsequential. We further explore these results using three physical examples of binary solution droplets: aqueous sucrose, aqueous citric acid, and aqueous shikimic acid droplets. Using the two derived analytical models, we study the water exchange lifetime. It is observed that the type of boundary condition becomes very significant when RH is very high in all cases. We conclude by discussing the observed discrepancy in the reported diffusion coefficient between isotopic water exchange and water sorption experiments.  In Chapter 5, the nonlinear diffusion of water in highly viscous and glassy aerosol particles is modeled and we discuss tracking the associated diffusion front. This tracking is accomplished by analyzing the optical behavior of spherical particle exposed to electromagnetic radiation during the diffusion process. Currently, the numerical multilayer Mie models require a concentration profile as an input. Obtaining this profile requires solving the nonlinear diffusion problem, which is very time consuming. We present an analytical model to simulate the position of morphology dependent resonances (MDRs) of a core-shell aerosol particle. Then, we compare the core-shell model with the previously developed multilayer Mie model. Results demonstrate that the derived characteristic equation can accurately calculate the positions of MDRs in a much faster way compared to the existing multilayer model. From simulation data, the most sensitive region to the gradient of refractive index is found to be very close to the particle surface. This sensitivity becomes insignificant at low relative humidities and limits the application of this work. Our model eliminates the complexity associated with using traditional numerical calculations based on water transport models to analyze single particle measurements.</description><description>Cette thèse comprend des études de recherche distinctes sur les particules de poussière atmosphérique et les particules d'aérosol visqueuses. Dans les chapitres 2 et 3, les principales sources de particules de poussière atmosphérique au Moyen-Orient sont étudiées. Nous analysons les images quotidiennes du capteur moderate resolution imaging spectroradiometer (MODIS) ainsi que des produits aérosols de Deep Blue pour sélectionner les événements de poussière survenus entre 2000 et 2012. Ensuite, l'identification de la source est effectuée sur les images des événements de poussière en utilisant une version améliorée de l'indice de poussière du Moyen-Orient (MEDI). Par la suite, nous classons les sources identifiées en fonction de leur intensité et de leur fréquence pour mieux comprendre la contribution de chaque source dans la génération des tempêtes de poussière. Les résultats montrent que l'Irak et la Syrie ont les sites de poussière très actifs les plus élevés parmi tous les pays étudiés dans la région. En outre, on étudie si les événements de poussière intenses et fréquentes observées sont liés à la désertification au cours des trois dernières décennies. En analysant les images Landsat TM (1984 et 2012), on constate que 39% des sources identifiées en Irak et dans ses régions environnantes se trouvent dans des régions nouvellement désertes. Enfin, ces résultats sont comparés à d'autres études et l'implication des résultats est discutée. Dans le chapitre 4, nous décrivons une formulation mathématique du problème de diffusion de l'échange d'eau et présentons des solutions analytiques pour ce problème dans le cas d'une particule sphérique. Deux conditions de limites différentes, 1) concentration à constante et 2) concentration à l'équilibrée à la surface de la particule, sont utilisées pour obtenir des solutions au problème de diffusion de l'échange d'eau. Ensuite, l'effet de ces conditions aux limites est étudié dans le cadre d'expériences de traceurs isotopiques. En utilisant une analyse sans dimension, il est démontré que la sorption prédite avec une concentration fixée sur la surface est toujours supérieure ou égale au modèle avec la condition de limite d'équilibre. Ces résultats suggèrent également qu'il existe de nombreux cas physiquement pertinents ou` la différence entre ces deux solutions est sans conséquence. Nous explorons davantage ces résultats en utilisant trois exemples physiques de gouttelettes de solution binaire: sucrose aqueux, acide citrique aqueux et gouttelettes d'acide shikimique aqueux. En utilisant les deux modèles analytiques dérivés, nous étudions la durée de vie de l'échange d'eau. On constate que le type de condition limite devient très significatif lorsque l'humidité relative est très élevé dans tous les cas. Nous concluons en discutant le décalage observé dans le coefficient de diffusion signalé entre les expériences isotopiques d'échange d'eau et de sorption d'eau.Dans le chapitre 5, la diffusion non linéaire de l'eau dans les particules d'aérosol très visqueuses et vitreuses est modélisée et nous discutons du déplacement du front de diffusion associé. Ce suivi est réalisé en analysant le comportement optique de la particule sphérique exposée au rayonnement électromagnétique pendant le processus de diffusion. Présentement, les modèles Mie multicouches numériques nécessitent un profil de concentration en tant qu'entrée. L'obtention de ce profil a besoin de la résolution du problème de diffusion non linéaire, qui prend beaucoup de temps. Nous présentons un modèle analytique pour simuler la position des résonances dépendantes de la morphologie (MDR) d'une particule d'aérosol à noyau- coquille. Ensuite, nous comparons le modèle noyau-coquille avec le modèle Mie multicouches précédemment développé. Les résultats démontrent que l'équation caractéristique dérivée peut calculer avec précision les positions des MDR de manière beaucoup plus rapide par rapport au modèle multicouche existant. </description><creator>Moridnejad, Ali</creator><contributor>Thomas Preston (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</subject><title>Characterizing dust storms and modeling diffusion in viscous atmospheric aerosol particles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gg436.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh999</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cw62r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Au cours de cette thèse, une méthode pratique de carbonatation prématurée du béton a été conçue. Un sujet largement publié ces dernières années, la cure accélérée du béton utilisant le CO2 a suscité l'intérêt du secteur du bâtiment, avec un nombre d'acteurs visant à industrialiser cette technique. Le défi que recèle la mise en œuvre de ce processus réside dans le besoin de pressions élevées pour assurer une pénétration efficace du CO2 au sein du béton. La majorité des chambres de maturation actuellement adoptée par l'industrie du béton préfabriqué sont incapables de résister à de telles pressions élevées. Pour remédier à l'usage de récipients sous pression coûteux et peu pratique, une approche de carbonatation qui marginalise le besoin de pression élevée a été développée et testée à l'échelle pilote en collaboration avec le partenaire industriel Boehmers. Cette approche prescrite a incorporé une pré-étape sous-vide créant une différentielle de pression qui a permis la carbonatation du béton à une pression sous-atmosphérique intitulée carbonatation sous-vide. L'étude préliminaire destinée à valider le concept a d'abord été effectuée au laboratoire et ensuite exécutée à l'échelle pilote. Les blocs de maçonnerie en béton étaient le produit préfabriqué utilisé au cours de cette recherche avec des mélanges conçus pour des blocs de béton normal et léger. Des tests paramétriques ont été effectués afin d'évaluer l'effet du pré-conditionnement (séchage), de la séquestration du CO2, de la résistance en compression, de l'indicateur de phénolphtaléine, des valeurs de pH et de la profondeur de carbonatation. Dans le cas du béton normal, la carbonatation sous vide à pression de CO2 quasi-ambiante a permis l'absorption moyenne de 15.9% de CO2 et un béton plus dense ayant une résistance d'un jour de 170% du spécimen de référence. Alors que le béton léger a entrainé une consommation ¬¬moyenne de 15.1% de CO2, un gain de force en âge précoce n'a pas été observé. Néanmoins, cette technologie conçue de carbonatation sous vide, a démontré son efficacité lors du mûrissement du béton et sa viabilité à remplacer les chambres de cure de béton à pression élevée.</description><description>In this thesis, a more practical methodology was conceived for the early-age carbonation of concrete. A widely published topic in recent years, the accelerated curing of concrete using CO2 has managed to pique the interest of the building sector, with a number of outlets seeking to industrialize this technique. The challenge of implementing, however, lies in the need of elevated pressures to achieve effective CO2 penetration within concrete. The overwhelming majority of curing chambers currently employed by the precast industry are incapable of withstanding such elevated pressures. Working with industrial partner Boehmers, this collaborative effort mainly sought to develop, and pilot-test, a carbonation approach that marginalizes the need for pressurized conditions, thus alleviating the need for expensive and impractical pressure vessels. The prescribed approach incorporated a vacuum pre-step such that a pressure-differential allowed carbonating concrete at sub-atmospheric gauge pressures, hence the term vacuum-carbonation. Proof-of-concept was first carried out in laboratory settings and then scaled to an industrial pilot. Concrete masonry units (CMU) were the targeted precast product for this study, with mix designs for both normal-weight and light-weight concrete. Parametric based testing was carried out to evaluate the effects of pre-conditioning (or drying), vacuum, and pressure-differential, on CO2 uptake, compressive strength, phenolphthalein indication, pH, and carbonation depth. For normal weight concrete, vacuum carbonation curing at low vacuum and near ambient CO2 pressures led to an average CO2 uptake of 15.9 %, and a denser concrete with a one-day strength around 170% that of the benchmark control batch. With respect to lightweight concrete, while CO2 uptake averaged 15.1%, an accelerated early-age strength gain was not observed. Nonetheless, the devised vacuum carbonation curing technique demonstrated its efficacy in curing concrete and its viability in replacing carbonation curing at elevated pressures.</description><creator>Abdul-Baki, Ghalia</creator><contributor>Yixin Shao (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Development of vacuum carbonation curing technology for concrete at ambient conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z0828.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw62r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r5621</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present a study of the role of regularity of perturbations in the control of quantumfluctuations appearing in the first law of thermodynamics in quantum mechanics. These fluctuations areencoded in the so-called heat full statistics measure, motivated by considering differences in energymeasurements at times 0 and t. We introduce the suitable notions of regularity of the perturbationthat ensure polynomial or exponential decay of this measure at infinity. We also obtain control in t,and necessity of these conditions for decay in concrete models of quantum field theory. </description><description>On présente une étude du rôle de la régularité des perturbations dans le contrôle desfluctuations de la chaleur qui entrent en jeu dans le premier principe de la thermodynamique enmécanique quantique. Ces fluctuations sont décrites par les queues de la mesure dite statistiquescomplètes de la chaleur, motivée par un protocole de mesure à deux temps de l'énergie aux temps 0et t. On introduit les notions appropriées de régularité de la perturbation qui assurent une décroissance polynomiale ou exponentielle de ladite mesure à l'infini. On obtient aussi un contrôle entemps et la nécessité de ces conditions dans des modèles concrets de théorie quantique des champs.</description><creator>Raquépas, Renaud</creator><contributor>Vojkan Jaksic (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Heat full statistics and regularity of perturbations in quantum statistical mechanics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z56k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r5621</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg44g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le fonctionnement moteur des personnes atteintes de sclérose en plaques varie entre une capacite normale et des déficiences graves. Les symptômes hétérogènes de ce maladie neurologique chronique sont dus en partie aux lésions cérébrales structurales, qui sont localisées de façon diffuse à travers le cerveau et risque de détériorer au cours de la maladie. La convergence des lignes de preuve suggèrent que les lésions cérébrales et l'invalidité associée à la sclérose en plaques peuvent être liées tout deux aux neurotransmetteurs excitateur et inhibiteur les plus prévalent du cerveau : le glutamate et l'acide γ-aminobutyrique (GABA). L'activité de ces neurotransmetteurs peuvent être estimé de façon non-invasive chez les humains en se servant de biomarqueurs dérivés de la stimulation magnétique transcrânienne, impliquant l'analyse des potentiels évoqués en électromyographie. Les niveaux de glutamate et de GABA endogènes dans différentes régions du cerveau peuvent également être évalués en toute sécurité chez les humains vivants utilisant la spectroscopie de résonance magnétique (1H-MRS). En utilisant une nouvelle combinaison de techniques multimodales non invasives, ce projet a étudié l'hypothèse selon laquelle le GABA et le glutamate sont impliqués dans les caractéristiques radiologiques et cliniques de la sclérose en plaques, en mettant l'accent sur la fonction motrice. Les principaux résultats ont été les suivants: (1) Compte tenu d'une combinaison de biomarqueurs multimodaux, l'inhibition peut être augmentée globalement pendant la phase de remise à l'état stable de la forme rémittente de la sclérose en plaques, alors que l'inhibition peut diminuer dans les sous-formes de la maladie progressive; (2) Plusieurs marqueurs dérivés de SMT et de MRS de l'activité intracorticale ou des niveaux de neurometabolite endogènes sont modérément corrélés avec les mesures de lésions cérébrales structurelles évaluées à l'aide de méthodes avancées de neuroimagerie; (3) Lors de l'ajustement pour l'ampleur des lésions cérébrales structurelles, les marqueurs du niveau de GABA dans le cortex sensorimoteur inférieur (estimé avec 1H-MRS) et une activité inhibitrice intracorticale plus élevée (estimée avec la SMT) sont liés à une performance motrice manuelle plus faible. L'ensemble de cet oeuvre fournit un aperçu innovateur de l'implication du glutamate et du GABA dans les caractéristiques radiologiques et cliniques de la sclérose en plaques, et souligne des cibles thérapeutiques potentielles et les biomarqueurs pertinents pour la fonction motrice dans cette maladie.</description><description>Clinical disability experienced by people with multiple sclerosis ranges from non-existent to severe motor and cognitive impairments. The heterogeneous symptoms of this chronic neurological disease are partially attributed to structural brain damage, which is variably disseminated throughout the brain and likely to worsen over the disease course. Converging lines of evidence suggest that multiple sclerosis-associated brain damage and disability may both be linked to the brain's most prevalent excitatory and inhibitory neurotransmitters, glutamate and γ-aminobutyric acid (GABA), respectively. Activity of these neurotransmitters can be estimated non-invasively in humans using transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS)-derived biomarkers, involving analyses of evoked electromyographic data. Endogenous glutamate and GABA levels in various brain regions can also be safely estimated in living humans using proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy (1H-MRS). Using a novel combination of non-invasive multimodal techniques, the hypothesis that GABA and glutamate are implicated in radiological and clinical features of multiple sclerosis was investigated, with a focus on motor function. The main findings were: (1) Considering a combination of multimodal biomarkers, inhibition may be increased overall during the stable remission phase of the relapsing-remitting form of multiple sclerosis, whereas inhibition may decrease in progressive disease sub-forms;  (2) Several TMS- and 1H-MRS-derived markers of intracortical activity or endogenous neurometabolite levels are moderately correlated with measures of structural brain damage assessed using advanced neuroimaging methods; (3) When adjusting for neuroimaging evidence of structural brain damage, markers of lower sensorimotor GABA level (estimated using 1H-MRS) and higher intracortical inhibitory activity (estimated using TMS) are related to poorer upper limb motor performance. This body of work provides novel insight into the involvement of glutamate and GABA in radiological and clinical features of multiple sclerosis, and points toward potential therapeutic targets and biomarkers relevant to motor function in this disease.  </description><creator>Nantes, Julia</creator><contributor>Lisa Koski (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Non-invasive markers of GABA and glutamate are related to radiological and clinical features of multiple sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h742.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg44g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892d500</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Discrete exterior calculus" (DEC) est une théorie assez récente obtenue par le developpément d'opérateurs discrets permettant un calcul simplicial analogue au calcul différentiel et intégral des formes différentielles. DEC est fondé sur la géometrie algébrique des complexes simplicials et exploite la reciprocité entre une triangulation et sa construction duale de façon à reproduire les propriétées geométriques clés des formes differentielles utiles pour le calcul scientifique. Dans la littérature, la théorie fut dejà utilisée pour affronter des problèmes variés appartenant à des domaines tels que l'homologie, la geométrie riemannienne, la dynamique des fluides, la méchanique discrète, incluant le calcul des variations en vision par ordinateur et en animation. Jusqu'à présent, établir la convergence des methodes produites par DEC reste un problème non resolu. Dans cette thèse, nous partagerons de récentes découvertes qui élargissent notre compréhension de cette question dans le cas des probèmes d'équations différentielles avec conditions limites pour des formes de degré zero (fonctions à valeurs réeles). Nous discuterons également des difficultés encontrées lorsqu'on tente d'étendre ces résultats à des ordres supérieurs.</description><description>Discrete exterior calculus (DEC) is a fairly recent structure-preserving discretization of exterior calculus. It is based on the algebraic geometry of simplicial complexes, and exploits the interplay between a triangulation and its dual to reproduce the key geometric features of differential forms that are useful for computational purposes. It has been used to tackle problems ranging from homology, riemannian geometry, fluid dynamics and discrete mechanics, including variational problems in computer vision and animation. However, establishing a convergence theory for DEC remains an open problem. In this thesis, we will share recent advancements towards such a theory for the case of boundary value problems on 0-forms (real-valued functions), and the main difficulties one encounters in trying to extend these results to higher-order settings will be discussed.</description><creator>Schulz, Erick</creator><contributor>Gantumur Tsogtgerel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Convergence of discrete exterior calculus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b859b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892d500</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988n556</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermobaric effects on geostrophic (QG) turbulence is investigated numerically. In QG turbulence, theories of inverse energy cascades are based on conservation of  energy and enstrophy. Thermobaric forcing breaks potential vorticity (PV) conservation and thus affects the classical picture of QG energy turbulence. In this thesis, we consider a modified version of QG (MQG) that takes into account thermobaric effects. We develop a numerical scheme for integrating this system and carry out simulations to examine how thermobaricity impacts the evolution of the flow. In a thermobaric fluid, lateral variability of the relative contributions of temperature and salinity in determining density affects the buoyancy frequency, N^2(x,y,z,t). This departs from traditional  quasigeostrophy in which N^2 is a function of z alone. Because of this horizontal dependence, the 3D elliptic inversion cannot be separated into 2D inversions to recover the streamfunction from QG potential vorticity for each vertical mode. Therefore, a different numerical technique is required for the elliptical inversion. We use a multigrid method, and a parallel version (openMP) of the source code is developed to carry out our simulations.Results suggest that thermobaric effects act to enhance the small scale structure of the flow. This is seen, for example, in the vertical velocity and potential vorticity fields. Although both small vertical  and horizontal scales are introduced, the effect appears to be mainly concentrated in the horizontal. Power spectra show a strong impact at high horizontal wavenumbers, with the low wavenumber part of the spectrum left relatively unaffected.</description><description>Les effets thermobariques sur la turbulence geostrophique (QG) sont  ́etudiès à l'aide de simulations num ́eriques. En turbulence QG, les cascades inverses d' ́energie sont bas ́ees sur la conservation de l' ́energie et de l'enstrophie. Le forage thermobarique viole la conservation de la vorticit potentielle (PV) et modifie ainsi la ph ́enom ́enologie classique. Dans cette thèse, nous considrons une version modifi ́ee de QG (MQG) qui prend en compte les effets thermobariques. Nous d ́eveloppons un schma num ́erique pour intgrer ce système et nous lanons des simulations afin d'examiner comment les effects thermobariques modifient l' ́ecoulement. Dans un fluide thermobarique, la variabilit ́e lat ́erale des contributions relatives de la temp ́erature et de la salinit ́e d ́etermine la densit ́e, et donc modifie la fr ́equence de flottabilit ́e, N^2 (x, y, z, t). Cela s' ́ecarte du système QG typique pour lequel N^2 est une fonction de z seulement. En raison de cette d ́ependance horizontale, l'inversionelliptique 3D ne peut pas être s ́epar ́ee en inversions 2D pour obtenir la fonction de courant à partir de la vorticit ́e potentielle pour chaque mode vertical. Par cons ́equent, une technique num ́erique diff ́erente est n ́ecessaire pour l'inversion elliptique. Nous utilisons une m ́ethode multigrille, et une version parallèle (openMP) du code estd ́evelopp ́ee pour r ́ealiser nos simulations. Les r ́esultats suggèrent que les effets thermobariques augmentent l' ́energie contenue aux petites  ́echelles. Cela se voit, par exemple, dans les champs de vitesse verticale  et de vorticit ́e potentielle. Bien que des fines structures soient introduites verticalement et horizontalement, l'effet semble principalement concentr ́e à l'horizontale. Les spectres de puissance d ́emontrent un impact notable sur les hauts nombre d'ondes horizontaux tandis que les petits nombre d'ondes demeurent relativement peu affect ́es.</description><creator>Islam, Mo Rokibul</creator><contributor>David N Straub (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</subject><title>A numerical study of thermobaric effects on geostrophic dynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c989v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n556</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913s36b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the XVIth and XVIIth centuries, more than twenty texts depicting the fictive conversations between women from low social extraction (fishwives, washerwomen, etc.) were published under the name of "caquet". This eclectic collection of texts can be divided into three subgroups, each formally and thematically distinct. The texts from the first group, published between 1530 and 1600, are versified and present many similarities with the "farcesque" production from the end of the XVth century. The texts from the second group, published during the first quarter of the XVIIth century are, for their part, written in prose, and use the same narrative frame : the daily meetings of bourgeois women at the bedside of one of their peers who is resting after childbirth. As for the last subgroup, it is consisted of a series of mazarinades in which female gossipers are reflecting on current political matters. Only the texts from the second subgroup – all gathered in the Recueil général des caquets de l'accouchée (1623) – have truly received attention from critics (mostly from a sociocritic perspective). The only article which offers a diachronic study of this corpus in order to define this literary genre also grants a much greater importance to the Recueil general, resulting in a biased reading of anterior and posterior "caquets", which are treated as either the prefiguration or the denaturation of this work (Gérin 1988). This thesis offers a new and more encompassing definition of this literary genre, focusing on its tendency to comment its own enunciative modalities. Indeed, metadiscursivity seems to be a prominent feature of this corpus, which negotiates the tension between the need for legibility and the misogynistic depiction of female loquacity, perceived as unintelligible.</description><description>Aux XVIe et XVIIe siècles paraissent sous l'intitulé « caquet » une vingtaine de textes faisant entendre le bavardage d'assemblées féminines fictives, dont les membres sont généralement de basse extraction sociale (lavandières, harengères, poissonnières, chambrières, etc.). Au sein de cet ensemble textuel éclaté, trois sous-groupes peuvent être dégagés sur la base de ressemblances thématiques et formelles. Tous versifiés, les caquets produits entre les années 1530 et 1600 présentent de nombreuses affinités avec la production farcesque de la fin du XVe siècle. En prose, ceux parus durant le premier quart du XVIIe siècle se démarquent par leur recours à un cadre narratif commun : les réunions quotidiennes de bourgeoises dans la chambre d'une femme relevant de couches. Le dernier sous-ensemble est constitué de mazarinades où les commères font état des misères du temps. Seul le deuxième sous-ensemble – constitué d'opuscules réunis sous le titre Recueil général des caquets de l'accouchée (1623) – a bénéficié de l'attention soutenue de la critique, essentiellement dans une perspective sociocritique. La seule étude ayant adopté une approche diachronique dans l'optique de définir ce genre littéraire accorde également une importance de premier plan au Recueil général : les caquets antérieurs et postérieurs ne seraient respectivement que les préfigurations et les dénaturations de cette œuvre parachevée, dont le réalisme bourgeois constituerait tout l'intérêt (Gérin 1988). Ce mémoire se veut une nouvelle tentative de définition générique des Caquets, définition exempte du critère réaliste et de toute lecture téléologique. Nous proposons d'appréhender ces écrits par leur tendance commune à discourir sur leurs propres modalités énonciatives. La métadiscursivité semble en effet un trait saillant de ce corpus, qui négocie la tension entre l'exigence de lisibilité du texte narratif et la représentation misogyne d'une parole réputée inintelligible.</description><creator>Veilleux, Christian</creator><contributor>Diane Desrosiers (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>French Language and Literature</subject><title>Rhéteurs de basse-cour: le genre littéraire du caquet (XVle-XVlle siècles)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr78f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913s36b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236474t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un neurone reçoit un signal sensorielle et synaptique depuis ses dendrites. Les dendrites de différents types de cellules neuronales présentent des motifs d'arborisation variés, une caractéristique clé qui fournit à chaque type de cellule des propriétés spécifiques pour le traitement de l'information. Malgré les associations décrites entre les anomalies de la morphologie de la dendrite et les pathologies humaines, les mécanismes cellulaires et moléculaires qui contrôlent le développement des dendrites restent mal compris. En utilisant la mouche à fruits Drosophila melanogaster comme modèle pour étudier le développement des dendrites in vivo, j'ai étudié le rôle du facteur de nucléation de l'actine Spire dans une classe de cellules nerveuses des larves de Drosophila appelées neurones d'arborisation dendritique. Avec l'immunohistochimie, j'ai constaté que Spire s'exprime en punctae au sein des arches dendritiques. Avec l'imagerie en direct, j'ai constaté que certains de ces punctae sont mobiles. Spire se trouve le long des arbres dendritiques et aussi aux extrémités et aux points de rencontre des branches. Il se co-localise fortement avec les marqueurs de l'appareil de Golgi et probablement avec d'autres composants de la voie endosomale / sécrétoire. Le Spire-box, un domaine potentiel de liaison à Rab GTPase, semble être important pour la localisation de Spire dans les dendrites. Il permettrait le déplacement de Spire des dendrites proximales à distales. Dans l'ensemble, cette recherche donne un aperçu des mécanismes qui sous-tendent le développement de la dendrite in vivo et pourrait avoir des implications plus larges pour comprendre la fonction des protéines liées à Spire dans d'autres contextes.</description><description>A neuron receives sensory and synaptic input through its dendrites. Dendrites in different neuronal cell types exhibit diverse arborization patterns, and this is a key feature providing each cell type with specific properties for information processing. Abnormalities in dendrite morphology have been associated with human diseases but, despite the importance of this, the cellular and molecular mechanisms that control the development of dendrites remain poorly understood. Using the fruit fly Drosophila melanogaster as a model to study dendrite development in vivo, I investigated the role of the actin nucleation factor Spire in a class of nerve cells in Drosophila larvae called dendritic arborization (da) neurons. Through immunohistochemistry I found that Spire is expressed in punctae within dendritic arbors, and with live imaging I found that some of these punctae are motile. Spire is found along dendritic shafts, and also at branch points and branch tips. It strongly co-localizes with markers of the Golgi apparatus, and likely with other components of the endosomal/secretory pathway. The Spire-box, a potential Rab GTPase-binding domain, appears to be important for Spire localization in dendrites. This research provides insight into mechanisms underlying dendrite development in vivo, and could have broader implications for understanding the function of Spire-related proteins in other contexts. </description><creator>Hanrahan, Caitlin</creator><contributor>Donald Van Meyel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Investigation of the actin-nucleator spire in controlling the morphology of neuronal dendrites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290d07j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236474t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qp709</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the continuous casting process, a large number of internal and surface defects, such as Oscillation Marks (OM), bubble and inclusion entrapments, Mold Powder Entrainment (MPE), internal and surface cracks and segregations, are encountered which are associated with the fluid flow inside the mold cavity. Appropriate fluid flow conditions in the mold region favorably affect the casting defects elimination and can generate the correct temperature distributions within the mold, which significantly decreases the possibility of breakouts and deep oscillation marks. The flow patterns can be directly influenced by the design of Submerged Entry Nozzle (SEN), mold geometry and dimensions, the operational casting conditions, and external flow modifiers.  The present Ph.D. study took advantage of today's numerical techniques and developed a numerical model to simulate asymmetrical fluid flows generated within a curved, square billet mold in presence of different flow modifiers. The fluid flow and electromagnetic numerical models are developed using the commercial packages, ANSYS-Fluent and COMSOL. All simulations are run on an SGI 288 core, High Performance Computing Cluster (HPCC), at the McGill Metals Processing Centre (MMPC) Stinson Laboratories, in Montreal, Canada. Two of the most important parameters which significantly influence fluid flows within the continuously casting molds are; 1), SEN's designs and location within the mold and 2), the applications of electromagnetic fields. Therefore, in this study, the fluid flow within the curved, square billet mold was evaluated under the effect of a multiple-port SEN's angle of rotation and the impact of Rotary Electro-Magnetic Stirring (EMS). In this study different SEN's angles of rotation, along with different types of Rotary-EMS, was applied, in order to determine optimum fluid flows within the mold region. The direct impingement of liquid steel towards mold corners was found strongly affecting the level fluctuations of liquid steel at the upper meniscus and probably result in MPE. Additionally, the Rotary-EMS generates swirling flows within the mold region. In previous research, it was found that the swirling flows generated by EMS in the mid-section of billet, bloom, or slab continuous casting molds, results in higher quality surfaces and microstructures of continuously cast products. However, the numerical results achieved in this study demonstrated that, by having an incorrectly SEN angle of rotation, the rotational Lorentz forces induced by a Rotary-EMS can be detrimental on the fluid flows near the top region of the mold. Therefore, nozzle location and Rotary-EMS can be combined to either drastically improve, or deteriorate, the quality of fluid regimes within the mold region. The calculation domain and the operational conditions used in this study correspond to the square billet mold and operational conditions practiced at the Rio Tinto Fer et Titane (RTFT) plant, located at Sorel Tracy, Quebec, Canada. The observed fluid flows with the proposed alternative location of SEN together with the effect of Rotary-EMS, decreased the meniscus level fluctuation and stabilized the layer of liquefied mold powder over the liquid steel meniscus, compared to the results delivered by the current operations. Additionally, a set of experiments were carried out in order to study the solidified microstructure for two different Aluminum alloys including, A356 and AA2024 under the effect of a Rotary-EMS. The experimental results show that, the rotational Lorentz forces induced due to the Rotary-EMS, modified the dendritic structure and significantly enhanced the homogenization of alloying elements in the solidified samples.</description><description>Dans le procédé de coulée continue (C.C), un grand nombre de défauts internes et superficiels, tels que les marques de l'oscillation (MO), bulle et piégeages d'inclusion, se rencontrent. De même, le entraînement de poudre du moule (EPM), fissures et ségrégations, sont associés à l'écoulement du fluide dans la région du moule. Conditions d'écoulement de fluide approprié dans la région du moule peuvent générer les correctes distributions de température dans le moule, ce qui diminue considérablement la possibilité d'éruptions et de profonde MOs. Les modèles d'écoulement peuvent être directement influencées par la conception du buse d'entrée submergée (BUS), la géométrie et dimensions de moule, les conditions opérationnelles de coulée et modificateurs des ecoulements externes.Le présente étude de doctorat à profité des techniques numériques d'aujourd'hui et développé un modèle numérique pour simuler les écoulements fluides asymétriques générées dans un moule carré courbé au sein de modificateurs de différents ecoulements. L'écoulement du fluide et des modèles numériques électromagnétiques sont développées en utilisant les paquets commerciaux,  ANSYS-Fluent et COMSOL. Toutes les simulations sont exécutées sur un noyau de SGI 288, High Performance Computing Cluster, dans les laboratoires du Centre de Traitement des Métaux McGill (MMPC) Stinson, à Montréal, Canada. Deux paramètres les plus importants qui influencent significativement l'ecoulement du liquide dans le moule du coulée en continu sont; 1) Dessins du BUS et emplacement à l'intérieur du moule et 2), les applications des champs électromagnétiques. Par conséquent, dans cette étude, l'ecoulement du fluide dans le moule carré courbé a été évalué sous l'effet d'un port multiple d'angle de rotation du BUS et l'impact d'agitation électromagnétique (AEM) rotatif. Dans cette étude différentes angles de rotation du BUS ainsi que différents types de AEM rotatif a été appliquée, afin de déterminer des ecoulements de fluides optimales au sein de la région du moule. L'impact direct de l'acier liquide vers les coins du moule a été constaté qu'affecte fortement les fluctuations de niveau de l'acier liquide le ménisque supérieur et probablement deviens à EPM.  En outre, l'AEM rotatif génère des tourbillonnement du fluide dans la région du moule. Dans des recherches antérieures, on a trouvé des fluides tourbillonnants générés par les AEM dans la section médiane du billet, bloom ou moules de coulée continue, entraîne des surfaces de qualité supérieures et microstructures des produits de coulé continu. Toutefois, les résultats numériques obtenus dans cette étude ont démontré que, en ayant un mauvais angle de rotation du BUS, les forces de rotation de Lorentz induites par le AEM rotatif peuvent être préjudiciables sur l'écoulement du liquide près de la région supérieure du moule. Par conséquent, les emplacement du buse et le AEM rotatif peuvent être combinés pour considérablement améliorer ou s'aggraver la qualité des régimes du fluide dans la région de moule. Le domaine du calcul et des conditions opérationnelles utilisées dans cette étude correspond au moule billet carrée et conditions opérationnelles pratiqué dans les operationes à Rio Tinto Fer et Titane (RTFT) situé à Sorel-Tracy, Québec, Canada. L'ecoulement du fluide observé avec l'emplacement alternatif proposé du BUS ainsi que l'effet du AEM rotatif, diminué la fluctuation de niveau du ménisque et stabilisé la poudre liquide du moule sur le ménisque en acier liquid, comparé aux résultats fournis par les opérations en cours. En outre, une série d'expériences ont été menées afin d'étudier la microstructure solidifiée pour deux différents alliages d'aluminium, y compris les A356 et AA2024 sous l'effet d'un AEM rotatif. Les résultats expérimentaux montrent que, les forces de Lorentz rotation induit en raison de la AEM rotatif modifié la structure dendritique et améliore de façon significative l'homogénéisation des éléments d'alliage.</description><creator>Aboutalebi, Mohammad Mahdi</creator><contributor>Roderick I L Guthrie (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Mihaiela Isac (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Modeling of transport phenomena and magneto-hydrodynamics for improved steel quality in square billet molds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042w496.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp709</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526f721</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:52:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This experience sampling study of 131 community adults (84 women, 47 men) examined the role of perfectionism in stress, emotion regulation, and affect in daily life. Participants completed measures of two higher-order dimensions of perfectionism (i.e., self-critical perfectionism [SCP], personal standards perfectionism [PSP]). Then, over eight consecutive days, they completed five repeated within-day reports and one retrospective daily report of stress, emotion regulation strategies (i.e., rumination, expressive suppression, reappraisal), and affect (i.e., negative affect, sadness). In contrast to PSP, SCP was moderately to strongly associated with aggregated within-day and aggregated daily stress, rumination, expressive suppression, negative affect, and sadness. Path modeling revealed that expressive suppression, rumination, and event stress tendencies explained why individuals with higher SCP tend to experience persistent negative affect and sadness. Multilevel modeling indicated that individuals with higher SCP/PSP, relative to those with lower scores, exhibited heightened emotional reactivity in response to daily stressors. In addition, rumination and expressive suppression were found to be particularly ineffective for individuals with higher SCP/PSP, whereas reappraisal revealed to be more effective for these individuals. These findings underline the importance of targeting emotion regulation tendencies in daily life to reduce distress for perfectionistic individuals. Keywords: perfectionism, self-criticism, stress, emotion (dys)regulation, affect.</description><description>Cette étude a examiné l'influence du perfectionnisme au quotidien sur le stress, la régulation émotionnelle et l'affect chez 131 adultes de la communauté (84 femmes, 47 hommes). Les participants ont complété des questionnaires évaluant leur niveau de perfectionnisme autocritique (SCP) et  de standards personnels (PSP). Ensuite, à chaque jour pendant huit jours consécutifs, ils ont rempli cinq rapports répétés au cours de la journée ainsi qu'un rapport sommaire en fin de journée portant sur leur stress, leur affect (tristesse, affect négatif), et leur emploi de stratégies de régulation émotionnelle (rumination, suppression expressive, réévaluation). Contrairement à PSP, SCP était plus fortement associé à l'expérience du stress, de la rumination, de la suppression expressive, de l'affect négatif et de la tristesse au cours de la journée et en fin de journée. Une analyse des pistes causales a démontré que le stress et les tendances à la suppression expressive et la rumination expliquent pourquoi les individus avec un SCP plus élevé sont enclins à éprouver de la tristesse et de l'affect négatif. Une modélisation à multiniveaux a indiqué que les individus ayant un SCP / PSP plus élevé, par rapport à ceux ayant des scores inférieurs, présentent une réactivité émotionnelle accrue face aux facteurs de stress quotidiens. De plus, la rumination et la suppression expressive se sont révélées particulièrement inefficaces pour les individus ayant une SCP / PSP plus élevée, tandis que la réévaluation s'est révélée plutôt efficace pour ces individus. Or, ces résultats soulignent l'importance de cibler les stratégies de régulation émotionnelle employées au quotidien par les perfectionnistes afin de réduire leur détresse.  Mots clés: perfectionnisme, autocritique, stress, régulation émotionnelle, affect.</description><creator>Prud'homme, Julie</creator><contributor>David Michael Dunkley (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Psychiatry</subject><title>Perfectionism and daily emotion regulation and well-being: An experience sampling study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r67r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526f721</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5900</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>