<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:32:26Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37550" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j9435</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The detection of breast cancer at its early stage reduces the treatment cost and the mortality rate. Microwave imaging techniques have been proposed to complement the existing X-ray mammography to screen women. They exploit the dielectric contrast between malignant and healthy tissue in the microwave range. The first subject of this thesis is to solve the problem of a plane wave scattered by a multi-layer sphere. From this model and the recent measurements of the dielectric properties of the breast tissue, we predict the strength of this response as the tumors are buried in different tissues. These results identify the requirements on the microwave radar systems for breast tumor detection. The second subject of this thesis is to use a commercial software, SEMCAD, to construct numerical breast models. We use the classification and regression tree analysis to approximate the heterogeneous tissue region, which averages out the noise inherited in the magnetic resonance images and reduces the number of solids to fill the tissue region. These breast models can be combined with complex antennas for full-wave electromagnetic simulations. A numerical evaluation of the microwave radar and microwave-induced thermoacoustic imaging technique is presented. We find that the contrast in radar signals is due to permittivity and conductivity, while the contrast in thermoacoustic signals is due to conductivity-heat capacity ratio. Due to the wave physics and the fact that human breast is electrically heterogeneous but acoustically homogeneous, images acquired from the thermoacoustic signals exhibit better quality than the images from the radar signals. Finally, we show that the antennas in microwave tomographic systems are for transmitting and receiving microwave signals, and the antennas in microwave-induced thermoacoustic systems are for heating. It is not feasible to construct a single system with antennas that simultaneously meet the requirements of these two systems.</description><description>La détection du cancer du sein au stade préecoce réduit le coût du traitement et le taux de mortalité. Les techniques d'imagerie micro-ondes ont été proposées pour compléter la mammographie existante par rayon X pour ausculter les femme. Ils exploitent le contraste diélectrique entre le tissu malin et le tissu sain dans le champ des micro-ondes. Le premier objet de cette thèse est de résoudre le problème d'une onde plane diffusée par une sphère multicouche. A partir de ce modèle et les mesures récentes des propriétés diéléctriques du tissu mammaire, nous pouvons également prédire la grandeur de cette réponse car les tumeurs sont enterrées dans différents tissus. Ces résultats mettent en évidence les critères exigés avec des systèmes radar à micro-ondes pour la détection de tumeur du sein. Le deuxième objet de cette thèse est d'utiliser un logiciel commercial, SEMCAD, pour construire des modèles numériques du sein. Nous utilisons la classification et l'analyse par arborescence pour estimer approximativement la zone de tissu hétérogène, ce qui représente en moyenne le bruit dans les images héritées par résonance magnétique et réduit le nombre de matières solides pour remplir la zone de tissu. Ces modèles du sein peuvent être combines avec des antennes complexes pour des simulations complètes par ondes électromagnétiques. Une évaluation numérique du radar micro-ondes des micro-ondes induites par la technique dimagerie thermo-acoustique est présentée. Il est constaté que le contraste dans les signaux radar est dû à la permittivité et à la conductivité, tandis que le contraste dans les signaux thermo-acoustiques est dû au rapport entre la capacité de la chaleur et celle de la conductivité. En raison de la physique des ondes et du fait que le sein maternel humain est électriquement hétérogène mais acoustiquement homogène, les images acquises à partir des signaux thermo-acoustiques présentent une plus grande qualité que les images obtenues à partir des signaux radar. Enfin, nous montrons que les antennes dans les systèmes à micro-ondes tomographiques sont pour transmettre et recevoir des signaux micro-ondes, et les antennes micro-ondes induite par les systèmes thermo-acoustiques sont pour le chauffage. Il n'est pas possible de construire un système unique avec des antennes qui peut répondre simultanément aux exigences de ces deux systèmes.</description><creator>Zhu, Guangran</creator><contributor>Milica Popovich (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Application of microwave techniques in breast imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967773f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j9435</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386p70c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Muscle wasting is a significant complication of many diseases. Previous work has shown that USP19 mRNA expression is increased in muscle undergoing atrophy in rodents [1]. To further explore the role of USP19 in muscle, siRNA-mediated silencing was used in L6 muscle cells. Depletion of USP19 resulted in increased major myofibrillar protein levels [2]. These effects of silencing USP19 on myofibrillar protein expression may be due to the effects of USP19 on the differentiation of muscle cells. Therefore, in this thesis I further characterized the mechanism by which depletion of USP19 enhances expression of myofibrillar proteins. MHC and tropomyosin mRNA levels were increased upon USP19 silencing, suggesting that the observed increases in protein levels were due to increased transcription. Myogenin, a transcription factor in the myogenic regulatory factor family that regulates muscle differentiation, was increased by more than two fold at both mRNA and protein levels when USP19 was silenced and found to be responsible for mediating the increase in myofibrillar protein expression. The negative role of USP19 in muscle differentiation was confirmed as overexpressing USP19 resulted in decreased myogenin and major myofibrillar protein expression at the molecular level and decreased myotube fusion at the morphological level. The regulation of USP19 itself during muscle differentiation was then investigated. The mRNA levels were found to increase by ~ 4 fold from day 0 to day 5 of differentiation, while there was a ~ 1.5 fold increase in protein levels. USP19 is localized in both the cytosol and the nucleus but there was increased localization in the nucleus on day 4 of muscle cell differentiationd. In conclusion, USP19 negatively regulates muscle differentiation.  Since new myoblast fusion and myofiber formation may occur during recovery from wasting, an inhibitor to  USP19 could be a new approach to the treatment of muscle wasting.</description><description>L'atrophie musculaire est une complication considérable de plusieurs maladies. Des études antérieures ont démontré que l'expression de l'ARN messager de USP19 est régulé à la hausse dans plusieurs modèles d'atrophie musculaire chez les rongeurs [1]. Afin de mieux comprendre le rôle de USP19 dans les muscles, nous avons utilisé des ARN interférents dans des cellules musculaires L6. La réduction des niveaux de USP19 a conduit à une augmentation des niveaux des protéines myofibrillaires prédominantes [2].  Les conséquences d'une réduction des niveaux de USP19 sur l'expression des protéines myofibrillaires pourrait être dû à l'effet de USP19 sur la différentiation des cellules musculaires. Par conséquent, dans cette thèse, j'ai caractérisé plus en profondeur le mécanisme par lequel une réduction de USP19 mène à une augmentation de l'expression de protéines myofibrillaires. Nous avons observé que les niveaux d'ARN messagers de MHC et de la tropomyosine sont augmenté suite à la réduction de USP19 par ARN interférent, ce qui suggère que la hausse des niveaux protéiques est dû à une augmentation de la transcription. Le facteur de transcription myogénine fait partie de la famille des facteurs de régulation myogénique impliqués dans la différentiation musculaire et est responsable de l'augmentation de l'expression des protéines myofibrillaires. Nous avons observé que le niveau de ces protéines sont augmentés de plus de deux fois autant au niveau de l'ARN messager qu'au niveau protéique quand USP19 est réduit par ARN interférent. Le rôle de USP19 dans la différentiation musculaire a aussi été démontré en surexprimant USP19 dans des cellules musculaires. Une augmentation des niveaux de USP19 a conduit à une réduction de l'expression des principales protéines myofibrillaires ainsi que la myogénine au niveau moléculaire et à une réduction de la différentiation des myotubes au niveau morphologique. La regulation de USP19 pendant la différentiation musculaire a donc été étudié. Les niveaux d'ARN messagers de USP19 sont augmentés ~4 fois durant les 5 premiers jours de différentiation alors que les niveaux protéiques sont augmentés ~1.5 fois. De plus, USP19 est localisé autant dans la partie cytosolique que dans le noyau cellulaire. Une augmentation de la localisation de USP19 dans le noyau au 4ème jour de différentiation a été observé. En conclusion, USP19 est un régulateur négatif de la différentiation musculaire. Puisque la formation de nouveau fibres musculaires peut apparaître suite à la récupération de l'atrophie, un inhibiteur de USP19 pourrait être une approche intéressante pour le traitement de l'atrophie musculaire.</description><creator>Miao, Miao</creator><contributor>Simon Sipen Wing (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>The role of USP19 deubiquitinating enzyme in muscle differentiation «in vitro»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gj099.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386p70c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698c887</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During high frequency stimulation, synaptic efficacy decreases due to the depletion of the readily releasable pool (RRP), and its replenishment is vital in maintaining synaptic transmission. According to the 'mobilization by liberation' model, stimulation and subsequent calcium accumulation frees vesicles from their cytoskeletal constraints, leading to the replenishment of the RRP. Additionally, okadaic acid (a phosphotase inhibitor) and staurosporine (a protein kinase inhibitor) have been shown to affect vesicular mobility. In this thesis, the 'mobilization by liberation' model is tested by evaluating how the dynamics of the vesicular system change with stimulation, calcium, temperature, and compounds which affect vesicular mobility. The parameters of a vesicular storage and release model were estimated using the excitatory post-synaptic currents recorded from rat hippocampal CA1 neurons. The fractional release increases with calcium, whereas the replenishment rate is calcium-independent. During long, high frequency stimulation, the fractional release remains constant and the replenishment rate decreases markedly and rapidly. Thus, stimulation induced changes of vesicular dynamics are not determined by calcium accumulation. Agents that affect vesicular mobility did not influence the replenishment rate, and these compounds were ineffective in influencing how the replenishment rate decreases with stimulation. Therefore, the replenishment of the RRP is unlikely to be associated with vesicular movement. The replenishment rate decreases during stimulation at low temperatures (&lt; 22C), and it increases at high temperatures (&gt; 28C). After prolonged stimulation, the replenishment rate recovers rapidly, to a steady-state level that is above its pre-stimulation estimate. The recovery of synaptic efficacy is thus an unreliable index of the replenishment rate. In conclusion, our results do not support the 'mobilization by liberation' model in excitatory synapses of the rat hippocampus, and future studies should clarify the underlying biophysical process of vesicular replenishment.</description><description>Lors de la stimulation à haute fréquence, l'efficacité synaptique diminue en raison de l'appauvrissement du 'readily releasable pool' (RRP), et le remplissage est essentiel au maintien de la transmission synaptique. Selon le modèle de la 'mobilization by liberation', la stimulation et l'accumulation subséquente de calcium libèrent les vésicules de leurs contraintes au cytosquelette, menant à un remplissage accéléré du RRP. La mobilité vésiculaire est également modulée par la phosphorylation, et l'acide okadaïque (un inhibiteur de phosphatase) mène à une augmentation du trafique vésiculaire. Inversement, la staurosporine (un inhibiteur de protéine kinase) limite le mouvement vésiculaire. Selon la tradition, le taux de remplissage est estimé à partir de l'efficacité synaptique suivant l'épuisement du RRP. Dans cette thèse, le modèle de la 'mobilization by liberation' est testé en évaluant comment les dynamiques vésiculaires changent avec la stimulation, la calcium, la température, et des composés qui affectent la mobilité vésiculaire. Les paramètres du système de stockage et de relâchement vésiculaire étaient estimés à partir des enregistrements des courants post-synaptiques excitateurs des neurones CA1 de l'hippocampe de rat. Le relâchement fractionnel augmente avec la calcium, alors que le taux de remplissage est calcium-indépendant. Pendant de longues stimulations à haute fréquence, le relâchement fractionnel demeure constant et le taux de remplissage diminue de façon marquée et rapide. Ainsi les changements dans la dynamique vésiculaires induits par la stimulation ne sont pas déterminés par l'accumulation de calcium. Les agents qui affectent la mobilité vésiculaire n'influencent pas le taux de remplissage, et ces composés n'ont pas d'effet sur la diminution du taux de remplissage lors de la stimulation. Ainsi, le remplissage du RRP n'est vraisemblablement pas associé au mouvement vésiculaire. Le taux de remplissage diminue durant la stimulation à faibles températures (&lt; 22C), et augmente à des températures plus élevées (&gt; 28C). Suite à une stimulation prolongée, le taux de remplissage reprend rapidement, à un niveau stable, qui est supérieur à l'estimé de pré-stimulation. La reprise de l'efficacité synaptique est ainsi un indice incertain du taux de remplissage. En conclusion, nos résultats éliminent le modèle de la 'mobilization by liberation', et des études futures devront clarifiées les processus biophysiques sous-jacents au remplissage vésiculaire.</description><creator>Bui, Loc</creator><contributor>Mladen I Glavinovic (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>Estimating the parameters of a vesicular storage and release system in rat hippocampus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967774q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698c887</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nn25c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The global effort to reduce the environmental impact of transportation has led to a renewed interest in electric vehicle technology.  One of the factors limiting the success of electric vehicles is the high cost of current battery technology.  Nickel-zinc batteries could potentially offer a low cost alternative for certain electric vehicle applications. This thesis explores the potential use of nickel-zinc batteries in a recreational-scale electric vehicle through the use of powertrain modeling and simulation.  A methodology was established to analyze the performance of the batteries at various temperatures and an internal resistance battery model was developed.  This model was then integrated into a previously validated powertrain model of an electric snowmobile in order to simulate the use of these batteries in a recreational vehicle application.  The results of these simulations were recreated experimentally in a laboratory environment with reasonable accuracy, confirming the validity of the battery model and the employed methodology. </description><description>L'effort mené à l'échelle mondiale pour la réduction de l'impact environnemental des transports a mené à un renouveau de l'intérêt porté aux véhicules électriques. Un des facteurs importants qui limitent le succès de ces véhicules est le coût élevé des piles disponibles. Des piles au nickel-zinc pourraient potentiellement offrir une alternative abordable qui conviendrait aux besoins énergétiques de certains véhicules électriques. Ce mémoire explore le potentiel des piles au nickel-zinc pour les véhicules récréatifs électriques, en faisant de la modélisation et des simulations de motorisation. La performance des piles à différentes températures fut analysée afin de créer un modèle de leur résistance interne. Ce modèle fut intégré dans un modèle de la motorisation d'une motoneige électrique afin de simuler la performance des piles dans un véhicule récréatif. Des tests en laboratoire ont produit des résultats comparables à ceux produits par simulation virtuelle, confirmant ainsi la validité du modèle de pile et la méthodologie employée.</description><creator>Turner, Jeff</creator><contributor>Peter Henry Radziszewski (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Modeling the behaviour of nickel- zinc batteries in a recreational-scale electric vehicle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763c038.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nn25c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354k45h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un contrôleur robuste est souvent conçu afin de maintenir la stabilité et la performance robuste d'un système linéaire invariant dans le temps. Durant l'implantation d'un tel contrôleur, deux problèmes se présentent. Premièrement, il est intéressant de savoir s'il est possible de simplifier le contrôleur robuste et si oui, jusqu'à quel point avant de l'implanter, tout en garantissant la performance robuste. Le deuxième problème se pose dans les applications à temps réel où le contrôleur devrait être refait ou ajusté plusieurs fois après la mise en service initiale. Il est important de savoir, concernant les deux problèmes ci-dessus, jusqu'à quel point le contrôleur modifié peut s'éloigner de l'original dans le domaine des fréquences.  Une condition suffisante et nécessaire pour la performance robuste ainsi qu'une condition suffisante sont dérivées sous forme de limites sur le module de la déviation maximum du contrôleur robuste sur une grille de fréquences pour un système à sortie unique et à entrée unique (SISO). Le cas d'entrées et sorties multiples (MIMO) est aussi traité en fournissant une limite sur la valeur singulière maximum de la réponse en fréquence du système calculée à chaque point de fréquence, formant une condition suffisante pour la performance robuste. Les limites ci-dessus sont utilisées avec la technique de réduction équilibrée (balanced truncation) afin de déterminer à quel point il est possible de réduire l'ordre du contrôleur sans perdre la performance robuste. Le nombre maximum d'états du contrôleur admissibles pour l'élimination est donné, sans vraiment devoir le modifier. Finalement, une méthode pratique est proposée pour réaliser un contrôleur robuste basé sur la commande par modèle interne (IMC) pour un système SISO. La réponse en fréquence du contrôleur robuste idéal est déjà fournie comme une fonction de la réponse en fréquence de toutes les composantes de système. Puis, le contrôleur idéal est approximé par un système stable et préférablement d'ordre peu élevé en gardant la performance robuste aux trois étapes : transformation inverse de Fourier rapide (IFFT), approximation par un système de réponse impulsionnelle finie (FIR) et conversion de FIR à réponse impulsionnelle infinie (IIR).</description><description>For a linear time-invariant (LTI) plant, a robust controller is often designed in order to maintain robust stability and performance of the system. In robust controller implementation, two problems might arise. First, it is interesting to know whether it is possible to simplify the controller and to what degree before its implementation while still maintaining system robust performance. The second concern arises in real-time applications where the controller may have to be retuned or redesigned several times after the initial implementation stage. In both problems, it is important to know how much a modified controller can deviate from the originally designed one in the frequency domain. The robust controller deviation is modeled as the controller uncertainty just like any other uncertainty with its own unique weighting function. A necessary and sufficient condition for robust performance as well as a sufficient condition is derived in the form of bounds on the magnitude of maximum deviation of the robust controller over a grid of frequency samples for a single-input single-output (SISO) structure. The multi-input multi-output (MIMO) case is also addressed by providing an upper bound on the maximum singular value of the system's frequency response derived at individual frequency samples, leading to a sufficient condition for robust performance. The above bounds are used in conjunction with the balanced truncation technique in order to determine how much the order of a robust controller can be reduced without losing robust performance. The order reduction limit is expressed as the maximum number of states that can be removed in a state-space realization of the robust controller for both SISO and MIMO system structures, without actually having to reduce the order. Finally, a practical approach is proposed in order to derive a robust internal model (IMC) controller for an SISO system structure. The ideal robust IMC controller is already provided as a function of the frequency response of all system components at every frequency sample. It is then approximated with a stable and preferably low order system while maintaining robust performance in three steps - the inverse fast Fourier transform (IFFT), the finite impulse response (FIR) approximation, and the FIR-to-IIR (infinite impulse response) conversion.</description><creator>Raissi Dehkordi, Vahid</creator><contributor>Benoit Boulet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Managing uncertainty in robust controller implementation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf90w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354k45h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r274s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une analyse de risques sismiques est effectuée pour Montréal, pour un scénario de tremblement de terre correspondant à un aléa de 2% en 50 ans avec le logiciel HAZUS-MH4 développé par le FEMA (Federal Emergency Management Agency). Les fichiers d'entrée des données ont été adaptés afin d'accepter les données pour la région de Montréal.  L'analyse est effectuée en discrétisant le territoire selon les secteurs de recensement, soit 522 au total.  La précision des estimations sur les conséquences d'un séisme dépend de la qualité et la quantité des données compilées. Les données recueillies pour la présente étude sur la région de Montréal incluent: 1) l'inventaire des bâtiments 2) les cartes de risques pour les effets de site, la liquéfaction et les glissements de terrain et 3) la répartition de la population à trois moments différents de la journée 4) le recensement démographique et 5) les cartes des mouvements du sol pour trois différentes équations de prédiction. Toutes ces données ont préparées et compilées dans des bases de données géo-référencées en format compatible avec le logiciel HAZUS. L'étude indique qu'environ 5% du parc immobilier serait endommagé pour des pertes économiques directes de 1,4 milliards de dollars.  Le nombre de victimes maximum est associé avec un scénario d'occurrence à 14:00 heures avec environ 500 personnes blessées.  L'incertitude épistémique a été considérée en considérant trois modèles d'atténuation proposés dans la littérature pour l'est de l'Amérique du Nord.  Les résultats indiquent que les risques sont très sensibles à l'incertitude épistémique et il est recommandé de considérer cette incertitude autant dans les études de risque que pour les analyses de l'aléa sismique.  Les prochaines étapes d'un projet d'évaluation des risques devrait étendre l'étude à la grande région métropolitaine et cibler des secteurs critiques tels que le centre-ville et le sud-est de l'île de Montréal.  La présente étude est limitée aux dommages aux bâtiments.  Il serait important de modéliser la vulnérabilité des lignes de vie et de quantifier leur impact sur l'estimation des risques.</description><description>Seismic loss estimation for Montreal, Canada is performed for a 2% in 50 years seismic hazard using the HAZUS-MH4 tool developed by US Federal Emergency Management. The software is manipulated to accept a Canadian setting for the Montreal study region, which includes 522 census tracts. The accuracy of loss estimations using HAZUS is dependent on the quality and quantity of data collection and preparation. The data collected for Montreal study region comprise: 1) the building inventory 2) hazard maps regarding soil amplification, liquefaction, and landslides 3) population distribution at three different times of the day 4) census demographic information and 5) synthetic ground motion contour maps using three different ground motion prediction equations. All these data are prepared and assembled into geodatabases that are compatible with the HAZUS software. The study estimated that roughly 5% of the building stock would be damaged with direct economic losses evaluated at 1.4 billion dollars for a scenario corresponding to the 2% in 50 years scenario. The maximum number of casualties associated with this scenario corresponds to a time of occurrence of 2pm and would result in approximately 500 people being injured.  Epistemic uncertainty was considered by obtaining damage estimates for three attenuation functions that were developed for Eastern North America.  The results indicate that loss estimates are highly sensitive to the choice of the attenuation function and suggests that epistemic uncertainty should be considered both for the definition of the hazard function and in loss estimation methodologies.  The next steps in the study should be to increase the size of the survey area to the Greater Montreal which includes more than 3 million inhabitants and to perform more targeted studies for critical areas such as downtown Montreal, and the south-eastern tip of Montreal.  The current study was performed mainly for the built environment; the next phase will need to include more information relative to lifelines and their impact on risks.</description><creator>Yu, Keyan</creator><contributor>Luc E Chouinard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Seismic vulnerability assessment for Montreal-an application of HAZUS-MH4</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pm33g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r274s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v269c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les brevets ayant trait aux biotechnologies sont octroyés depuis les années 1970. Les brevets servent d'incitatif, encourageant l'innovation et la distribution de biotechnologies en donnant aux inventeurs un control économique exclusif sur leurs inventions pour une période de temps donné. Les gouvernements d'Amérique du Nord et d'Europe ont donc utilisé les brevets en tant que politique publique pour encourager la recherche en biotechnologie, respectivement depuis les années 1980 et 1990. Cependant, malgré un objectif louable, il y a depuis quelques décénies plusieurs controverses par rapport aux brevets en biotechnologie. En effet, on distingue dans la littérature un septisisme de la part des auteurs, à savoir que les brevets pourraient freiner la recherche et restreindre l'accèes aux nouvelles biotechnologies. Alors que les données empiriques collectées jusqu'ici à ce sujet ne permettent que peu de conclusions, le débat pourrait être éclairé en prenant en compte les droits et responsabilités qui sont eu jeu.  Les droits de propriété intellectuelle en biotechnologies ne peuvent pas être justifiés d'un point de vu théorique, et donc des études empiriques supplémentaires et définitives sont nécessaires pour cerner le rôle des brevets en ce qui concerne l'innovation et la distribution de biotechnologies.</description><description>DNA patents have been being granted since the 1970s. Patents are meant to act as incentives, encouraging innovation and dissemination in biotechnology by granting inventors exclusive economic control of their inventions for a set period of time.  Governments in North America and Europe have therefore been using patents as a public policy tool to encourage the invention of health-related biotechnologies since the 1980s and 1990s, respectively.  However despite this laudable policy goal, there have also in recent decades been a number of controversies related to patenting in biotechnology.  Commentators are concerned that patents may in fact be having a detrimental effect on innovation of and access to health-related products and processes.  While empirical evidence that has been collected to date in relation to these concerns remains inconclusive, the debate may be clarified through the articulation of the rights and responsibilities that are at stake.  The scope and content of a human right to healthcare are ultimately society-dependent, but its articulation can clarify whether instrumental property rights granted to inventors are interfering with this right in an unacceptable way.  Intellectual property rights in health-related biotechnologies cannot be justified from a theoretical perspective, and so more definitive empirical data elucidating the role that patents play in regards to innovation and dissemination of health-related biotechnology is needed.</description><creator>Allen, Clarissa</creator><contributor>Iwao Hirose (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jonathan Kimmelman (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>Intellectual property and biotechnology: theoretical arguments and empirical evidence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19fb16q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v269c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gx851</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of the study was to determine if repeated exposure to a virtual reality (VR) audience environment would desensitize musicians suffering from performance anxiety when subsequently performing in front of a live audience. Sixteen university music students participated in the study. They performed in pretest and posttest concerts with live audiences. Each was assigned either to the VR condition or to a control waiting-list group. VR participants played during five weekly VR sessions, and were measured on a state anxiety inventory (SAI), heart rate and cortisol levels. Performances were recorded and evaluated by two professional musicians blindly. Other measures included a performance anxiety inventory (PAI) and the SAI. Results indicated that VR sessions elicited anxiety, as measured by cortisol levels. Also, mean PAI scores for both groups were lower at the posttest concert than at the pretest concert. Results suggest that VR exposure was not successful in helping musicians with performance anxiety.</description><description>Cette recherche avait comme objectif de déterminer si des expositions répétées à un auditoire virtuel (réalité virtuelle) pouvait désensibiliser des musiciens souffrant d'anxiété de performance à jouer devant un auditoire réel.  Seize étudiants en musique de niveau universitaire ont participé à la recherche. Ils ont participé à deux concerts devant des auditoires réels, à titre de prétest et de postest. Chaque participant fut assigné soit au groupe de contrôle ou au groupe exposé à l'auditoire virtuel.  Les étudiants exposés à la réalité virtuelle ont joué une fois semaine pour un total de cinq sessions durant lesquelles les fréquences cardiaques et les taux de cortisol furent mesurés.  Un questionnaire d'auto évaluation sur l'anxiété (State Anxiety inventory (SAI)) fut également administré. Les concerts furent enregistrés et évalués à l'aveugle par deux musiciens professionnels.  Le questionnaire d'auto évaluation sur l'anxiété (SAI) et le questionnaire sur l'anxiété de performance (Performance Anxiety Inventory (PAI)) furent administrés. Les résultats ont démontré que les sessions de réalité virtuelle ont engendré de l'anxiété chez les participants, tel qu'indiqués par les taux de cortisol. Par ailleurs, les deux groupes ont eu des scores plus bas sur le questionnaire de l'anxiété de performance (PAI) lors du concert de contrôle (postest). Les résultats semblent suggérer que l'exposition à la réalité virtuelle n'a pas aidé les musiciens avec l'anxiété de performance.</description><creator>Rahal Crawford, Christine</creator><contributor>Joel Wapnick (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Music</subject><title>Effects of exposure to virtual audience environments on performing musicians</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mc037.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx851</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n2043237</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le réchauffement planétaire est un des phénomènes les plus alarmants des nos jours. Il existe un consensus entre les scientifiques qu'afin de ralentir le réchauffement des océans et de l'atmosphère, les émissions de gaz à effet de serre anthropique (GES) devraient être réglementées. Étant le secteur de l'électricité un grand producteur de GES, ses émissions devraient faire partie de toute initiative globale de réglementation. Dans cette thèse, nous concevons et vérifions deux régimes de réglementation des émissions dans le contexte des marchés de l'électricité, un fondé sur le plafonnement et l'échange (CAT) et l'autre sur la taxe carbone (CTX). En outre, nous comparons la capacité des deux régimes pour atteindre les objectifs de règlementation d'émissions sujets aux facteurs de difficulté susmentionnés. Sous CAT, tout d'abord nous remplaçons la conception d'un marché de l'électricité oligopolistique horaire typique par un marché conjoint d'électricité et d'échanges de permis d'émission. Ce double marché tient compte des manipulations du marché de la part des Gencos (Genco gaming) pour tirer parti des coûts de production horaires, des intensités d'émissions des générateurs, des allocations horaires de permis auto-réparties par les Gencos, du droit d'échange de permis avec le marché externe et de l'élasticité de la demande. En outre, sous CTX, nous remplaçons le marché de l'électricité horaire par une version qui inclut une pénalité basée sur une taxe carbone. Ici, la manipulation du marché par les Gencos tire parti des coûts de production horaires, des intensités d'émission des générateurs, de l'élasticité de la demande et de la pénalité imposée par la taxe carbone. En outre, sous CAT, nous développons deux nouvelles approches pour partager parmi les Gencos le plafond sur les émissions imposé sur le secteur de l'électricité pendant l'intervalle d'engagement spécifié: (a) Les Gencos reçoivent gratuitement les permis d'un planificateur social (SP). Ceci est basé sur la maximisation du bien être sociale (SW) pour l'intervalle d'engagement entier, tout en comptabilisant les effets de ces permis sur le fonctionnement horaire du marché double de l'électricité et des permis ; (b) Les Gencos sont accordés de permis sur la base d'une vente aux enchères où, en plus d'optimisant le SW, le SP accepte des soumissions des Gencos à fin d'influencer l'attribution des permis, et où les Gencos payent pour leurs permis au prix de compensation de la vente aux enchères. En revanche, au titre du régime CTX, il n'y a aucun plafond d'émissions explicite. Plutôt, le plafond souhaité est atteint implicitement à travers une pénalité fiscale horaire, dont les paramètres sont calculés en maximisant le SW sur l'intervalle d'engagement. Ce calcul représente l'effet du taux de carbon horaire qui en résulte de la maximisation sur la manipulation strategique du marché par les Gencos et sur l'équilibre correspondant du marché oligopolistique. Enfin, la thèse offre une comparaison analytique et numérique approfondie de CAT et CTX sous différents scénarios. Les résultats de base suggèrent que les deux approches ont des sensiblement différents effets sur le marché et les profits, des effets qui défient certaines idées préconçues sur le règlement d'émissions. Ces résultats suggèrent que, dans l'attente d'autres études, nous concluons que la structure de taxe carbone développée dans cette thèse est le régime de réglementation d'émissions recommandée pour un marché de l'électricité oligopolistique. </description><description>Global warming is one of the most alarming phenomena facing our planet today.  There is a general consensus among scientists that in order to slow down the heating of the Earth's oceans and atmosphere, human-induced greenhouse gases (GHG) should be regulated.  Being a major GHG producer, the electricity industry's emissions should form part of any global emission regulation initiative.  In this thesis we develop an original equilibrium model for a cap-and-trade emission regulation scheme, as well as one for a carbon tax-based scheme, both applied to an oligopolistic electricity market.  The models account for the strategic behavior of power generating companies under emission regulation and explicitly illustrate how this behavior is influenced by the design of the scheme.  Both models respect the electricity sector's emission targets over a commitment interval, typically a year, while accounting for the effect of these targets (and regulation scheme) on the hourly operation of electricity markets given hourly variations in system demand.  Furthermore, in response to the global inclination to employ an auction-based approach to allocate emission permits under cap-and-trade, we develop a novel auction for commitment interval emission permits within the electricity sector, modeled as a tri-level mathematical problem with equilibrium constraints (MPEC).  The resulting permit allocation is not only influenced by bids from power generating companies, but also maximizes social-welfare by accounting for the effect of this allocation on the strategic behavior of generating companies and on the hourly operation of electricity markets. Groundwork results suggest that both schemes have significantly varying effects on market power and profits, effects that contest some preconceived ideas about both regulation schemes.  These results suggest that the carbon tax structure proposed in this thesis is the recommended emission regulation scheme for an oligopolistic electricity market.</description><creator>El Khatib, Sameh</creator><contributor>Francisco D Galiana (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Oligopolistic electricity markets under cap-and-trade and carbon tax</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vc83z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2043237</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204322z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Venetian polymath Francesco Algarotti (1712-1764) was an internationally-renowned intellectual in his time.  In 1737, he published a wildly successful popularization of Newtonian science for women entitled Il Newtonianismo per le dame, or Newtonianism for the Ladies.  The fame he acquired after its appearance continued to increase over the course of his career, with the result that he was invited to join the court of Frederick II (the Great) of Prussia, and subsequently that of Augustus III of Saxony-Poland.  In addition his sojourns at their respective courts in Berlin and Dresden, Algarotti travelled to and lived in many other European cultural centres, including Venice, Bologna, Rome, Paris, London, and St. Petersburg.  Over the course of his travels, he forged friendships with many of the leading thinkers of the period, including Eustachio Manfredi, Francesco Maria Zanotti, Laura Bassi, Voltaire, Emilie du Châtelet, Pierre-Louis Moreau de Maupertuis, Lord Hervey, Lady Mary Wortley Montagu, and Antioch Cantemir.  These contacts, and the numerous others he would come to form, would prove to be indispensable in the pursuit of his intellectual and financial goals.  Algarotti's ambition was to become an internationally renowned writer.  In a century in which scholarship was becoming increasingly international, and the market for, and reach of, printed material was considerably widened, aspiring writers faced both increased opportunities for fame and greater competition in securing the financial support they needed in order to pursue their art.  Algarotti's example illuminates both the structures behind these conditions, and the strategies that could be employed in order to negotiate them, in a pan-European context.  As an examination of his activities reveals, the formation, expansion, and maintenance of one's networks was crucial to one's intellectual success in eighteenth-century Europe.</description><description>Le penseur vénitien Francesco Algarotti (1712-1764) était un intellectuel de renommée internationale à son époque. En 1737, il a obtenu un franc succès en publiant un ouvrage de vulgarisation de la science newtonienne destiné à un public féminin, intitulé Il Newtonianismo per le dame, ou Le Newtonisme pour les dames. La notoriété qu'Algarotti a acquise avec cette publication a continué d'augmenter tout au long de sa carrière, et il fut conséquemment invité à joindre la cour de Frédéric II (Le Grand) de Prusse, puis celle d'Auguste III de Saxe-Pologne. En plus de ses séjours aux cours respectives de Berlin et de Dresde, Algarotti a voyagé et vécu dans plusieurs autres centres culturels européens, y compris Venise, Bologne, Rome, Paris, Londres et Saint-Pétersbourg. Au cours de ses voyages, il a forgé des amitiés avec plusieurs des grands penseurs de son temps, parmi lesquels Eustachio Manfredi, Francesco Maria Zanotti, Laura Bassi, Voltaire, Émilie du Châtelet, Pierre-Louis Moreau de Maupertuis, Lord Hervey, Lady Mary Wortley Montagu et Antioch Cantemir. Ces relations, ainsi que de nombreuses autres qu'il sera amené à développer, s'avéreront indispensables dans la poursuite de ses objectifs intellectuels et financiers. L'ambition d'Algarotti était de devenir un écrivain internationalement reconnu. Ce dernier a vécu au cours d'un siècle où le savoir devient de plus en plus international, un savoir à plus grande portée qui fait l'objet d'un marché, et dans lequel le monde de l'imprimé s'est considérablement développé. Les aspirants auteurs étaient confrontés, d'une part, à ces opportunités accrues d'acquérir la gloire, et d'autre part, à davantage de compétition afin de dénicher le support financier nécessaire à la poursuite de leur art. L'exemple d'Algarotti met en lumière les structures qui sous-tendent ces conditions, de même que les stratégies qui pouvaient être employées afin de les négocier, dans un contexte pan-européen. Ainsi que le révèle une analyse de ses activités, la formation, l'expansion et le maintien de ses réseaux était cruciale afin d'assurer son succès intellectuel dans l'Europe du dix-huitième siècle.</description><creator>Smeall, Cheryl Lynn</creator><contributor>Susan Elizabeth Dalton (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Valentin Boss (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>History - European</subject><title>How to become a renowned writer: Francesco Algarotti (1712-1764) and the uses of networking in eighteenth-century Europe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n80r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204322z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311t575</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude qualitative traite des limites actuelles de la recherche, de la théorie et de la pratique dans le domaine de la géropsychologie, et définit les besoins en consultation d'une population croissante de personnes âgées.  D'une façon générale, cette étude s'inspire d'une approche émique (c'est-à-dire spécifique à la culture) qui souligne l'importance de respecter l'unicité des groupes culturels en tenant compte de la perspective des membres de ces groupes dans l'avancement de la théorie psychologique, la recherche et la pratique (Arthur &amp; Collins, 2005).  En outre, l'étude répond au besoin de présenter les points de vue des clients sur l'amélioration des compétences multiculturelles des conseillers (Pope-Davis et al., 2002).  Motivée par la demande croissante en soins géropsychologiques et la nécessité sous-jacente d'évaluer l'expérience des personnes âgées qui ont recours à des conseillers psychologiques, une analyse narrative a été menée à l'aide de données d'entrevues présentant des réflexions et des récits de personnes âgées portant sur la question générale suivante : Quelles sont les expériences de thérapie psychologique vécues par des personnes âgées?  Six femmes et quatre hommes de plus de 65 ans ayant suivi une thérapie psychologique à un âge avancé ont participé à l'étude.  Des résultats de cette étude comprennent des expériences pertinentes de thérapie qui illustrent la valeur de la consultation psychologique et révélent l'importance de promouvoir des compétences des conseillers et plaidoyer à l'égard de patients plus âgés, tout en approfondissant la compréhension des forces et des limites des soins actuels en géropsychologie.  Les récits des participants ont permis de circonscrire des répercussions importantes pour la recherche, la formation et la pratique de la consultation géropsychologique.  En réponse au besoin croissant d'une recherche axée sur le client applicable aux compétences en consultation multiculturelle, cette étude présente les recommandations des participants pour des soins efficaces.</description><description>This qualitative study aims to address the limitations of current geropsychological research, theory, and practice as well as identify the counselling needs of the growing population of older adults.  Broadly speaking, this study was influenced by an emic (or culture-specific) approach that emphasizes the importance of attending to the uniqueness of cultural groups from the perspective of the members of those groups in the refinement of psychological theory, research, and practice (Arthur &amp; Collins, 2005).  As well, the study answered a call to include clients' perspectives in enhancing multicultural competence of counselors (Pope-Davis et al., 2002).  Guided by the increasing demand for geropsychological care and the associated need to gauge the current experiences of older adults undergoing psychological counselling, a narrative analysis was conducted using interview data of older adults' reflections and stories concerning the overarching question: What are older adults' experiences with psychological counselling?  Participants included six women and four men over the age of 65 who had undergone psychological counselling as an older adult.  Results from this study capture meaningful counselling experiences which highlight the value of psychological counselling and shed light on the importance of promoting competent counselling and advocacy for older clients, while deepening the understanding of the strengths and limitations of current geropsychological care.  Informed by participants' narratives, important implications can be gleaned for research, training, and practice of geropsychological counselling.  Responding to the call for client-centered research on multicultural counselling competence, this study provides participants' recommendations for competent care. Keywords: Older adults, narrative analysis, psychological counselling.</description><creator>Hunter, Winnifred Morag</creator><contributor>Park, Jeeseon (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Sinacore, Ada L. (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Psychology </subject><title>A qualitative study of older adults' experiences with psychological counselling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794082266.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311t575</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655m56t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an analysis of works derived from Russian literature and cinematography as grouped by the morphemes 'kavkaz' and 'plen' in their titles. During the last 200 years at least ten such works have appeared, the most famous being Pushkin's Prisoner of the Caucasus. These have become a fascinating phenomenon of Russian culture and the goal of my study is to analyze the intertextual links among these works. The study as a whole is based on the approaches developed by Lotman, Barthes, Zholkovsky, Likhachev and others. Thus it takes into account the specific social, historical and cultural background, underlying the phenomenon. Motif structures and its significant elements, such as 'plen', 'smert', 'zhizn', 'zerkalo', etc. are also taken into account. This is new to scholarly literature and has not previously been attempted.</description><description>La thèse présente une analyse de contenu d'oeuvres issues de la littérature et du cinéma russes regroupées par l'apparition des morphèmes «kavkaz» et «plen» dans leurs titres. Depuis deux siècles, au moins dix œuvres similaires sont apparues dont la plus connue Prisonnier du Caucase d'Alexandre Pouchkine. Celles-ci sont devenues un fascinant phénomène de la culture russe et l'objectif de mon étude est d'analyser l'intertextualité des liens parmi ces œuvres. L'étude est basée dans son ensemble sur les approches développées par Lotman, Barthes, Zholkovsky, Likhachev, et autres. L'étude prend aussi en considération de façon spécifique l'arrière-plan social, historique et culturel, soulignant le phénomène. La structure des thèmes et ses éléments fondamentaux tels «plen», «smert», «zhizn», «zerkalo», etc. ont aussi été pris en considération. Cela est donc nouveau dans une publication académique et n'a jamais été tenté auparavant. Cette étude développe donc des clés d'interprétation pour ces textes. Elle réinterprète les thèmes sur lesquels les textes sont fondés et souligne les thèmes qui n'ont jamais été utilisés précédemment dans la littérature.</description><creator>Migdissova, Svetlana</creator><contributor>Paul Murray Austin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Literature - Slavic and East European </subject><title>An analysis of a Russian cultural phenomenon: A.S. Pushkin's prisoner of the caucasus and beyond</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333653q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655m56t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593v0565</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fatigue is common and disabling in multiple sclerosis (MS). It is distinct from sleepiness. Both fatigue and sleepiness have been associated with sleep-disordered breathing, particularly obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) in other populations. While fatigue in MS is probably multi-factorial, OSA may play an important role. The main objectives of this project were to evaluate the relationship of OSA to fatigue and sleepiness in MS patients vs. normal controls, and to evaluate predictors of severe fatigue in MS subjects. Stable, ambulatory MS patients without known sleep disorders were recruited from the Montreal Neurological Hospital MS clinic. Normal controls were age and sex frequency-matched. All participants underwent diagnostic overnight polysomnography and a multiple sleep latency test (objective measure of daytime sleepiness). Fatigue was measured with the Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS) and the Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory (MFI), and subjective sleepiness with the Epworth Sleepiness Scale (ESS). Covariates included age, sex, body mass index, MS disability level, depression, pain and restless legs syndrome severity. OSA, defined as an apnea-hypopnea index (AHI) ≥ 15, was found in 36 of 62 (58%) MS subjects and 15 of 32 (47%) control subjects – OR (95% CI) 1.57 (0.67, 3.74). After adjusting for confounders, severe fatigue (FSS &gt; 5) and the MFI-mental fatigue scale (&gt; group median) were associated with AHI and respiratory-related arousals, in MS but not in control subjects. MFI-mental fatigue, in MS subjects, was also associated with intermittent hypoxemia. Subjective and objective sleepiness were not related to OSA in either group. In a multivariate model for MS subjects alone, the significant predictors of severe fatigue were the MS disability level – OR (95% CI) 1.88 (1.18, 3.33) and severe OSA (AHI ≥ 30) – OR (95% CI) 19.55 (2.31, 322.09). In summary, while OSA was not more frequent in MS than in control subjects, it was associated with severe fatigue only in MS subjects. No association was found with sleepiness. Severe fatigue in MS subjects showed a marked association with severe OSA, and a less pronounced association with MS disability level. In that OSA is a treatable condition, these findings open the door to further research that may lead to important changes in management of severely fatigued MS subjects. </description><description>La fatigue est fréquente et incapacitante dans la sclérose en plaque (SP). Elle est distincte de la somnolence. La fatigue et la somnolence ont été associées aux troubles respiratoires du sommeil, particulièrement à l'apnée obstructive du sommeil (AOS). La fatigue dans la SP est vraisemblablement multifactorielle, mais l'AOS pourrait y jouer un rôle important. Les principaux objectifs de ce projet étaient d'évaluer le rapport entre l'AOS et la fatigue ainsi que la somnolence chez les patients atteints de SP comparativement au sujets témoins, et d'évaluer les facteurs associés à la fatigue sévère chez les sujets atteints de SP. Des patients atteints de SP stables et ambulatoires sans troubles du sommeil connus ont été recrutés à la clinique de SP de l'Hôpital Neurologique de Montréal. Le groupe de sujets contrôle a été assorti en âge et sexe. Tous les participants ont passés une polysomnographie diagnostique et un test itératif de latence à l'endormissement (mesure objective de la somnolence diurne). La fatigue fut mesurée par la 'Fatigue Severity Scale' (FSS) et le 'Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory' (MFI), et la somnolence subjective avec l'échelle de somnolence Epworth (ESS). Les autres variables étaient l'âge, le sexe, l'indice de masse corporel, le niveau d'incapacité lié à la SP, la dépression, la douleur et la sévérité du syndrome des jambes sans repos. L'AOS, défini par un indice d'apnée-hypopnée (IAH) ≥ 15, a été retrouvée chez 36 des 62 (58%) sujets SP et 5 des 32 (47%) sujets témoins – rapport de cote (RC, IC 95%) 1.57 (0.67, 3.74). Après ajustement pour les facteurs confondants, la fatigue sévère (FSS &gt; 5) et le MFI – fatigue mentale (&gt; médiane du groupe) étaient associés avec l'IAH et les micro-éveils respiratoires, chez les sujets SP mais non chez les sujets contrôle. Le MFI – fatigue mentale, chez les sujets SP, était aussi associé à l'hypoxémie intermittente. Ni la somnolence subjective, ni objective n'étaient associées à l'AOS dans aucun des 2 groupes. Dans un modèle à plusieurs variables pour les sujets SP seulement, les seules variables prédisant la fatigue sévère étaient le niveau d'incapacité – RC (IC 95%) 1.88 (1.18, 3.33) et l'AOS sévère (IAH ≥ 30) – RC (IC 95%) 19.55 (2.31, 322.09). En résumé, quoique l'AOS n'aie pas été plus fréquente dans la SP que chez les sujets témoins, elle était associée à la fatigue sévère chez les sujets SP seulement. Aucune association avec la somnolence n'a été mise en évidence. La fatigue sévère chez les sujets SP était associée de façon marquée à l'AOS sévère, et de façon moins prononcée au niveau d'incapacité.  Comme l'AOS est une condition qui se traite, ces résultats ouvrent la porte à des recherches plus poussées qui pourraient ultérieurement changer la prise en charge des patients atteints de SP avec fatigue sévère.</description><creator>Kaminska, Marta</creator><contributor>Kevin Schwartzman (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Daria Trojan (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Sleep-disordered breathing and fatigue in multiple sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh997.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593v0565</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w881n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>France's transition from an agrarian-aristocratic to an industrial-consumer society accelerated in the late nineteenth century due to important innovations in the retail industry. The department store introduced fixed prices and rapid turnover of goods, making consumption easier and faster. These innovations were then spread to the working class of Paris at the Grands Magasins Dufayel. The store became more than merely a retail destination, however, as it supplied a form of leisure space and consumer entertainment in the working-class area of northern Paris. It also diffused advertising promoting a vision of a future consumer society in which the working class would enjoy greater material wealth and social opportunities, rendering traditional paternalism obsolete. In spite of its prominence in late nineteenth-century Paris, however, the Dufayel department store has been largely dismissed by current historiography which sees the advent of consumer culture as a fundamentally bourgeois phenomenon. But by considering the Dufayel experiment on its own terms rather than as an imitation of bourgeois consumer culture we gain new insights on several aspects of late nineteenth-century consumer culture. We learn that in many ways the bourgeoisie was ambivalent with respect to the emergence of consumer culture, seeking whenever possible products or advertisements that hid their mass-produced origin. In this light the department store itself, far from being a tool for the dissemination of bourgeois values, was often a threat to those values, and its elaborate advertising was needed to distract the bourgeois shopper from this fact. Bourgeois ambivalence about consumer culture was expressed in the outbreak of food-adulteration anxiety in the late nineteenth-century press, when consumer culture was associated with the decline in quality and, more importantly, the loss of authenticity in French food. Finally we are able to see how one example of consumer technology--the phonograph--triumphed in turn-of-the-century Paris because promoters were able to exploit class divisions in order to shape the public into a common consumer market. </description><description>La transformation de la France d'une nation agraire et aristocratique à une société de consommation industrielle s'est accélérée en fin du XIXe siècle en raison d'importantes innovations dans le secteur commercial. Le grand magasin a introduit les prix fixes et les taux de rotation rapide des marchandises, ce qui a rendu la consommation plus facile et plus rapide. Ces innovations ont ensuite été étendues à la classe ouvrière de Paris aux Grands Magasins Dufayel. Le magasin est devenu plus qu'une simple destination de détail en fournissant de l'espace de loisir et de divertissement dans les quartiers populaires du nord de Paris. Il a également diffusé la publicité proposant une vision de la société de consommation future dans laquelle la classe ouvrière bénéficierait d'une nouvelle richesse matérielle ainsi que des opportunités sociales, rendant obsolète le paternalisme traditionnel. En dépit de son importance à la fin du XIXe siècle, Dufayel a été largement ignoré par l'historiographie actuelle qui voit la culture de la consommation comme un phénomène fondamentalement bourgeois. Mais en considérant l'expérience Dufayel selon ses propres termes, plutôt que comme une imitation de la culture bourgeoise, nous pouvons acquérir de nouvelles connaissances sur plusieurs aspects de la culture de consommation à la fin du XIXe siècle. Nous apprenons que de nombreuses façons la bourgeoisie était ambivalente à l'égard de la culture de consommation, recherchant les produits ou les publicités qui déguisait leur origine industrielle. Dans cette perspective le grand magasin lui-même, loin d'être un outil pour la diffusion des valeurs bourgeoises, a souvent menacé ces valeurs; sa publicité était un moyen de détourner l'acheteur bourgeois de ce fait. Cette ambivalence a été exprimée dans la presse du XIXe siècle sous la forme de l'anxiété à propos du frelatage alimentaire quand la culture de consommation a été associée à une baisse de qualité et à la perte de l'authenticité de la cuisine française. Enfin nous pouvons voir comment une technologie de consommation - le phonographe - a triomphé à Paris quand les promoteurs ont réussi à exploiter les préjugés de classe afin de créer un marché de consommation commun.</description><creator>Wemp, Brian</creator><contributor>John William Hellman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>History - European</subject><title>The Grands Magasins Dufayel, the working class, and the origins of consumer culture in Paris, 1880-1916</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dt58m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w881n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268949d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A novel approach whereby one can use probiotic bacteria for the purpose of topical and oral therapy is presented. More specifically, a treatment modality using enzymatically active probiotic production of gaseous nitric oxide (gNO) for wound healing, antimicrobial, cosmetic, and dermatologic therapy is presented. In another aspect, a probiotic treatment modality for metabolic disease and metabolic syndrome using nitrate reductase (NiR) active probiotic bacteria is explored. In concurrence to these requirements, several in-vitro methods are designed and discussed in this report. For some of these studies the use of alginate microcapsules is explored. Results show that probiotic patches can be used for the production of gNO above therapeutic levels and for therapeutic durations and that probiotic gNO-producing patches are highly bacteriostatic, bactericidal, and fungicidal. Results show that the novel gNO-producing probiotic patch can be used to improve wound healing and increase the likelihood of wound closure in ischemic and infected full-thickness dermal wounds in a New Zealand White Rabbit model and that daily application of the patch is safe with respect to body weight, blood morphology, haematology, blood biochemistry, and methemoglobin levels. Also, results show that novel NiR-active probiotic bacteria can be selected for nitrate reductase (NiR) activity in-vitro, and can be microencapsulated or delivered free under simulated GI conditions, and in the presence of various food matrices while maintaining NiR activity, confirming the lab scale feasibility of the approach in delivering the probiotic orally for treating hypertension, inflammatory bowel disease, gastric ulcers, diabetes and thrombosis. These findings may provide effective, safe, and less costly alternatives for delivering gNO topical and oral for therapy.</description><description>Une nouvelle approche selon laquelle on peut utiliser des bactéries probiotiques dans le but de la thérapie topique et de la thérapie par voie orale est présentée. Plus précisément, une modalité de traitement, utilisant des probiotiques à activité enzymatique produisant de l'oxyde nitrique gazeux (NOg) pour la cicatrisation des plaies, ainsi que comme thérapies antimicrobiennes, cosmétiques et dermatologiques, est présenté. Dans un autre aspect, une modalité de traitements probiotiques pour les maladies métaboliques et les syndromes métaboliques en utilisant du nitrate réductase (NiR) bactéries probiotiques actives est explorée. En accord à ces exigences, plusieurs méthodes in vitro sont conçus et discutés dans le présent rapport. Pour certaines de ces études l'utilisation de micro capsules d'alginate est explorée également. Les résultats montrent que les correctifs probiotiques peuvent être utilisés pour la production de NOg au-dessus des niveaux thérapeutiques et pour des durées thérapeutiques et que les  patches de NOg-producteurs de probiotiques  sont très bactériostatiques, bactéricide et fongicide. Les résultats montrent que les nouvelles patches de NOg producteurs de probiotiques peuvent être utilisés pour améliorer la cicatrisation et augmenter la probabilité de fermeture de la plaie dans les plaies de pleine épaisseur ischémique et infectés par voie cutanée dans un modèle néo-zélandais White Rabbit et que l'application quotidienne des patches est sécuritaire en proportion avec le poids du corps, la morphologie du sang, l'hématologie, biochimie sanguine, et les niveaux de méthémoglobine. En outre, les résultats montrent que les nouvelles NiR-bactéries probiotiques actives peuvent être sélectionnés pour la nitrate réductase (NiR) l'activité in vitro, et peut être micro encapsulées ou remis gratuitement dans des conditions simulées GI, et en présence de diverses matrices alimentaires, tout en maintenant l'activité NiR, confirmant ainsi la faisabilité échelle du laboratoire de l'approche dans la réalisation des probiotiques par voie orale pour le traitement de l'hypertension, les maladies inflammatoires de l'intestin, les ulcères gastriques, le diabète et la thrombose. Ces résultats peuvent s'avérer efficaces, sûrs, et des solutions moins coûteuses pour offrir NOg topiques et oraux pour le traitement.</description><creator>Jones, Mitchell</creator><contributor>Satya Prakash (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Enzymatically active probiotic bacteria for topical and oral therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z508r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268949d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w95w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'insuffisance cardiaque (IC) et la goutte sont des conditions médicales fréquentes qui sont des causes importantes de morbidité et de mortalité au Canada et aux États-Unis.  Nous avons entrepris une étude populationelle « case-control » avec des données administratives de la province du Québec pour investiguer l'association entre la goutte ou l'allopurinol avec le prognostic de l'IC.  Notre analyse démontre qu'un antécedent de goutte est associé à une hausse du taux de réadmissions à l'hôpital pour l'IC et une augmentation de la mortalité parmi les patients avec IC (RR ajusté 1.63; 95% CI 1.48-1.80).  Cependant, nous demontrons que la prise d'allopurinol est associée à une réduction de la réadmission à l'hôpital pour IC et une diminution de la mortalité (RR ajusté 0.69, 95% CI 0.60-0.79).  Comme notre étude est observationelle, les facteurs confondants qui ne sont pas disponibles ou qui sont inconnus peuvent biaiser nos résultats.  Nous présentons une nouvelle méthode qui permet l'estimation et le contrôle de ces facteurs confondants basée sur l'estimation du « confounding rate ratio ».  Nous présentons un example utilisant cette nouvelle méthode, et nous discutons les suppositions, les limitations et les considérations statistiques de cette méthode.   </description><description>Heart failure (HF) and gout are common medical conditions that lead to significant morbidity and mortality in Canada and the US.  We conducted a population-based nested case-control study to investigate the associations between gout, allopurinol use and HF outcomes using administrative data from the province of Quebec.  Our analysis demonstrates that a history of gout is associated with increased HF readmission and death in HF patients (adjusted RR 1.63; 95% confidence interval (CI) 1.48-1.80).  We also show that chronic allopurinol use, a common medication for gout, is associated with reductions in adverse outcomes in HF patients with a history of gout (adjusted RR 0.69, 95% CI 0.60-0.79). Due to the observational nature of our study, residual confounding due to unknown or unmeasured confounding could still bias our findings.  Herein, we present a novel method to estimate and control for such confounding by estimating the confounding risk ratio during the null induction time.  Use of this method is illustrated using an example from the literature and we discuss the assumptions, limitations and statistical considerations of our method. </description><creator>Thanassoulis, George</creator><contributor>James Brophy (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Louise Pilote (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Gout and allopurinol use in heart failure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zs52t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w95w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t6258</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'automutilation non-suicidaire (AMNS) est un phénomène qui prend de plus en plus d'ampleur chez nos jeunes.  Certains chercheurs ont donc entamé des études, afin d'identifier les facteurs de risques et les influences sociales qui initient et encouragent l'AMNS dans cette portion de la population.  Malgré les nombreux facteurs sociaux qui peuvent influencer un jeune à s'initier à l'AMNS, plusieurs scientifiques ont débuté des recherches plus approfondies sur les mécanismes d'apprentissages liés à l'AMNS.  Ces dernières ont tenté d'établir des différences entre les groupes de personnes auto-blessantes et ceux qui ne s'auto-blessent pas.  En particulier, dans le domaine de la maitrise de soi-même et de la capacité à régulariser leurs émotions ainsi que tous les facteurs sociaux qui pourraient inciter une personne à entamer l'AMNS.  De plus, cette étude s'est penchée sur l'influence de chacun de ces facteurs dans sa contribution à l'initiation à l'AMNS et sa contribution aux fréquences élevées de l'utilisation de l'AMNS.  Une série de mesures psychosociales a été complétée auprès d'étudiants dans leur première année universitaire dont la moitié s'identifiait comme personne qui pratique l'AMNS ou qui l'avait déjà pratiqué.  Les résultats démontrent que les personnes auto-blessantes différaient des personnes qui ne s'auto-blessaient pas dans les trois domaines examinés, témoignant des difficultés à régulariser leurs émotions et à avoir moins de maitrise sur soi-même dans la plupart des domaines examinés.  De plus, les personnes auto-blessantes subissent plus intensément l'influence sociale dans deux des trois domaines étudiés.  Pour prédire l'engendrement de l'AMNS, la capacité de régulariser ses émotions et l'apprentissage sociale sont les facteurs prépondérants.  Par contre, la maitrise de soi-même ne semble pas contribuer de façon significative à ce qu'une personne se joigne au groupe d'AMNS.  Finalement, la régularisation de ses émotions est le seul facteur ayant un lien probant avec la fréquence élevée d'AMNS. Ni la maitrise de soi-même ni l'apprentissage sociale n'influencent la fréquence de l'AMNS chez une personne auto-blessante.  Il est possible que la première tentative d'AMNS soit reliée à la régularisation des émotions et aux facteurs d'apprentissage social, mais une personne qui continue cette pratique le fait plus particulièrement pour des raisons de renforcement automatique.  Cette modification du système de renforcement fonctionnel est étudiée par rapport à des publications récentes sur le sujet, et les implications pour les chercheurs et les intervenants en milieu social seront discutées en conséquence.</description><description>Due to reports of high rates of non-suicidal self-injury (NSSI) among adolescents and young adults in the community, researchers have begun to examine the role of risk factor and social influence of NSSI on the initiation and maintenance of these behaviours among youth.  Despite numerous reports of the social factors that surround youth who engage in NSSI, the need for a more comprehensive understanding about the learning mechanisms involved in NSSI engagement has arisen.  The present study sought to examine differences between groups of self-injurers and non-self-injurers on the dimensions of emotion regulation and self-control, as well as the presence of social learning related to NSSI.  Additionally, the present study directly examined the predictive power of each variable with regard to the likelihood of initial engagement in NSSI, as well as high frequency NSSI.  A series of psychosocial measures were completed by first-year university students, and results were compared across groups of self-injurers and non-self-injurers.  Results indicated that self-injurers differed from non-self-injurers in all three areas examined, reporting more difficulties in emotion regulation and lower levels of self-control in most areas.  In addition, self-injurers reported a higher level of social learning in two of the three areas of social learning examined.  For initial NSSI engagement, social learning was found to be the strongest predictor, with emotion regulation also predicting NSSI to a lesser extent.  In contrast, emotion regulation was the only variable that significantly predicted a self-injurer's likelihood of engaging in high frequency NSSI.  Neither social learning nor self-control played a role in the occurrence of frequent NSSI among self-injurers.  It is possible that for some, the first episode of NSSI may be related to either social learning factors, emotion regulations difficulties,  or both, whereas the same behaviour may continue at a high frequency for reasons more closely tied to its emotion regulatory benefits. This shift in functional reinforcement is explored in relation to recent publications in the field, and implications for researchers and service providers are discussed.</description><creator>Holly, Shareen</creator><contributor>Nancy Lee Heath (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Psychology </subject><title>Non-suicidal self-injury among university students: examining emotion regulation, self-control, and social learning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cj576.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t6258</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hw86p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the early 1970s, mathematician and economist Nicolas Georgescu-Roegen developed an alternative framework to macro-economics (his hourglass model) based on two principles of classical thermodynamics applied to the earth-system as a whole. The new model led him to the radical conclusion that "not only growth, but also a zero-growth state, nay, even a declining state which does not converge toward annihilation, cannot exist forever in a finite environment" (Georgescu-Roegen 1976, p.23). Georgescu-Roegen's novel approach long served as a devastating critique of standard neoclassical growth theories. It also helped establish the foundations for the new trans-disciplinary field of ecological economics. In recent decades however, it has remained unclear whether revolutionary developments in "modern non-equilibrium thermodynamics" (Kondepudi and Prigogine 1998) refute some of Georgescu-Roegen's initial conclusions and provide fundamentally new lessons for very long-term macro-economic analysis. Based on a broad historical review of literature from many fields (thermodynamics, cosmology, ecosystems ecology and economics), I argue that Georgescu-Roegen's hourglass model is largely based on old misconceptions and assumptions from 19th century thermodynamics (including an out-dated cosmology) which make it very misleading. Ironically, these assumptions (path independence and linearity of the entropy function in particular) replicate the non-evolutionary thinking he seemed to despise in his colleagues. In light of modern NET, I propose a different model. Contrary to Georgescu-Roegen's hourglass, I do not assume the path independence of the entropy function. In the new model, achieving critical free energy rate density thresholds can abruptly increase the level of complexity and maximum remaining lifespan of stock-based civilizations.</description><description>Au début des années 1970s, le mathématicien et économiste Nicolas Georgescu-Roegen développa une alternative radical au modèle de macro-économie standard de l'époque : son « sablier  entropique ». Celui-ci fut fondé sur des principes de thermodynamique classique appliqués à l'ensemble du globe. La nouvelle approche thermodynamique de Georgescu-Roegen a longtemps servi de forte critique des théories de croissance économique conventionnelles, ainsi qu'au fondement d'une nouvelle science interdisciplinaire : l'économie écologique, ou aussi, la bioéconomie. Néanmoins, à travers ces dernières décennies, il est demeuré incertain si d'importantes découvertes en thermodynamique de systèmes hors d'équilibre (NET) (Prigogine 1980, 1984, 1998): 1) ne réfuteraient pas plusieurs prémices et conclusions de Georgescu-Roegen. C'est ce que j'ai ici tenté d'investiguer, à l'aide d'une recherche dans l'histoire de plusieurs sciences. Je conclue que le modèle initiale de Georgescu-Roegen (le « sablier entropique »)  dépend de plusieurs conceptions et prémices scientifiques maintenant considérées comme dépassées. En guise de développements dans le domaine de la thermodynamique de systèmes hors d'équilibre, je propose un nouveau modèle, qui ne prend pas pour acquis que les limites (thermodynamique) d'évolution d'un système macro-économique soit indépendant de la trajectoire du système en question. En particulier, la capacité d'atteindre des seuils critiques de densité de flux énergétique peut changer de façon radicale non-seulement le niveau de complexité (structurel et fonctionnel) d'une civilisation, mais aussi les limites de longévité d'une civilisation (problème qui est centrale à l'approche de Georgescu-Roegen).</description><creator>Poisson, Alexandre</creator><contributor>Peter Gilbert Brown (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography </subject><title>Implications of Modern Non-Equilibrium Thermodynamics for Georgescu-Roegen's Macro-Economics: Lessons from a Comprehensive Historical Review</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pm351.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw86p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p4572</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La Formation Lindsay, qui se trouve au sud-est de l'Ontario, a recemment été selectionée pour la construction d'un repositoire souterrain de dechets nucleaires. Puisque les elements radionucleaires sont entreposé sous la terre, leur migration est normalement empechée en utilisant des barrieres artificielles. Cela dit, pour créer un projet qui sera efficace pour la demi-vie des isotopes radioactives, de 50 000 a 100 000 ans, il faut aussi considérer la formation de roches sous le site comme étant une barriere additionelle. Cette thèse examine l'utilisation des tests de pulsion hydraulique pour estimer la perméabilitée de la Roche Calcaire Lindsay. Les tests ont été faits sur des cylindres ayant un diametre de 100 mm. Ces cylindres ont été prélevés de la roche dans la direction parallèle au plan de stratification ainsi que perpendiculairement cette direction. Durant les tests, les specimens ont été sujet a des pressions uniformes qui ont été variées de 5 MPa a 20 MPa. Ceci a causé une augmentation de la permeabilitée dans les spécimens perpendiculaires au plan de sratification d'environ 7 fois la permeabilitée originale, et une petite diminution de la permeabilitée dans la direction des plaines de déposition. Malgré les changements aux valeurs de la perméabilitée dans les spécimens, ces valeurs sont restées ≤10^-22 m^2, ce qui indique que le site est idéal pour la construction d'un repositoire souterrain.</description><description>The Lindsay Formation located in southern Ontario has been selected as a site for the construction of a deep geological repository for low to intermediate level nuclear waste. In order to prevent the migration of any radionuclides escaping the engineered barriers within the repository, the underlying material, Lindsay Limestone, must also be treated as an additional barrier. This thesis examines the use of hydraulic pulse testing in order to estimate the permeability of Lindsay Limestone. Tests are performed on 100 mm diameter samples cored both perpendicular to and along the bedding planes. The samples are subjected to isotropic confining stresses that are cycled from 5 MPa to 20 MPa resulting in a seven times increase in permeability perpendicular to the bedding plane, and a slight decrease parallel to the bedding plane. Including the recorded alterations, permeability estimates all remain ≤10^-22 m^2 showing that the material is a good candidate for a geological repository.</description><creator>Letendre, Antoine</creator><contributor>Selvadurai, A. P. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Permeability changes in Lindsay Limestone due to isotropic compression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gq09h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p4572</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc847</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Modified nucleosides form an important class of antiviral and anticancer agents, and nucleic acids bearing modified nucleosides hold great promise as therapeutic agents. Oxepane nucleosides and nucleic acids are members of this important class of compounds. Oxepane nucleosides have a seven-membered carbohydrate ring instead of the canonical five-membered pentafuranose ring. This thesis describes work in the development of new synthetic approaches and routes in the synthesis of oxepane nucleosides. In chapter 2, the synthesis of oxepane nucleosides based on the ring expansion approach is described. Building on previous work in the Damha lab, studies in the synthesis of oxepane nucleosides by a ring expansion approach were carried out. In particular, oxepane nucleosides were synthesized using thioglycoside derivatives. Routes in the modification of the oxepane scaffold were explored, but later abandoned in favor of new synthetic approaches to oxepane nucleosides. In chapter 3, work towards the development of new routes in the synthesis of oxepane nucleosides by ring-closing metathesis is described. This new approach to the synthesis of oxepane nucleosides allows for the use of commercially-available nucleosides and circumvents the difficulties observed in glycosylation reaction employed in the previous approach. In chapter 3, various synthetic routes are examined, and work towards the development of viable routes is described. In particular, the direct addition of Grigard reagents to nucleosides dialdehydes, followed by Grubbs II mediated ring closing metathesis serves as a proof-of-principle of the synthesis of oxepane nucleosides by a ring closing route. </description><description>Les nucléosides modifiés sont des agents thérapeutiques très efficaces contre le cancer et contre des virus.  Les oxepanes font partie de ce groupe important. Au lieu d'avoir un cycle de 5 atomes, les oxepanes ont un cycle modifié de 7 atomes. Cette thèse décrit la recherche sur le développement de nouvelles méthodes pour la synthèse des oxepanes. Dans le deuxième chapitre, la synthèse des oxepanes par la méthode d'expansion de cycle est traitée. Notamment, la synthèse des oxepanes par le biais des hétérosides contenant des thiols est décrite. Dans le troisième chapitre, de nouvelles méthodes pour la synthèse des oxepanes sont étudiées. Toutes ces approches ont pour but ultime d'utiliser la métathèse d'alcènes comme l'étape clé. Notamment, l'addition directe des réactifs de Grignard à des nucléosides contenant deux aldéhydes, suivi d'une métathèse d'alcène, constitue une démonstration de faisabilité de cette approche synthétique. </description><creator>Gallant, Pascal</creator><contributor>Masad J Damha (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Synthesis of oxepane nucleosides by ring expansion and ring closing routes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n7362.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc847</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pf737</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Atrial fibrillation (AF) is the most sustained arrhythmia in the population and is associated with increased morbidity and mortality. A variety of cardiac disease entities, including valve disease, cardiomyopathies, hypertension and diabetes increase the risk of AF. However, present drug therapies are ineffective and can even increase the risk of dangerous ventricular tachyarrhythmias. Studies in animal models show that AF is associated with atrial remodeling that favors AF induction and maintenance. The mechanisms of atrial remodeling depend on the underlying pathology. Atrial remodeling caused by atrial tachycardia or AF itself is primarily electrical, associated with changes in the expression and function of ion channels. These changes are reflected in decreased atrial refractory periods, impaired refractoriness adaptation to rate and conduction slowing. Together, these electrical changes increase the incidence of AF. Heart failure (HF), an important cause of AF, induces another type of atrial remodeling. HF-remodeling is characterized by conduction heterogeneity and altered atrial structural properties. In particular, interstitial fibrosis plays a major role in the stabilization of reentry circuits and prolongation of AF duration.Although many studies have described a large number of the changes associated with each form of remodeling, the underlying mechanisms remain poorly understood. The goal of this thesis was to clarify the molecular mechanisms underlying the atrial remodeling associated with AF. In my first study, I put forward the hypothesis that atrial remodeling caused by atrial tachycardia and that resulting from HF differ in terms of the time course and nature of underlying changes in cardiac gene expression. I indeed discovered that the changes in gene expression induced by atrial tachycardia and HF were qualitatively different and evolved differently over time. The changes by atrial tachycardia were limited and showed time-dependent adaptation, whereas the changes induced by HF were qualitatively greater and more varied, and showed qualitative evolution with the development of the pathology. In my second study, I put forward the hypothesis that HF caused by ventricular "tachycardiomyopathy" causes differential gene-expression changes in atria versus ventricles and that these changes evolve over time. This study highlighted the signaling pathways implicated in atrial remodeling like those of MAP kinases, ubiquitin/proteasome systems and apoptosis, along with specific metabolic pathways like the electron-chain transport system and Krebs cycle at the ventricular level.Even though the large-scale study of gene-expression changes allowed us to identify certain signaling systems, they do not detect post-translational alterations. In our third study, I put forward the hypothesis that tachycardia-induced HF causes progressive changes in the proteins involved in different functional groups that play an important role in atrial pathophysiology. My results highlighted proteins linked to oxidative stress, metabolism and contractile proteins.In my final study, I decided to explore a new therapeutic avenue for AF prevention based on the molecular pathophysiology of AF. I had identified the MAP kinase ERK as a particularly important molecule in atrial remodeling caused by myocardial infarction in the rat and I had obtained results implicating a microRNA (miR21) in signaling leading to pathological ERK hyperphosphorylation. I therefore suggested that atrial interstitial fibrosis could be prevented by targeting underlying microRNA-related mechanisms and thereby reduce the inducibility and maintenance of AF caused by HF. My study is not yet completed but the preliminary results suggest beneficial effects of anti-miR21 treatment in preventing AF. In conclusion, my studies indicate the molecular pathophysiology underlying AF and suggest that it can be exploited to develop new therapeutic approaches.</description><description>La fibrillation auriculaire est l'arythmie supra-ventriculaire soutenue la plus commune et est associée à un taux élevé de morbidité et de mortalité.  Les traitements pharmacologique actuels demeurent inefficaces et entraînent parfois même une augmentation du risque d'arythmies ventriculaires. Les études effectuées sur différents modèles animaux ont démontré que la fibrillation auriculaire était associée à un remodelage auriculaire qui favorisait son induction et son incidence. Les mécanismes de remodelage auriculaire diffèrent selon la pathologie sous-jascente. Le remodelage auriculaire induit par une tachycardie auriculaire ou une fibrillation auriculaire est principalement électrique, associé à l'altération de l'expression et de la fonction de canaux ioniques. Ces changements se reflète par un raccourcissement des périodes réfractaires, une diminution d'adaptation au rythme et un ralentissement de la vélocité de conduction, augmentant ainsi l'incidence de la fibrillation auriculaire. L'insuffisance cardiaque, induit un remodelage auriculaire principalement caractérisé par une hétérogénéité de conduction associée à une altération des propriétés structurelles de l'oreillette. Notamment, la fibrose interstitielle joue un rôle majeur dans la stabilisation de circuits de réentrée et la prolongation de la durée de la fibrillation auriculaire. Bien que plusieurs études aient décrit un grand nombre de changements associés à chacun de ces types de remodelage, les mécanismes qui sous-tendent ces changements demeurent mal connus. Dans notre première étude, nous avons émis l'hypothèse selon laquelle le remodelage auriculaire induit par la tachycardie auriculaire et celui induit par une défaillance cardiaque diffèreraient au point de vue de l'évolution temporelle et de la nature des changements au niveau génomique. Nous avons constaté que les changements d'expression génique induits par la tachycardie auriculaire et par la tachycardie ventriculaire étaient qualitativement différents et évoluaient de façon différente dans le temps. Comparativement aux changements survenant au niveau auriculaire, les changements ventriculaires observés au point de vue biochimique et histopathologique différaient en terme d'intensité et de progression temporelle. Dans notre deuxième étude, nous avons émis l'hypothèse que l'insuffisance cardiaque induite par une tachycardie soutenue entraînait des changements d'expression génique qui diffèreraient entre les oreillettes et les ventricules et ces changements seraient évolutifs. Cette étude nous a permis de mettre en évidence l'implication des voies de signalisations telles que la voie des MAP kinases, l'apoptose et le système ubiquitine/protéosome au niveau auriculaire et certaines voies métaboliques au niveau ventriculaire. Bien que l'étude des changements d'expression génique nous permette de mettre en évidence certaines voies de signalisation, les changements survenant au niveau post-transcriptionel ne sont pas toujours détectables par une approche génomique. Dans notre troisième étude, nous avons donc émis l'hypothèse que l'insuffisance cardiaque induite par une tachycardie ventriculaire entraînait un remodelage auriculaire qui impliquerait des changements évolutifs importants d'expression de protéines de différents groupes fonctionnels. Nos résultats ont montré un changement au niveau de protéines liées au stress oxydatif, au métabolisme et aux protéines contractiles. Dans notre dernière étude, nous avons exploré une nouvelle avenue thérapeutique dans le traitement préventif de la fibrillation auriculaire. Nous avons suggéré que la fibrose interstitielle pourrait être prévenue par la modulation de mécanismes de régulation de l'expression de gènes par des microARN, qui réduirait l'inductibilité et le maintien de FA en contexte d'insuffisance cardiaque. Nos résultats préliminaires suggèrent un effet bénéfique du traitement anti-miR21 pour réduire la fibrillation auriculaire.</description><creator>Cardin, Sophie</creator><contributor>Stanley Nattel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</subject><title>Molecular mechanisms underlying atrial remodeling</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580r776.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pf737</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732df15x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>CONTEXTE La surveillance des maladies infectieuses est un défi en constante évolution et un progrès continu au niveau des méthodes et des infrastructures est nécessaire pour répondre à la demande. Une nouvelle approche est la surveillance syndromique, où le personnel de santé publique, assisté de collecte automatisée de données et d'alertes statistiques, surveille des indicateurs de santé en temps quasi-réel. Plusieurs systèmes de surveillance syndromique s'appuient sur les diagnostics issus de bases de données administratives. Parce que ces codes de diagnostics ne font pas l'objet d'audits, l'effet de variations dans leur codage sur les définitions syndromiques demeure inconnu. OBJECTIFS 1) Évaluer la faisabilité d'identifier des syndromes à partir des diagnostics issus des services facturés par les médecins. 2) Évaluer l'exactitude de définitions syndromiques basées sur les diagnostics issus des services facturés par les médecins.3) Identifier les caractéristiques du médecin, du patient, de la rencontre médecin-patient et du mode de facturation associées au coefficient de prédiction positif (CPP) des définitions syndromiques. MÉTHODES &amp; RÉSULTATS ÉTUDE 1: Cette étude a porté sur un seul syndrome (respiratoire). Nous avons comparés les cas positifs et négatifs identifiés à partir de la facturation, aux dossiers médicaux. Un échantillon de 9 médecins généralistes Montréalais a été utilisé. Les diagnostics de 3 526 visites effectuées par 729 patients ont été extraits des dossiers médicaux, et reliés à la facturation. La sensibilité et le CPP des diagnostics d'infection respiratoire issus de la facturation étaient 0.49 et 0.93. Cette étude de faisabilité a permis la planification d'une validation à grande-échelle de plusieurs définitions syndromiques. ÉTUDE 2: Cette étude a porté sur 5 syndromes: fièvre, gastro-intestinal, neurologique, cutané et respiratoire. Nous avons sélectionné aléatoirement 3600 médecins pratiquant au Québec en 2005-2007 et, parmi tous les services facturés, 10 visites par médecin. Pour chaque visite, le diagnostic du dossier médical a été obtenu grâce à une révision de dossier à double insu. La sensibilité, la spécificité, le CPP et le coefficient prédictif négatif (CPN) des définitions syndromiques basées sur les diagnostics issus de la facturation ont été estimés. 1098 (30.5%) médecins ont participé à l'étude et 10529 visites ont été validées. La sensibilité des définitions syndromiques variait de 0.11 pour la fièvre à 0.44 pour le syndrome respiratoire. La spécificité et le CPN étaient élevés pour tous les syndromes. Le CPP variait de 0.59 pour la fièvre à 0.85 pour le syndrome respiratoire. ÉTUDE 3: Nous avons restreint notre échantillon aux 4330 visites des 1098 médecins de l'étude 2 où le diagnostic de la facturation correspondait à l'un des syndromes. Nous avons utilisé une régression logistique multi-variée afin d'estimer l'association entre l'accord facturation-dossier et les caractéristiques du médecin, du patient, de la rencontre médecin-patient et du mode de facturation. La probabilité que le dossier médical confirme un syndrome présent selon la facturation était plus élevée lorsque le médecin avait facturé plusieurs visites pour le même syndrome récemment, avait une charge de travail moindre, et lorsque le patient était plus jeune et moins défavorisé socialement. CONCLUSIONS Cette étude a été la première validation à grande-échelle de définitions syndromiques basées sur les diagnostics issus des services facturés par les médecins. Nous avons découvert que la sensibilité de ces définitions est faible, le CPP varie de moyen à élevé, et la spécificité et le CPN sont élévés. Nous avons identifiés maintes caractéristiques du médecin, du patient, de la rencontre médecin-patient et du mode de facturation associées au CPP des définitions syndromiques, dont plusieurs sont accessibles aux agences de santé publique et pourraient être utilisées pour améliorer les systèmes de surveillance syndromique.</description><description>BACKGROUND Keeping pace with the rapidly evolving demands of infectious disease monitoring requires constant advances in surveillance methodology and infrastructure. A promising new method is syndromic surveillance, where health department staff, assisted by automated data acquisition and statistical alerts, monitor health indicators in near real-time. Several syndromic surveillance systems use diagnoses in administrative databases. However, physician claim diagnoses are not audited, and the effect of diagnostic coding variation on surveillance case definitions is not known. Furthermore, syndromic surveillance systems are limited by high false-positive (FP) rates. Almost no effort has been made to reduce FP rates by improving the positive predictive value (PPV) of surveilled data. OBJECTIVES 1) To evaluate the feasibility of identifying syndrome cases using diagnoses in physician claims. 2) To assess the accuracy of syndrome definitions based on diagnoses in physician claims. 3) To identify physician, patient, encounter and billing characteristics associated with the PPV of syndrome definitions. METHODS &amp; RESULTS STUDY 1: We focused on a subset of diagnoses from a single syndrome (respiratory). We compared cases and non-cases identified from physician claims to medical charts. A convenience sample of 9 Montreal-area family physicians participated. 3,526 visits among 729 patients were abstracted from medical charts and linked to physician claims. The sensitivity and PPV of physician claims for identifying respiratory infections were 0.49, 95%CI (0.45, 0.53) and 0.93, 95%CI (0.91, 0.94). This pilot work demonstrated the feasibility of the proposed method and contributed to planning a full-scale validation of several syndrome definitions. STUDY 2: We focused on 5 syndromes: fever, gastrointestinal, neurological, rash, and respiratory. We selected a random sample of 3,600 physicians practicing in the province of Quebec in 2005-2007, then a stratified random sample of 10 visits per physician from their claims. We obtained chart diagnoses for all sampled visits through double-blinded chart reviews. Sensitivity, specificity, PPV, and negative predictive value (NPV) of syndrome definitions based on diagnoses in physician claims were estimated by comparison to chart review. 1,098 (30.5%) physicians completed the chart review and 10,529 visits were validated. The sensitivity of syndrome definitions ranged from 0.11, 95%CI (0.10, 0.13) for fever to 0.44, 95%CI (0.41, 0.47) for respiratory syndrome. The specificity and NPV were high for all syndromes. The PPV ranged from 0.59, 95%CI (0.55, 0.64) for fever to 0.85, 95%CI (0.83, 0.88) for respiratory syndrome. STUDY 3: We focused on the 4,330 syndrome cases identified from the claims of the 1,098 physicians who participated in study 2. We estimated the association between claim-chart agreement and physician, patient, encounter and billing characteristics using multivariate logistic regression. The likelihood of the medical chart agreeing with the physician claim about the presence of a syndrome was higher when the physician had billed many visits for the same syndrome recently (RR per 10 visits, 1.05; 95%CI, 1.01-1.08), had a lower workload (RR per 10 claims, 0.93; 95%CI, 0.90-0.97), and when the patient was younger (RR per 5 years, 0.96; 95%CI, 0.94-0.97) and less socially deprived (RR most vs least deprived, 0.76; 95%CI, 0.60-0.95). CONCLUSIONS This was the first population-based validation of syndromic surveillance case definitions based on diagnoses in physician claims. We found that the sensitivity of syndrome definitions was low, the PPV was moderate to high, and the specificity and NPV were high. We identified several physician, patient, encounter and billing characteristics associated with the PPV of syndrome definitions, many of which are readily accessible to public health departments and could be used to reduce the FP rate of syndromic surveillance systems.</description><creator>Cadieux, Geneviève</creator><contributor>David Buckeridge (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Robyn Tamblyn (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Public Health</subject><title>Assessing and improving the accuracy of surveillance case definitions using administrative data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k663v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732df15x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hd987</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette recherche s'intéresse à la façon d'évaluer les compétences grammaticales dans les cours universitaires d'écriture langue seconde (L2). Selon la littérature, les compétences grammaticales comprennent la syntaxe et la morphologie (Purpura, 2004; Weigle, 2002) de même que les formes lexicales, la cohésion et la gestion de l'information au niveau sous-phrastique, phrastique et supra-phrastique (Purpura, 2004). Par conséquent, les professeurs d'écriture devraient, lors de l'étude de textes en L2, miser sur la morphosyntaxe et sur d'autres aspects grammaticaux utiles à l'organisation de l'information et assurant la cohésion au niveau de la phrase, du paragraphe et du texte. En s'appuyant sur une approche méthodologique mixte  (Creswell &amp; Plano Clark, 2007), utilisant une triangulation de données qualitatives et quantitatives, cette recherche vise à déterminer quels sont les indicateurs de performance grammaticale sur lesquels s'appuient les professeurs d'écriture (n = 2) lorsqu'ils évaluent les compositions de leurs étudiants (n = 33). Les étudiants de l'échantillon étaient inscrits à une université canadienne anglophone et suivaient un cours d'anglais de niveau intermédiaire ou avancé. D'autre part, cette recherche a pour objectif de déterminer à quel point l'apprentissage des étudiants est influencé par les critères d'évaluation de leur professeur. Dans la première partie de la recherche, les compositions des étudiants et les notes de grammaire données par le professeur ont été collectées et analysées quantitativement, en utilisant des mesures de justesse et de complexité grammaticales comme indicateurs de la compétence morphosyntaxique.  Elles ont également été analysées qualitativement dans un cadre linguistique systémique fonctionnel afin de déterminer la compétence des étudiants à gérer l'information dans leurs textes. Dans la seconde partie de la recherche, des questionnaires ont été administrés aux étudiants et certaines entrevues ont été menées afin d'évaluer la connaissance qu'avaient les étudiants des critères d'évaluation de leur professeur en ce qui a trait à la grammaire. Dans la troisième partie, les professeurs ont été interviewés au sujet de leurs critères et priorités dans l'évaluation de la grammaire. Enfin, les résultats des trois parties et des quatre sources d'informations ont été réunis afin d'en arriver à une interprétation globale des conclusions. Les résultats révèlent que les professeurs d'écriture priorisent surtout la justesse grammaticale lorsqu'ils évaluent les compétences grammaticales de leurs étudiants. Par conséquent, les professeurs d'écriture semblent s'appuyer sur une définition plus limitée  de la compétence grammaticale dans l'évaluation des textes de leurs étudiants que ce qui est défini par la littérature à ce sujet, ce qui a nécessairement un effet sur la façon d'apprendre des étudiants qui suivent des cours d'écriture. Cette thèse se termine par une discussion qui met en lumière ce qu'impliquent ces résultats et où sont émises certaines recommandations au sujet de l'évaluation en écriture dans un cours de L2.</description><description>This study investigates how grammatical ability is assessed in L2 academic writing classrooms. In the assessment literature, grammatical ability is defined to include syntax and morphology (Purpura, 2004; Weigle, 2002) and lexical forms, cohesion, and information management on the subsentential, sentential, and suprasentential levels (Purpura, 2004). Writing teachers would, therefore, need to attend to morphosyntactic and other grammatical aspects in L2 texts that serve to organize information and create cohesion on the sentence, paragraph, and text levels. In a mixed methods triangulation design (Creswell &amp; Plano Clark, 2007) using both quantitative and qualitative methods, this study examines the indicators of grammatical ability that writing teachers (n = 2) attend to when assessing their students' (n = 33) grammatical ability in academic essays in one high-intermediate and one advanced L2 writing course at an English-medium university in Canada. In addition, the study considers to what extent the students' learning is affected by the teachers' assessment criteria. In the first phase of this study, the students' essay exams and the teacher-assigned grammar grade were collected and analyzed quantitatively using accuracy and complexity measures as indicators of morphosyntactic ability. They were also examined qualitatively within a framework of systemic functional linguistics to assess the students' ability to manage information in their texts. In phase two, student questionnaires were administered, and student interviews were conducted to determine the students' knowledge of the teachers' assessment criteria for grammar. In phase three, the teachers were interviewed about their criteria and their priorities in the assessment of grammar. Finally, the results from all three phases and all four data sources were integrated to come to an overall interpretation of the findings. The results indicate that writing teachers focus above all on grammatical accuracy when assessing their students' grammatical ability. Consequently, writing teachers seem to assess a reduced construct of grammatical ability in academic writing, compared to definitions in the L2 assessment literature. This emphasis has an impact on how students learn in these L2 writing classrooms. This dissertation concludes with a discussion of implications and makes recommendations for L2 writing assessment based on the findings of this study.</description><creator>Neumann, Heike</creator><contributor>Carolyn E Turner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Tests and Measurements </subject><title>What's in a grade? A mixed methods investigation of teacher assessment of grammatical ability in L2 academic writing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494d52q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hd987</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53x1095</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'immigration constitue une composante importante de croissance de la population canadienne. Les politiques d'immigration sont élaborées pour attirer et retenir des immigrants qui réussiront leur intégration au sein de la société canadienne. Pourtant, plusieurs professionnels immigrant au Canada ne vivent pas une intégration professionnelle réussie, ce qui entraîne des conséquences au niveau de l'intégration sociale. Cette thèse décrit les expériences de travail ainsi que l'évolution de l'identité de carrière de dix Sri Lankaises d'ethnie cingalaise ayant immigré au Québec, au Canada, entre 1977 et 2007. Cette thèse qualitative se sert d'une méthodologie narrative afin d'explorer le développement de l'identité de carrière au Sri Lanka, les expériences de travail au Québec et la rétrospective du développement de carrière au cours de la vie. Les résultats démontrent un développement de carrière au Sri Lanka encouragé par la famille et les systèmes de soutien, et propulsé par des facteurs socioculturels et économiques favorisant l'éducation et l'emploi. Les participantes ont démontré des comportements de carrière autonomes visant des buts professionnels assortis aux valeurs professionnelles et aux traits de personnalité. Plusieurs d'entre elles avaient une carrière bien établie. Après leur immigration à Montréal, au Canada, les participantes ont été confrontées à plusieurs obstacles au développement de carrière, ces derniers provenant des systèmes d'immigration, d'éducation, du marché du travail et du contexte socioculturel. L'expérience de ces obstacles est associée à de profonds changements affectifs et cognitifs liés à l'identité de carrière et des changements de comportement, d'aspirations professionnelles, de valeurs d'emploi et de cheminement professionnel. L'identification de carrière et la satisfaction d'emploi ont initialement chuté, alors que les participantes ont vécu des pertes reliées aux changements professionnels. De plus, elles étaient accablées par les exigences de l'adaptation et les fardeaux familiaux et financiers. Celles ayant vécu le plus longtemps au Québec ont atteint un niveau de satisfaction professionnelle modeste après avoir modifié leurs objectifs de carrière, tandis que les autres se situent entre l'espoir et la résignation professionnelle. Cette étude se conclut avec des recommandations pour l'amélioration de la recherche, la pratique d'activités de counselling et des politiques reliées à l'emploi et à l'intégration des immigrants.</description><description>Immigration is a significant component of Canada's population growth, and immigration policies are designed to attract and retain qualified immigrants to improve the likelihood of successful integration into Canadian society.  However, many professionals who migrate do not fare well in the Canadian labour market, which is problematic because workforce integration is an important aspect of successful resettlement.  This dissertation describes the career experiences and career identity evolution of ten Sri Lankan Sinhalese women who immigrated to Quebec, Canada between 1977 and 2007.  This qualitative study uses a narrative methodology to explore these women's career identity development in Sri Lanka, their career experiences in Quebec, and their retrospective lifespan career identity development.  The findings showed that career identity development in Sri Lanka was encouraged by family and support networks, and propelled by sociocultural and economic factors that encouraged women's education and employment.  Participants demonstrated career behaviours that were goal-oriented and self-directed and had career goals that aligned with career values and personality traits.  They embarked on their intended career trajectories and several had well-established careers in Sri Lanka.  After immigrating to Montreal, Canada, participants experienced significant barriers to career development from immigration, educational, sociocultural and employment systems.  The experience of these barriers was associated with profound affective and cognitive changes to career identity and modifications to career behaviours, career aspirations, career values, and career trajectories.  Identification with their career and career satisfaction sharply decreased initially, as participants experienced losses associated with their career changes, as well as feeling overwhelmed by the multiple demands of resettlement and the dual burdens of parenting and income-generation.  The longest-residing participants attained a modest level of career satisfaction after changing their career goals and identities while others ranged between hopeful expectation and resignation to current occupations.  This dissertation makes an initial examination of the career identities and career experiences of a population of South Asian immigrant women which may inform future research.  This study concludes with recommendations for theory, practice, and policy related to immigrant employment and resettlement.</description><creator>De Silva, Nilmini</creator><contributor>Jack Destefano (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jeeseon Park (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Psychology - General</subject><title>Sri Lankan women's career identity evolution after immigration to Montreal, Quebec, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd75n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x1095</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644w83p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anthropogenic greenhouse gas emissions are the main cause of increasing global temperatures. Climate change will affect crop production in Canada and, in turn agriculture has the potential to mitigate climate change. Analysis of historical climate and corn yield data, and field and greenhouse experiments were carried out in order to study the effect of climate variability and changes on corn yield, the adaptability of cropping systems to climate change conditions, the effect of tillage on soil greenhouse gas emissions (CO2 and N2O) associated with corn and soybean production, and the potential of Nod factors to increase biomass as way to mitigate CO2 emissions. In southwestern Quebec, corn yield variability has been strongly associated to July temperature and May precipitation during the last three decades. Field studies showed that switchgrass and sorghum-sudangrass were best adapted to dry and warm climate events. No-till improved corn yield when spring temperatures were warmer than normal. Soil CO2 fluxes were associated with temperature, while soil N2O fluxes were associated with precipitation. Conventional tillage (CT) had greater CO2 emissions than no-till (NT), particularly after disking in the spring. Both tillage systems had large N2O emission peaks during the wettest part of the season. In corn, peaks of N 2O occurred after nitrogen fertilizer application. NT had greater N 2O emissions than CT in the corn production systems; however, CT had greater N2O fluxes than NT in the soybean production system. Nod factors sprayed on soybean increased photosynthesis and biomass under controlled conditions. In the field, yield was increased by Nod factors under CT, but not under NT, and drought reduced the soybean response to Nod factors.</description><description>Les émissions anthropogènes de gaz à effet de serre sont la cause principale de l'augmentation globale des températures. Les changements climatiques vont affecter la production agricole au Canada, et en retour, l'agriculture pourrait limiter les changements climatiques. L'analyse de données historiques du climat et des rendements de maïs, combinés avec des expériences de serre et en champ ont été entreprises pour étudier l'effet de la variabilité et des changements de climat sur le rendement de maïs, l'adaptabilité des systèmes agricoles aux changements climatiques, l'effet du travail du sol sur les émissions de gaz à effet de serre (C02 et N20) associées avec la production de maïs et de soya, et le potentiel des facteurs Nod d'augmenter la biomasse pour limiter les émissions de CO2. L'analyse des données historiques ont démontré qu'au sud-ouest du Québec, la variabilité des rendements de maïs est fortement associée avec les températures de juillet et les précipitations de mai pendant les dernières trois décennies. Les expériences au champ ont démontré que le panic raide, et le sorghum-sudangrass sont les mieux adaptés aux conditions chaudes et sèches. Le semis direct a augmenté les rendements de maïs lorsque les températures printanières étaient plus chaudes que la normale. Les flux de C02 étaient associés avec la température, mais les flux de N20 étaient associés avec les précipitations. Le travail du sol conventionnel (CT) a produit plus d'émissions de CO2 que le semis direct (NT), particulièrement après le disquage au printemps. Les deuxsystèmes ont montré un large pic d'émission de N20 pendant les périodes les pluspluvieuses. Dans le maïs, les pics de N20 ont été détectés après la fertilisation enazote. NT a montré des émissions de N20 plus importantes que CT en productionde maïs, mais CT a montré des flux de N20 plus important que NT en productionde soya. Les facteurs Nod vaporisés sur le soya ont augmenté la photosynthèse etla biomasse sous conditions controllées. Au champ, le rendement a été augmentépar les facteurs Nod sous CT, mais pas sous NT, et la sécheresse a réduit laréponse du soya aux facteurs Nod.</description><creator>Almaraz Suarez, Juan Jose.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Corn -- Yields -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Crops and climate -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Climatic changes -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Climate change and crop production in southwestern Quebec : mitigation and adaptation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Juan Jose Almaraz Suarez, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pv59g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w83p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37575</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>