<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:53:52Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gz13d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:09:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There exists an embedded assumption that broadcasting must be employed to strengthen the Canadian national identity. Despite efforts to Canadianize our broadcasting system, however, Canadians are watching more and more American television and have more choice of American programming. This has led to a fear of American television as a threat to Canada's continuance as a separate and independent country. By studying the contemporary Canadian context with respect to Canadian drama, the following questions will be addressed: Are Canadian interests dependent on communication policy? Is Canadian dramatic programming essential to the maintenance and enhancement of national identity and cultural sovereignty? Can the illusive quality "Canadian" be defined? Do television dramas made in Canada have distinctively Canadian characteristics and if so, how are these characteristics perceived by audiences? What are the options and alternatives that Canadian policy makers and programmers must face in the midst of the massive internationalization of culture and the onset of the 500 channel universe? In answering these questions, this study sets out to demonstrate how Canadian dramatic programming can be distinctive and unique in a way which still maintains an audience loyalty and a relevance to the Canadian way of life.</description><creator>Goldman, Marni Lisa</creator><contributor>Levin, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Television broadcasting -- Social aspects -- Canada</subject><subject>National characteristics, Canadian</subject><subject>Television broadcasting -- Canada -- Influence</subject><subject>Television programs -- United States</subject><subject>Television programs -- Canada</subject><title>"Oh say can you see, eh?" : the Canadian identity debate and its relation to television</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm30v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz13d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p58k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:09:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Occupationism recently has been introduced and defined as discrimination on the basis of one's occupation (Carson, 1992; Krumboltz, 1991, 1992). In this qualitative study, the existence of occupationism is investigated through the examination of the results of interviews with six funeral directors. The statements of the participants describing occupationist acts (either positive or negative) were classified into a number of categories at both fine-grained and more superordinate levels. Implications of the results for the proposed occupationism construct and suggestions for future research and career interventions are discussed.</description><creator>Akçali, F. Özge</creator><contributor>Carson, Andrew D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Discrimination</subject><subject>Undertakers and undertaking</subject><title>Occupationism : occupational discrimination in relation to funeral directors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p918k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p58k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg44q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:09:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thin film solar cells of CdS/CuInSe$ sb2$ fabricated on electrodeposited CuInSe$ sb2$ films were studied to determine the diffusion length of minority carriers. The relationships between capacitance versus voltage, capacitance against frequency were first investigated. A dispersion effect of the capacitance-voltage curves was observed, confirming the presence of either interface states or deep levels in the depletion region. The minority carrier diffusion length was measured by two different methods, namely the photocurrent and capacitance method and the differential photocurrent method. For a cell with an efficiency of about 5% with a doping concentration in the order $10 sp{16}$ cm$ sp{-3}$ in the CuInSe$ sb2$ substrate, the electron diffusion length was in the range from 0.3 to 0.9 $ mu$m. This value is relatively small as compared with that for monocrystalline CuInSe$ sb2$ devices due to the presence of interface states and deep levels in the thin film cells. However, the value is comparable to that observed on vacuum deposited CuInSe$ sb2$ thin film cells. Optical absorption coefficient $ alpha$ for the CuInSe$ sb2$ film was deduced using the differential photocurrent method. The results are comparable to those on the electrodeposited CuInSe$ sb2$ thin films reported in the literature.</description><creator>Li, L. (Lee)</creator><contributor>Shih, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Measurements of electron diffusion length in CdSCuInSe2 solar cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r7589.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg44q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd635</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:09:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this work was to evaluate the technical feasibility of potable water production from both sea water and sodium chloride solutions via the membrane distillation process. Membrane distillation is a thermally driven process in which a hydrophobic microporous membrane separates a hot or warm saline solution from a cold desalinated one. Water, in the form of vapour, migrates from the hot solution to the cold one. Two different hollow fibre membrane distillation modules were used to conduct experiments. Tests were performed to determine the sensitivity of permeate flux and quality to stream temperatures and flowrates, and feed concentration. The hot side temperature was found to have a greater effect on the water flux than the cold side temperature. Water flux values ranged from 0.5 to 1.6 Kg/m$ sp2$hr with salt removals of over 99.99%. A semi-empirical model, based on well established heat and mass transfer correlations, was developed and its predictions were validated with the experimental results.</description><creator>Lacoursière, Stéphanie</creator><contributor>Simandl, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Water purification by membrane distillation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb48k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd635</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d201d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:09:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The implementation of a knowledge-based expert system to check on inpatients' conditions is described. In our development of a bedside computerized ICU, graphical user interface (GUI) and graphical visualization have been extensively exploited to facilitate the natural and effective representation of clinical information for patient care, the transition from the manual system to computerized system and users interaction with the system. The input comprises the heart rates, the blood pressures, and the central venous pressures of several inpatients. The algorithm is made up of two parts. The first one, written in C acquires and classifies the data. The second part compares the classified data with the medical information stored in its data base, and draws a conclusion regarding the patient's condition. C Language Integrated Production System (CLIPS) 5.0 is the knowledge-based expert system utilized. The results obtained from the Expert system are displayed using the Simple Raster Graphics Package (SRGP). This system has been implemented and tested on a variety of inputs, and the results are depicted.</description><creator>Hosseinzadeh, Abolfazl</creator><contributor>Malowany, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A rule-based system for vital sign monitoring in intensive care</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j317j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d201d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm924</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of quench conditions on the properties of fumed silica generated using an arc process was studied. The process consisted of vaporizing quartz particles in a batch transferred arc reactor using the radiative energy from an Ar/NH$ sb3$ thermal plasma. Ammonia was used to increase the vaporization rate of quartz. The hot gas stream exiting the reactor contained a mixture of the decomposition products of NH$ sb3$ and SiO$ sb2$. This included SiO$ sb{ rm (g)}$, O$ sb2$, H$ sb2$ and N$ sb2$. Rapid quenching of this gas stream with steam resulted in the production of a fumed silica aerosol. Collection of the product took place in a baghouse filter. The quench conditions studied included pre-quench temperature, T$ sb{ rm q}$, and supersaturation, P$ sb{ rm s}$, quench rate, R$ sb{ rm q}$, and quench stoichiometry, S$ sb{ rm q}$. P$ sb{ rm s}$ was defined as the molar ratio of SiO$ sb{ rm (g)}$ flow, calculated from the quartz weight loss during an experiment, to the SiO$ sb{ rm (g)}$ flow predicted at equilibrium. S$ sb{ rm q}$ was the molar ratio of steam to SiO$ sb{ rm (g)}$ flow. In general, high pre-quench temperatures, high quench rates, and low pre-quench supersaturation ratios, produced high surface area powders. Quench stoichiometry did not have an effect here, but the use of a large excess of steam in the quench caused the degree of surface hydroxylation to be high. In all cases, the characteristic chain-like aggregate shape and an amorphous morphology were produced. The thickening and thixotropic ability of the powders was found to be significant compared to commercial brands of fumed silica. The best fumed silica produced during the study was found to be 46% as effective as Aerosil$ sp circler$ 200 and 60% as effective as Cab-O-Sil$ sp circler$ M-5. The experimentally generated powders were not equivalent to the commercial brands due to a lack of surface area. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Addona, Tony</creator><contributor>Munz, R. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The effect of quench conditions on the properties of fumed silica produced using an arc process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv87b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm924</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010s20q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following utterance is an exploration into the interactive space of glass and the disparity found in metaphors of its transparency. The rhetoric of transparency is initially scrutinized through a story that elaborates, in audacious generalizations, on the totalitarianism that comes out of the atheist rationalism of the Enlightenment. These generalizations are probed specifically in a look at the role of glass architecture and the consequent suppression of the body to a belief in an all-powerful reason. The inquiry then switches to the operation of the destabilizing effect of a space that devours with its reflections and spatial ambiguities. As absolute transparency is defied by experience in the material world, the space of glass is investigated as an instrument for dissolving the identity of controlling institutions. From the subversive character of reflections, the final look is at the possible emergence of a new attitude and thinking inspired by that experience which does not serve ideological certitudes, but contradicts them.</description><creator>Hamel, Catherine</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1991</date><subject>Glass construction</subject><title>Reflections on glass : trials and tribulations of a lingering observer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k63p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s20q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x591v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydro-Quebec's electricity exports greatly affect our economy and our environment. They may be concluded either under "interconnection agreements" to sell excess capacity and production during off-peak periods, or completed under "firm sales" contracts. Hydro-Quebec exports could thereby replace production plants that are needed and difficult to build south of the border. Economics and regulation of the American industry have led to the writing of too much rigidity into the clauses. There are long term, responsibility, major force and other clauses that prevent the contracts from adapting to the changing competitive market conditions. Utilities involved in such international sales would be well advised to adopt standard formats, preferably of medium term duration. In this way, Hydro-Quebec will ensure itself of becoming a specialized supplier of electricity to the United States and thereby take advantage of its low production costs.</description><creator>Labbé, Jean-François</creator><contributor>de Mestral, A. L. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Energy.</subject><title>Les contrats d'exportation d'électricité Québec - USA</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q18z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x591v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xn69k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Whereas EEC merger law has always been influenced by a tradition of hospitality to industrial concentrations combined with receptivity to government regulations, US merger law evolved originally from a tradition of inhospitality to concentrations and a strong preference for competition over government regulation of performance to a sensitive approach to consumer's interests and a more tolerant stance towards mergers. Therefore, although influenced by different history and focus both sets of merger law have certain common features and objectives and seem to head towards a better coordination of their respective antitrust authorities and a lessening of U.S./E.E.C. jurisdictional conflicts over merger enforcement.</description><creator>Voinot, Eric P.</creator><contributor>Janda, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Business Administration, General.</subject><title>Horizontal merger laws in the U.S. and the E.E.C. : a comparison</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505239h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn69k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sr971</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation is an investigation into the architectural meaning of Kasimir Malevich's suprematist works and, more specifically, into the meaning of his Architectons of horizontal and vertical constructions. A critical "rewinding" of the diverse and seemingly contradictory suprematist periods--starting with the artist's chef d'oeuvre, his Funeral-Performance and moving backwards to the figurative works, the Architectons and then, to the 1913 Black Square, in its beginnings in futurist Zaum poetry--makes patent the fragmentary nature of the meaning of those periods and introduces Suprematism-as-Architecture as the meaning of Suprematism in its entirety. Malevich's extensive written work is the guiding thread we follow in trying to demonstrate how the full meaning of Suprematism echoes, in the context of our Nietzschean world, Martin Heidegger's presentation of questions concerning building. Suprematism-as-Architecture equally opens up avenues of questioning concerning modern man's relation to the attainment of an architectural meaning, i.e., of a thinking-dwelling.</description><creator>Cardoso, Tarcisio</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Architecture -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Malevich, Kazimir Severinovich, 1878-1935</subject><subject>Suprematism in art</subject><title>Suprematism-as-architecture : opening the way to K. Malevich's work</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb39f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr971</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn50z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the mechanical design of the prototype of a planar three degree-of-freedom parallel manipulator with revolute joints and the design and implementation of a closed-loop control circuit which controls the motors of the constructed manipulator. Mechanical design here is understood as the decision-making process involved in tasks such as: material selection, structural design and drive selection. In this study the aforementioned tasks for the three degree-of-freedom parallel manipulator are described in detail and their conclusions are used for the construction of the manipulator. Finally a motor speed/control system for the control of the selected motors, to form a complete microprocessor-controlled DC motor servopositioning system, is designed. The final application circuit which includes additional hardware as well, is implemented connected and tested with the motors of the constructed prototype. In addition an introduction to parallel processing and an interface proposal are made as a first step towards the next phase of this project.</description><creator>Kounias, Sophia E. S.</creator><contributor>Vroomen, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Design, manufacture and control of a planar three degree-of-freedom parallel manipulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs92g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn50z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x3376</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a program of research aimed at examining the social psychological consequences of being a victim of discrimination. An experimental paradigm was developed to determine if, and to what extent, disadvantaged group members perceive the discrimination that confronts them. Women were asked to react to negative feedback after receiving information about the probability that they had been discriminated against. When discrimination was made ambiguous, subjects minimized their personal experience with discrimination and attributed their failure to themselves. A second experiment investigated the role of perceived control as a potential cause of minimization of personal discrimination. The results indicated that disadvantaged group members were reluctant to blame their performance on discrimination because in so doing, they were placing control for their outcomes in the hands of others rather than themselves. The findings are discussed in terms of their implications for the on-going victimization of disadvantaged group members.</description><creator>Ruggiero, Karen M.</creator><contributor>Taylor, Donald M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Sex discrimination against women -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Social perception.</subject><subject>Self-esteem in women.</subject><title>The social psychological consequences of being a victim of discrimination</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj297.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3376</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257g964</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of the present investigation was to evaluate the role of the pulmonary diffusion capacity (as measured by DLco) in relation to exercise-induced hypoxemia in elite athletes working at near maximal exercise intensities. Twenty-four elite cyclists were submitted to a direct measurement of VO$ sb2$ max on cycle ergometer which permitted classification into one of two groups. "Desaturaters" (N = 13) if oxyhemoglobin saturation (SaO$ sb2$%), as determined by finger oxymetry, fell below 91% or "non-desaturaters" if SaO$ sb2$% remained above 91%. Subsequent determinations of the transfer capacity for CO (DLco) were made using a 3 second breath-hold technique (Gould 2400/2450), at rest as well as at 60% and 90% of previously determined VO$ sb2$ max ($&gt;$4.0 1/min). The results show an increase in DLco from rest to the first exercise intensity (desat: 41.7 $ pm$ 5.7 to 55.1 $ pm$ 4.7; non-desat: 41.1 $ pm$ 5.8 to 57.2 $ pm$ 6.9 mlsCO/mmHg/min) without much further increase to the maximal workload (desat: 61.0 $ pm$ 6.0; non-desat: 61.4 $ pm$ 9.5 mls CO/mmHg/min). No significant differences in DLco were found between the two groups at rest or either of the two exercise intensities. Significant differences between the desat and non-desat groups were found for FVC, post-exercise FEF$ sb{25-75 %}$, and VE/VO$ sb2$. The present results are in agreement with previous reports showing arterial desaturation in 50% of highly-trained subjects when VO$ sb2$ max $&gt;$4.0 1/min. The present investigation cannot clearly establish the role of DLco in this response. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kiteala, Lori</creator><contributor>Turcotte, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Oxygen -- Physiological transport</subject><subject>Anoxemia</subject><subject>Cycling -- Physiological aspects</subject><title>The relationship between exercise intensity, pulmonary diffusion and hemoglobin saturation in competitive endurance athletes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d859g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257g964</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv67m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the last half of the nineteenth century, a remarkable number of European artists were influenced by Japanese art and culture, a trend which has been labelled "Japonisme." Among the major Post-Impressionist artists, Paul Cezanne (1839-1906) alone has been viewed as untouched by this influence, largely because of the strong three-dimensional quality of his art. This study provides a reassessment of the issue of Cezanne and "Japonisme" by concentrating on the flat, two-dimensional aspect of his art. The development of Cezanne's conceptualized and schematized treatment of the Mont Sainte-Victoire theme is considered both formally and iconographically in relation to the image of Mt. Fuji by the influential Japanese printmaker, Katsushika Hokusai (1760-1849). Illustrating that Cezanne's path toward Modernism in painting may have been influenced by the Japanese print, and particularly the art of Hokusai, this study leads to a more profound understanding of Cezanne's development and the ideographic language of his images of Mont Sainte-Victoire.</description><creator>Matsumoto, Kaoru</creator><contributor>Kiefer, Carol Solomon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Cézanne, Paul, 1839-1906.</subject><subject>Katsushika, Hokusai, 1760-1849</subject><title>Cézanne and Hokusai : the image of the mountain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064782p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv67m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh661</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with al-Mawardi's concept of the imamate as expounded not only in al-Ahkam al-Sultaniyyah, but also in his other political treatises which are related to the subject. It is divided into a long introduction, two chapters, and a conclusion. After first introducing the controversial issue of the imamate and its historical background, the introduction exposes al-Mawardi's life, career and works, and discusses views on him expressed by modern scholars. The first chapter discusses the nature of the imamate focusing on its origin and necessity, the methods whereby the imam comes to power, the imam's duties and the possibilities for him to be deposed. The second chapter examines the political subdivision within the imamate and its consequences, namely, the presence of other institutions: the wazirate and the amirate. The conclusion sums up the general concept of the imamate in the works of al-Mawardi.</description><creator>Nafis, Muhammad</creator><contributor>Adams, Charles J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Imams (Shiites)</subject><title>The concept of the imamate in the works of al-Māwardī</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257g97d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh661</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182n225</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to answer the following questions, each of which corresponds, sequentially, to chapter in this thesis: (1) What is the internal composition and the historical contextualization of the 18th chapter of the Qur'an, the Surat al-Kahf? (2) Who is al-Khadir, a figure in the Surat al-Kahf, verses 66-82? How has he been described in Muslim commentary and how has he been analyzed in nineteenth and twentieth century scholarship; and with whom has he been associated and/or identified in such commentary and scholarship? (3) How are probable prototypes or parallels of Khadir portrayed in non-Islamicate documents traceable to before the advent of Islam? (4) What are the characteristics of the association/identification of Khadir with Elijah (Ilyas)?</description><creator>Jervis, James Paul</creator><contributor>Adams, Charles J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>Al-Khāḍir : origins and interpretations : a phenomenological study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq76g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182n225</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j746k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the history of the Acehnese Islamic empire, focusing on the events leading up to its decline in both its internal stability and its hegemony in the surrounding regions in the second half of the seventeenth century. During the given period (1641-1699) the empire was ruled successively by four female rulers. The thesis deals with the political and economic developments in this period. Aceh was an Islamic empire in the Indonesian archipelago which emerged as the greatest and most influential Islamic power in the region from the middle of the sixteenth century to the early seventeenth century. It reached its golden age during the reign of Sultan Iskandar Muda (1607-1636) who succeeded in developing the empire into an unrivaled Muslim power whose control included the West Sumatran coast and the Malay peninsula. During his reign, Aceh became the holder of the political and economic hegemony in the region. Towards the second half of the seventeenth century, the power of Aceh gradually declined from its peak both internally and externally. Internally, political disintegration paved the way for the process of power transition between political groups within the empire. Externally, both the political importance and the economic supremacy of the empire in the region was drastically reduced. Consequently, its power again shrank back into the north-Sumatran area from which the empire originally emerged.</description><creator>Auni, Luthfi</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Indonesia -- History -- 1478-1798</subject><subject>Aceh (Indonesia) -- History</subject><title>The decline of the Islamic empire of Aceh (1641-1699)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698953q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j746k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1618247</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The design of thermomechanical processing schedules to control microstructures requires the knowledge of the austenite-to-ferrite transformation start temperature (Ar$ sb3$). Further, in curved mold continuous casting, transverse cracking occurs during the unbending procedure to straighten the solidified curved strand, and this can also strongly depend on the austenite-to-ferrite transformation. In both of these industrial processes, during deformation, the temperature usually decreases continuously. Thus, two new methods to determine the Ar$ sb3$, based on continuous cooling compression (CCC) and continuous cooling torsion (CCT), have been developed. While the latter is applicable for low and high strains, the former can be only used for low strains. The aim of this investigation was to determine the effect of deformation in the single phase austenite and two phase austenite plus ferrite region on the transformation and dynamic transformation behaviour of austenite-to-ferrite. CCC tests were carried out on a low carbon steel and the influence of strain, strain rate, cooling rate and austenite grain size, was examined. During the application of strain, the generated dislocations cause an increase in stored strain energy. This energy adds to the driving force for austenite-to-ferrite transformation, increasing the kinetics of this transformation, raising the Ar$ sb3$ in this way. The faster kinetics leads to a finer polygonal ferrite grain size after transformation. In contrast to the effect of increasing strain, accelerated cooling rates decrease the transformation start temperature, but can still lead to grain refinement via high nucleation rates. By increasing the cooling rate, fine acicular ferrite with a high aspect ratio could be obtained. Since, the ferrite grain size is directly related to austenite grain size, by varying austenite grain size, a wide range of ferrite grain sizes could be obtained. Finally, deforming close to the Ar$ sb3$ maximizes the strain effect on dynamically transformed ferrite.</description><creator>Pandi, Rassoul</creator><contributor>Yue, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Dynamic transformation of austenite to ferrite in low carbon steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c90r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1618247</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b088z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the past number of years, the study of language has been engaged in increasingly by a wide variety of academic disciplines and fields. Perhaps this bears witness to the growing appreciation of the pivotal role that language plays in our formation as individual persons, as peoples and as cultures. As a particular kind of speech, liturgical language takes seriously the multi-dimensional nature of human reality, and, among other things, addresses itself to the profound questions of meaning posed by the human condition, as well as the 'needs' that arise in the posing of these questions. Further, as a rich communicative complex, liturgical language is itself multi-dimensional and multi-valent. This study is undertaken to investigate the meaning of this kind of language. To do this, the analytical 'lenses' of Ritual, Performative Language Theory, and Metaphor will be employed and discussed.</description><creator>Bailey, Anthony D. (Anthony Dean Arthur)</creator><contributor>McLelland, Joseph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Meaning (Philosophy)</subject><subject>Liturgical language</subject><title>An investigation into the meaning of liturgical language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr61h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b088z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95052408</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Simulated learned helpless behavior was examined among gifted, gifted underachievers, and unselected children. Using the Intellectual Achievement Responsibility (IAR) Scale (Crandall, Katkovsky, &amp; Crandall, 1965), after the children read a brief story and cast themselves in a failing role, the three groups of children were compared before and after the intervention (a week or two after the initial testing) on their positive and negative IAR scores. Learned helplessness theory would predict that helpless children would have high negative scores (attributing failure to themselves) and low positive scores (attributing success to external factors). Negative IAR scores did not differ or change across trials. Positive IAR scores for both gifted groups declined considerably over trials. The unselected group's positive IAR scores differed from those of both groups of gifted children in that they declined but not as drastically at posttest. All three groups' positive scores decreased to varying degrees across trials, indicating that nobody took personal responsibility for success after imagining themselves as a failure. In this respect, one aspect of learned helpless behavior was elicited. The results suggest that gifted children are capable of showing behavior which might indicate learned helplessness.</description><creator>Corber-Wiltzer, Cheryl Lisa</creator><contributor>Shore, Bruce M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Helplessness (Psychology) in children</subject><title>Learned helplessness in gifted, gifted underachieving, and unselected children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p2332.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052408</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b8094</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research has shown that young minority children often like other racial groups as much or more than their own-group, while young majority children express dislike for children of other racial groups and prefer children who are similar to themselves in race and language. As majority children grow older, their tolerance for children of other races increases, in part, because of changes in cognitive level. The study investigated the pattern of development of attitudes associated with cognitive maturity among a group of black children. Measures of racial attitudes and preferences were related to cognitive maturity as assessed by measures of conservation but were not related to the racial constancy task. The attainment of more mature racial cognitions did not lead to the expected changes in attitudes and preference. This would suggest that the relationship between racial bias and racial identity constancy was more complex than had been hypothesized.</description><creator>McShine, Marcelle Leontine</creator><contributor>Pedersen, Eigil (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Children, Black -- Attitudes</subject><title>Differences in racial attitudes related to cognitive maturity in black children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k7155.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b8094</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg00d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis tries to bring together al-Ghazali's thoughts about different aspects of education, scattered in numbers of works of different kinds and aims at presenting his educational theory in its complete picture. His life, his intellectual career, his mental crises, as well as the solution to these crises were deeply influential in the formation of his educational thought; and it appears that al-Ghazali was remarkably successful in absorbing the conflicting schools of thought of his time. The theoretical aspect of his educational thought consists of a psychology that focuses on a series of mental operations by which man attains knowledge. Being a Sufi, al-Ghazali holds that knowledge can be attained through either sensual-rational or purely spiritual ways, believing the latter to be the source of true knowledge. Consequently, in his classification, he places spiritual sciences over the rest of the sciences. The practical aspect of his thought concerning education centers on the duties of student and teacher which must be fulfilled to ensure the success of the learning process.</description><creator>Asari, Hasan</creator><contributor>Little, D. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Ghazzālī, 1058-1111 -- Views on education</subject><title>The educational thought of Al-Ghazālī : theory and practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c314.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg00d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw499</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The extraterritorial application of antitrust law has been extensively developped since 1957. In the same way as the United States have tried to apply antitrust laws to Europe, the EC now wishes to apply this kind of legislation to companies outside the EC, using the criteria of jurisdictional competence in conformity with public international law. Three successive theories have been put forward: The "Effect theory" which has been much debated on its concordance with international law. The theory of "Enterprise Unity" has the desadvantaye that it cannot be applied to all foreign undertakings. Finally, the Commission and the Court of Justice have recently relied on the theory of the "Location of Anticompetitive Conduct". This last theory stands as a compromise between the first two and has broader potential application. As the competence of jurisdiction, the "enforcement jurisdiction over foreign undertakings is governed by international principles and is also constrained by blocking statutes. Nevertheless, the EC Commission knows how to make the most of its enforcement powers and most of the time, foreign companies submit to its decisions because the jurisdictional competence is well established. International cooperation is developing progressively through formal and informal agreements but the diplomatic way to resolve international litigation remains predominant.</description><creator>Gaborieau, Pascale</creator><contributor>Mestral, Armand Ile (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>L' évolution de l'application extraterritoriale du droit de la concurrence européen</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x93h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw499</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k23z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the influence of definiteness and movement on Mohawk free word order from the perspective of Government and Binding Theory. On the one hand, Mohawk data show that the relative order of NP's with respect to the verb does not determine definiteness and that the particle ne is not a definite determiner, the language lacking this type of "pure" marker for this feature, all of which contradicts previous claims. It is argued that pragmatic considerations will determine the interpretation of nominals. On the other hand, the evidence shows that there is no movement operation in the production of free word order in Mohawk, unlike in other scrambling languages. The evidence is accounted for by the fact that NP's are base generated in adjunct position (Baker 1991a) and coindexed with pro's in argument position which are licensed by the rich agreement morphology on the verb.</description><creator>Chamorro, Adriana</creator><contributor>Baker, Mark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Mohawk language -- Word order.</subject><subject>Mohawk language -- Definiteness.</subject><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Word order.</subject><title>On Mohawk word order</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk178.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k23z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb41g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis traces the self-creation and autonomy of the woman artist figure in Virginia Woolf's To the Lighthouse, Doris Lessing's The Golden Notebook, and Margaret Atwood's Cat's Eye. The first chapter conveys the progression of autonomy and self-creation in Western-European philosophy through contemporary thinkers such as Charles Taylor, Robert Pippin, Alexander Nehamas, and Richard Rorty. This narrative culminates in a rift between public and private, resulting from the push--especially by Nietzsche--toward a radical, unmediated independence. Taylor and Rorty envision different ways to resolve the public/private rift, yet neither philosopher distinguishes how this rift has affected women by enclosing them in the private, barring them from the public, and delimiting their autonomy. The second chapter focusses on each woman artist's resistance to socially scripted roles, accompanied by theories about resistance: Woolf with Rachel Blau DuPlessis on narrative resistance, Lessing with Julia Kristeva on dissidence, and Atwood with Stephen Hawking and Kristeva on space-time. The third chapter contrasts the narratives of chapters 1 and 2 and reveals how the woman artist avoids the problematic public/private rift by incorporating the ethics developed within the private into her art; she balances her creative goals with responsibility to others. Drawing on the work of women moral theorists, this thesis suggests that women's self-creation and autonomy result in an undervalued but nevertheless workable solution to the public/private rift.</description><creator>Sharpe, Martha</creator><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Atwood, Margaret, 1939- Cat's eye</subject><subject>Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941. To the lighthouse</subject><subject>Lessing, Doris May, 1919- Golden notebook</subject><title>Autonomy, self-creation, and the woman artist figure in Woolf, Lessing, and Atwood</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763903v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb41g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>