<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:09:25Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):45775" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bs26z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pick-and-place robots play an important role in industry, performing packaging and assembly tasks. To meet the demand for increasingly fast manipulators, new designs of parallel robots are being developed, as they have distinct speed advantages over their serial counterparts. Recently, a two-limbed, four-degree-of-freedom manipulator with high rotatability of its gripper and an isostatic (fully constrained) structure, the latter improving its assemblability, was introduced. The robot produces Schönflies motion, that is, three independent translations and one rotation about an axis of fixed direction; it is therefore classed as a Schönflies motion generator (SMG). The premiere prototype of this design, termed the PepperMill-Carrier (PMC), was developed and tested, as reported in this thesis. The development of innovative two-degree-of-freedom cylindrical actuators that drive the robot, termed C-drives, is also reported. Workspace analyses and experimental and simulation results are included. The prototypes successfully prove the concepts of the PMC and the C-drive. Recommendations are provided to guide further development. </description><description>Les robots à transfert rapide jouent un rôle important dans l'industrie et servent à l'emballage et à l'assemblage. Afin de répondre à la demande pour des manipulateurs de plus en plus rapides, de nouveaux concepts de robots parallèles sont actuellement en développement, bénéficiant d'avantages en terme de vitesse par rapport aux robots sériels. Récemment, un manipulateur avec deux jambes, quatre degrés de liberté, une importante mobilité rotationnelle de son effecteur et une structure isostatique a été proposé, cette dernière améliorant l'assemblabilité du robot. Le robot est capable de produire des déplacements du type Schönflies, c'est-à-dire trois translations indépendantes et une rotation autour d'un axe à direction fixe ; il est ainsi désigné générateur de mouvements Schönflies (GMS), ou SMG en anglais. Le premier prototype de ce concept, nommé le "PepperMill-Carrier" (PMC), a été réalisé et testé, tel que décrit dans ce mémoire. La mise au point d'actionneurs cylindriques novateurs à deux degrés de liberté, nommés "C-drives", qui entraînent le robot, est aussi décrite. De plus, des analyses d'espace de travail et des résultats d'expériences et de simulation sont inclus. Les prototypes parviennent à valider les concepts du PMC et du C-drive. Des recommandations sont proposées afin de guider le développement futur du robot.</description><creator>Friedlaender, Thomas</creator><contributor>Jorge Angeles (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Design, control and testing of a pick-and-place robot and its novel actuators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v846g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bs26z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g043</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the fact that the bicycle modal split is low, an increase in urban cycling activity has started to appear in many urban areas in Canada and the United States. However, as bicycle flows increase so do concerns for cyclist safety which have been pushed to the forefront. In this context, the need for new planning tools and data collection methods to investigate bicycle activity and safety have emerged in the field of transportation engineering. Studies focusing on investigating the link between cyclist safety, geometric design and built environment characteristics as well as traffic conditions are rare in the current literature. Even rarer are studies focused on investigating safety across different facilities, for the different road users who share these facilities and the factors affecting their injury occurrence. Tools to estimate bicycle volumes at the entire network level are missing. All previous safety studies have considered a sample of sites and have not been able to compute and map risk in the entire network of intersections and road segments. Dangerous decelerations as a surrogate safety measure for cyclists has yet to be investigated for the entire network. To date little is known about cyclist speeds and travel times along segments and delays through intersections at the disaggregate level for the entire network. In order to address these limitations, the general objective of this thesis is to propose new methods to model and estimate bicycle activity and injury risk at different spatial levels combining different sources of data. The proposed methods are then used to identify risk factors as well as to map risk indicators based on accidents and hard braking along corridors and at intersections in the entire network. More specifically, the objectives of this thesis are, to: 1) develop a Bayesian modeling framework to simultaneously model injury and activity outcomes for cyclists and study the role of geometric design and built environment characteristics on both outcomes, 2) carry out a comparative analysis between the injuries, levels of flow and risk for the three modes at signalized and non-signalized intersections and investigate the impact of vehicle traffic on the safety of non-motorized modes, 3) improve current methods for determining bicycle exposure measures by combining manual counts, automatic counts and GPS trip data to estimate and map bicycle flows, injuries and risk throughout the entire network of intersections and road segments, 4) develop a methodology to obtain deceleration rate for cyclists at intersections and segments using GPS data, explore the relationship between observed injuries and deceleration rate, and 5) develop a methodology to estimate cyclist speeds, travel times and delays in a road network using GPS data and identify the factors affecting cyclist speeds along segments. Among the contributions, this thesis proposed a modeling framework to simultaneously study cyclist injury occurrence and bicycle activity to overcome the issues of endogeneity. A similar methodology was then applied from a multimodal perspective, to study the activity and safety outcomes for cyclists, pedestrians and motor-vehicle occupants. This thesis expanded on the previous safety work by developing and applying a methodology to combine short and long-term count data with a new source of bicycle GPS data, from a Smartphone application, to compute and map average annual daily bicycle flows and cyclist risk of injury throughout the entire network of intersections and road segments. Using the smartphone GPS data, hard deceleration data was extracted and proposed as a surrogate safety measure and its correlation with accidents was evaluated. Finally, a methodology to compute speeds and delays was proposed. The results from this thesis were then combined into a routing concept capable of identifying the safety, shortest and fastest routes based on each cyclist's preferences.</description><description>Bien que la fraction des déplacements effectués à vélo soit encore faible, l'usage du vélo augmente désormais dans les villes des États-Unis et du Canada. Dans ce contexte, de nouvelles méthodes de collecte de données et de nouveaux outils de planification ciblant l'usage et la sécurité du vélo urbain ont émergé. Néanmoins, les connaissances actuelles comportent d'importantes lacunes. Peu de recherches ont investigué l'association entre la sécurité des cyclistes, la géométrie routière, l'environnement bâti et la circulation des véhicules. Les facteurs influençant la sécurité de différents usagers de la route, dans différents contextes, restent peu connus. Aucun outil ne permet d'estimer les volumes de cyclistes sur l'ensemble d'un réseau routier. Les recherches antérieures sont basées sur des échantillons de convenance et n'ont pas pu estimer ou cartographier le risque de blessures sur l'ensemble d'un réseau routier, incluant intersections et segments routiers. La décélération des cyclistes sur le réseau routier pourrait être un indicateur indirect de leur sécurité. Enfin, la vitesse et la durée des déplacements à vélo sur les segments routiers ainsi que les délais aux intersections sont peu connus. L'objectif général de cette thèse est de proposer de nouvelles méthodes pour modéliser et estimer l'activité cycliste et le risque de blessures en intégrant différentes sources de données. Les méthodes proposées permettront d'identifier les facteurs de risque environnementaux et de cartographier le risque de blessures, basé sur les accidents et les indicateurs indirects. Les objectifs spécifiques de cette thèse sont : 1) développer un modèle d'analyse Bayésien pour étudier simultanément les déterminants de l'activité cycliste et du risque de blessures, notamment l'influence de l'environnement bâti et de la géométrie des routes; 2) réaliser une analyse comparative de l'exposition, du nombre et du risque de blessures pour trois modes de transport, aux intersections signalisées et non-signalisées, 3) améliorer les méthodes actuelles permettant d'estimer l'exposition des cyclistes, en combinant des comptages manuels, des comptages automatiques et des données GPS sur les déplacements, afin d'estimer et de cartographier l'activité cycliste et le risque de blessures sur l'ensemble du réseau routier; 4) développer une méthode pour obtenir le taux de décélération des cyclistes sur les segments routiers et aux intersections, en utilisant des données GPS sur les déplacements, et explorer son association avec les blessures observées; 5) développer une méthode basée sur des données GPS pour estimer la vitesse des cyclistes, la durée des déplacements et les délais, et identifier les facteurs influençant la vitesse des cyclistes sur les segments routiers. Cette thèse propose un cadre d'analyse pour étudier simultanément l'activité cycliste et le risque de blessures et ainsi surmonter l'enjeu de l'endogénéité. Une méthodologie similaire a été utilisée dans une perspective multimodale, afin d'étudier l'exposition et le risque de blessures pour les cyclistes, les piétons et les automobilistes. Cette thèse développe et applique une méthodologie pour calculer et cartographier le débit journalier annuel moyen de cyclistes ainsi que le risque de blessures sur l'ensemble du réseau routier, en intégrant des comptages avec une nouvelle source de données GPS sur les déplacements cyclistes, provenant de téléphones intelligents. Les données GPS ont aussi été utilisées pour mesurer les décélérations subites des cyclistes, et cet indicateur indirect du risque d'accident a été corrélé avec le nombre estimé de cyclistes blessés. Enfin, une méthodologie basée sur les données GPS a été développée pour calculer la vitesse des cyclistes sur les segments routiers et les délais aux intersections. Les résultats de cette thèse ont été intégrés pour identifier les trajets cyclistes les plus sécuritaires, les plus courts et les plus rapides.</description><creator>Strauss, Jillian</creator><contributor>Patrick Morency (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Luis Miranda-Moreno (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>New methods for modeling and integrating bicycle activity and injury risk in an urban road network</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w5194.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g043</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wj973</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ever since Aviram and Ratner's revolutionary paper in 1974 that proposed that molecules could conduct electrical current molecular electronics has attracted a great deal of interest as a potential replacement for silicon technology.   Using molecules in electronic devices offers many advantages including high device density due to their small size and the ability to integrate new functions into devices with well-designed synthesis.  One such example is sensing as the conduction in a molecular wire has been shown to be incredibly sensitive to its local environment.  Proof-of-concept experiments have demonstrated that the conduction of oligophenylene vinylene (OPV), a well-studied molecular wire, is sensitive to nitroaromatic molecules.  In order to be able use molecules in molecular electronic devices though it is necessary to be able to control their switching between the on and off state.  Preliminary work has attempted to understand how voltage-induced switching works in bipyridyl-dinitro oligophenylene ethynylene dithiol (BPDN).  The subsequent step is to look at integrating these molecules into functional devices. One proposed way for integrating conducting molecules into functional devices is to form networks of densely-packed gold nanoparticles and molecular wires between metal electrodes on insulating substrates.  This design requires that nanoparticles be spaced closely enough together otherwise molecular wires will fail to bind between neighbouring nanoparticles thus decreasing device efficiency.  Biomolecules have proven to be excellent templates for self-assembly and offer the advantage of being able to work under mild, aqueous conditions.  Two examples are peptides and viruses. Peptides are known to provide excellent control over the size, shape and assembly of inorganic materials.  Their activity can further be enhanced by fusing two different functional domains together to form a fusion peptide which is multifunctional in nature.  Viruses are highly desirable templates for self-assembly for a variety of reasons including their monodispersity and well-defined shapes.  The tobacco mosaic virus is one such example and its coat protein is capable of forming different assemblies depending on pH and ionic strength.  One assembly of interest is the 20S disk which is 18 nm in diameter.  In this work the Flg-A3 peptide was first used to form gold nanoparticles which can form stable aggregates upon interaction with metal ions.  These aggregates are then bound in high density to silicon dioxide surfaces using the A3-QBP1 peptides.  The Flg-A3 gold nanoparticles were also covalently bound to tobacco mosaic virus disks with the hopes of eventually being able to increase the size of the aggregates that it forms.   The gold nanoparticles were covalently bound to the N terminus of this structure which is located on the circumference of the disk for further studies of their aggregation properties.The final step focused on making functional devices from oligophenylene vinylene and these gold nanoparticle networks formed using fusion peptides.  The nanoparticle networks were plated on silicon dioxide substrates with lithographically-defined gold electrodes.  They were treated with ultraviolet ozone cleaning in order to remove the peptide prior to using these films for electrical measurements with oligophenylene vinylene. </description><description>Depuis l'article révolutionnaire d'Aviram et Ratner en 1974 qui avait proposé que les molécules peuvent conduire l'électricité le domaine d'électroniques moléculaires a attiré beaucoup d'intérêt.  L'usage des molécules dans les appareils électroniques offre plusieurs avantages incluant une haute densité dans ces systèmes á cause de leur taille petite et la possibilité d'intégrer les nouvelles fonctions dans les fils moléculaires avec la synthèse.  Un exemple serait le développement d'un détecteur parce que la conduction d'une molécule est sensible à son environnement local.  Les expériences ont montré que la conduction d'oligophenylene vinylene (OPV), un fil moléculaire bien étudié, diminue dans la présence des molécules nitroaromatiques.  Pour utiliser les fils moléculaires dans les appareils électroniques il faut qu'ils puissent changer entre un état de conduction élevée et un état bas. Les expériences préliminaires avec bipyridyl-dinitro oligophenylene ethynylene dithiol (BPDN), une molécule qui peut changer entre les deux états avec la tension, ont essayé de découvrir un lien entre la structure et ce fonctionnement.    La prochaine étape est d'intégrer ces molécules dans un appareil fonctionnel. Une stratégie proposée pour intégrer les fils moléculaires dans un appareil fonctionnel est la formation des ensembles des fils moléculaires et nanoparticules métalliques sur les substrats isolants.  Les nanoparticules doivent être assez proches sinon les fils n'attachent pas entre eux.  Il faut qu'il y ait quelque chose pour contrôler l'espace.  C'est établi que les biomolécules sont les modèles excellents pour diriger auto-assemblage et elles marchent sous les conditions douces et aqueuses.  Les peptides et les virus sont deux exemples.  Les peptides peuvent contrôler la taille, forme et l'assemblage des matières inorganiques.  Si on fusionne deux domaines avec deux fonctions différentes c'est possible de créer un peptide de fusion qui est un exemple d'un matériel multifonctionnel.  Les virus sont un modèle idéal pour auto-assemblage à cause de leur monodispersité et leur forme bien définie.  Le virus de la mosaïque du tabac est un virus bien étudié et il peut se former les assemblages différents qui dépendent sur pH et la force ionique.  Le disque 20S, qui a un diamètre de 18 nm, est un de ces assemblages et il serait un bon modèle pour l'auto-assemblage.Dans ce travail le peptide, Flg-A3 est utilisé pour synthétiser les nanoparticules d'or et diriger leur assemblage quand il interagit avec les ions de métal.  Ces assemblages se fixent en haute densité sur les surfaces du dioxide de silicium avec le peptide A3-QBP1.  Pour augmenter la région où les nanoparticules s'assemblent les nanoparticules Flg-A3 étaient attachées d'une manière covalente à l'extérieur du disque du virus de la mosaïque du tabac.  Comme ça ce sera possible de former les bagues des nanoparticules et étudier leur auto-assemblage. La dernière étape est d'intégrer oligophenylene vinylene dans ces ensembles des nanoparticules.  Les assemblages des nanoparticules Flg-A3 se sont fixés sur les surfaces du dioxide de silicium avec A3-QBP1.  Les substrats contiennent les électrodes d'or qui sont définies par la lithographie.  Ils sont traités avec le nettoyage à l'ozone ultraviolet avant de les utiliser pour les expériences électriques avec oligophenylene vinylene.</description><creator>Del Re, Julia</creator><contributor>Amy Blum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Building molecular electronic devices from the bottom up</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dw05q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wj973</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rm11k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the recent major earthquakes experienced around the world and the adverse impacts on population, infrastructure and economy, various countries are increasingly concerned with improving their preparedness and resilience to the threat of seismic hazards. To this end, the utilization of high-performance protective systems, such as dampers and seismic isolation, is becoming a common practice for the seismic design of new buildings as well as the seismic retrofit of existing ones. Such devices have the potential to achieve a building response modification during an earthquake and protect its structural and non-structural content. This behaviour is particularly important for high-importance buildings, such as hospitals, that should remain functional in the aftermath of an earthquake. This thesis proposes a retrofit scheme for a 1960s, nine-storey, steel-frame hospital building that involves the integration of a triple friction pendulum seismic isolation system to achieve seismic resilience and continuous functionality in the event of a major earthquake. This hospital is representative of Type 2 Construction, a typical 1960s steel moment-resisting frame design philosophy. Many of these frames were not designed to resist seismic loads. They tend to be extremely flexible based on today's design practice and therefore may collapse due to P-Delta effects. The seismic retrofit system is designed and evaluated in accordance with ASCE/SEI 41-13 (ASCE 2013a), FEMA P-750-09 (FEMA 2009a) and CAN/CSA S16-09 (CSA 2009). The original and retrofitted configurations of the hospital building are modelled in three-dimensions using an open source simulation platform and are subjected to a set of 40 ground motions from both Quebec City and Vancouver. The ground motions have been selected such that they represent the seismic hazard in these two urban regions. The original configuration building exhibits excessive deformations under the Quebec City ground motions and is pushed to collapse under five of the Vancouver ground motions. With the retrofitted configuration, the seismic behaviour of the hospital building is drastically improved and continuous functionality is achieved even under the most damaging ground motions. A life-cycle cost assessment is also performed in order to quantify and compare the earthquake-induced losses between the original and retrofitted configurations. In conclusion, this thesis provides valuable insights into the implementation, evaluation and numerical modeling of seismic isolation systems, promoting the use of these systems to increase life safety and economic stability in Canada in the case of earthquake hazards.</description><description>Les évènements sismiques majeurs qui sont survenus à travers le monde récemment ont eu un impact défavorable sur les populations, l'infrastructure et l'économie. Par conséquence, plusieurs pays s'intéressent de plus en plus à devenir mieux préparés contre les séismes. L'utilisation des technologies sismiques d'haute performance, tels que les amortisseurs et l'isolation sismique, devient pratique courante dans la conception sismique des nouveaux bâtiments ainsi que dans la modernisation de bâtiments existants. Ces technologies peuvent modifier le comportement d'un bâtiment durant un séisme afin de protéger les éléments structuraux et non-structuraux dans le bâtiment. Ce comportement est particulièrement important pour les bâtiments d'haute importance, tels que les hôpitaux, pour lesquels la fonctionnalité continue suivant des séismes majeurs est essentielle. Dans cette thèse,  une approche de modernisation est développée pour un hôpital en acier de neuf étages construit dans les années 1960. L'approche de modernisation inclut l'intégration d'un système d'isolation sismique de pendules à friction triple, afin de rendre le bâtiment résistant aux séismes ainsi que d'atteindre la fonctionnalité continue du bâtiment suivant des séismes majeurs. La conception de l'hôpital a été basé sur la construction de type 2, une philosophie de conception des années 1960s pour les ossatures en acier résistants aux moments. La plupart de ces bâtiments n'était pas conçu pour résister les séismes. Ces bâtiments sont extrêmement flexibles comparés aux bâtiments qui sont conçus basé sur les normes d'aujourd'hui. En conséquence, ils peuvent être à risque de s'effondrer sous les effets de « P-Delta ». L'approche de modernisation développée dans cette thèse est conçue et évaluée suivant les recommandations de ASCE/SEI 41-13 (ASCE 2013b), FEMA P-750-09 (FEMA 2009b) et CAN/CSA S16-09 (CSA 2009). Des modèles numériques en trois dimensions de l'hôpital original et de celui modernisé avec l'isolation sismique sont crées utilisant un logiciel « code source ouvert ». Ils sont analysés avec 40 séismes représentant l'aléa sismique de la ville de Québec et 40 séismes représentant l'aléa sismique de Vancouver. Le bâtiment original subit des déformations excessives sous les séismes de la ville de Québec et il s'effondre sous cinq des séismes de Vancouver. Le comportement du bâtiment modernisé avec l'isolation sismique s'est amélioré de façon considérable et la fonctionnalité continue est maintenue sous tous les séismes. Afin de quantifier et comparer les pertes engendrées par les séismes, les coûts du cycle de vie du bâtiment original et du bâtiment modernisé avec l'isolation sismique sont estimés.En conclusion, cette thèse fournit de l'information utile quant à l'évaluation et la modélisation numérique de systèmes d'isolation sismique. Les résultats de la thèse  promeuvent l'utilisation de ces systèmes afin d'augmenter la sécurité des individus et la stabilité économique au Canada face aux séismes.</description><creator>Walker, Samantha</creator><contributor>Dimitrios Lignos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Seismic retrofit of a 1960's, nine-story, steel-frame hospital building using triple friction pendulum seismic isolation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w56f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm11k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343v86q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En astronomie gamma utilisant les réseaux de télescopes Tcherenkov (Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes (IACTs)), le temps disponible pour l'observation est limité par un certain nombre de facteurs. Par exemple, les caméras du télescope sont composées de tubes photomultiplicateurs (PMT) et donc très sensibles à la lumière. Dans les longueurs d'ondes les plus pertinentes pour l'astronomie gamma, le ciel est 100 fois plus lumineux durant lapleine lune que pendant la nouvelle lune. L'augmentation du bruit dans les données en raison de photons au clair de lune dégrade la qualité des données et, plus important encore, accélère le vieillissement des PMT. Ainsi, les IACTs ont historiquement été contraints d'observer uniquement durant les nuits claires, sans lune, ou durant les nuits où la lune est seulement partiellement illuminée et basse dans le ciel. Il existe deux approches pour contourner les limites imposées par le clair de lune: réduire les gains des PMT, ou utiliser des filtres à ultraviolet pour bloquer certaines parties du spectre électromagnétique. L'observatoire VERITAS, qui exploite quatre IACTs à l'Observatoire Whipple dans le sud de l'Arizona, est généralement limité à des lunes illuminées à un maximum de 35%. Grace à l'utilisation de ces deux nouveaux modes d'observation, VERITAS est en principe maintenant capable d'observer même pendant la pleine lune, bien qu'en pratique les quelques jours aux alentours de la pleine lune sont généralement réservés à l'entretien du télescope. Le résultat final est une augmentation de 29% du temps d'observation par année, dont la moitié est à peu près égale en qualité aux standards de période sombre en ce qui concerne la plupart des objectifs scientifiques de VERITAS. Dans ce travail, les deux modes d'observation sont décrits en détails. Afin de produire des outils d'analyse pour les données «clair de lune», de nombreuses comparaisons entre les données et des simulations Monte Carlo ont été faites pour vérifier le modèle de détecteur. Les études du seuil d'énergie résultant, la sensibilité de l'observatoire et les erreurs systématiques sont également présentées. Enfin, les premiers résultats scientifiques du programme d'observation en clair de lune sont présentés: la détection d'une éruption provenant du blazar 1ES 1727+502.</description><description>In gamma-ray astronomy using Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes (IACTs), the amount of observing time available is limited by a number of factors. One such factor is that the telescope cameras are made of photomultiplier tubes (PMTs) and are thus highly sensitive to light. The sky is 100 times brighter during full Moon than new Moon at the wavelengths most relevant to ground-based gamma-ray astronomy; the increased noise in the data stream due to moonlight photons both degrades the data quality and, more importantly, accelerates ageing of the PMTs. Thus, IACTs have historically been limited to observing during clear, moonless nights, or on nights where the moon is only partially illuminated and low in the sky. There are two approaches to circumventing the limits imposed by moonlight: observing using reduced PMT gains, or by using UV bandpass filters to block out parts of the moonlight spectrum. The VERITAS experiment, which consists of four IACTs at the Whipple Observatory in southern Arizona, was typically limited to when the moon was 35% illuminated. Using two new observing modes (one based on each of the aforementioned methods), VERITAS is in principle able to observe through the full Moon. The end result is an additional ∼ 29% observing time in a year, of which half has a data quality comparable to standard dark time data for the purposes of many of the VERITAS science goals. In this work, the two observing modes will be thoroughly described. In order to produce analysis tools for the bright moonlight data, extensive data/Monte Carlo comparisons have been made to verify the detector model. Studies of the resulting energy threshold, array sensitivity, and systematic errors are also presented. Finally, the first science results from the VERITAS Bright Moonlight Program are presented: the detection of a flare from the blazar 1ES 1727+502.</description><creator>Griffin, Sean</creator><contributor>David Hanna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>The VERITAS bright moonlight program</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss888.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v86q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mz43g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte : Les structures de gestion en collaboration sont essentielles à la transformation de la prestation des soins de santé et le modèle de leadership de collaboration offre une telle approche. Les infirmières et les médecins sont particulièrement bien placés pour partager un rôle de direction dans le cadre d'une collaboration. Toutefois, on en sait très peu sur le fonctionnement de cette collaboration dans un établissement de soins de santé. La majeure partie des connaissances sur la relation infirmière-médecin est fondée sur des recherches à l'échelon de l'unité clinique et selon le point de vue des infirmières seulement. Objectif: Cette étude de la théorie ancrée vise à expliquer comment les infirmières et médecins gestionnaires collaborent dans un partenariat officiel pour s'attaquer aux problèmes de gestion clinique. Méthode: Une structure de gestion infirmière-médecin a été adoptée en 2008 dans l'ensemble d'un hôpital d'enseignement affilié à une université canadienne, située dans un centre urbain. Les infirmières et médecins gestionnaires de chaque service ou programme devaient travailler officiellement en partenariat pour traiter des questions de gestion clinique. En 2013, des partenariats infirmières-médecins du département de chirurgie ont été choisis pour composer un échantillon aux fins de l'étude, suivant la recommandation d'intervenants importants qui étaient d'avis que ce département illustrait bien la collaboration. Un échantillonnage théorique a ensuite été réalisé pour étudier les caractéristiques des concepts émergents et des catégories. Au total, 36 entrevues comptant 21 participants (12 infirmières et 9 médecins) ont été enregistrées en version audio puis transcrites textuellement. Les participants ont été observés durant 142 heures (110 heures au niveau de la haute direction et 32 heures au niveau de la gestion clinique). Des notes ont été prises au sujet de 90 événements qui ont été suivis. La récapitulation entre collègues, le retour d'information des participants et autres personnes concernées et une vérification de toutes les décisions méthodologiques, ont assuré la fiabilité des données. Des comparaisons constantes, un codage ouvert et ciblé, une sensibilité théorique et des notes ont servi à l'analyse des données. Résultats : Une théorie sur le partenariat intentionnel a été élaborée. Les agendas professionnels des infirmières et médecins gestionnaires qui comprennent leurs intérêts et objectifs liés à leur collaboration servent de point de départ au partenariat intentionnel. La théorie explique comment les infirmières et médecins gestionnaires adaptent leurs agendas professionnels pour tirer avantage du partenariat en suivant un processus qui consiste à accepter la nécessité de la collaboration, à oser prendre des risques conjointement et à créer une responsabilité commune. Certains partenaires peuvent assumer un rôle de direction ou contribuer de manière différente à chaque étape du processus. Établir sa crédibilité, gagner la confiance de l'autre puis conserver son respect représentent les conditions essentielles du partenariat et le fondement de la collaboration et d'une communication efficace. Les stratégies délibérées des dirigeants principaux donnent une impulsion au processus de partenariat intentionnel. Conclusion : La théorie présente des stratégies qui sous-tendent les processus ainsi que les caractéristiques qui influent sur la manière dont s'établit et évolue la relation entre infirmière et médecin gestionnaires. Les résultats peuvent être appliqués dans les secteurs de la santé et de l'éducation.</description><description>Background:  In today's healthcare organizations, the pace of technological change, increasing complexity, competitive demands and risks involved in decision making have made it difficult for one individual to lead alone.  Collaborative management structures are critical to transforming healthcare delivery and a co-leadership model offers one such approach. Nurses and physicians are uniquely positioned to share the executive roles of co-leadership; however, little is known about how this management dyad operates in the healthcare setting. Most of what is known about the nurse-physician relationship has been based on research at the clinical unit level from the nurses' perspective. Objective:  This grounded theory study seeks to explain how nurse and physician managers in formalized "partnerships" work together to address clinical management issues.  Methods/Procedures: A nurse-physician management structure (Partnered Management Model) was adopted throughout an urban Canadian university affiliated teaching hospital in 2008 where nurse and physician managers in each division or program were expected to formally "partner" with each other to address clinical management issues.  Dyads were purposefully sampled in the Department of Surgery in 2013 on the recommendation of key stakeholders who believed the department effectively illustrated nurse-physician "partnerships".  This was followed by theoretical sampling to elaborate on properties of emerging concepts and categories.  A total of 36 interviews with 21 participants (12 nurses, 9 physicians) were audio-recorded and transcribed verbatim. The total time spent in observation was 142 hours (110 hours at senior management level and 32 hours at clinical management level) with field notes recorded for 90 observed events.  Peer debriefing, informant/participant feedback and an audit trail of all methodological decisions ensured the trustworthiness of the data. Constant comparison, open and focused coding, theoretical sensitivity and memos were used in the data analysis. Findings:   A substantive theory on intentional partnering was generated.  Nurses' and physicians' professional agendas, which included their interests and purposes for working with each other, served as the starting point of intentional partnering.  The theory explains how nurse and physician managers align their professional agendas to reap the benefits of partnering through the processes of accepting mutual necessity, daring to risk together and constructing a shared responsibility. Some partners may take the lead or contribute differently in each of the processes. Essential conditions such as being credible, earning trust and safeguarding respect built a foundation for partnering and communicating effectively.  Deliberate strategies from senior leadership provided momentum in the intentional partnering process.  Conclusions:  The theory elucidates the strategizing that underlies the processes as well as the characteristics that influence how the nurse/physician management relationship develops and evolves. The findings may inform the process of developing effective partnerships between nurses and physicians as they take on co-management responsibilities in an evolving healthcare system. The findings may also be applied to health professional management education.Keywords:  nurse-physician, co-leadership; management dyad, collaboration, grounded theory, strategy, professional agenda, health system</description><creator>Clausen, Christina</creator><contributor>Margaret A Purden (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Melanie Lavoie-Tremblay (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Nursing</subject><title>Intentional Partnering: How nurse and physician managers in formalized dyads work together to address clinical management issues in a hospital setting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032593w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mz43g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Ingram School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0969995</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Le nombre élevé de naissances par césarienne au Canada est préoccupant dû aux risques qui y sont associées. Les recommandations pour réduire les taux de césarienne comprennent la prévention de naissances par césarienne d'urgence chez les femmes à faible risque (c.-à-d. grossesse monofoetale et à terme et présentation céphalique), en particulier pour les indications discrétionnaires (ex souffrance foetale, travail prolongé). Les femmes migrantes enceintes (c.-à-d. les femmes nées ailleurs qu'au Canada) originaires des pays à revenu faible et intermédiaire (PRFI) présentent des profils de risques sociaux et médicaux plus élevés que les femmes nées au Canada. La recherche établissant les facteurs prédictifs de césarienne chez les femmes migrantes est déficiente.Objectif: Identifier les facteurs prédictifs de césarienne (c.-à-d. migration, biologiques, médicaux, sociaux et sanitaires) chez les femmes migrantes originaires des PRFI qui accouchent à Montréal, Canada. Méthode: Une étude cas-témoin a été réalisée. Le cadre d'échantillonnage comprenait des femmes migrantes originaires des PRFI vivant au Canada depuis moins de 8 ans et ayant accouché entre mars 2014 et janvier 2015 dans trois hôpitaux de Montréal. Les données des femmes ayant accepté de participer à l'étude ont été recueillies à partir des dossiers médicaux et au moyen d'entrevues conduites avec le questionnaire  «Soins de maternité qui répondent aux besoins des migrantes» (disponible en 8 langues). Les femmes migrantes à faible risque ayant eu un accouchement vaginal (témoins) et un accouchement par césarienne en urgence pour des indications discrétionnaires (cas) ont été analysées. Une régression logistique à variables multiples a été utilisée pour identifier les facteurs prédictifs d'une césarienne d'urgence chez les femmes migrantes.Résultats: La taille de la population étudiée est de 1848 femmes migrantes (1615 témoins, 233 cas). Les facteurs prédictifs de césarienne d'urgence étaient: âge maternel ≥ 35 ans (RC=2.90, 95% IC 1.89-4.44), primiparité (RC=3.79, 95% IC 2.47-5.82), liquide amniotique teinté de méconium (RC=2.48, 95% IC 1.71-3.60), indice de masse corporelle élevé/prise de poids excessive durant la grossesse (RC=1.49, 95% IC 1.03-2.15), admission à l'hôpital lors de la phase précoce du travail (RC=6.69, 95% IC 3.60-12.44), et vivant au Canada depuis moins de 2 ans (RC=2.02, 95% IC 1.03-3.99). Une mauvaise santé maternelle (RC=1.44, 95% IC 0.99-2.08) était presque significative. Parmi les femmes migrantes vivant au Canada depuis moins de 2 ans, les facteurs prédictifs étaient: âge maternel ≥ 35 ans (RC=2.34, 95% IC 0.99-2.08), liquide amniotique teinté de méconium (RC=2.64, 95% IC 1.53-4.56), admission à l'hôpital lors de la phase précoce du travail (RC=7.68, 95% IC 3.12-18.88), et ayant un statut humanitaire (RC=4.24, 95% IC 1.16-15.46); les femmes qui faisaient du diabète et/ou de l'hypertension gestationnelle avaient un risque plus élevé d'avoir une césarienne d'urgence (RC=2.09, 95% IC 0.99-4.42), mais ce n'était pas statistiquement significatif. Conclusion: Les femmes migrantes ayant un statut humanitaire et qui sont récemment arrivées sont particulièrement à risque de nécessiter une césarienne d'urgence sans que ce soit pleinement explicable par des facteurs médicaux. Les professionnels de la santé devraient considérer la plus grande vulnérabilité de ces femmes et s'assurer d'un support adéquat durant la maternité. L'état de santé est aussi un facteur prédictif important de césarienne d'urgence même chez les femmes migrantes à faible risque et les professionnels de la santé devraient considérer les circonstances particulières des femmes migrantes lors de la prestation de service. L'admission à l'hôpital lors de la phase précoce du travail devrait être évitée autant que possible. La recherche est nécessaire pour en apprendre davantage sur les soins de maternité des femmes migrantes et leur impact potentiel sur le type d'accouchement.</description><description>Background: The high number of caesarean births performed in Canada is of concern due to associated risks. Recommendations to reduce caesarean rates include targeting emergency caesarean births among low-risk women (i.e., vertex, singleton, term pregnancies), particularly for discretionary indications (e.g., fetal distress, failure to progress). Pregnant migrant women (i.e., women born outside of Canada) from low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) have a higher health- and social-risk profile compared to non-migrants, and research establishing evidence of predictors for emergency caesarean births among migrant women is lacking. Objective: To identify predictors (i.e., migration, biological, medical, social, and health service) of emergency caesarean births among low-risk migrant women from LMICs giving birth in Montreal, Canada. Methods: The research design was case-control. The sampling frame included migrant women from LMICs and living in Canada less than eight years who gave birth during the period from March 2014-January 2015 in three Montreal hospitals. Data for consenting women were collected from medical records and through interview using the Migrant-Friendly Maternity Care Questionnaire (MFMCQ) (available in eight languages). Low-risk migrant women who delivered vaginally (controls) and by emergency caesarean birth for discretionary indications (cases) were analysed.  Multi-variable logistic regression was used to identify the predictors of emergency caesarean births among migrant women. Results: The study population included 1848 migrant women (1615 controls and 233 cases). Predictors of emergency caesarean births identified were: maternal age ≥ 35 years old (OR=2.90, 95% CI 1.89-4.44), primiparity (OR= 3.79, 95% CI 2.47-5.82), meconium staining (OR=2.48, 95% CI 1.71-3.60), high body mass index (BMI) and/or excessive pregnancy weight gain (OR=1.49, 95% CI 1.03-2.15), admission for delivery during early labour (OR=6.69, 95% CI 3.60-12.44), and living in Canada less than two years (OR=2.02, 95% CI 1.03-3.99). Poor maternal health (OR=1.44, 95% CI 0.99-2.08) trended towards significance. Among women living in Canada less than two years, predictors were: maternal age (OR=2.34, 95%CI 1.10-4.98), meconium staining (OR=2.64, 95% CI 1.53-4.56), admission for delivery during early labour (OR=7.68, 95% CI 3.12-18.88), and having a humanitarian migration classification (OR=4.24, 95%CI 1.16-15.46); women with gestational diabetes and/or hypertension showed greater odds for an emergency caesarean birth, but this did not reach significance (OR=2.09, 95% CI 0.99-4.42).Conclusions:  Recently-arrived migrant women with a humanitarian migration classification are particularly vulnerable to undergoing an emergency caesarean and this is not fully explained by medical factors.  Healthcare providers should be alert to their greater vulnerability and ensure that maternity care is supportive. Health status is also an important predictor of emergency caesarean even among low-risk migrant women and healthcare providers should consider the unique circumstances of migrant women when treating health conditions. Early admission for delivery should be discouraged when possible. Research is needed to learn more about the experiences of maternity care of migrant women and the potential impact they have on mode of birth. </description><creator>Merry, Lisa Alison</creator><contributor>Anita J Gagnon (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Sonia Elizabeth Semenic (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Nursing</subject><title>Predictors of emergency caesarean births among low-risk migrant women from low-and middle-income countries giving birth in Montreal, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032592m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0969995</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Ingram School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zf03x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Logic is generally assumed to be essentially concerned with rule-based inferences aimed at the definitive establishment of propositions, or at least their support, or on the contrary their countering. Yet, such truth-adjusting moves of thinking are not the only moves that can produce the adjustment of propositions in natural thinking conditions, and truth is not the only dimension of propositions that can be adjusted (e.g., explanations make propositions appear more normal without affecting their truth). The main goal of this thesis was to inventory and describe all the functional and structural variety of thinking moves as they appear in natural conditions, and to examine how these conditions can affect their production. To this end, a sample of legal memoranda written by law students was collected and analyzed. Defining a move operator as a possible combination of an adjusting move function and a logical move structure, this study aimed to develop an inventory all of the move operators found to be at use in the studied sample, and to extend this empirical inventory into a theoretical inventory by completing its emerging functional and structural regularities. These inventories show that thinking moves can serve a variety of adjusting functions, depending on the adjusted dimension (truth, normality, informativeness, etc.) and on the orientation of the adjustment (positive or negative), and that they can do so on the basis of different logical structures for each move function. By analyzing the use frequencies of move operators across the sample and under different conditions within the sample, it was possible to assess the effects of different types of cognitive resources (knowledge, situational information, etc.) on the use of move operators. It is shown that the use of move operators in producing thinking moves is strategic and goal-oriented, being reflective of the particular demands of the context to an extent that depends on thinking skills. While the objective of this research were primarily exploratory, these results suggest that the execution of the logical process of thinking move production depends not only on the move operators at use in thinking, but also on the properties of a number of non-logical systems that function to process the available cognitive resources and generate the logical process's initial content in the form of premises and frames.</description><description>La logique s'intéresse prioritairement aux inférences, qui sont des unités de pensée permettant d'établir définitivement comme vraie les propositions énoncées, ou du moins de les supporter en ce sens, ou au contraire de les contrer en démontrant leur fausseté. Bien que possiblement complexe, de telles unités de pensée sont fondamentales en ce qu'elles peuvent s'exprimer d'un seul coup, par la seule adjonction d'une proposition à une autre, et en ce qu'elles permettent l'ajustement positif ou négatif de la valeur de vérité des propositions énoncées. Pourtant, les inférences ne sont pas les seules unités fondamentales de pensée qui permettent l'ajustement positif ou négatif des propositions, et la valeur de vérité n'est pas la seule valeur des propositions qui puisse être ajustée. Par exemple, les explications permettent l'ajustement de leur valeur de normalité, c'est-à-dire de leur degré de conformité avec les attentes de l'interlocuteur, sans altérer leur valeur de vérité. Le but principal de cette thèse est d'inventorier et de décrire les différentes fonctions d'ajustement que peuvent remplir les unités fondamentales de pensée produites en conditions normales de réflexion, ainsi que les structures logiques qu'elles peuvent avoir en remplissant ces fonctions. Nous définissons un opérateur d'unité fondamentale de pensée comme une combinaison possible (en conditions normales) d'une fonction d'ajustement et d'une structure logique. Aux fins de cet inventaire, un corpus de notes de service rédigées par des étudiants de première année en droit a été constitué et analysé en utilisant des techniques d'analyse de discours. Il en a résulté un inventaire empirique de tous les operateurs logiques ayant sous-tendu la production d'au moins une unité fondamentale de pensée dans le corpus. Un inventaire théorique de ces opérateurs a pu ensuite être constitué sur la base de l'inventaire empirique ainsi obtenu en complétant ses régularités fonctionnelles et structurelles émergentes. Ces inventaires empirique et théorique montrent que les unités fondamentales de pensée produite en conditions naturelles de réflexion présentent une variété fonctionnelle et structurelle qui dépasse largement le domaine traditionnel de la logique, qui s'intéresse essentiellement aux unités permettant l'ajustement des valeurs de vérité. Ainsi, les fonctions d'ajustement observées peuvent aussi concerner leur valeur de normalité, d'information, d'utilité, disponibilité, etc. En analysant la fréquence d'utilisation des opérateurs d'unités fondamentales de pensée inventoriées dans leurs différentes conditions d'utilisation dans le corpus, il a été possible d'examiner les effets de ces conditions et de leurs ressources cognitives particulières sur l'usage de ces opérateurs lors de la production d'unités fondamentales de pensée. Il a été ainsi possible de montrer que cet usage est stratégique et qu'il dépend largement de l'information situationnelle relative aux contraintes imposées par le problème à résoudre et par la tâche particulière à effectuer pour résoudre ce problème, ainsi que de la connaissance du domaine où s'effectue cette tâche. Bien que cette étude soit exploratoire, de tels résultats suggèrent que le processus de production d'unités fondamentales de pensée dépend non seulement de processus logiques, mais aussi d'un certain nombre d'autres processus cognitifs (e.g., processus de mémoire), qui sont eux aussi nécessaires au traitement des ressources cognitives disponibles.</description><creator>Alie, Claude</creator><contributor>Alenoush Saroyan (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Carl H Frederiksen (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</subject><title>Thinking moves: A theory of logic structures and functions of natural moves of thinking based on a study in legal argumentation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x2114.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zf03x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gn84n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RésuméLa connaissance des mathématiques en enseignement, ou la CME, est une connaissance des mathématiques importante unique aux enseignants et en enseignement. Un domaine de la CME, la connaissance des mathématiques spécialisées (CMS), inclut la capacité d'interprétation de solutions non standards des étudiants, de créer des représentations pour des idées mathématiques pertinentes, et d'expliquer des algorithmes mathématiques communs (Ball, Thames, &amp; Phelps, 2008). Plusieurs mesures sont présentement disponibles pour ceux qui veulent mesurer la CMS,  mais notre compréhension de ce domaine reste incomplète, surtout parmi les enseignants en formation, qui, grâce à un manque d'expérience de l'enseignement, possedent probablement une CMS moins développée que celle des enseignants professionnels (Hill, 2010). Les pratiques et dispositions des enseignants, tout en n'étant pas une partie des cadres existants pour CMS, sont susceptibles de jouer un rôle clé dans l'élaboration de la nature de cette connaissance mathématique unique. Cette étude a cherché d'examiner la CMS de 11 enseignants en formation dans des entrevues structurées (Ginsburg, Jacobs, &amp; Lopez, 1998) qui ont duré une heure. Dans chaque entrevue, les enseignants en formation ont été demandés d'interpréter des solutions inventées par des étudiants en répondant à deux problèmes: une impliquant une comparaison de fractions et une deuxième impliquant la multiplication des nombres à plusieurs chiffres. Les données recueillies et codées dans cette étude indiquent que les enseignants en formation ont besoin d'un plus grand soutien dans deux domaines clés de la CMS: créer des représentations pour des idées mathématiques pertinentes et d'interpréter les solutions standards et non-standards des étudiants. En outre, il semblerait que les enseignants en formation bénéficieraient des efforts de developper une disposition flexible, car que telle flexibilité apparaît d'augmenter la CMS (Hill. Dean &amp; Goffney, 2007 ). Les résultats de cette étude vont informer les formateurs d'enseignants lorsqu'ils conçoivent des cours dans le but d'utiliser le peu temps qu'ils sont fournis dans la préparation des enseignants en formation.Mots-clés: connaissance des mathématiques en enseignement, connaissance des mathématiques spécialisées, dispositions, enseignant en formation</description><description>AbstractMathematical knowledge for teaching, or MKT, is a critically important knowledge of mathematics unique to teachers and teaching. One aspect of MKT, specialized content knowledge (SCK), involves the ability to interpret nonstandard student solutions, represent relevant mathematical content non-symbolically, and explain standard math algorithms (Ball, Thames, &amp; Phelps, 2008). A number of measures are currently available to those seeking to assess teachers' SCK, and still, this knowledge domain has "yet to be fully mapped" (Hill, 2010, p. 537). Nowhere is this lack of mapping more apparent than among pre-service teachers, who, due to a lack of teaching experience, are likely to exhibit SCK that is markedly different from that displayed by their in-service counterparts (Hill, 2010). Teacher practices and dispositions, while not a part of existing frameworks for SCK, are likely to play a key role in shaping the nature of this unique mathematical knowledge. This study sought to examine the nature of 11 pre-service teachers' specialized content knowledge, practices, and dispositions through the use of hour-long structured interviews (Ginsburg, Jacobs, &amp; Lopez, 1998). In each interview, study participants were asked to interpret non-standard student solutions to two math problems, one involving a comparison of fractions and another involving multi-digit multiplication. Data gathered in this study indicate that pre-service teachers, unlike experienced teaching professionals, require greater support in two key aspects of SCK: generating non-symbolic representations and interpreting non-standard student solutions (Hill, 2007; Hill, 2010). Additionally, it would appear as though pre-service teachers would benefit from efforts to foster a flexible disposition, as such flexibility appears to augment one's specialized content knowledge (Hill. Dean  &amp; Goffney, 2007). The results of this study will inform teacher educators, who must make difficult choices when deciding how to design courses so as to make efficient use of what little time they are given to prepare pre-service teachers (Ball, Sleep, Boerst, &amp; Bass, 2009; Hill, 2010; Kajander, 2010).Keywords: mathematical knowledge for teaching, specialized content knowledge, disposition, pre-service teacher</description><creator>Jarry-Shore, Michael</creator><contributor>Marta Kobiela (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Education - Mathematics </subject><title>An exploration of pre-service elementary teachers' mathematical knowledge for teaching</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h81q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn84n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386n40f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of the polymerization and association of simple organic substances, and the nature of the super molecular state is the subject of intensive investigation at the present time, and is a problem, which as yet remains unsolved. Many important isolated facts have been discovered and a variety of (1) theories proposed, but, as Haworth points out withregard to polysaccharides, but which may be applied to polymerization and the supermolecular state in general, " - no finality is to be expected in the present state of knowledge. The time is probably not distant when greater harmony of opinion will prevail and opposing conceptions which reveal only parts of truth will be reconciled by a comprehensive generalization." [...]</description><creator>Jahn, Edwin C.</creator><contributor>Hibbert, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1929</date><subject>Cellulose Chemistry.</subject><title>Nature of the supermolecular state of certain aldehyde and ethylene oxide derivatives : Part I. The action of sodium on crotonaldehyde ; Part II. The ethylene oxide ring in relation to the supermolecular state.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gg746.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n40f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74ct512</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Separated by an ocean, which with the advance of navigation grows narrower each year, are Japan and Canada, two countries which, in history, ideals, civilization, and culture, have nothing in common. One is a group of comparatively small islands off the Coast of Asia, limited in area, the other occupies almost half ot the Continent of North America. The inhabitants of the former belong to the Mongolian, those of the latter to the Caucasian race. One has an ancient civilzation which begins before the dawn of human history, the other's history goes back only a few centuries. One has the culture and the characteristics of the Orient, the other those of the Occident. To a casual observer, these countries have nothing in common. [...]</description><creator>Johnston, Agnew H.</creator><contributor>Kemp, H. &amp;Goforth, W. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1929</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>Diplomatic relations between Canada and Japan, withspecial reference to underlying economic and political conditions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt234.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74ct512</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rm12v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To the steel-making countries of the world, the question of manganese deposits and their control is one of Tital interest, for manganese is an essential element in the production of all steel of a commercial grade. With the leading steel producing countries the United States, England, Germany, and France devoid of resources of manganese sufficient to meet even a small fraction of their requirements, the rivalry for financial control of deposits outside their industrial domain, has been extremely keen during the past few years. [...]</description><creator>Hopper, Ronald V.</creator><contributor>Clark, J. &amp; McBride, W. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1929</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The manganese deposits of Tchiatouri, Georgia,Russia.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tf984.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm12v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d945b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Knowledge of the time rate of diffusion of fluids through solids is of interest on account of its bearing on the structure of solids. Much light can be cast upon the size and arrangements of the insterstitial spaces by such studies, and this often may lead to important applications in the field of surface chemistry, particularly in the case of coloidal systems such as gels. A most interesting field is that presented by the glass of gels which swell by processes of sorption. [...]</description><creator>Johnston, Harry W.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1929</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The penetration of wood by liquids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698b44z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d945b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c5482</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many professional cellists recognize the challenges inherent in performing and teaching contemporary music for their instrument. Whereas original musical discourses and unexpected variations of sounds are exciting to learn and perform, with new works come new and daunting technical challenges. Many works written over the last 50 years require significantly more preparation time than traditional works of similar technical difficulty. The growth of technical literature and methods has lagged behind the pronounced expansion of technical demands: thus, cellists now stand in urgent need of innovative technical methods, uniquely designed to effectively address the challenges of the rapidly growing contemporary cello repertoire. In this paper I consider strategies for approaching these challenges using new methods as well as variations of traditional methods. After exploring the development of cello technique and the methods commonly used today, I propose a new, personalized work-model for the preparation of contemporary repertoire that balances physical practice with critical thinking. Three works for solo cello, Kaija Saariaho’s Sept Papillons, Geof Holbrook’s Wish, Want, Need, and Helmut Lachenmann’s Pression, act as the reference for a sample of extended techniques. After analysing the challenges presented by these techniques, I provide examples of solutions in the form of preparatory exercises.</description><description>De nombreux violoncellistes professionnels reconnaissent les défis liés à l'exécution et à l'enseignement de la musique contemporaine pour leur instrument. Alors que les discours musicaux originaux et les variations de sonorités inattendues sont passionnants à apprendre et à exécuter, avec de nouvelles oeuvres proviennent de nouveaux et redoutables défis techniques. Pour nombre des oeuvres écrites au cours des 50 dernières années, la préparation nécessite beaucoup plus de temps que pour celle d’oeuvres traditionnelles de difficulté technique similaire. La croissance de la littérature et des méthodes reliées à la technique du violoncelle est plus lente que l'expansion rapide des exigences techniques : de ce fait même, les violoncellistes se trouvent aujourd’hui face à un besoin urgent de nouvelles méthodes d’apprentissage innovantes, spécialement conçues pour répondre efficacement aux défis du répertoire contemporain pour violoncelle. Dans cet article, je considère des stratégies pour aborder ces défis en utilisant de nouvelles méthodes ainsi que des variations des méthodes traditionnelles. Après avoir exploré le développement de la technique du violoncelle et les méthodes couramment utilisées aujourd'hui, je vous propose un nouveau modèle de travail personnalisé pour la préparation du répertoire contemporain qui concilie la pratique physique avec la pensée critique. [...]</description><creator>Stewart, Andrea</creator><contributor>Haimovitz, Matt (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Violoncello -- Methods -- Methods.</subject><subject>Violoncello -- Instruction and study.</subject><subject>Violoncello -- Studies and exercises.</subject><title>Modernizing our Methods:An Exploration of Innovative and Extended Techniques in Contemporary Music for Cello</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rr72k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c5482</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059cb30c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"The history of the world consists mostly in the memory of those ages, quite few in number, in which some part of the world has risen above itself and burst into flower or fruit". (1). Flowering periods such as this have occurred in different parts of the world and at different ages, in one or another of the fine arts - literature in Elizabethan England, painting in Cinquecento Italy, architecture in Mediaeval France - but it is a commonplace to say that there is nothing in history parallel to the consummate achievement of fifth century Hellas in all the fields of culture. Consequently, nowhere else shall we find that art and literature serve so well as commentaries upon each other, and reflect so clearly the same characteristics of the race and period which produced them. [...]</description><creator>Auld, Jean M.</creator><contributor>Traquair, * &amp; Woodhead, W. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1929</date><subject>Greek.</subject><title>The inter-relation between Attic tragedy and Greek art ofthe Classical period.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fp63g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059cb30c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Greek</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924f57q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Toccata Seconda occupies a unique place in Sorabji’s oeuvre: it was written on the cusp of his mature language, and was also the last work Sorabji played in public, in 1936. It was also the last major work to be heard in public until the 1960s (see section 7.2). The concert was given for his friend Erik Chisholm’s Active Society for the Propagation of Contemporary Music in Glasgow. It was presumably the last of his works to be heard in public for several decades. He did, toward the end of his life, sanction certain public performances of his works by some enterprising pianists who had sought and received his blessing. [...]</description><creator>Chaulk, Jeremy</creator><contributor>Wapwick, Joel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Music -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Sorabji, Kaikhosru Shapurji, 1892-1988. Toccatas, piano, no. 2.</subject><subject>Piano music -- Analysis, appreciation.</subject><title>Kaikhosru Shapurji Sorabji's Toccata Seconda</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161909b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f57q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d7147</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'oeuvre d'un auteur s'explique par son milieu, par son éducation, par les tendances d'esprit, qui se manifestent même dans sa jeunesse. Les détails sur le milieu et sur l'éducation d'un écrivain sont assez faciles à trouver mais les détails sur la croissance de l'âme et de l'esprit sont très rares et inférés par le critique par des arguments "à priori". Ces détails, toujours intéressants souvent importants, sont indispensables pour la compréhension à fond d'une oeuvre assez individualiste que celle de Mademoiselle Marle Lenéru. Et ces détails, on les possède dans son petit cahier journalier, "l'agenda usuel de l'âme". [...]</description><creator>Banfill, Gladys M.</creator><contributor>McCullagh, * &amp;Furness, L. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1929</date><subject>French.</subject><title>La theatre de Marie Leneru.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw62h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d7147</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q908z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis itself is composed of two sections. The first is a copy of the paper submitted for publication, and contains accounts of the fundamental points and the data. The second section is written as a supplement to the first. In it there is as historical account of the Stark effect in rrvdxoton and Peliam,ana detailed discussions of points which were passed over somewhat briefly in the first section. It has been the aim of the writer to avoid as much as possible detailed descriptions of experimental methods or mathematicalanalyses which are already in the literature. Such descriptions would be mere repetition without point. In such cases a general outline is riven and the reader is referred to the original work for the finer details. [...]</description><creator>Langstroth, George Otty.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Relative intensities of Stark components in helium.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v46k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q908z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qf973</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Throughout the description of the experiments dealing with the subject, it will appear that the catalytic influence of hydrocloric, hydrocromic and sulphuric acids on the rate of hydrolysis of hydrogen cyanide has been subjected to the extensive investigation. This has involved the measurement of reaction velocities at various temperatures and under differing conditions of acid content. Of such experimentation that carries on at 65 degrees C. will be found to be given greatest prominence due to the fact at at this temperature low acid concentrations gave results susceptible to most accurate measurement. [...] </description><creator>Peiker, Alfred Louis.</creator><contributor>Kreible, V. &amp; Maass, O. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The mechanism for the hydrolysis of hydrogen cyanide.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zt44s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qf973</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n395p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From the Arctic to the Gulf of Mexico extends the greatest expanse of territory in the world where a single language is spoken. Over 130,000,000 people, drawn from every country in the old world, are found living side by side and using a common tongue. It is true, there are certain sections of this great area in which English takes a secondary place to some other, but as a general rule one would be quite safe in referring to the whole territory as English-speaking, with one notable exception----the extensive use of the French language in certain parts of Canada and the United States. [...]</description><creator>Lande, Harold B.</creator><contributor>Hemmeon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>Economic factors affecting the trend of language in theProvince of Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff688.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n395p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk30f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Every great writer, ancient or modern, however subjective is work may be, however universal in its appeal, reflects some aspect of the age in which he lives - either its religiousideals, its philosophic speculations, its social needs, or its politIcal problems. This statement is especially appropriate when made with referenoe to the great Attic dramatists,each whom gives a criticism of life which is not only "for all time", but particularly applicable to the age and civilization in whioh they lived and wrote. The reason for this iseasily explained. [...]</description><creator>Moore, Ruth Evelyn.</creator><contributor>Woodhead, W. &amp; Noad, A. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>Classics.</subject><title>Patriotism and political propaganda in the plays of Euripides.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wt34c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk30f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Classics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mq419</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Like every man of genius Thomas Carlyle has been the subject of much discussion, favourable and unfavourable. Like every man who has grasped the elemental facts of human nature and given them enduring form, he remains a theme of perennial interest. No study of the personality and works of such a man can fail to be rewarding. Because he, like his master Goethe, had the eye that flashes direct into the heart of things, because his chief concern was with the permanent needs of humanity, because he struggled with the ultimate problems of life, and because of his intensely original manner of dealing with these problems, the souls of men cannot lose contact with him. Carlyle is a man who is sometimes hard to understand, and easy to misunderstand. It is true that he falls into apparent inconsistencies and leaves us in doubt, at times, as to the actual meaning of his thought. [...]</description><creator>Gough, Roger Whitfield.</creator><contributor>Hendel, C. &amp; Noad, A. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>English.</subject><subject>Carlyle, Thomas, 1795-1881 -- Political and social views.</subject><title>The political philosophy of Thomas Carlyle, with special emphasis upon his theory of the hero.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tz00x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq419</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dj49t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Dominion of Canada and the United States of America, together comprising over 85 per cent of the total area of the North American continent, occupy the most unique position of all the countries of the world, in that they are separated by a boundary of over 3,000 miles, stretching across the entire width of the.continent, terminated on the East by the Atlantic Ocean and by the Pacific Ocean on the West. A cursory glance at a map of the physical features of north America will show that the boundary itself for the most part is a political rather than a geographical division. Within each country, section is definitely separated from section by certain natural barriers which of course are clearly reflected in the physical character of the boundary line. Between eastern Canada and eastern United States, western Canada and western United States, no material difference exists. [...]</description><creator>Hamilton, Andrew Wilfred.</creator><contributor>Leacock, S. &amp; Kemp, H. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>Economics &amp; Political Science.</subject><subject>Canada -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><subject>United States -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><title>Migration of population between Canada and the United States.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb52r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj49t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics and Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827f46z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When one is studying the development of an author it is not always necessary to know anything about his life to appreciate his work, but the experiences of Eugene O'Neill are so frequently reflected in his work that his biography is of much importance if one is to understand thoroughly his dramatic productions. For O'Neil1 writes about certain modes of living so convincingly because he knows them intimately. Eugene G1adstone O'Nei11 was born in New York City, on October 16, 1888. His father was a famous actor, and, as his mother used to accompany her husband on his road tours, Eugene's first seven years were spent mainly in larger towns all over United States. [...]</description><creator>Jenkins, Lloyd H.</creator><contributor>Hendel, C. &amp; Files, H. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>O’Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>English.</subject><subject>O’Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953 -- Technique.</subject><title>Dramatic technique and tragic values in the work of Eugene Gladstone O’Neill.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wn24x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827f46z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n03j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The important work begun by Fletcher in 1898 and carried on for the following ten years by Fletoher in oollaboration with Hopkins established the theory upon which all subsequent work on muscular activity has been based. By following the gaseous exchanges in isolated amphibian muscles, particularly on the effect of oxygen in delaying loss of irritability, they proved that the excess oxygen used as a result of contraction and the extra carbon dioxide given off were taking place in the same oyole of changes. some product of activity which accumulated in the absence of oxygen was believed to bring about stiffening and loss of power to contract. [...]</description><creator>Grant, Elizabeth Rhoda.</creator><contributor>Collip, J. &amp; Long, C. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1930</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Studies in glycogen metabolism.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3014257.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n03j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):45800</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>