<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:40:35Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39400" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb36s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Days of Victory is a piece of music for a chamber orchestra of sixteen players, approximately thirteen minutes in duration. The accompanying analytical essay provides an extensive general description of its systems of pitch organization, and a more specific account of their operation in this piece. These systems function by linking dyads together to create a harmonic language that favours asymmetrical chord formations. Also included is an outline of its form, which uses four contrasting types of sections in recurrence. The essay comments on the stylistic tendencies of the piece in terms of rhythm, texture, and orchestration. This is followed by a brief exploration of the aesthetic implications of the music in relation to its title, which is drawn from a short excerpt of the Koran.</description><creator>Kambeitz, Nikolas</creator><contributor>Bouliane, Denys (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chamber orchestra music -- Scores</subject><title>The days of victory /</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hf06d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb36s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s670z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human impression of the color of an object is the same whether it is viewed foveally or peripherally, despite the non-uniformity of the spatial distribution of the photoreceptors on the retina. It is proposed that it is precisely the changing retinal signal resulting from moving the eye that leads to the perception of color constancy. Adhering to a bilinear model, which provides a parametrization of surface patch and illuminant spectra in a scene, the problem addressed in this thesis is defined to be that of estimating these spectral parameters, given only the spectral response of the sensor. The inherent non-uniqueness and thus ill-posedness of the problem lies in that different spectra of lights and surfaces can lead to the same photosensor response. In this thesis, a multi-sensor regularization technique that solves for the surface reflectance and lighting parameters is developed. This technique sequentially acquires measurements from independent sensors over the scene. Evidence for the parameters is spatially accumulated through a Bayesian probability formulation, which is a statistical approach to designing solutions to perceptual problems. Two cases are presented: (i) one with two sets of sensors, each with different absorption characteristics, and (ii) one in which there is a Gaussian variation in the absorption characteristics across the photoreceptor array. Simulations indicate that there is improvement in the parameter estimation with the additional information provided by the extra sensors. Improvement is also observed in the two-sensors case when the camera is moved to acquire multiple images of the same scene.</description><creator>Skaff, Sandra</creator><contributor>Clark, James J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Active Bayesian color constancy with non-uniform sensors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537295r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s670z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k9168</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the dynamics of quadrupedal running via the bounding gait is studied. To analyse the properties of the passive dynamics of Scout II, a model consisting of a body and two massless spring-loaded prismatic legs is introduced. A return map is derived to study the existence of periodic system motions. Numerical studies of the return map show that passive generation of cyclic motion is possible. Most strikingly, local stability analysis of the return map shows that the dynamics of the open loop passive system alone can confer stability of the motion. Stability improves at higher speeds, a fact which is in agreement with recent results from biomechanics showing that the dynamics of the body become dominant in determining stability when animals run at high speeds. Furthermore, pronking is found to be more unstable than bounding, which explains why Scout II shows a "preference" for the bounding gait. These results can be used in developing a general control methodology for legged robots, resulting from the synthesis of feed-forward and feedback models that take advantage of the mechanical system.</description><creator>Poulakakis, Ioannis</creator><contributor>Buehler, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>On the passive dynamics of quadrupedal running</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tx053.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k9168</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161812f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Wood Poles are extensively used in North America as supports for electric distribution lines. On average, wood poles have a service life of 40 years with a replacement cost of approximately $2000. Since the distribution network is of relatively recent construction, maintenance and replacement costs have been relatively small compared to the total number of poles in service. The goal of this thesis is to use the FORM/SORM algorithm to evaluate the reliability of a single pole and the results obtained when applied to a sample of 887 wood poles inspected in the field. The procedure was also applied to a sample of poles designed according to the current codes in order to calibrate the evaluation procedure. The results indicate that the proposed procedure will improve the current maintenance and replacement strategy by guarantying a more uniform level of reliability throughout the network and by decreasing by up to 33% the number of wood pole replacements. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Sa, Yingshi, 1965-</creator><contributor>Chouinard, Luc E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Reliability analysis of electric distribution lines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx73d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161812f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj517</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a new theoretical approach based on the concept of velocity singularities developed by Mateescu for airfoils in subsonic flows and for wing-body systems in supersonic regime. The present approach uses the velocity singularities in the Trefftz plane to derive the contributions of the wing incidence and chord changes in the solution of the circulation variation along the wing span. The new specific functions derived for these contributions contain both natural and forced symmetry and anti-symmetry terms, and represent the first correct mathematical modeling of the physical problem. The new forced symmetry and anti-symmetry terms and the new contributions of the incidence and chord distribution changes, which were missing from the previous methods, determine a high level of accuracy of the solution, which is free of spurious oscillations. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Seytre, Jean-François</creator><contributor>Mateescu, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Theoretical solutions for finite span wings of arbitrary shapes using velocity singularities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db868.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj517</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c245v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Indiepop was, and is, a musical genre that coalesced around UK punk and post-punk in the early 1980s. From punk, indiepop borrowed certain ideas about the politics of cultural production. What differentiated it from punk was its sound: a decidedly pop emphasis on short, melodic song structures and seemingly simple instrumentation. In embracing independent production, indiepop staked a claim for subculture authenticity over the inauthentic mass products of the mainstream music industry. Yet the defining musical elements were characteristic of the historically feminine pop idiom. The result was indiepop, where masculine authenticity and feminine pop forms melded together and created a music scene that fit uneasily within traditional definitions of subculture. This thesis explores the means by which participants in indiepop, through a concerted project to write their version of musical history, made sense of their particular scene and its place within the larger sphere of (masculine) rock culture.</description><creator>Wurster, Jessica</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Femininity</subject><subject>Punk rock music</subject><subject>Popular music -- 1991-2000</subject><subject>Popular music -- 2001-2010</subject><subject>Popular music -- 1981-1990</subject><title>"Taking 'girly music' seriously" : femininity and authenticity in indiepop</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g206x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c245v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr60z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Jacques Ferron, Quebecois writer famous for his incisive and polemic style, has created his literary works with numerous genres of great diversity. Although the author has never published any poetic works, the manuscripts found at the National Library of Quebec demonstrate all the interest Ferron had for the poetic genre. In fact, the Jacques-Ferron Archives contain over fifty poetic texts, which are being edited for this study. The first part, which presents Ferron's unpublished poems, also exposes the editorial principles that guided the task of transcribing the manuscripts. In the second part of this study, I reflect upon the idea of "conscience generique " (generic conscience), priorly established by Michal Glowinski. Once having demonstrated that Jacques Ferron used his poetic material to write some of his tales or plays, I build upon the hypothesis that his profound knowledge of poetry reading and writing modes influences him to change his literary approach to this genre. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Gagné, Geneviève</creator><contributor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Ferron, Jacques -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Jacques Ferron, poète</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333427p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr60z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m001</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine elite women's ice hockey, with particular emphasis on various aspects of aggression associated with the sport. A qualitative research methodology was employed. Participants included 4 coaches and 15 hockey players, from three elite levels of women's hockey. Each coach was interviewed using an in-depth open-ended format. Each athlete participated in a focus group interview. Commonalities emerged from the coach and athlete data, which resulted in the creation of three higher-order themes that were called (1) state of women's hockey, (2) coach and athlete issues, and (3) aggression in women's hockey. The data focused on the lives of those involved with the sport (coaches and athletes) and topics that were unique to women's ice hockey, including aggression. These results advance information concerning women's sport, coaching, and aggression in elite female athletics.</description><creator>Vanier, Julie L.</creator><contributor>Bloom, Gordon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Women hockey players -- Psychology</subject><subject>Aggressiveness</subject><subject>Hockey for women</subject><title>Aggression in elite women's ice hockey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365712k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m001</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp271</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper examines the exegetical history of the prohibition against kindling fire on the Sabbath day. Since its biblical inception Ex. 35:3, the prohibition against kindling fire on the Sabbath, has undergone a multiplicity of interpretations. The texts examined in this paper survey the treatment of this verse from its inception through to the twentieth century and the advent of electricity. Over generations exegetes have understood this biblical verse to be a prohibition against kindling, burning, and even cooking. The debates concerning the legal status and implications of the verse have additionally been outlined in this paper. Tracing the history of this verse, therefore, provides insight into the meaning of the verse and its halakhic implications.</description><creator>Weiser, Deborah</creator><contributor>Levy, B. Barry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Fire -- Religious aspects -- Judaism.</subject><subject>Sabbath (Jewish law)</subject><title>Fire and the Sabbath : a look at Exodus 35:3 and the Jewish exegetical history of the biblical prohibition against using fire on the Sabbath day</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999856w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp271</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj53s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years there has been considerable interest and research examining psychological distress resulting from athletic injuries, as well as coping strategies for an enhanced recovery. The purpose of this study was to examine the psychological effects of sport related concussions and to determine if participation in support groups can reduce these psychological side effects. Participants included concussed male and female varsity or comparable elite level athletes who were placed in either a control or an experimental group. All subjects completed the Profile of Mood States and the Post Concussion Rating Scale. Participants in the experimental group received three support group intervention sessions, while those in the control group received no intervention. Data was analyzed using descriptive statistics. It was revealed that participants in the experimental group improved their mood state. In addition to the impact of support groups on concussed athletes, factors influencing their moods were also identified including the concussion history of the athletes, the stage of rehabilitation, gender, and number of concussion symptoms.</description><creator>Horton, Amanda S.</creator><contributor>Bloom, Gordon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Sports injuries -- Patients -- Rehabilitation -- Psychological aspects</subject><subject>Brain -- Concussion</subject><subject>Self-help groups</subject><title>The impact of support groups on the psychological state of athletes experiencing concussions /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95052298.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj53s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765372961</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study focuses on the relationship between Hooker's doctrine of law and his concept of "participation," which is an important feature of his sacramental doctrine. In The Lawes of Ecclesiasticall Politie (V.50--67), Richard Hooker discusses the saving work of Christ and man's participation in him through faith and the sacraments. How does Hooker understand participation in God? Hooker speaks of the Atonement, Justification and sacraments in the vocabulary of the magisterial Reform, but (perhaps uniquely) understands the same doctrines within the framework of law, the instrument by which God orders his creation. Hooker defines law in terms of Aristotelian causes to describe a process of participation: the causes that inform the natures, operations and ends of creatures accomplish a hierarchical process of emanation of being from God and return to God. Law therefore mediates between God and creation. Creatures participate in God through the natural law, but after the fall, man's participation is restored through the divine law. Hooker's account of the Incarnation and Atonement, justification through faith, and sacramental participation---the main features of the divine law---therefore takes into account the idea of law. Hooker's treatment of participation, then, is based on categories in classical physics, and his doctrine of law influences his treatment of specific theological loci.</description><creator>Irish, Charles W.</creator><contributor>Kirby, W. J. Torrance (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Hooker, Richard, 1553 or 4-1600. Ecclesiastical polity.</subject><subject>Law (Theology) -- History of doctrines -- 16th century.</subject><subject>Mediation between God and man -- Christianity -- History of doctrines -- 16th century.</subject><title>"The participation of God himself" : law and mediation in the thought of Richard Hooker</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n25r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765372961</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784n58q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a systematic review regarding the way technology supports adult learning in communities of practice. It presents the systematic review procedure that was developed, based on NBS CRD (2001) protocol, from publication sources relevant to the topic. It includes the identification of research from an initial question that is: how does technology support adult learning in communities of practice. In addition, it presents a search strategy, a study quality assessment, a data extraction strategy and a synthesis of findings. Because most of the pertinent research is qualitative, a typology of qualitative research and a critical appraisal checklist for quality assessment were designed and are presented. The results presented have synthesized evidence from studies that meet certain quality criteria and they are discussed in terms of (a) the kinds of technologies applied in communities of practice, and (b) successful features of the technology that seem to contribute to learning.</description><creator>Heo, Gyeong Mi, 1971-</creator><contributor>Breuleux, Alain (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Education -- Data processing</subject><subject>Social learning</subject><subject>Distance education</subject><subject>Organizational learning</subject><title>A systematic review of technology to support adult learning in communities of practice /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r29k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784n58q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193b840</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study evaluated the mechanical durability of ice hockey helmets for multiple impacts at defined energy levels. A monorail drop testing apparatus was used to conduct controlled impact tests according to the CSA standard (CAN/CSA-Z262.1-M90). Five ice hockey helmet models were tested, for a total sample of 45 helmets. All helmets were impacted up to 50 times at each of in four different locations (i.e. front, right side, back, and crown), at one of 40, 50 or 60 J of kinetic energies. In general, by increasing the impact energy, the impact acceleration attenuation properties of the helmets was decreased significantly (from 4% to 80%). Although all the helmets meet the CSA standards, attenuation properties were found to be substantially reduced beyond three repeated impacts and above 40 J impact energy. In particular, all helmets showed effective multiple impact attenuation properties at the crown, front, and rear sites; however, poor multiple impact attenuation durability was evident at the side.</description><creator>Hakim-Zadeh, Roghieh</creator><contributor>Pearsall, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Hockey -- Equipment and supplies -- Testing</subject><subject>Helmets -- Testing</subject><title>Durability of ice hockey helmets to repeated impacts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf69v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b840</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs389</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Geological and high-field-strength element (HFSE) relationships for Chester Group felsic volcanic rocks and corresponding sub-volcanic intrusives in the south-east Swayze greenstone belt (SESGB) indicate deposition in an dynamic volcanic-arc tectonic setting, from two separate magmas with calc-alkaline and HFSE-depleted trace element signatures respectively. Chester Group, Yeo Formation rocks have undergone a regionally extensive sericite-quartz (type 1) alteration, involving the loss of 3.25 wt.% Na2O, addition of 12 wt.% SiO2 and 2.2 wt.% K2O, and 13% net mass-gain, indicating water/rock ratios of at least 6. Chlorite-sericite +/- biotite +/- garnet (type 2) alteration at paleo-hydrothermal vent sites was localized along synvolcanic fault structures. Type 2 alteration was accompanied by a loss of 2.44 wt.% Na2O and 8.69 wt.% SiO2, and a gain of 5.90 wt.% Fe2O3, requiring water/rock ratios of at least 432. Hydrothermal sediments or iron formation (IF) within the SGB are composed largely of Si and Fe. Base-metal mineralization in the SESGB and other localities in the SGB is hosted by brecciated hydrothermal sediments, overlain and flanked by, more broadly distributed pelitic IF, enriched in large ion lithophile elements (LILE), Al2O3, TiO2 and HFSE, with distinct Fe2O3/TiO2 versus Al2O 3/(Al2O3 + Fe2O3 + MnO) ratios indicative of mixing with locally derived volcanic material. Well-laminated BIF-type hydrothermal sediments are distributed widely throughout the SGB and are enriched in MnO, depleted in LILE, HFSE and transition elements, and have a wide range of Ce/Ce* values reflecting diverse redox conditions in paleodepositional environments distal to hydrothermal venting. Thermodynamic calculations suggest that hydrothermal fluids responsible for generation of hydrothermal sediments have lower temperatures (250--300°C) but similar pH (~4) to polymetallic volcanogenic massive-sulphide ore-forming fluids.</description><creator>Wright, Christopher, 1974-</creator><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Geology and lithogeochemistry of the Chester Group and hydrothermal sediments of the Swayze greenstone belt, Superior province, Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb66j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs389</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p399</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Networks and their services have been growing rapidly in recent years, so has the complexity of configuring the network operations. In order to manage the rapidly expanding networks, new management protocols are thus needed to change the network management from configuration of individual devices to automation of the whole network. SNMPCONF, a policy-based configuration with SNMP protocol, is proposed by IETF to meet this requirement. SNMPCONF is suggested to configure networks with a policy MIB (Management Information Base). However, deploying this protocol in existing network devices needs more work, because the policy MIB defined by SNMPCONF is not implemented now in the present network and no configuration MIB defined. Even if the configuration MIB and policy MIB implemented by vendors in future, some existing devices may not be upgraded to support these MIB for their hardware limitation (e.g., memory limit). Another problem is found in the communication between a SNMP supported network and the SNMP unsupported networks (e.g. telecommunication network where TL1 is used in North America). In this study, CLI and TL1 are used to help solving these problems. Based on Modular SNMP from University of Quebec at Montreal, a JAVA framework to deploy SNMPCONF with this approach is implemented and tested on a network built with Cisco routers (Cisco IOS 12.0, routers ranged from Catalyst 2600 to 2900). The preliminary work shows the SNMPCONF can be implemented by wrapping CLI commands as accessory functions in policy language without configuration MIB. As shown in this work, another advantage of this approach is that policy execution is atomic and persistent.</description><creator>Xiao, Zhifeng, 1966-</creator><contributor>Ratzer, Gerald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A policy based network configuration framework /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x610.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p399</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt524</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cubilin is a peripheral membrane protein that co-operates with the endocytic receptor megalin to mediate the endocytosis of ligands in various polarized epithelia. Megalin is expressed in the male reproductive tract where is has been implicated in the process of sperm membrane remodeling. A potential role for cubilin in the male reproductive tract has not been explored. Using RT-PCR, we found that cubilin and megalin mRNAs are expressed in the efferent ducts, corpus and cauda epididymides, and proximal and distal vas deferens. Immunohistological analysis revealed that cubilin was expressed in non-ciliated cells of the efferent ducts, principal cells of the corpus and cauda epididymides and vas deferens. Electron microscopic immunogold labeling showed cubilin in endocytic pits, endocytic vesicles and endosomes of these cells. The expression profile of cubilin in the male reproductive tract was coincident with that of megalin except in principal cells of the caput epididymidis. Double immunogold labeling showed that cubilin and megalin co-localized with one another within the endocytic apparatus and recycling vesicles of efferent duct cells. Neither protein was found in lysosomes. Injection of RAP, an antagonist of megalin interaction with cubilin, reduced the level of intracellular cubilin in cells of the efferent ducts and vas deferens. In conclusion, cubilin and megalin are co-expressed in cells of the epididymis and vas deferens and the endocytosis of cubilin in these tissues is dependent on megalin. Together, these findings highlight the potential for a joint endocytic role for cubilin and megalin in the male reproductive tract.</description><creator>Van Praet, Oliver</creator><contributor>Morales, Carlos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Co-expression and interaction of cubilin and megalin in the adult male rat reproductive system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt09q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt524</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw367</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of the time of application of Gibberellic Acid (GA3) and Lipo-Chitin Oligosaccharides (LCOs) on annual production of globe artichoke (Cynara scolymus L.) cultivars 'Imperial Star' and 'Green Globe' was studied in 2000 and 2001. In order for flowering to occur plants must undergo a period of vernalization. In 2000, plants received 54 chilling (vernalizing) hours, an amount sufficient to induce flowering in 100% of the Imperial star and 25% of the Green Globe control plants. Applications of 25ppm GA3 at the 6 and 10-leaf stage reduced the time to flowering by 11 days, increased uniformity of flower bud production, and also increased yield of Imperial Star. GA3 had no significant effect on Green Globe plants. LCO fraction C (an identified and collected nod factor peak in retention time of 32.56 minutes) had minimal effect on growth and development for both cultivars in 2000. In 2001 plants received no vernalizing temperatures and in addition were exposed to 89 hours of temperatures greater than 32°C which could devernalize the plants. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Yang, Yang, 1973-</creator><contributor>Stewart, Katrine A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Artichokes -- Yields -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Gibberellic acid.</subject><subject>Oligosaccharides.</subject><title>Application of gibberellic acid (GA3) and lipo-chitin oligosaccharides (LCOs) on annual production of globe artichoke (Cynara scolymus L.) in southwestern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t823k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw367</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg44t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Filter-feeding black fly larvae in lake outlet streams convert suspended bacteria and algae into benthic biomass, available to fish. Positive correlations between larval abundance and both bacterioplankton and phytoplankton were significant at the p &lt; 0.10 level among 5 outlet streams of varying trophic status in the Eastern Townships of Quebec, and either food type alone explained ~28% of the variance in larval abundance among streams (Chapter 1), suggesting bacterioplankton and phytoplankton to play similar roles in larval distribution. However, when larvae were removed from 3 of 6 oligotrophic outlet streams examined in the Mauricie region of Quebec, calculated ingestion rates revealed larvae to ingest roughly 20 times more phytoplankton carbon than bacterial carbon (Chapter 2). Phytoplankton ingestion rates were high enough to satisfy daily carbon requirements, but bacterivory was low (Chapter 2), indicating that bacterial biomass contributes little to black fly diets in most systems, and will be less useful than phytoplankton biomass when using food to predict larval distribution. The majority of bacteria in streams form a carbon link to fish through sediment food webs, rather than through black fly larvae.</description><creator>Parkes, Alice</creator><contributor>Kalff, Jacob (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Simuliidae -- Larvae -- Ecology -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Simuliidae -- Food -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>The role of bacteria and algae in the diet and distribution of black fly larvae /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x327z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg44t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r509h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>About 40% of human pregnancies are unsuccessful and many of these are thought to be genetically normal. Our hypothesis is that decidual NK cells in abortion prone pregnancies produce IFN-gamma which primes macrophages. These primed macrophages are then triggered by a second signal to become the major effectors in early embryo resorption. Analysis of individual implantation sites was performed at day 9 of pregnancy to determine the cytokine profile of these NK cells and if NK cells selectively infiltrate the decidua of embryos that will undergo resorption. Use of a pan-NK cell marker (DX5) allowed labeling of decidual NK cells for flow cytometric analysis. Magnetic labeling and isolation of DX5+ cells from individual embryos was followed by RT-PCR and southern blot analysis. This thesis prevents evidence that a number of the embryos are infiltrated by higher numbers of DX5+ NK-cells with an incidence that is similar to the occurrence of early embryo loss in this experimental model. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ng Thow Hing, Christopher</creator><contributor>Baines, Malcolm (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>The role of natural killer cells in murine early embryo loss /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c41n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r509h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n9821</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several dosimetric parameters were measured for three very small radiation fields (1.5, 3, and 5 mm diameter at the machine isocenter) with a small ionization chamber and a new type of radiochromic film. The experiments were carried out on a Clinac-18 linac and the fields were shaped by specially manufactured collimators. When measuring dose profiles, the ionization chamber measurements were first corrected for response variation in off-axis direction, and then deconvolved to eliminate the blur due to the poor resolution of the chamber. The measured data agreed with Monte Carlo simulations within the established statistical uncertainties. Dynamic stereotactic radiosurgery was carried out on the same accelerator using the very small radiation beams. The dose distributions and their displacements from the laser-defined isocenter of the linac were measured and then compared to 3-D Monte Carlo calculations. The results proved that dynamic radiosurgery with very small beams has potential for clinical use.</description><creator>Paskalev, Kamen A.</creator><contributor>Podgorsak, Ervin B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Dosimetry of very small photon fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j00c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n9821</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz48r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tree classifiers partition the feature space into regions based on simple binary decisions called splitting rules. It can be shown that many splitting rules are not universally consistent, meaning that they may not converge to the optimal solution. This thesis introduces a method for growing decision trees grown with a consistent splitting rule, using random jumps and local optimizations to avoid an otherwise computationally expensive task. The tree classifier is tested on synthetic and natural data, showing comparable performance with other machine learning methods. In addition, a new data set is introduced to perform automatic classification of underwater mines from sonar imagery. Features are extracted and performance evaluated using the new splitting rule.</description><creator>Myers, Vincent L.</creator><contributor>Devroye, Luc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A tree classifier based on a consistent splitting rule /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd60r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz48r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w97g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Onchocerca volvulus, a filarial nematode, is the causative agent of onchocerciasis. O. volvulus is a human parasite with no animal model host and is endemic in the tropics. O. volvulus material is scarce and must be conserved as part of the Onchocerciasis Control Program. A genomic library was constructed to provide a substantial source of renewable genetic material, in place of original parasite DNA. Currently there is only one glutamate-gated chloride channel that has been sequenced from O. volvulus, but this has not yet been characterized. This GluClx partial cDNA sequence isolated by Cully et al., 1997, may be found in GenBank, accession number U59745. Specific primers were designed to amplify this gene from the genomic library. A fragment of this gene was isolated but the primers were non-specific, amplifying genes in addition to GluClx. A motif is a short recognition sequence within a protein that may allow the modification of the protein. The cysteine loop in the N-terminal of all the ligand-gated ion channels is interesting because it contains the neurotransmitter-gated ion channel signature sequence. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Halstead, Meredith</creator><contributor>Beech, Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Ivermectin.</subject><subject>Onchocerciasis.</subject><subject>Onchocerca volvulus.</subject><subject>Drug resistance.</subject><subject>Chloride channels.</subject><title>Putative glutamate-gated chloride channels from Onchocerca volvulus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r738.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w97g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v8382428</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A bilateral, canine uncemented total hip arthroplasty model was used to assess the effect of widely ranging stem stiffness on femoral stem fixation and peri-implant remodeling. A porous coated titanium stem, with stiffness properties similar to those of the canine femur was compared, with a porous coated composite stem that was more flexible than the canine femur. The femora were analyzed for the extent of bone ingrowth, the extent of radiopaque line formation, peri-implant cortical area, intracortical porosity, and bone remodeling. Despite the marked increase in stem flexibility with the composite stem, there was no statistically significant difference in the overall degree of femoral stress shielding, cortical area, or cortical porosity when compared with the stiffer titanium stem at either time period. Overall, the tissue response to the more flexible composite stem resulted in less bone ingrowth and more radiopaque line formation at the bone-implant interface than with the titanium stem. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Harvey, Edward J.</creator><contributor>Bobyn, J. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>The effective limit of implant flexibility in optimizing femoral bone remodeling and stem fixation after non-cemented total hip arthroplasty /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806178j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8382428</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd09c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the role of prolactin (PRL) as an autocrine/paracrine survival and/or growth factor in the human breast cancer cell line T47D and the signaling pathways that mediate this function. Utilizing an oligonucleotide antisense to human PRL (hPRL) mRNA to inhibit endogenous PRL production in T47D cells, we found that PRL contributes to the viability of the T47D cells. Furthermore, exogenous PRL stimulation mediates the activation of the protein kinase B/Akt (PKB/Akt) in the mammary epithelial cell lines HC11 and MCF-10, as well as T47D cells. PRL stimulation led to the phosphorylation of the pro-apoptotic protein Bad, a member of the Bcl-2 family, as well as the phosphorylation and subsequent cytoplasmic sequestration of FKHRL1, a member of the forkhead family of transcription factors. Utilizing the P13kinase inhibitor LY294002, the Jak2 inhibitor Ag490, and the Src kinase inhibitor PP2, we illustrated that PRL-mediated activation of PKB/Akt was dependent on both P13kinase and Src kinase activity, but independent of Jak2 kinase activity. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Hartley, Strachan</creator><contributor>Ali, Suhad (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, General.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Prolactin mediated activation of survival pathways in human breast cancer cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g694v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd09c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268704n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dietary fatty acid (FA) composition and energy restriction (ER) independently affect serum leptin levels; however it is not known whether this correlates with changes in obese (ob) gene expression. Herein, we assessed whether dietary FA composition and ER influence white adipose tissue (WAT) ob mRNA by Northern analysis. Animals consumed diets containing tallow (BT), safflower oil (SO) or fish oil (FO) ad libitum or at 60% ad libitum intakes. Serum leptin values were not different between levels of energy intake. ER decreased weight gain and WAT weights, which positively correlated with serum leptin values. WAT ob mRNA levels were in the rank order: FO &gt; SO &gt; BT in depots of all groups with ER showing a lower level of ob mRNA. Data show similarity in ob mRNA levels between depots with discordance in circulating leptin levels. These data suggest that energy restriction exerts greater control over leptin production than dietary fat source.</description><creator>Hynes, Geoffrey Ronald</creator><contributor>Jones, J. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Leptin.</subject><subject>Adipose tissues.</subject><subject>Fatty acids in human nutrition.</subject><title>Effects of dietary fatty acid composition and energy restriction on adipose tissue obese mRNA, fatty acid composition and serum leptin levels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p402.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268704n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39425</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>