<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:55:32Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42825" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128g27k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Alzheimer’s disease (AD) is the most prevalent cause of the millions of cases ofdementia worldwide. AD pathology begins to progress decades before symptoms of dementia areapparent, providing a large window of opportunity to alter the progress of pre-symptomatic AD.To understand AD progression in its pre-symptomatic stage, and eventually evaluate preventionstrategies, we cannot rely on symptoms. We must therefore rely on disease markers of progression.Current biomarkers use invasive, time-consuming, and expensive methods. Therefore, we aimedto examine whether central auditory processing (CAP) can be used as an alternative marker forAD progression. Methods: The Synthetic Sentence with Ipsilateral Competing Message (SSI-ICM) was used to test speech-in-noise comprehension (n = 114), and the Dichotic SentenceIdentification (DSI) for binaural separation (n = 118). The Repeatable Battery for Assessment ofNeuropsychological Status (RBANS) was used to test cognition. Participants also underwentlumbar punctures and genetic testing. Linear mixed effects models assessed the relationshipbetween measures of CSF and cognition, and CAP, controlling for covariates. Results: CAP didnot vary in time, correlate in time with AD biomarkers (ie. CAP did not vary with biomarkerevidence of AD pathology), or correlate in time with cognitive performance (ie. CAP did not varywith cognitive decline in immediate memory, attention, and total RBANS score). We did find thatthe SSI-ICM worse ear score predicted decline in total RBANS score; however, this finding didnot survive correction for multiple comparisons. Moreover, baseline CAP did not predict changein AD biomarkers or cognitive performance. Conclusion: Although the results presented in thisthesis do not support the idea of CAP being a predictor or surrogate marker of incipient AD, it isstill worth exploring as a potential biomarker</description><description>Introduction: La maladie d’Alzheimer (MA) est la principale cause de millions de cas de démencedans le monde. La pathologie de la MA commence à se développer des décennies avant que lessymptômes de démence n'apparaissent, offrant ainsi une grande fenêtre d'opportunité pourmodifier les progrès de la MA pré-symptomatique. Pour comprendre la progression de la maladieau stade pré-symptomatique et éventuellement évaluer les stratégies de prévention, nous nepouvons pas nous fier aux symptômes. Nous devons donc nous fier aux marqueurs de progressionde la maladie. Les biomarqueurs actuels utilisent des méthodes invasives, chronophages etcoûteuses. Par conséquent, nous avons cherché à examiner si la fonction auditive centrale (FAC)peut être utilisé comme marqueur alternatif de la progression de la MA. Méthodes: Le test dephrase synthétique avec message contradictoire (SSI-ICM) a été utilisé pour tester lacompréhension de la parole dans le bruit (n = 114) et l'identification de phrase dichotique (DSI)pour la séparation binaurale (n = 118). La batterie répétable pour l'évaluation de l'étatneuropsychologique (RBANS) a été utilisée pour tester la cognition. Les participants ontégalement subi des ponctions lombaires et des tests génétiques. Les modèles linéaires à effetsmixtes ont évalué la relation entre les mesures du LCR et de la cognition, et le FAC, en contrôlantles covariables. Résultats: Le FAC n'a pas varié dans le temps, n'a pas corrélé dans le temps avecles biomarqueurs de la MA (le CAP n'a pas varié en fonction de preuves de la pathologie de la MAchez les biomarqueurs) ou corrélé dans le temps avec la performance cognitive (mémoireimmédiate, attention et score total RBANS). Nous avons constaté que le score de pire oreille SSI-ICM prédit une baisse du score total RBANS; toutefois, cette constatation n'a pas survécu à lacorrection pour les comparaisons multiples. De plus, la FAC de base ne prédit pas de changement des biomarqueurs de la MA ni de la performance cognitive. Conclusion: Bien que les résultatsprésentés dans cette thèse n'appuient pas l'idée que la FAC soit un prédicteur ou un marqueur desubstitution de la maladie d'Alzheimer naissante, il reste intéressant d'explorer celle-ci en tant quebiomarqueur potentiel</description><creator>Kazazian, Christina</creator><contributor>Megha Chakravarty (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Central auditory processing as a marker for preclinical Alzheimer's disease progression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794082487.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128g27k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dr46n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'association entre hypertension et la maladie d'Alzheimer (MA) a été mise en évidence par des études identifiant le système rénine-angiotensine (SRA) comme voie potentielle dans la pathologie de la MA. Divers composants du SRA étant altérés dans la MA, leur dérégulation pourrait contribuer aux changements neuropathologiques et au déclin cognitif de la MA. Les antagonistes des récepteurs type 1 de l’angiotensine II (AT1R), une classe d'antihypertenseurs, ont réduit l'apparition et la progression de la MA. Des travaux ayant administré le losartan, un antagoniste des AT1Rs, à un modèle de souris de la MA, ont montré une récupération des déficits cognitifs et cérébrovasculaires, et des effets antiinflammatoires et antioxydants puissants. Les mécanismes d’action de ces bénéfices demeurent largement inconnus. Ma thèse visait à déterminer si les bénéfices du losartan résultaient de l’activation des récepteurs type 2 de l’angiotensine II (AT2R) ou des récepteurs de l’angiotensine IV (AngIV) (AT4R), et si leur activation chronique pouvait reproduire les bénéfices du losartan chez des souris transgéniques de la MA qui sur-expriment les mutations humaines Suédoise et Indiana de la protéine précurseur de l'amyloïde (souris APP). Des souris âgées de trois mois ont été traitées avec du losartan (10 mg/kg/jour, 4 mois), suivi d'une administration intracérébroventriculaire (icv) de véhicule ou de divalinal (24 nmol/jour, antagoniste AT4Rs). Divalinal a aboli les bénéfices du losartan sur l’apprentissage spatial et la mémoire, et a bloqué ceux sur la fonction vasodilatatrice et la biodisponibilité de l’oxyde nitrique (NO) dans les artères cérébrales. Divalinal a annulé les effets antiinflammatoires du losartan, mais n’a pas affecté ses effets sur le stress oxydatif. Ni le losartan ni le divalinal n’a altéré la pression artérielle ou la pathologie amyloïde. Dans un deuxième projet, des souris APP âgées de 4.5 mois ont été traitées avec véhicule ou l’AngIV (1.3 nmol/jour, icv). L’AngIV a rétabli l'apprentissage spatial et la mémoire chez les souris APP. L'AngIV a aussi normalisé le couplage neurovasculaire, les réponses vasodilatatrices, la biodisponibilité du NO et les taux d'AT4Rs dans l'hippocampe, sans affecter la pression artérielle. L’AngIV a réduit le stress oxydatif, et normalisé la prolifération cellulaire et l’arborisation dendritique des cellules granulaires de l’hippocampe, sans bénéfices sur la neuroinflammation et la pathologie amyloïde. Dans le dernier projet, des souris APP âgées de 2.5 mois ont reçu du losartan (10 mg/kg/jour, 7 mois) suivi d'une administration de PD123319 (1.6 nmol/jour, icv, antagoniste AT2Rs). D’autres souris ont reçu 1 mois (1 nmol/jour, icv) ou 7 mois (10 mg/kg/jour) de l’agoniste AT2Rs, le Composé 21 (C21). PD123319 n’a pas contré les avantages du losartan sur la mémoire à court terme; mais a réduit ses bénéfices sur l'apprentissage spatial et la mémoire. Aucun des traitements au C21 n’a exercé d’effets bénéfiques sur la mémoire. PD123319 a contré la capacité du losartan à rétablir le couplage neurovasculaire, un résultat compatible avec la capacité du C21 à normaliser cette réponse. L'administration de PD123319 a réduit les avantages du losartan sur la biodisponibilité du NO, tandis que le C21 n'a eu aucun effet. Ni les traitements au PD123319 ni ceux au C21 n'ont altéré la fonction vasodilatatrice ou la microgliose. PD123319 n'a eu aucun effet sur l'astrogliosis ou la pathologie amyloïde, alors que ces deux marqueurs ont été réduits par le C21. Ces résultats identifient les AT4Rs comme mécanisme possible des bénéfices du losartan et une cible prometteuse pour restaurer les déficits cognitifs et cérébrovasculaires de la MA. Ils soulignent le potentiel des analogues de l'AngIV à prévenir la MA. Les AT2Rs semblent impliqués dans certains bénéfices du losartan; mais le peu d’effets positifs du C21 suggèrent qu’aux doses choisies, l’activation des AT2Rs n’est pas une approche thérapeutique efficace de la MA</description><description>The association between hypertension and Alzheimer’s disease (AD) led to the emergence of pre-clinical and clinical findings that identified the renin angiotensin system (RAS) as a potential pathway to be considered in the pathogenesis of AD. Since various components of RAS are found to be altered in AD, it is possible that this dysregulation may contribute to many neuropathological dysfunctions, as well as the hallmark of AD, progressive cognitive decline. Correspondingly, a subset of antihypertensive medications, known as angiotensin receptor blockers that antagonize the RAS’s angiotensin II type 1 receptors (AT1Rs), reduce the onset and progression of AD. Prior work that administered the AT1R blocker losartan (10 mg/kg/day) to a well-characterized transgenic AD mouse model that overexpresses Swedish and Indiana mutations of the human amyloid precursor protein (APP mice) showed rescue of cognitive and cerebrovascular dysfunctions, and potent anti-inflammatory and antioxidant benefits. My thesis sought to elucidate whether losartan’s benefits occurred through angiotensin II type 2 receptors (AT2Rs) or angiotensin IV (AngIV) receptors (AT4Rs), and whether chronic AT2R or AT4R activation could mimic losartan’s benefits in APP mice. In project one, 3-month-old mice were treated with losartan (10mg/kg/day, 4 months), followed by intracerebroventricular (icv) administration of vehicle or divalinal (24 nmol/day, a selective AT4R antagonist) in the final month of losartan treatment. Divalinal countered losartan’s capacity to rescue spatial learning and memory, and blocked losartan’s benefits on vasodilatory function and baseline nitric oxide (NO) bioavailability. Divalinal reverted losartan’s anti-inflammatory effects, independent of its antioxidant benefits. Neither losartan nor divalinal treatment altered blood pressure or amyloid pathology. In my second project, 4.5 month-old APP mice were administered vehicle or AngIV (1.3nmol/day) icv via osmotic minipumps. AngIV-treatment restored short-term memory, spatial learning and memory retention in APP mice. Furthermore, AngIV administration normalized neurovascular coupling, vasodilatory responses, and NO bioavailability in the vessel wall, without affecting blood pressure. AngIV-treatment reduced oxidative stress, normalized hippocampal AT4R levels, and increased cellular proliferation and dendritic arborization independent of persisting neuroinflammation and amyloid pathology. In my final project, APP mice (2-3 months old) received losartan (10 mg/kg/day, 7 months), followed by concomitant icv administration of vehicle or AT2R antagonist PD123319 (1.6 nmol/day) via osmotic minipumps. Another group of APP mice received 1 month of the selective AT2R agonist Compound 21 (C21, 1.6 nmol/day, icv) via osmotic minipumps, while others were treated with C21 (10 mg/kg/day, 7 months) in their drinking water. PD123319 failed to counter losartan’s short-term memory benefits; yet, countered spatial learning and memory retention. PD123319 countered losartan’s sensory-evoked neurovascular coupling rescue, reduced NO bioavailability benefits, and had no effects on vasodilatory function, gliosis, or amyloidosis. C21 treatments had no benefit on any memory parameter, NO bioavailability, vasodilatory function, or microgliosis. C21 did, however, normalize sensory-evoked neurovascular coupling, as well as reduced astrogliosis and amyloidosis. Overall, our findings identify the AngIV cascade as a primary mechanism mediating losartan’s benefits, and a promising target for restoring amyloid--related cognitive and cerebrovascular deficits. They further point to AngIV analogs potential in clinical studies aimed at preventing or treating AD. AT2Rs were identified as mediating selective benefits of losartan intervention; yet, since AT2R agonism failed to mimic losartan’s cognitive benefits, our results suggest that at the selected doses, AT2R activation is not be an effective therapeutic approach for AD</description><creator>Royea, Jessika</creator><contributor>Edith Hamel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Unraveling the role of the Renin Angiotensin System in cerebrovascular and memory deficits in Alzheimer’s disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h168k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dr46n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kv621</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer de la peau est le cancer malin le plus fréquent chez les adultes. Son incidence mondiale augmente, surtout au niveau des régions anatomiques les plus exposées au soleil, telles que la tête et le cou. Le carcinome à cellules basales est le plus fréquent, représentant environ 80% des cancers de la peau de type non-mélanome, suivi du carcinome squameux et du carcinome sébacé.Le standard de diagnostic des cancers de la peau est l’excision chirurgicale de la lésion, suivi d’une analyse histopathologique. La nature délicate de la peau située dans la région péri-oculaire ainsi que la petite taille des biopsies posent souvent un défi dans le diagnostic de ces cancers ; engendrant des faux négatifs. De plus, ces procédures causent un certain inconfort pour le patient. Étant donné les avancées récentes dans le domaine de l’imagerie médicale, il y a un besoin évident pour une meilleure méthode de diagnostique non-invasive.La tomographie par cohérence optique (TCO) est une méthode rapide et non-invasive qui offre une visualisation tri-dimensionelle des lésions en temps réel. Son utilisation en ophtalmologie est courante afin d’étudier la santé de la rétine, et elle devient de plus en plus populaire auprès d’autres spécialités de la médecine.Des recherches en cours visent à valider la TCO pour des fins dermatologiques. Cependant, aucune étude ne se concentre sur les cancers de la peau en région péri-oculaire. Notre étude vise donc à offrir aux médecins une alternative d’imagerie non-invasive afin de diagnostiquer les cancers de la peau de la région péri-oculaire.Cinquante patients avec des lésions suspectes de cancer malins ont été recrutés et soumis à un examen clinique suivi d’une séance d’imagerie par TCO avant l’excision de leur lésion. Une série de caractéristiques ont été identifiés sur chacune des images obtenues par TCO et elles ont été comparées à la coupe histopathologique leur correspondant. Au total, huit caractéristiques identifiées par TCO se sont avérées être équivalente à leur représentation histopathologique.La fiabilité de chacun des critères fût ensuite vérifiée par différents groupes d’évaluateurs. Pour chacune des huit caractéristiques identifiées par TCO, un accord juste à modéré fut observé. Cependant, les images TCO représentant des cancers malins sont différenciés des images normales avec une précision de 100%. Nos résultats suggèrent que l’interprétation des images par TCO est dépendante de l’expérience de l’évaluateur et nous prédisons une courbe d’apprentissage lorsque plus d’images seront obtenues.Chacun des cas fut par la suite classé selon la qualité des images TCO obtenues, et les caractéristiques histologiques de chacune des lésions fut estimée. Nous observons aucun lien entre la qualité des images TCO et la cellularité des lésions, non plus avec le niveau d’inflammation ou d’élastose solaire en périphérie des lésions. La région anatomique de la lésion ne semble pas affecter l’imagerie par TCO. Cependant, nous observons une faible diminution de la qualité de l’image TCO pour les lésions à propriétés infiltratives, tels les carcinomes à cellules basales de type ‘morpheatype’ ainsi que pour les lésions démontrant une importante couche de kératine.En somme, nos résultats affirment que la TCO est une méthode d’imagerie capable de démontrer des caractéristiques tumorales qui sont comparables à celles vue par analyse histopathologique. Nos observations suggèrent que certaines caractéristiques sont plus fortement associées à certains diagnostics, permettant d’obtenir en quelque sorte une ‘biopsie optique’ et de peaufiner le diagnostic.Notre approche originale et non-invasive permettra ainsi d’augmenter la précision du diagnostic et mènera ainsi à une meilleure prise en charge du patient</description><description>Skin cancer is the most frequent malignancy in adults. Its incidence is increasing worldwide, especially on the sun-exposed areas of the skin such as the head and neck. Basal cell carcinoma accounts for about eighty percent of non-melanoma skin cancers, followed by squamous cell carcinoma and sebaceous carcinoma.The gold standard for diagnosis of skin cancers is the surgical excision of the lesion for histopathological analysis. Current challenges with peri-ocular lesions are the difficulty of sampling due to their delicate anatomical regions and the small size of the biopsies, leading to false negatives. Moreover, surgical procedures are not without risk to the patient. Recent advances in imaging technologies highlight an evident need for a non-invasive diagnostic tool for skin cancers.Optical coherence tomography (OCT) is a fast, non-invasive imaging modality that offers real-time, three-dimensional visualization of anatomical structure. Its use in ophthalmology to assess retinal health is already well established and other medical specialties are now turning towards OCT imaging.Ongoing research to validate the use of OCT imaging in dermatology appears to be promising, yet there is no reported evidence focusing on peri-ocular skin cancers. Our study aims to provide clinicians with fast and non-invasive alternatives to biopsies in order to diagnose peri-ocular skin malignancies.Fifty patients with peri-ocular lesions suspicious of skin malignancies were recruited and subjected to clinical examination and OCT imaging of their lesion prior to the surgical removal. Clinical and OCT images were analyzed, and relevant OCT features were identified for each lesion. OCT images were then compared to their corresponding histopathological sections and eight relevant OCT features are recognized as being equivalently represented on histopathology. The reliability of each OCT feature was assessed by different groups of graders. For the eight pre-defined OCT features, we observe a fair to moderate agreement between graders. However, neoplastic lesions can be discerned from normal skin with 100% accuracy. Our result suggest that interpretation of OCT images is dependent on the grader’s experience and a learning curve is predicted as more images are obtained.Cases were grouped based on the quality of the OCT image and histomorphological features for each lesion were assessed. We observe no relation between the quality of the OCT images and the cellularity of the lesion, nor with the degree of inflammation or the severity of the solar elastosis surrounding the lesion. The anatomical location of the lesion does not seem to influence the quality of the OCT image. We observe a slight decrease in the quality of imaging for infiltrative lesions such as morpheatype basal cell carcinoma or for lesions with a prominent keratotic crust.Altogether, our results show that optical coherence tomography is an imaging methodology capable of showing features of skin lesions that correspond to histopathological findings associated with skin malignancies, such as in an ‘optical biopsy’. Current work suggests that specific features can be helpful in ruling-in or ruling-out certain diagnosis, providing clinical guidance to the treating clinician.Our novel, non-invasive, methodology will allow to increase diagnostic precision and lead to a better patient care</description><creator>Bergeron, Sabrina</creator><contributor>Miguel Noel Burnier (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Pathology</subject><title>The use of anterior segment optical coherence tomography to assess peri-ocular skin cancers: an optical biopsy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816r863.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kv621</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc95r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis makes a case for the tax law treatment of multinational enterprises (MNEs) as unitary firms by Nigeria and other African countries under the recently negotiated African Continental Free Trade Agreement (AfCFTA). MNEs strategically exploit their legal structures in order to shift their global profits to low or no tax jurisdictions and away from the countries where their real economic activities occur. Treating MNEs as unitary firms has the potential to significantly curtail these tax avoidance practices. Doing so is particularly important for African countries because they are more dependent on corporate income tax revenues for their national budgetary needs. Most of the corporate tax revenue in these countries must come from foreign-owned firms as these firms dominate the large revenue-generating sectors of their economies, such as oil and gas, mining, agriculture and manufacturing.Two of the main obstacles to the adoption of unitary taxation for MNEs are the corporate legal structures that divide companies across legal jurisdictions, followed closely by the lack of consensus on a workable strategy to implement unitary taxation on a global scale. This thesis answers both of these challenges by providing theoretical and doctrinal support for the unitary approach and by showing the practical aspects and impacts of such adoption through the use of a case study. The thesis accomplishes the first task by revisiting the theories and principles guiding the international tax system and their limitations in today’s global and integrated economic environment. Using Stephen Hymer’s theory of foreign direct investment (FDI) and the single enterprise theory, the thesis demonstrates that treating related entities in MNEs or subsidiaries and their parent companies as unitary firms is both legally and economically coherent despite the traditional view of the corporation as an entity separate from its owners. The thesis then uses Nigeria’s experience in taxing MNEs as a case study to demonstrate how unitary approach would significantly reduce tax avoidance and protect the domestic tax base. It extends its recommendations to other African countries as the AfCFTA comes into effect</description><description>Cette thèse plaide en faveur d'un traitement fiscal des entreprises multinationales (EMN) en tant qu'entreprises unitaires par le Nigéria et d'autres pays africains dans le cadre de l'accord AfCFTA (African Continental Free Trade Agreement). Les entreprises multinationales exploitent les structures juridiques de manière stratégique afin de transférer leurs profits globaux aux juridictions à faible imposition ou sans imposition fiscale, et hors des pays où leurs activités économiques sont réellement exercées. Traiter les entreprises multinationales comme des entreprises unitaires pourrait potentiellement limiter considérablement ces pratiques d’évasion fiscale. Cela est surtout important pour les pays africains, qui dépendent particulièrement des impôts sur les sociétés pour répondre à leurs besoins budgétaires nationaux. La majeure partie des recettes fiscales des sociétés dans ces pays doit provenir d'entreprises étrangères, qui dominent les grands secteurs générateurs de revenus de leur économie, tels que le pétrole et le gaz, les mines, l'agriculture et l'industrie manufacturière. Deux obstacles principaux empêche l’adoption d’une fiscalité unitaire pour les entreprises multinationales: soit des structures actuelles qui permet la division des entreprises entre régions juridiques, ainsi que l’absence de consensus sur une stratégie viable pour mettre en œuvre la fiscalité unitaire à l’échelle mondiale. Cette thèse répond à ces deux défis en apportant un soutien théorique et doctrinal à l'approche unitaire, et en montrant les aspects pratiques et les impacts d’une telle approche à l'aide d'une étude de cas. La thèse accomplit la première tâche en revisitant les théories et les principes qui guident présentement le système fiscal international et leurs limites vis à vis le context global et l’environnement économique d’aujourd’hui. En utilisant la théorie de l'investissement direct étranger (IDE) de Stephen Hymer et la Théorie de l'entreprise unique, cette thèse montre que le traitement des filiales et leurs sociétés mères ou les entités des EMNs en tant qu’entreprises unitaires est à la fois juridiquement et économiquement cohérent, malgré la vision traditionnelle que l'entreprise devrait être une entité distincte de ses propriétaires. La thèse utilise ensuite l’expérience du Nigéria et leur taxation des EMNs comme étude de cas pour démontrer en quoi une approche unitaire permettrait de réduire de manière significative l’évasion fiscale et de protéger l’assiette fiscale nationale. Il étend ses recommandations à d'autres pays africains au fur et à mesure de l'entrée en vigueur de l'AfCFTA</description><creator>Ezenagu, Alexander</creator><contributor>Allison Christians (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Unitary taxation of multinational enterprises for a just allocation of income: Nigeria as a case study of Africa’s largest economies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jd10n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc95r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj4309023</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le récepteur du facteur de croissance épidermique (EGFR), un conducteur oncogène éminent, a été un objet majeur dans l'avènement de la médecine personnalisée et a obtenu un succès considérable sous la forme d’anticorps et d’inhibiteurs de kinase de tyrosine d'EGFR (EKI). Les vésicules extracellulaires (VE) sont des fragments de membrane qui jouent un rôle important dans la communication cellulaire à courte et longue distance en transportant un chargement biologiquement actif, y compris des protéines, des lipides et des acides nucléiques. Les VE jouent un rôle crucial dans la transformation cellulaire, l'angiogenèse et la métastase. Cette thèse explore la relation entre le traitement EKI et les vésicules extracellulaires, relation qui sert de vecteur pour de potentiels effets biologiques fortuits à la suite du traitement avec des agents ciblés. Nous avons observé des réponses cellulaires et examiné des profils de formation de vésicules dans plusieurs lignées de cellules cancéreuses avec statuts et expressions différents de mutation d'EGFR en réponse de traitement avec dacomitinib, un EKI de deuxième génération. Nous spéculons que la quantification des VE reflète la réponse au traitement médicamenteux, car les lignées de cellules sensibles au dacomitinib augmentent la production de vésicules alors que les cellules résistantes ne le font pas. En outre, nous avons observé que la quantité d’ADN associé aux VE était liée à la concentration de médicament dans les cellules sensibles. Les cellules endothéliales ont montré des réponses différentes lorsqu'elles ont été cultivées en présence de VE dérivés de cellules traitées au dacomitinib par rapport aux VE dérivées de cellules non traitées, ce qui suggère que le traitement EKI modifie le potentiel angiogénique des VE libérées. Nous postulons que, en raison de leurs caractéristiques physiques et des réponses cellulaires associées aux concentrations de médicaments correspondantes, les VE dérivées du traitement EKI appartiennent à un sous-type émergent de vésicules apoptotiques semblables à des exosomes</description><description>Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR), a prominent oncogenic driver, has been a major target in the advent of personalized medicine and has elicited considerable success in the forms of antibodies and EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors (EKI). Extracellular vesicles (EVs) are membrane fragments that mediate short- and long-distance cellular communication by stably carrying biologically active cargo including proteins, lipids, and nucleic acids. EVs play key roles in cellular transformation, angiogenesis, and metastasis. This thesis explores the relationship between EKI treatment and extracellular vesicles as a conduit for potential unintended biological effects as a result of treatment with targeted agents. We observed cellular responses and examined vesiculation profiles in several cancer cell lines with varying EGFR mutation status and expression in response to second-generation EKI dacomitinib. We speculate that quantification of EVs reflects response to drug treatment, as cell lines sensitive to dacomitinib increase vesiculation while cells that are resistant do not. Further, we observed that EV-associated DNA content was relative to drug concentration in sensitive cells. Endothelial cells exhibited different responses when cultured in the presence of EVs derived from dacomitinib-treated cells and untreated cells, suggesting that EKI treatment modifies the angiogenic potential of released EVs. We postulate that, due to their physical characteristics and associated cellular responses at corresponding drug concentrations, EVs derived from EKI treatment belong to an emerging subtype of apoptotic exosome-like vesicles</description><creator>Pan, Catherine</creator><contributor>Janusz Rak (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Targeted agents as modifiers of extracellular vesicle-mediated cellular communication pathways in cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qp18b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj4309023</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kg06t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the collapse of multilateral trade talks in the 2000s, Preferential Trade Agreements (PTAs) have become the dominant institution through which countries negotiate and commit to new trade rules. As opposed to the multilateral World Trade Organization (WTO), PTAs create rules between a small number of members. While formally permitted under multilateral rules, such agreements thereby represent a transformation in the governance of the global trade regime to one in which new market access is negotiated on a discriminatory basis. Yet for the most part, PTAs also reflect enduring post-war liberal economic principles. This thesis explores this combination of continuity and change in the context of the political economy of trade. What effect has the proliferation of new trade deals had on the politics of trade? Why have the prevailing norms of trade cooperation remained relatively stable, despite the proliferation of new governing institutions? The thesis shows that legal agreements like PTAs establish precedent. Negotiators vie to set this precedent, and subsequently to leverage it in future negotiations. The argument is based on the domestic politics of trade negotiations. Gaining domestic approval of new treaty text is challenging. Once set however, new trade rules become a reference point for future deals, establishing path-dependencies that disproportionately benefit first-movers. These distributional implications have increased the opportunities for the politics of precedent-setting to play out domestically and internationally.The thesis presents three empirical studies that develop and test this argument. The first study explores how trade rules emerge and evolve. I argue that by institutionalizing hard-won negotiating positions with less-important partners, negotiators improve the odds of replicating preferred terms in later, more significant deals. Statistical analysis on the timing and sequencing of trade agreements supports the argument. The second study looks beyond the establishment of new agreements, asking when and why they are renegotiated. New data on trade treaty renegotiations show that revisions to past deals are surprisingly common, with most amendments resulting in deeper commitments. In contrast to the standard view, renegotiations are not a breakdown in cooperation. They are a renewal of vows. The third study turns to the international politics created by preferentialism in the trade regime. Exclusion from preferential deals creates incentives for countries to join new agreements or to establish their own competing deal. Analysis of countries’ voting behavior in the United Nations shows these dynamics create political fallout, with the potential to either sweeten or sour political ties. Worryingly, ostensibly cooperative agreements may sometimes lead toless global cooperation by reinforcing existing divisions. The importance of precedent in international negotiations offers a new perspective on the rules of the global economy. International economic institutions are a forum where negotiators vie to set favored standards by establishing and exploiting influential legal language</description><description>Depuis l’échec des négociations commerciales multilatérales dans les années 2000, les accords commerciaux préférentiels (ACP) sont devenus l’institution dominante par laquelle les pays négocient de nouvelles règles commerciales. Contrairement à l’Organisation mondiale de commerce (OMC), les ACP créent des règles entre un plus petit nombre de membres. Alors formellement autorisés dans le cadre de l’OMC, de tels accords représentent donc une transformation de la gouvernance du régime commercial mondial en un système dans lequel le nouvel accès aux marchés est négocié de manière discriminatoire. Cependant, les ACP reflètent également les durables principes économiques libéraux de l’après-guerre. Cette thèse explore cette juxtaposition de continuité et de changement dans le contexte de l’économie politique du commerce. Quel effet l’augmentation d’ACPs a-t-elle eu sur la politique des échanges commerciaux? Pourquoi les normes en matière de coopération commerciale sont-elles restées relativement stables malgré l’augmentation de nouvelles institutions gouvernementales? Cette thèse montre que les accords juridiques tels que les PTA créent un précédent. Les négociateurs rivalisent pour créer ce précédent et ensuite pour en tirer parti dans les négociations suivantes. L’argument se base sur la politique domestique des négociations commerciales. Obtenir l’approbation nationale du nouveau texte de traité est difficile. Une fois définies, toutefois, les nouvelles règles commerciales deviennent un point de référence pour les futures transactions, en établissant des dépendances du chemin qui profitent de manière disproportionnée aux pionniers. Cette répartition inégales des revenus motive les conflits politiques sur la création de précédents, au niveau national et international.La thèse présente trois études empiriques qui développent et testent cet argument. Lapremière explore l’émergence et l’évolution des règles d’échanges commerciaux. En institutionnalisant les positions de négociation durement gagnées avec des partenaires moins importants, les négociateurs peuvent plus facilement reproduire des clauses preferees lors de négociations ultérieures plus importantes. L’argument est validé par l’analyse statistique sur l’enchaînement des accords commerciaux. La deuxième étude va au-delà de l’établissement de nouveaux accords pour demander quand et pourquoi sont-ils renégociés. De nouvelles données sur les renégociations des accords commerciaux montrent que les pays-membres révisent leurs accords étonnamment fréquemment. En outre, la plupart des changements résultent en des engagements plus profonds. Contrairement à la perspective habituelle, les renégociations n’aboutissent pas à une rupture de la coopération, mais à un réengagement. La troisième étude s’intéresse à la politique internationale créée par la caractère préférentielle du régime commercial. L’exclusion des accords préférentiels incite les pays à adhérer à de nouveaux accords ou à établir leur propre accord concurrent. Mais l’analyse du comportement électoral des pays au sein des Nations Unies montre que l’exclusion des accords a également un effet politique. En effet, des accords de coopération peuvent parfois renforcer les divisions existantes.L’importance des précédents dans les négociations internationales offre une nouvelle perspective sur les règles de l’économie mondiale. Les institutions économiques internationales constituent un forum où les négociateurs se disputent pour définir des normes en établissant et en exploitant le langage juridique</description><creator>Castle, Matthew</creator><contributor>Krzysztof Pelc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Political Science</subject><title>The political economy of preferential market integration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483p55h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kg06t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d841b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La sclérose en plaques est une maladie inflammatoire et démyélinisante qui affecte chroniquement le système nerveux central. Son étiologie est multifactorielle et mal comprise; les thérapies courantes misent sur la suppression de l’activité immunitaire reconnue comme source de la pathologie. Des débris de myéline toxiques s’accumulent dans les lésions induites par la maladie lors des blessures au système nerveux central. Les phagocytes immunitaires innés, les macrophages périphériques dérivés de monocytes et les microgliocytes résidentes sont centraux aux processus de nettoyage des débris et de promotion de la réparation des tissus. La fonction des macrophages et des microgliocytes est dirigée par de leur métabolisme intracellulaire. Dans cette étude, nous nous concentrons sur la glycolyse et la phosphorylation oxydative, les deux principales voies bioénergétiques utilisées par les cellules mammifères. Les cellules “M1”/pro-inflammatoires/neurotoxiques augmentent la glycolyse et diminuent la phosphorylation oxydative, tandis que les cellules “M2”/anti-inflammatoires/neuroprotectrices augmentent la phosphorylation oxydative et diminuent la glycolyse. Ces changements au métabolisme bioénergétique sont impératives aux bon fonctionnement des cellules immunitaires innées. La contribution du métabolisme bioénergétique au fonctionnement des macrophages et des microgliocytes phagocytaires demeure inconnue. Ici, nous démontrons que la phagocytose de la myéline requiert la phosphorylation oxydative et qu’une capacité de métabolisme bioénergétique augmentée est associée avec une plus grande capacité de phagocytose. Pour l’Objectif 1, nous identifions des tendances dans le métabolome humain primaire au niveau des macrophages qui suggèrent que ces cellules assument un phénotype métabolique de type “M2” (augmentation de la phosphorylation oxydative) lors d’un traitement de myéline. Pour l’Objectif 2, nous démontrons que les microgliocytes humaines primaires ont des réservoirs de glycolyse et de phosphorylation oxydative significativement plus élevés que les macrophages. Cela est reflété dans leur capacité significativement plus élevée de phagocytose de la myéline et de résistance accrue aux inhibiteurs pharmacologiques du métabolisme bioénergétique. Globalement, nos résultats démontrent comment le métabolisme oxydatif et/ou les voies associées peuvent régir l’engloutissement du substrat par les cellules immunitaires innées, un domaine d’étude qui reste sous-exploré. Notre étude propose des nouvelles connaissances sur les macrophages et la fonction microgliale, des nouvelles cibles thérapeutiques et des nouvelles voies pour la recherche sur la sclérose en plaques</description><description>Multiple sclerosis is an inflammatory, demyelinating disease that chronically affects the central nervous system. Its aetiology is multifactorial and not well-understood; current therapies focus on quelling immune activity that is recognized as perpetrators of disease pathology. Toxic myelin debris build up in multiple sclerosis lesions upon injury of the central nervous system. Innate immune phagocytes, peripheral monocyte-derived macrophages and resident microglia, are central to clearing debris and promoting tissue repair. Macrophage and microglial function are driven by the wiring of their intracellular metabolism. In this study, we focus on glycolysis and oxidative phosphorylation, the two main bioenergetic pathways used by mammalian cells. “M1”/pro-inflammatory/neurotoxic cells adopt increased glycolysis and decreased oxidative phosphorylation whereas “M2”/anti-inflammatory/neuroprotective cells adopt increased oxidative phosphorylation and decreased glycolysis. These changes in bioenergetic metabolism are imperative for proper innate immune cell function. The contributions of bioenergetic metabolism to macrophage and microglial phagocytic functions are currently unclear. Here, we show that myelin phagocytosis requires oxidative phosphorylation and that increased capacity for bioenergetic metabolism is associated with increased capacity for phagocytosis. In Aim 1, we find trends in the primary human macrophage metabolome that suggest they assume a “M2”-like (pro-oxidative phosphorylation) metabolic phenotype upon myelin treatment. In Aim 2, we show that primary human microglia have significantly higher reservoirs for glycolysis and oxidative phosphorylation than macrophages – reflected in their significantly higher capacity for myelin phagocytosis and increased resistance to pharmacological inhibitors of bioenergetic metabolism. Altogether, our results demonstrate how oxidative metabolism and/or associated pathways may govern substrate engulfment by innate immune cells, an area of study that remains underexplored. Our investigation proposes new insights into macrophage and microglial function, new therapeutic targets for disease, and new avenues for multiple sclerosis research</description><creator>Lin, Yun Hsuan</creator><contributor>Jack P Antel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Macrophage and microglial capacity for bioenergetic metabolism correlates with myelin phagocytosis: implications for multiple sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67ws083.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d841b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kg073</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les algorithmes de plongement lexical (word embedding) produisent des représentations de mots très fiables utilisées par les modèles de réseau neuronal dans une multitude de tâches de traitement automatique du langage naturel (TALN) (Goldberg, 2016). En tant que tel, il est impératif que les praticiens en TALN comprennent comment leurs représentations de mots sont produites et pourquoi elles ont un tel impact.Le présent travail de recherche présente le cadre Simple Embedder, généralisant les algorithmes de pointe de plongement lexical (y compris Word2vec et GloVe) dans le cadre de modèles généralisés de bas rang (Udell et al., 2016). Nous en déduisons que ces deux algorithmes tentent de produire des produits scalaires des (vecteur d’) embeddings qui approchent des statistiques d’information mutuelle ponctuelle (PMI) dans le corpus. Une fois posés dans le cadre Simple Embedder, la comparaison de ces modèles révèle que ces algorithmes de plongement ressemblent tous à une simple estimation du maximum de vraisemblance (MLE) de la PMI paramétrée par le produit scalaire (des embeddings). Cette estimation engendre notre nouveau modèle de plongement lexical, Hilbert-MLE, comme étant représentant canonique du cadre Simple Embedder.Nous comparons empiriquement ces algorithmes avec des évaluations sur 17 ense bles de données différents. Hilbert-MLE observe systématiquement la deuxième meilleure performance pour chaque évaluation extrinsèque (classification des nouvelles, analyse des sentiments, étiquetage morpho-syntaxique et étiquetage supersense), tandis que le meilleur modèle dépend de la tâche. De plus, Hilbert-MLE observe systématiquement la plus faible variance dans les résultats quant à l’initialisation aléatoire des poids dans les rèseaux LSTM bidirectionnels. Nos résultats empiriques démontrent que Hilbert-MLE est un algorithme de plongement lexical très cohérent pouvant être intégré de manière fiable dans les systèmes existants de TALN pour obtenir des résultats de haute qualité</description><description>Word embedding algorithms produce very reliable feature representations of words that are used by neural network models across a constantly growing multitude of NLP tasks (Goldberg, 2016). As such, it is imperative for NLP practitioners to understand how their word representations are produced, and why they are so impactful.The present work presents the Simple Embedder framework, generalizing the state-of-the-art existing word embedding algorithms (including Word2vec (SGNS) and GloVe) under the umbrella of generalized low rank models (Udell et al., 2016). We derive that both of these algorithms attempt to produce embedding inner products that approximate pointwise mutual information (PMI) statistics in the corpus. Once cast as Simple Embedders, comparison of these models reveals that these successful embedders all resemble a straightforward maximum likelihood estimate (MLE) of the PMI parametrized by the inner product (between embeddings). This MLE induces our proposed novel word embedding model, Hilbert-MLE, as the canonical representative of the Simple Embedder framework.We empirically compare these algorithms with evaluations on 17 different datasets. Hilbert-MLE consistently observes second-best performance on every extrinsic evaluation (news classification, sentiment analysis, POS-tagging, and supersense tagging), while the first-best model depends varying on the task. Moreover, Hilbert-MLE consistently observes the least variance in results with respect to the random initialization of the weights in bidirectional LSTMs. Our empirical results demonstrate that Hilbert-MLE is a very consistent word embedding algorithm that can be reliably integrated into existing NLP systems to obtain high-quality results</description><creator>Kenyon-Dean, Kian</creator><contributor>Jackie Cheung (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Doina Precup (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Word embedding algorithms as generalized low rank models and their canonical form</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rd22p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kg073</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78th46s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mes recherches portent sur la pédagogie des arts plastiques et du dessin technique au XIXème siècle, plus précisément sur les théories de l’habitude et leurs formations (également appelé "mémoire procédurale" et "mémoire musculaire"). Ce projet soutient la thèse selon laquelle l’opposition à l’habitude est un concept rétrospectif qui empêcherait les universitaires contemporains de comprendre son importance dans le cadre de la pédagogie artistique à l'époque de la modernité. J’affirme que l’habitude est l'un des concepts les plus fondamental de la pensée philosophique, essentiel dans l’enseignement du dessin tel que nous le connaissions autrefois. Historiquement, l’habitude est considérée comme une menace potentielle dans la formation de la pensée libre et la créativité; depuis des siècles, de nombreux critiques, historiens, et philosophes, tel que Kant, ont décrit l’habitude comme l'anathème de la production artistique et de l’innovation industrielle. Par conséquent, beaucoup de textes historiques et théoriques en histoire de l’art ont soutenu que les artistes du XIXème siècle esquivaient l’enseignement officiel dans le but de saper le caractère déterministe des habitudes et la routine promue par l’Académie. Cette thèse s'appuie sur la recherche fondamentale et originale pour pousser l’histoire de l’art dans une direction pluridisciplinaire. Motivé par les questions non résolues sur le rôle joué par les philosophies de l’esprit dans le développement des pratiques artistiques du XIXème siècle, ce projet examine comment la science et la psychologie ont construit les moyens d’instruire l’art</description><description>This dissertation examines nineteenth-century French drawing pedagogy’s relationship to concepts of habit and habit formation (also known as procedural and muscular memory). In the nineteenth century, habit was understood as any set of behaviors acquired through repetition and performed unconsciously. Habit was the acquisition of reflexes and thought patterns; it was the incorporation into one’s own mind and body certain modes of comportment and movement that became automatic and “second nature” over time. Within historical philosophical, scientific, and artistic discourses, habit often was interpreted negatively and perceived as a threat to autonomy and as anathema to creativity. As a result, many art historical studies have argued that nineteenth-century artists, particularly those linked to the avant-garde, eluded artistic training to undermine the well-worn habits or routines advocated by the Academy. Contrary to this consensus, my doctoral thesis shows how fundamental habit was to the philosophical tensions at play in drawing education itself and how its impact was much greater than previously thought. I argue that the opposition to habit is a retrospective art historical conceit that has prevented many scholars from understanding its importance to nineteenth-century art pedagogy. Through archivally-rooted chapters focused on four influential pedagogues—the philosopher Félix Ravaisson, the academician Eugène Guillaume, the instructor Horace Lecoq de Boisbaudran, and the draftsman Félix Régamey—this thesis analyzes “habitual” drawing practices to shed new light on the education of expert eyes, the material practices of schematization, and the global impact of French artistic training</description><creator>Cooperstein, Shana</creator><contributor>Mary Hunter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Art History and Communications Studies</subject><title>Reading between the lines: drawing habits in nineteenth-century France</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n744r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78th46s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rj805</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:18:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des figures importantes du multiculturalisme libéral, Will Kymlicka et Alan Patten, soutiennent que les politiques multiculturelles (PMCs) correspondent aux principes d’une société multiculturelle idéale et se concentrent sur une gamme étroite de minorités culturelles. Selon moi, les PMCs devraient plutôt être conçues comme la réponse à des circonstances non-idéales. Je défends aussi une conception plus étendue du multiculturalisme, qui s’intéresse à tous les groupes minoritisés.Ma thèse critique les approches qui cherchent à déterminer les droits que les minorités culturelles auraient dans un monde juste. Cette méthode crée des distorsions entre la théorie et la pratique du multiculturalisme. Les multiculturalistes libéraux pensent que les minorités culturelles devraient être protégées, car elles sont vulnérables, même en circonstances idéales. Or, la plupart des groupes qui demandent des PMCs n’existeraient pas dans ces circonstances. De plus, quand on observe le multiculturalisme en théorie non-idéale, on constate qu’être une culture n’est pas une condition nécessaire et suffisante pour faire partie du sujet du multiculturalisme. Le multiculturalisme se concentre plutôt sur des groupes qui ont été minoritisés dans des circonstances non-idéales. Après avoir montré que les multiculturalistes ne démontrent pas que les cultures constituent un cas unique pour les théories de la justice, j’argue qu’on devrait s’intéresser à tous les groupes minoritisés.Selon moi, les membres de groupes minoritisés ont droit à des traitements différenciés par le groupe à cause de leur vulnérabilité. Je propose une analyse originale de la vulnérabilité en tant que disposition extrinsèque : la vulnérabilité n’advient que lorsqu’un groupe ou un individu fait face à des circonstances qui le disposent à subir un dommage. Par exemple, les personnes racisées sont vulnérables, non pas à cause de leurs propriétés intrinsèques, mais bien parce qu’elles font face à des circonstances qui augmentent le risque d’injustice. La minoritisation d’un groupe ethnique génère aussi une vulnérabilité extrinsèque. Ma thèse est que c’est cette vulnérabilité, et non pas l’importance de la culture, qui génère l’obligation d’accorder des droits différenciés par le groupe. Ainsi, c’est l’obligation de répondre aux situations de vulnérabilité qui fournit les fondements normatifs d’une théorie multiculturelle non-idéale</description><description>Prominent liberal multiculturalists, Will Kymlicka and Alan Patten, argue that multicultural policies (MCPs) instantiate the principles of an ideal multicultural society and concentrate on a narrow range of cultural minorities. On my view, MCPs should rather be conceived as responses to non-ideal circumstances of group and group-based vulnerability. I also defend a broader account of multiculturalism that covers all minoritized groups. My negative thesis is that seeking to determine the rights that cultural minorities would have in a just world creates distortions between the theory and the practice of multiculturalism. Mainstream multiculturalists argue that cultural minorities should be protected because they would be vulnerable, even in ideal circumstances. However, most of the groups that actually claim MCPs would not exist in these circumstances. Moreover, when we look at multiculturalism in non-ideal theory, we realize that culture is not necessary and sufficient to be part of the subject of multiculturalism. Rather, multicultural politics are concerned with groups that acquired a lower status in non-ideal circumstances. These groups were minoritized. After showing that multiculturalists fail to show that cultures constitute a unique case for theories of justice, I argue that we should be concerned with all minoritized groups. My positive thesis is that members of minoritized groups are entitled to group-differentiated treatment because of their vulnerability. To support that claim, I articulate a new analysis of vulnerability as an extrinsic disposition: vulnerability arises only when a group or individual faces circumstances that dispose it to be damaged. For example, racialized individuals are vulnerable, not because they have special essential or intrinsic properties, but because they face adverse circumstances like systemic injustice that increase their likelihood of suffering group-based injustices. Similarly, the minoritization of an ethnic group gives rise to an extrinsic vulnerability. My claim is that it is group and group-based vulnerability, not the value of culture or its relationship with the principles of liberal justice, that generate obligations to extend group-differentiated treatment to individuals. In sum, our obligations to respond to situations of vulnerability provide the normative foundations for a non-ideal theory of multiculturalism</description><creator>Armstrong, Frédérick</creator><contributor>Daniel Weinstock (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Natalie Stoljar (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Jacob Levy (Supervisor3)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>Minoritization and vulnerability: New foundations for a non-ideal theory of multiculturalism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kc71r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rj805</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v2836</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’apprentissage automatique (AA) est devenu rapidement une expertise recherchée, ceci dans de nombreux domaines. La demande en compétence augmente plus vite que l’offre. Cela se reflète dans l'état actuel de la recherche sur l'enseignement de l’AA où il y les travaux peu nombreux restent principalement focalisés sur les étudiants en informatique. Pour développer ce domaine de recherche, cette thèse se concentre sur la façon d'enseigner l’AA aux adultes n’ayant une pas de formation technique. Nous avons mené dix entretiens avec des professeurs d'université pour recueillir leur connaissance du contenu pédagogique (CCP) - connaissance des instructeurs sur la façon d'enseigner un sujet particulier. Dans l'analyse qualitative, nous avons en particulier identifié les différents aspects de la CCP, commes les préconceptions, les barrières à la compréhension des étudiants et les tactiques pédagogiques utilisées par les enseignants. Cela inclut respectivement la surestimation l'AA, les difficultés mathématiques et la la sélection stratégique des cas d’étude. De cette analyse qualitative s’est dégagée une série d’objectifs pédagogiques pour lesquels nous avons établi une classification suivant la taxonomie Structure of Observed Learning Outcomes (SOLO). Les objectifs faciles à enseigner, comme par exemple le traçage des algorithmes, correspondent aux bas niveaux de notre classification SOLO. Inversement, les objectifs considérés comme difficiles à enseigner sont associés aux niveaux élevés. Cela indique que les algorithmes eux-mêmes ne sont pas la partie difficile de l’apprentissage de la AA. Les résultats de notre CCP ont ensuite été organisés selon cette taxonomie pour présenter une liste des obstacles rencontrés par les étudiants et les stratégies d’enseignement associées en relation avec chaque étape de SOLO. Cette organisation fournit un guide utile pour faire progresser les étudiants selon la taxonomie SOLO en anticipant mieux leurs difficultés tout en proposant des tactiques pédagogiques pertinentes. Nous concluons par des considérations pratiques basées sur des questions critiques pour la conception de cours pour les éducateurs d’aujourd’hui ainsi que plusieurs orientations prometteuses pour l’innovation dans l’enseignement de l’AA couvrant les outils de visualisation et la programmation pour les utilisateurs finaux</description><description>Machine learning (ML) has rapidly become a sought after skill across numerous domains and sectors. Indeed, the need for those who understand ML is rising faster than can be met. This is reflected in the current state of ML education research, where there is little empirical work, and is mostly on courseware and about computer science students. To expand this research area, this thesis focuses on how to teach ML, specifically to adults with a non-technical background.  We conducted ten interviews with university instructors to elicit pedagogical content knowledge (PCK) --  an instructor's knowledge on how to teach a particular topic. In the qualitative analysis, we identified aspects of PCK, such as student preconceptions, student barriers, and pedagogical tactics adopted by instructors. These included students overestimating the abilities of ML, student difficulty with math, and instructors strategically choosing instructional datasets. Furthermore, specific learning goals emerged in our analysis. We classified them into the Structure of Observed Learning Outcomes (SOLO) learning taxonomy, wherein a pattern emerged. Learning goals described as easy to teach, such as tracing algorithms, were consistent with lower levels of the SOLO Taxonomy. Learning goals described as hard to teach, such as evaluating and tuning models, were consistent with higher levels of the SOLO taxonomy. This indicates that the algorithms themselves are not the difficult part about learning ML. Our PCK findings were then organized into this taxonomy to present a list of student barriers and teaching strategies related to each SOLO stage. This organization provides a useful guide for supporting student development through better anticipating student difficulty and providing pertinent pedagogical tactics. We conclude with practical uses for educators today through critical course design questions and several promising directions for innovation in teaching ML, including visualization tools and end-user programming</description><creator>Sulmont, Elisabeth</creator><contributor>Elizabeth Patitsas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Machine learning for end-users: exploring learning goals and pedagogical content knowledge</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702qb71x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v2836</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999b97j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse s’intéresse à l’évolution de l’attitude de la Chine à l’égard de l’arbitrage international. Contrairement à l’approche conventionnelle axée sur la règle qui étudie l’attitude de la Chine à travers son adhérence à l’arbitrage international ou encore sa conformité aux normes et principes internationaux, cette thèse adopte une perspective transcivilisationnelle du processus de prise de décision afin d’esquisser le portrait des interactions de la Chine avec les cours et les tribunaux internationaux, ce qu’elle ressent, pense, dit et comment elle se conduit – dans le passé, le présent et le futur. Compte tenu de la période d’intervention, de l’impérialisme des puissances occidentales et des différences culturelles sino-occidentales, la Chine a longtemps considéré l’arbitrage international comme un outil de pouvoir politique occidental, et ainsi adopté une position ambivalente par rapport aux cours et tribunaux internationaux, tels que la Cour permanente d’arbitrage, la Cour permanente de justice international et Cour internationale de justice. La réforme et l’ouverture initiées en 1978 ont marqué l’élan du changement d’attitude de la Chine. Les pratiques, observations et leçons en matière d’arbitrage et d’arbitrage relatif aux traités d’investissement de l’OMC tirées par la Chine au cours de cette dernière décennie témoignent de son accoutumance au régime juridique international et des bénéfices que lui offre l’arbitrage international. Par un pouvoir croissant et une capacité juridique accrue, une nouvelle tendance semble émerger dans l’attitude future de la Chine à l’égard de l’arbitrage international. La Chine était en effet auparavant ‘invitée’ à participer à l’arbitrage international. Dans le futur, il appert que la Chine s’intéressera davantage à la réinterprétation, voire à la modification des règles d’arbitrage international, qui seront alors marquées par l’emprunte singulière de la Chine dans leur caractéristique, leur fonction et leur vision. S’appuyant sur une perspective culturelle et sociojuridique, cette thèse tente de déconstruire, reproduire et repenser l’image de la Chine en arbitrage international. En plus des règles internationales ‘noires ou blanches’, cette étude explore également comment la culture traditionnelle chinoise, la culture occidentale et leurs interactions façonnent la Chine moderne et l’approche du régime de l’arbitrage international</description><description>This thesis observes the evolution of China’s attitude towards international adjudication. Unlike the conventional rule-oriented approach which studies Chinese attitudes merely through China’s acceptance of international adjudication or its compliance with international rules and principles, this thesis—applying a transcivilizational decision-making process perspective—profiles how the Chinese feel, think, say and behave in past, present and future contexts when they interact with international courts and tribunals. Given the long period of intervention and imperialism by Western powers and the significance of Sino-Western cultural differences, China has traditionally characterized international adjudication as a Western-made tool for power politics and has therefore adopted an ambivalent position on international courts or tribunals such as the PCA, PCIJ, and ICJ. The “reform and opening-up” that started in 1978 provided China with momentum to change its attitude towards international adjudication. Recent decades have demonstrated how China, through observing, learning and practicing in WTO adjudication and investment arbitration, has accustomed itself to the international legal regime and has come to realize the value of international adjudication. With its growing power and improved legal capacity, a new tendency seems to be emerging in China’s future attitude towards international adjudication. Previously, China was “asked” to participate in international adjudication and to abide by many Western-dominated norms. However, this dissertation predicts that, in the future, China will show more interest in reinterpreting, or even remaking, rules of international adjudication with a salient Chinese character, a Chinese feature and a Chinese vision. While presenting the evolution of China’s attitude, this thesis also tries to deconstruct, reproduce and rethink the image of China in international adjudication with a legal-sociological perspective: it explores how traditional Chinese culture, Western culture and their interactions have shaped modern China and its approach to the international adjudicatory regime</description><creator>Tao, Nanying</creator><contributor>Andrea Bjorklund (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Law</subject><title>China's attitude towards international adjudication: A transcivilizational process perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19fb25p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999b97j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b5491</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alcohol consumption is an activity enjoyed responsibly by most. However, forthose struggling with addiction, alcohol may quickly become a catalyst for behaviourdefined by law as criminal. In fact, the majority of criminal offenders in Canada suffer tosome degree from an alcohol use disorder. Given the prevalence of addiction amongcriminal offenders, the Canadian criminal justice systems and its judges should beprepared to best deal with addicted offenders. This thesis will outline some of the mostcommon responses and themes of discussion among judges who are faced with anoffender suffering from an alcohol use disorder. Further, key terms relating to alcohol usedisorders, crime and sentencing will be defined. The original research and analysis of thisthesis will ultimately enable the first classification of its kind of judicial discourse onalcohol use disorders by theme of discussion, thus enabling an analysis of the impact thatthese various strains of discussion may have on the outcome of the accused or offender.The themes identified include incapacitation, recognition of rehabilitative efforts,acknowledgment of state responsibility, alternative treatment, and discussion of reform.Beyond the academic specificities of this study, this thesis has attempted to articulate thepossibility that the criminal may not always be solely responsible for a crime and thatsociety may have a contributory role in labelling the individual as criminal. Furthermore,the ‘criminal’ may simply be an addict</description><description>La consommation d'alcool est une activité appréciée d’une manière responsablepar la plupart des gens. Cependant, l'alcool peut rapidement devenir un catalyseur pourles comportements qui sont qualifiés comme étant criminels par la loi. En fait, la majoritédes délinquants au Canada souffrent dans une certaine mesure d'un trouble lié à l'alcool.Étant donné la prévalence de cette dépendance dans le système, comment le système dejustice pénale canadien et ses juges traitent-ils le délinquant alcoolique? Quels sont lesréponses et les thèmes de discussion les plus courants parmi les juges confrontés à undélinquant souffrant d'un trouble de l'alcoolisme? Cette thèse définira les termes clésrelatifs aux troubles de la consommation d'alcool, à la criminalité et à la détermination dela peine. La recherche et l’analyse originale de cette thèse permettront au final lapremière classification du discours judiciaire sur les troubles de la consommationd’alcool par thème de discussion, permettant ainsi d’analyser l’impact de ces différentestensions de discussion sur la détermination de la peine de l’accusé ou du délinquant.Les thèmes identifiés comprennent l’incapacité, la reconnaissance des efforts deréadaptation, la reconnaissance de la responsabilité de l’État, le traitement alternatif et ladiscussion sur la réforme. Au-delà des spécificités académiques de cette étude, cette thèsea tenté d'expliquer la possibilité que le criminel ne soit pas toujours seul responsable d'uncrime et que la société puisse jouer un rôle contributif en qualifiant l'individu de criminel.En outre, le «criminel» peut simplement être un toxicomane</description><creator>McClure, Ellen</creator><contributor>Marie Manikis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Alcohol use disorders and crime: identifying and analysing the role of judicial discourse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x3501.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b5491</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bh022</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Heterotrimeric G proteins, comprised of α, β, and γ subunits, are responsible for relaying signals from G protein-coupled receptors (GPCR) to downstream effectors. In recent years, the obligate Gβγ dimers have been found at multiple subcellular sites where they serve both canonical and novel non-canonical roles. Yet, the lack of characterization on the five Gβ and twelve Gγ isoforms found in mammals has led to the misleading view of the different Gβγ complexes as a single entity. Of particular importance to this project, the invertebrate C. elegans, unlike mammals, possesses only two Gβ homologues. Here, we aimed to characterize mammalian Gβ1 and Gβ4 from both functional and evolutionary perspectives by means of biosensor-based signalling assays using the two C. elegans Gβ homologues, GPB1 and GPB2.With both siRNA-induced knockdown and CRISPR-directed knockout lines, we observed that downstream of carbachol-stimulated endogenous M3-AChRs in HEK 293 cells, the loss of Gβ1 led to potentiation of calcium release, while the loss of Gβ4 led to a decrease in calcium release and an increase in nuclear ERK activation. Interestingly, concurrent expression of GPB1 with Gβ4 knockdown led to the rescue of calcium release, suggesting that the core function in M3-AChR- mediated calcium signalling is partially conserved in the C. elegans Gβ homologue GPB1. The effect of knockdown of Gβ1 could not be rescued by GPB1 expression suggesting that this function was not conserved. GPB2 was not able to rescue calcium signalling effects of either Gβ1 or Gβ4. Moreover, we detected Rho activation induced by Gαq and Gα12/13 downstream of both M3-AChRs and AT1Rs and found that Gβ1 might serve as a negative regulator for these events. We also showed that the loss of Gβ1 and Gβ4 had no effect on M3-AChR-mediated DAG production and PKC activation, β2AR-mediated adenylyl cyclase activation, and β-arrestin recruitment downstream of AT1Rs. Lastly, we used microscopy to characterize the morphology and proliferation rate of the CRISPR-directed Gβ knockout cell lines showing that the loss of Gβ1 could result in a reduced ability to proliferate</description><description>Les protéines G hétérotrimériques, composées des sous-unités α, β, et γ, sont responsables de la transmission des signaux des récepteurs couplés aux protéines G (RCPG) aux effecteurs en aval. Ces dernières années, les dimères obligatoires Gβγ ont été découverts sur plusieurs sites subcellulaires où ils remplissent des rôles canoniques et non canoniques. Cependant, le manque de caractérisation des isoformes de 5 Gβ et de 12 Gγ trouvés chez les mammifères a conduit à une vision trompeuse des différents complexes de Gβγ en tant qu’une entité unique. D'une importance particulière pour ce projet, l'invertébré C. elegans, contrairement aux mammifères, ne possède que deux homologues de Gβ. Ici, nous avons cherché à caractériser Gβ1 et Gβ4 chez le mammifère des points de vue fonctionnel et évolutif au moyen d’essais de signalisation basés sur des biosenseurs utilisant les deux homologues de C. elegans Gβ; GPB1 et GPB2. L’inhibition de l’expression de Gβ par siARN ou par CRISPR et la stimulation du récepteur M3-AChR endogène dans les cellules HEK 293 montre que la perte de Gβ1 entraînait une potentialisation de la libération de calcium, alors que la perte de Gβ4 conduits à une diminution de la libération de calcium et à une augmentation de l'activation de la voie ERK au niveau du noyau. Il est intéressant de noter que l’expression simultanée de GPB1 avec l’inhibition de Gβ4 a conduit à la récupération de la libération de calcium, ce qui suggère que la fonction essentielle de la signalisation calcique médiée par M3-AChR est partiellement conservée dans GPB1, l’homologue Gβ de C. elegans. L'effet de la suppression de Gβ1 n'a pas pu être sauvé par l'expression de GPB1 suggérant que cette fonction n'a pas été conservée. GPB2 n'a pas été en mesure de récupérer les effets de signalisation du calcium de Gβ1 ou de Gβ4. De plus, nous avons détecté l'activation de Rho par Gαq et Gα12/13 en aval de M3-AChR et de AT1R et nous avons constaté que Gβ1 pourrait servir comme régulateur négatif de ces événements. Nous avons également montré que la perte de Gβ1 et Gβ4 n'avait aucun effet sur la production de DAG médiée par M3-AChR et l'activation de la PKC, sur l'activation de l'adénylyl cyclase médiée par β2AR et sur le recrutement de β-arrestine en aval de AT1R. Enfin, nous avons utilisé la microscopie pour caractériser la morphologie et le taux de prolifération des lignées cellulaires Gβ knockout dirigées par CRISPR, montrant que la perte de Gβ1 pourrait entraîner une réduction de la capacité de prolifération</description><creator>Zheng, Xiao Ming</creator><contributor>Terence Hebert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</subject><title>Exploring the functional diversity of mammalian G-beta isoforms from an evolutionary perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k9548.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bh022</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bz63t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le CAN (Controller Area Network) est un bus de communication reliant les calculateurs entre eux et constitue une pièce maitresse dans les réseaux multiplexes utilisés dans l’industrie automobile et aéronautique. Durant la dernière décennie, de multiples études et recherches ont été menées autour de la sécurité du protocole CAN et de ses applications dans l’industrie automobile. Leurs conclusions sont sans appel car non seulement elles ont mis en lumière de nombreuses failles de sécurité, offrant le champ libre aux potentiels pirates informatiques, mais ont aussi confirmé l’urgence de solutions pour prévenir leur exploitation, compte tenu de la nature omniprésente de cette industrie dans notre société.Dans le domaine aéronautique, un nouveau protocole de communication construit au- dessus du CAN a été proposé : l’ARINC-825 (Aeronautics Radio, Incorporated 825 Specifi- cation), maintenant dans sa 4eme version. Nous pensons que la norme ARINC-825 pourrait souffrir des mêmes vulnérabilités que celles du CAN, et que la communauté des chercheurs en sécurité dans l’industrie aéronautique n’a pas réussi à résoudre à cause d’un manque d’accès aux données. Les stratégies existantes sont basées sur l’acquisition des données au niveau de la couche application, mais sont incapables de répliquer la communication au niveau de la couche liaison. La réplique au niveau de la couche liaison s’avère indispensable selon nous, car la recherche en attaques dans le domaine automobile a montré l’existence de faiblesses sécuritaires au niveau du CAN.Etant donné que l’ARINC-825 existe à un niveau supérieur d’abstraction, il est suscep- tible d’être tout aussi vulnérable au niveau de la couche liaison. Nous introduisons donc l’ARINC-825TBv2, une plateforme de simulation HIL (hardware-in-the-loop), intégrée au niveau de la couche liaison, et permettant aux chercheurs en sécurité aéronautique d’observer le trafic ARINC-encodé CAN en données réelles. Nous présentons Gaslighter, un nouveau modèle d’attaque prédictive, et intégré au banc de test afin de démontrer son efficacité. De plus, nous mettons en place un algorithme Z-score permettant de détecter les intrusions, et validé au travers de Gaslighter et de données CAN réelles. Enfin, nous démontrons que plus le nombre de messages envoyés dans la simulation augmente, plus la précision du Z-score chute en dessous d’une prédiction aléatoire</description><description>The Controller Area Network (CAN) is a crucial link-layer communication protocol that forms the core of networking in cars and in aviation. In the last decade, there has been increased research and scrutiny around the security of the CAN protocol and its deployment in the automotive industry. Researchers have not only postulated numerous attack vectors that give an attacker unprecedented capabilities, but have been able to validate and exploit them due to the ubiquitous nature of the automobile.In the aerospace industry, a new communications protocol built on top of CAN has been proposed: the Aeronautics Radio, Incorporated 825 Specification, now in its fourth draft. We believe that ARINC-825 could suffer the same vulnerabilities as CAN, and that the aerospace security research community has been unable to tackle this problem because of a lack of access to data. Existing data collection strategies revolve around application-level data, but are unable to replicate link-layer level communication. We find replication at the link-layer level to be critical as research into automotive attacks show that vulnerabilities exist at the CAN-level. As ARINC-825 exists at a higher level of abstraction, it too is potentially vulnerable at the link-layer.We introduce ARINC-825TBv2, a hardware-in-the-loop link-layer simulation platform that allows aerospace security researchers to observe ARINC-encoded CAN traffic with re- alistic data. We present a novel, predictive attacker Gaslighter that we integrate into the testbench, and demonstrate its effectiveness. Furthermore, we implement an intrusion de- tection algorithm Z-Score and validate it using Gaslighter and realistic CAN data. We show that as the number of messages in the simulation increases, the accuracy of Z-Score drops to below that of a random predictor</description><creator>Yu, Derek</creator><contributor>Brett Meyer (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>ARINC-825TBv2: a hardware-in-the-loop simulation platform for aerospace security research</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j5411.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bz63t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90f054v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La maladie d'Alzheimer (MA) est la forme la plus courante de démence, touchant environ 500 000 personnes au Canada et 24 millions de personnes à travers le monde. Comme il est connu que la MA est étroitement liée aux métabolismes des lipides et du cholestérol dans le cerveau et sa périphérie, (c.-à-d. des forts taux de lipoprotéines de basse densité (LDL) et des taux élevés de polymorphisme de l'ApoE4 sont tous deux des facteurs de risque bien établis) il est important de développer des modèles hautement alignés au profil humain de la MA, notamment en ce qui concerne les mécanismes du métabolisme lipidique. Notre laboratoire a conclu que lorsque la protéine de transfert des esters de cholestérol (CETP), une protéine qui stimule le transfert des esters de cholestérol des particules HDL aux particules VLDL et LDL, est exprimée dans les souris sous un promoteur humain, un profil humanisé des particules de lipoprotéine des rongeurs en survient. Étonnamment, lorsque les souris CETP furent croisés avec le modèle murin de l'Alzheimer 5xFAD exprimant de l'APP humain, une augmentation de 10 fois des niveaux des Aβ solubles (largement admis comme étant un marqueur pathognomonique primaire de la maladie) ainsi qu'une augmentation de 5 fois des niveaux de Aβ insolubles dans le cerveau de double mutants transgéniques ont été constatés. Dans le cadre de mon projet de maîtrise, j'ai trouvé que les astrocytes exprimant hApoE4 ont des gouttelettes lipidiques plus grosses et plus nombreuses que les astrocytes exprimant hApoE3. De plus, j'ai observé que la protéine de transfert des esters de cholestérol recombinante (rCETP) peut moduler les lipoprotéines astrocytaires dans des systèmes acellulaires selon l'activité de l'isoforme hApoE et de la CETP. Malgré cela, ni la CETP sécrétée par les astrocytes hApoE exprimant la CETP de façon stable, ni la rCETP exogène n’avaient d’effets dépendant de l’activité sur les taux de Aβ dans les systèmes de co-culture astrocyte-APP-SY5Y. Enfin, dans ma thèse de maîtrise, j'ai développé et caractérisé des virus CETP spécifiques du foie avec un pouvoir infectieux in vivo élevé, qui pourront être utilisés pour de futures analyses qui permettront de déterminer si la CETP périphérique confère des modifications de la production d'Aβ cérébrale et de caractériser les profils de cholestérol/lipoprotéines dans le système nerveux central et périphérique</description><description>Alzheimer’s disease (AD) is the most common form of dementia affecting about 500,000 people in Canada and 24 million people worldwide. As AD has been known to be heavily related to lipid &amp; cholesterol metabolism both in the brain and in the periphery, as evidenced by both high plasma LDL levels and increased occurrence of the apolipoprotein E ε4 polymorphism being well-established risk factors, it is important to develop models highly aligned to the human AD profile, particularly in terms of lipid metabolism-related processes. Our lab found that when cholesteryl ester transfer protein (CETP), a protein that shuttles cholesteryl esters from HDL particles to VLDL and LDL particles, is expressed in mice under the human promoter, a humanized profile of rodent lipoprotein particles occurs. Remarkably, when CETP mice were crossed with the Thy1-APP Tg Alzheimer mouse model expressing human APP, a 5-fold increase in soluble and insoluble Aβ levels in the brains of double transgenic mutants were seen. In my MSc research, I found that human apolipoprotein E4 (hApoE4)-expressing astrocytes have larger and more lipid droplets compared to human apolipoprotein E3 (hApoE3)-expressing astrocytes. Furthermore, I found that recombinant CETP (rCETP) can modulate astrocytic lipoproteins in cell-free systems in dependence of hApoE isoform and CETP activity. Despite this, neither secreted CETP from stably CETP-expressing hApoE astrocytes nor exogenous rCETP had activity-dependent effects on Aβ levels in astrocyte-SY5Y co-culture systems. Finally, in my master’s thesis, I developed and characterized liver-specific CETP viruses with high in vivo infectivity, which can be used for future analyses of whether peripheral CETP confers changes in brain Aβ production and cholesterol/lipoprotein profiles in both the CNS and periphery</description><creator>Efrem, Sasen</creator><contributor>Lisa Munter (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</subject><title>The cholesteryl transfer protein and apolipoprotein E in Alzheimer's disease models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kc721.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90f054v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nd294</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La communication vocale est un outil important dans la vie quotidienne. Elle est nécessaire dans certains métiers tels que l'enseignement, ou les arts de la scène. Les affections des cordes vocales telles que les cicatrices peuvent entraîner la dysphonie et nuire à la qualité de vie. En vue du développement de thérapies efficaces, il est important de pouvoir accéder aux informations détaillées sur la structure tissulaire du larynx humain et du larynx des modèles animaux utilisés pour les études de traitements potentiels. Cette thèse détaille les progrès réalisés dans le développement des modèles anatomiques du larynx humain et du larynx des animaux de laboratoire créées à partir d'images de microtomographie aux rayons X. Elle décrit ensuite l'application séquentielle de l'imagerie par résonance magnétique, de la microtomographie aux rayons X, de la microscopie non-linéaire, et de l'analyse d'images à une étude sur les lapins portant sur la cicatrization des cordes vocales suite à une intervention chirurgicale</description><description>Vocal communication is an important aspect of daily life for most people, and for many is required for their occupation. Conditions affecting the vocal folds, including scarring and other pathologies, may result in dysphonia and impair quality of life. When developing therapies, it is crucial to access detailed information about the tissue structure of the human larynx and of any animal models used to investigate treatments. This thesis details progress toward developing anatomical atlases and three-dimensional computer models of human and laboratory animal larynges from ex vivo microcomputed tomography images with image segmentation. Then, it describes the sequential application of magnetic resonance imaging, microcomputed tomography, and nonlinear microscopy with image analysis to a rabbit model study probing vocal fold scarring following surgery. This study proposes an imaging--analysis pipeline for animal studies involving vocal fold injury. Finally, it ties together information gleaned from these studies and outlines future directions motivated by their results</description><creator>Kolosova, Ksenia</creator><contributor>Paul Wiseman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Multimodal imaging and analysis of laryngeal structure and vocal fold injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365942q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nd294</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r7569</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contamination of scarce water resources with pollutants is a grave environmental problem of global concern. Many researchers are developing materials and technologies for contaminant abatement and efficient water treatment. Among various proposed nanomaterials, graphene and its derivatives have shown remarkable potential for efficient removal of contaminants from water. The versatile chemistry and high specific surface area of GO are key to successful removal of a wide array of classical and emerging contaminants from water; however, the aqueous stability of GO is an obstacle for its practical use in water treatment facilities, since recovering contaminant-loaded GO from the treated water is a major challenge. Self-assembly of GO into porous 3D macrostructures (3DMs) such as sponges has been proposed as a solution for the aqueous stability problem of particulate GO. Although GO sponges have been shown to remove various contaminants from water, their available surface area and mechanical properties are often few orders of magnitude lower than that of GO nanosheets. In the first part of this thesis, we critically reviewed the literature on GO 3DMs having environmental applications. Using the available data in the literature, we developed a critical link between the materials properties of GO 3DMs and their environmental performance. We identified key controlling parameters for tuning the environmental performance of GO sponges such as their specific surface area, bulk density, and elastic modulus. In the second part of the thesis, we explored various strategies for improving the performance of the GO sponges by tailoring their identified key properties, such as pore architecture, elastic modulus, bulk density and hydrophobicity.We used excess amounts of VC as reducing agent and soft-templating phase for synthesizing reduced GO (rGO) sponges with hierarchical porosity. The resulting sponges comprised bimodal pore architecture with highly interconnected pores. We also used cellulose nanocrystals (CNCs), naturally sourced cellulosic nanorods, in conjunction with rGO to obtain hybrid rGO-CNC sponges. CNCs significantly improved the mechanical properties of the sponges, and also contributed to increasing the available surface area of the hybrid sponges by inhibiting the restacking of rGO nanosheets during the self-assembly process. The nanohybrid sponges exhibited exceptional performance in removing traditional and emerging contaminants from water such as dyes, heavy metal ions, toxins, hormones, and pharmaceuticals. The improved mechanical properties enabled their regeneration and reuse with minimal destruction of their structure.In another study, we compared the performance of hierarchical rGO sponges synthesized with excess amounts of VC with uniformly-porous rGO sponges processed by non-excess amounts of VC in absorbing oils and organic solvents. Oils and organic solvents are removed by physical absorption in the pore spaces of the sponges. The low density and the highly porous hierarchical sponge showed remarkably higher absorption capacity than the uniformly porous sponge, despite their similar surface chemistry. Given that the mitigation of marine oil spills is highly desirable, we investigated the effect of simulated marine environment on the physical and mechanical properties of the hierarchical rGO sponges. We observed that exposure to marine conditions had no significant effect on the properties of the sponges.Finally, we studied sponges processed by hydrothermal heating of GO colloids for removal of oils and organic solvents. One parameter promoting the absorption of oils and organic solvents is the hydrophobicity of the sponges. We increased the hydrophobicity of the hydrothermal sponges by functionalizing them with L-tryptophan, a highly hydrophobic essential amino acid. L-tryptophan acted as a green reducing agent.The hydrophobic sponges showed remarkable removal capacity for oils and organic solvent</description><description>La contamination des ressources en eau par des polluants est une préoccupation environnementale majeure. Un grand nombre de chercheurs internationaux développent des technologies dans le but d’éliminer les contaminants et d’améliorer le traitement de l’eau. Parmi la grande variété de nanomatériaux, le graphène et ses dérivés ont montré un potentiel remarquable pour l’élimination efficace des contaminants de l’eau. Grâce à sa fine structure atomique 2D en nano-feuillets, les oxydes de graphène (OG) ont de très larges surfaces spécifiques. Les OG sont ornés de myriades d’oxygènes faisant partie de groupes fonctionnels tels que les époxydes, les carbonyles ou les hydroxyles. Les fonctions carboxyles des OG les rendent facilement dispersibles dans l’eau à un pH environnemental. La chimie versatile et la large surface spécifique des OG sont les clés qui peuvent permettre de retirer de l’eau un large éventail de contaminants, classiques et émergents. Cependant, la stabilité des OG dans l’eau est un obstacle pour son utilisation pratique au sein des installations de traitements des eaux.L’auto-assemblage des OG en macrostructures poreuses 3D (3DM) est une solution qui a été proposée pour contrecarrer le problème de mobilité des particules de OG dans l’eau. Les dispersions aqueuses de OG peuvent s’auto-assembler en ces matériaux poreux 3DM par chauffage hydrothermal, ou par l’intermédiaire de l’utilisation d’un agent chimique réducteur comme la vitamine C (VC). Bien que les éponges de OG aient montré de bons résultats en ce qui concerne l’élimination des polluants de l’eau, la surface disponible et leurs propriétés mécaniques sont significativement plus faibles que celles des feuillets de OG. L’empilage des feuillets de OG lors du procédé d’auto-assemblage et le manque de pores interconnectés sont les deux principales raisons expliquant cette diminution de la surface spécifique. De plus, les mauvaises propriétés mécaniques qui sont le résultat des interactions – entre les feuillets de OG auto-assemblés, empêchent la réutilisation de ces éponges.Dans une première partie de cette thèse, une revue critique de l’état de l’art est conduite sur les OG 3DM qui ont des applications environnementales. Grâce aux données accessibles dans la littérature, nous mettons en évidence les liens existants entre les propriétés des OG 3DM et leur performance environnementale. Nous identifions les paramètres clés permettant de contrôler les performances des éponges de OG comme leur surface spécifique, leur densité, et leur module élastique. Dans une seconde partie de la thèse, nous explorons différentes stratégies afin d’améliorer les performances des éponges de OG en adaptant ces paramètres clés tels que l’architecture des pores, le module élastique, la densité et la mouillabilité de la surface.Nous avons utilisé un excès de VC en tant qu’agent de réduction et une phase dite «soft-templating phase» pour la synthèse des éponges faites de OG réduits (rOG) et de pores hiérarchisés. Les éponges résultantes ont une architecture de type pore bimodaux, avec une forte inter-connectivité entre les pores. Nous avons également utilisé des nanocristaux de cellulose (NCC), issus de nano-bâtonnets de cellulose, en association avec des OG afin d’obtenir des éponges hybrides rOG-NCC. Les NCC améliorent de façon significative les propriétés mécaniques des éponges. De plus, ils contribuent à l’augmentation de la surface spécifique disponible des éponges hybrides en empêchant l’empilement des feuillets rOG pendant le procédé d’auto-assemblage. Les éponges hybrides montrent des performances exceptionnelles concernant le retrait des contaminants traditionnels et émergents de l’eau, comme les colorants, les métaux lourds, les toxines, les hormones et les médicaments. L’amélioration de leurs propriétés mécaniques rend possible leur régénération et leur réutilisation avec un minimum de dégradation au niveau de leur structure</description><creator>Yousefi, Nariman</creator><contributor>Nathalie Tufenkji (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Porous 3D macrostructures of graphene oxide for water treatment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547w779.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r7569</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vz16d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le glioblastome multiforme (GBM) est la forme la plus courante et la plus avancée d’astrocytome primaire cérébrale malin chez l’adulte. Le pronostic reste mauvais, malgré un traitement agressif par chirurgie, radiothérapie et chimiothérapie avec un agent alkylant, le Témozolomide (TMZ). La protéine de réparation de l'ADN, l'O6-méthylguanine-ADN-méthyltransférase (MGMT), interfère avec la cytotoxicité du TMZ. Des mutations faux-sens à haute fréquence du gène suppresseur de tumeur TP53 confèrent des activités mutantes oncogéniques (mut) p53, telles que la résistance à la chimioradiothérapie. Une étude précedente de notre laboratoire a démontré les effets cytotoxiques de PRIMA-1MET (APR-246), une petite molécule conçue pour restaurer la fonction wtp53 de mutp53, et a mis en évidence ses effets différentiels basés sur l'expression de MGMT indépendamment du statut de p53. Dans cette étude, nous avons analysé les mécanismes sous-jacents pour les effets indépendants de p53 et les différences basées sur MGMT en relation avec les effets inhibiteurs de prolifération induits par PRIMA-1MET. Nous avons émis l'hypothèse que PRIMA-1MET peut médire ses effets indépendants de p53 grâce à la modulation de l'équilibre redox et que cet équilibre est modifié en fonction des niveaux de MGMT.En utilisant des lignées cellulaires GBM isogéniques pour MGMT et avec un statut p53 différent, nous avons montré que PRIMA-1MET induit des espèces réactives de l'oxygène (ROS) et réduit l’expression de la thiorédoxine réductase 1 (TrxR1) indépendamment du statut de p53. Nous avons validé l'importance de l'induction ROS pour la cytotoxicité PRIMA-1MET en utilisant des agents pharmacologiques qui modulent les niveaux de ROS tels que ROS « scavenger », N-acétylcystéine et ROS inducteur, L-Buthionine-Sulfoximine qui affectent significativement les effets antiprolifératifs de PRIMA-1MET. Nous avons mis en évidence des preuves d'une nouvelle relation potentielle entre MGMT et balance redox. Les lignées cellulaires isogéniques ayant une expression MGMT élevée ont présenté une expression élevée de TrxR1, de faibles taux de ROS alors que leurs homologues ont présenté une faible expression de TrxR1 et des niveaux élevés de ROS. Cette relation est confirmée à la suite d'un traitement par O6-Benzylguanine, un inhibiteur MGMT et Auranofin, un inhibiteur de TrxR1 bien caractérisé et approuvé par le FDA pour l’arthrite rhumatoïde.Malgré quelques limites dans cette étude, y compris le petit nombre de lignées cellulaires, nous fournissons un modèle hypothétique pour expliquer les effets différentiels de la cytotoxicité induite par PRIMA-1MET basé sur l’expression de MGMT. Des expériences supplémentaires sont nécessaires pour mieux comprendre ces nouvelles découvertes et leur pertinence clinique, en particulier pour réorienter Auranofin en tant que nouvelle stratégie de ciblage de TrxR1 à utiliser en combinaison avec PRIMA-1MET. Ces résultats peuvent finalement conduire à l'utilisation de stratégies de traitement efficaces pour améliorer le mauvais pronostic des patients diagnostiqués avec GBM</description><description>Glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM) is the most common and advanced form of astrocytic primary brain malignancy in adults. The prognosis remains poor, despite aggressive treatment with surgery, radiation and chemotherapy using the alkylating agent, Temozolomide (TMZ). The DNA repair protein, O6-methylguanine-DNA-methyltransferase (MGMT) interferes with TMZ cytotoxicity. High frequency missense mutations of the TP53 tumor suppressor gene confer oncogenic mutant (mut) p53 activities, such as resistance to chemoradiation.       A previous study from our lab demonstrated the cytotoxic effects of PRIMA-1MET (APR-246), a small molecule designed to restore wild-type function to mutp53 and shed light into its differential effects based on MGMT expression irrespective of p53 status. In this study, we investigated the underlying mechanisms for p53-independent effects and MGMT-based differences in PRIMA-1MET-induced cytotoxicity in GBM. We hypothesized that PRIMA-1MET may mediate its p53-independent effects through modulation of redox balance and that this balance is altered based on levels of MGMT.       Using GBM cell lines isogenic for MGMT and with a different p53 status, we showed that PRIMA-1MET induced reactive oxygen species (ROS) and decreased thioredoxin reductase 1 (TrxR1) expression levels irrespective of p53 status. We further validated the importance of ROS induction for PRIMA-1MET cytotoxicity using pharmacological agents that modulate ROS levels such as ROS scavenger, N-acetylcysteine and ROS inducer, L-Buthionine-Sulfoximine which significantly affected the anti-proliferative effects of PRIMA-1MET. Strikingly, we provide evidence for a potential novel relationship between MGMT and TrxR1. Isogenic cell lines with high MGMT expression exhibited high expression of TrxR1, low levels of ROS while their counterparts exhibited low TrxR1 expression and high ROS levels. This relationship is confirmed following treatment with O6-Benzylguanine, an MGMT inhibitor and Auranofin, a well-characterized TrxR1 inhibitor, FDA-approved for rheumatoid arthritis.    Despite a few limitations in this study, including the small number of cell lines, we provide a hypothetical model to explain the differential effects of PRIMA-1MET-induced cytotoxicity based on MGMT expression. Additional experiments are required to grasp the clinical relevance of these new findings, specifically for repurposing Auranofin as a new TrxR1-targeting strategy to use in combination with PRIMA-1MET. These findings will ultimately lead to the development of efficient treatment strategies to improve the dismal outcome of patients diagnosed with GBM</description><creator>Raveendrakumar, Rehka Whyshnavy</creator><contributor>Siham Sabri (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Relationship between MGMT and Thioredoxin Reductase 1: Implications in response to PRIMA-1MET (APR-246) and the design of novel targeting strategies in Glioblastoma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vn265.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vz16d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s456j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse présente la première traduction anglaise de F.H. Jacobi's On Divine Things and their Revelation (1811 ; dorénavant, Divine Things) avec commentaire. Cet ouvrage marque pour Jacobi l’émancipation de la pensée rationnelle à partir des limites fixées par les Lumières en matière de religion. L’objectif de Jacobi était de développer une nouvelle définition de la rationalité. Et c’est un objectif qu’il a cherché à atteindre indirectement en puisant dans des sources différentes mais en accord. L’intention de cette thèse est double : examiner les efforts de Jacobi pour introduire une nouvelle forme de rationalité ; expliciter les limites de cette rationalité dans la mesure où Jacobi a réussi à la définir. En général, mon analyse montre que, même si Jacobi s’appuie beaucoup sur la doctrine des postulats de Kant pour exposer sa position, son concept de rationalité cherche à s’éloigner du mode de pensée transcendantal Kantien - en effet, à s’éloigner de toute la tradition de philosophie moderne. Néanmoins, étant donné que Jacobi opère toujours dans les cadres de pensée typiques des Lumières ; malgré son opposition, sa pensée est finalement cohérente avec lui.Plus précisément, je démontre que la raison de Jacobi est correctement définie, non pas par l'acte de postuler, mais par l'acte de percevoir des choses qui sont réellement extérieures à leur perception. Cette perception, qu'elle soit fondée sur la raison ou sur le sens, est intuitive. Jacobi reconnaît, bien sûr, que la perception elle-même, et plus encore le système de représentations conceptuelles qui en découle, est un produit subjectif. C'est l'intérêt indu de cet aspect subjectif de la connaissance qui masque l'appréhension objective de la réalité que la raison (redéfinie par Jacobi) accueille par ailleurs et donne ainsi lieu à des représentations de la réalité parfois utiles, mais toujours illusoires. Les choses divines de Jacobi est le manifeste d’un nouveau réalisme. C’est un réalisme, cependant, que pour être fidèle à lui-même nécessite, selon Jacobi, l’assentiment aux choses divines. Là où, pour Kant, la théologie rationnelle ne peut être que le produit d’une postulation subjective, pour Jacobi, c’est là que le réalisme est plutôt atteint. En cela, tout en combattant Kant, Jacobi fonctionne toujours selon les termes de la problématique qu'il a définie</description><description>This dissertation presents the first English translation, together with commentary, of F.H. Jacobi´s On Divine Things and their Revelation (1811; henceforth, Divine Things). This work marked for Jacobi the emancipation of rational thinking from the bounds set to it by the Enlightenment in matters of religion. Jacobi’s goal was to develop a new definition of rationality. And this is a goal that he sought to achieve indirectly by drawing from different but consonant sources. The intention of this dissertation is twofold: to examine Jacobi’s efforts at introducing a new form of rationality; to make explicit the limits of this rationality inasmuch as Jacobi succeeded in defining it.In general, my analysis shows that, while Jacobi relies heavily on Kant’s doctrine of postulates to lay out his position, his considered concept of rationality seeks to distance itself from the Kantian transcendental mode of thinking – indeed, to distance itself from the entire tradition of modern philosophy. Nevertheless, since Jacobi still operates within the frameworks of thought typical of the Enlightenment, despite his opposition to it, his thought is ultimately continuous with it.More specifically, I demonstrate that reason for Jacobi is properly defined, not by the act of postulating, but the act of perceiving things which are truly external to the perceiving of them. This perceiving, whether reason- or sense-based, is intuitive. Jacobi recognizes, of course, that the perceiving itself, and even more so the system of conceptual representations based on it, is a subjective product. It is the undue interest in this subjective aspect of cognition that obscures the objective apprehension of reality that reason (as redefined by Jacobi) otherwise houses, and thus gives rise to at times useful, but always illusory, representations of reality. Jacobi’s Divine Things is the manifesto of a new realism. This is a realism, however, that in order to be true to itself requires according to Jacobi the assent to divine things. Where for Kant rational theology can be only the product of subjective postulation, for Jacobi it is rather where realism is rather achieved. In this, while countering Kant, Jacobi still operates within the terms of a problematic as set by him</description><creator>Livieri, Paolo</creator><contributor>George Di Giovanni (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Garth Green (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Religious Studies</subject><title>F.H. Jacobi's "On divine things and their revelation." A study and translation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gj28h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s456j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k955j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines late 19th- and early 20th-century Arabic literary texts on China to challenge the Eurocentric scholarly assumption that writers in the Nahda period drew their models of modernity solely from Europe. Surviving only in fragmented and unexplored archives, a large body of Nahdawi literature set in China offers a new stage for understanding the political and social discourses that constituted Arab modernity projects. While existing understandings of the Nahda have emphasized the emergence of sovereign nation-states modelled on European countries, the aspirations that emerge from Nahdawi novels, journalism, biographies, and theatre focused on China define modernity as a process of establishing transnational, south-south relations. Nahdawis wrote about China not by reading Chinese works directly, but by translating European Orientalist sources on China into Arabic. This circuit of textual exchange requires a new analytic for unpacking the multi-lingual layers of mediation involved in Arabic interest in China. This dissertation develops the concept of “triangular translation” as an analytic to explore these contours. By contrast to the standard paradigm that views translation as a bi-directional transaction between two languages, Nahdawi literary texts dealing with China retain a trace of at least three linguistic layers: the original Chinese, Orientalist renderings in European languages, and translation into Arabic. Triangular translation as a model allows for the exploration of the possibilities that these deep textual elements opened up for staging questions in Arabic about constitutional reform and gender equality through the language of ethnographic engagement with Chinese culture. Shifting the mastery of the western gaze away from the Arab world, triangular translation shows a way to analyze how Arab culture redeploys that gaze in relation to the rest of the world, for specific political and cultural purposes tied to the establishment of a transnational regional identity</description><description>Cette thèse analyse des textes littéraires arabes de la fin du XIXe - début du XXe siècle portant sur la Chine afin de défier le présupposé académique eurocentrique considérant que les auteurs de la Nahda empruntèrent leur modèle de la modernité uniquement à l'Europe. Survivant seulement sous la forme d'archives fragmentaires et inexplorées, un important corpus de littérature Nahdawi prenant place en Chine offre une nouvelle perspective à la compréhension des discours politiques et sociaux qui constituèrent les projets de modernité arabes. Alors que les conceptions existantes de la Nahda ont mis l'accent sur l'émergence d'états-nations souverains modelés sur les pays européens, les aspirations qui émergent des romans, articles journalistiques, biographies et des pièces de théâtre Nahdawi se focalisant sur la Chine définissent la modernité comme un processus d'établissement de relations transnationales, de coopération Sud-Sud. Les Nahdawis écrivirent sur la Chine, non en lisant directement des œuvres écrites en chinois, mais en traduisant en arabe des sources orientalistes européennes portant sur la Chine. Ce circuit d'échanges textuels requiert une nouvelle analytique afin d'éplucher les couches multilingues de médiation impliquées par l'intérêt arabe envers la Chine. Cette thèse développe le concept de "traduction triangulaire" en guise d'analytique visant à explorer ces contours. En contraste avec le paradigme standard percevant la traduction comme une transaction bidirectionnelle entre deux communautés linguistiques, les textes littéraires Nahdawi traitant de la Chine portent la trace d'au moins trois couches linguistiques: celle originale en chinois, son rendu orientaliste en langues européennes et sa traduction en arabe. La traduction triangulaire, en tant que modèle, permet l'exploration des possibilités que ces éléments textuels profonds ouvrent à la mise en perspective des questionnements arabes sur la réforme constitutionnelle et l'égalité des sexes par le truchement du langage de l'engagement ethnographique vis-à-vis de la culture chinoise. En contrebalançant de diverses manières la prépondérance du regard occidental sur le monde arabe, la traduction triangulaire montre comment la culture arabe redéploye ce regard vis-à-vis du reste du monde, à des fins politiques et culturelles spécifiques en lien avec l'établissement d'une identité régionale transnationale</description><creator>Yang, Peiyu</creator><contributor>Michelle Laura Hartman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Islamic Studies</subject><title>Triangular translation: Interpreting Nahdawi literary production on China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dh75g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k955j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hk95w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pain is often poorly managed both in-hospital and post-hospital discharge and is associated with harmful outcomes such as increased falls, loss of autonomy and low quality of life and can, in certain instances, evolve into chronic pain. Mobile applications (apps) downloadable on devices such as smartphones and tablets can offer targeted interactive interventions to support patients in acute pain self-management following hospital discharge. However, little is known about the availability and quality of mobile apps for acute pain management in older adults, and the current levels of technology adoption and electronic health (eHealth) literacy in a population of older adults seen in orthopedic clinics. Furthermore, it is important to seek the voice of clinicians when developing a mobile app so that the content is evidence-based, credible and of high value. In this scholarly work, we sought to 1) identify mobile apps currently available for self-management of acute pain and characterize their features (content and functionalities),  2) identify the current level of technology adoption and eHealth literacy among older adults who recently suffered a fracture, to determine if use of mobile digital devices to optimize care interventions would be feasible, acceptable and 3) identify what clinicians believe are the most important content or functionalities to include in a mobile application for self-management of acute pain in older adults following a recent skeletal fracture. Following an environmental scan, where we were unable to identify high quality mobile apps for the self-management of acute pain, we conducted two surveys. In the first, we invited adults ≥50 years with a recent fracture to complete a self-administered survey composed of 21 closed-ended questions, including the eHealth literacy scale (eHEALS). A total of 401 participants completed the survey (women: 64%; ≥65 years old: 59%). Most respondents (81%) owned at least one mobile device: smartphone (49%), tablet (45%). The majority (65%) of older adults participating in this survey used the Internet in the 6 months prior to the survey (50-64 years: 84%; 65-74 years: 76%; ≥75 years: 61%) and approximately 69% of those who used the Internet had high eHealth literacy (eHEALS ≥26). Among adults ≥75 years who reported owning a smartphone and/or tablet, 60% had recently used the Internet and 64% indicated being interested in using technology to improve their health. Although the eHEALS scores and technology adoption in the ≥75 years group were significantly lower compared to younger age groups, our results do support the development of mobile applications for the management of acute pain in this patient population with recent fractures. In the second study, we surveyed clinicians across Canada with expertise in osteoporosis, fractures, rehabilitation and pain management using a snowball sampling method. The survey constituted of one question sent through email asking for recommendations for the most important content or functionalities to include in a mobile app for the self-management of acute pain following a recent fracture. Forty-two clinicians responded to our survey (response rate 1st wave 60%; 2nd wave 60%) and 230 references were extracted. Appropriate medical information, pain management modalities, pain self-management strategies were the most cited content recommendations while the primary app functions highlighted were the ability to receive direct feedback from the app (interactiveness), pain self-monitoring and access to healthcare providers. This work will support the development of a mobile app that will meet evidence-based standards and will support self-management of acute pain following a skeletal fracture in older individuals. This will improve quality of life by reducing pain levels while engaging in activities of daily living and promote healthy lifestyle behaviors to reduce the risk of subsequent injurious falls</description><description>La douleur est souvent mal gérée tant à l'hôpital qu'à la sortie de l'hôpital et est associée à des conséquences telles que l'augmentation du nombre de chutes, la perte d'autonomie et une qualité de vie médiocre. Les applications mobiles (apps) téléchargeables sur des appareils tels que les smartphones et les tablettes peuvent offrir des interventions interactives ciblées pour aider les patients à prendre en charge eux-mêmes la douleur aiguë après leur sortie d'hôpital. Cependant, on dispose peu d'informations sur la disponibilité et la qualité des apps pour la gestion de la douleur aiguë chez la personne âgée, ainsi que sur les niveaux actuels d'adoption de la technologie et de littératie en matière de santé électronique (cyber-santé) chez les patients qui visite la clinique d'orthopédie. En outre, il est important de rechercher la voix des cliniciens lors du développement d'une app afin que le contenu soit fondé sur des preuves, crédible et de grande valeur. Dans ce travail savant, nous avons cherché à 1) identifier les apps actuellement disponibles pour l’autogestion de la douleur aiguë et à caractériser leurs caractéristiques (contenu et fonctionnalités), 2) à identifier le niveau actuel d’adoption de la technologie et de connaissances en cyber-santé chez la personne âgée récemment atteintes d’une fracture, afin de déterminer si l'utilisation d'appareils numériques mobiles pour optimiser les interventions de soins serait faisable, acceptable et 3) déterminer, d’après les cliniciens, le contenu et/ou fonctionnalités les plus importants à inclure dans une application mobile de gestion autonome de la douleur aiguë chez la personne âgée suite à une fracture récente du squelette. Après une analyse de l'environnement, dans laquelle nous n'avons pas pu identifier d'apps de haute qualité pour l'autogestion de la douleur aiguë, nous avons mené deux sondages. Lors du premier, nous avons invité des adultes âgés de 50 ans ou plus présentant une fracture récente à remplir un sondage auto-administré composé de 21 questions fermées, y compris l’échelle de littératie en cyber-santé (eHEALS). Au total, 401 participants ont répondu au sondage (femmes: 64%; ≥ 65 ans: 59%). La plupart des répondants (81%) possédaient au moins un appareil mobile: smartphone (49%), tablette (45%). La majorité (65%) des adultes âgés participant à cette enquête ont utilisé Internet au cours des 6 mois précédant l'enquête (50 à 64 ans: 84%; 65 à 74 ans: 76%; ≥ 75 ans: 61%) et environ 69% de ceux qui utilisaient Internet avaient une haute littératie en cyber-santé (eHEALS ≥26). Parmi les adultes de 75 ans et plus ayant déclaré posséder un smartphone et/ou une tablette, 60% avaient récemment utilisé Internet et 64% étaient intéressés par l'utilisation de la technologie pour améliorer leur santé. Nos résultats appuient le développement d'applications mobiles pour la gestion de la douleur aiguë chez cette population de patients souffrant de fractures récentes. Dans la deuxième étude, nous avons interrogé, à l'aide d'une méthode d'échantillonnage “snowball”, des cliniciens à travers le Canada possédant une expertise en ostéoporose, fractures, réadaptation et en gestion de la douleur. L'enquête consistait en une question envoyée par courriel électronique demandant des recommandations sur le contenu ou les fonctionnalités les plus importants à inclure dans une app pour l'autogestion de la douleur aiguë suite à fracture récente. Quarante-deux cliniciens ont répondu à notre sondage (taux de réponse 1ère vague 60%; 2ème vague 60%) et 230 références ont été extraites. Les informations médicales appropriées, les modalités de gestion de la douleur, les stratégies de gestion de la douleur étaient les recommandations les plus citées, tandis que les fonctions principales mentionnées furent la possibilité de recevoir un retour direct de l'app (interactivité), l'auto-surveillance de la douleur et l'accès aux prestataires de soins de santé</description><creator>Cherid, Chams-Eddine</creator><contributor>Suzanne Morin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>eHealth: Towards improving self-management of acute pain in older adults following a fracture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290f92j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk95w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gs560</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Exposure to cases involving traumatic elements is common for certain attorneys. Such exposure is a possible trigger for the development of a posttraumatic stress disorder. The scientific literature on this issue is scarce, but suggests that attorneys suffer from posttraumatic stress symptoms (PTSS) at a large scale. Moreover, no study has examined the economic impact of PTSS among attorneys to our knowledge. The present exploratory study investigated these last two aspects. The first objective was to assess the long-term prevalence rate (eight-month period) of probable PTSS among attorneys and to assess the factors associated to it. The second objective was to report the Canadian economic impact for the past year of probable PTSS among attorneys. Overall, 284 attorneys were invited to complete the survey and 159 completed the entire survey. The measures assessed PTSS levels, past traumatic event exposure, quality of life, loss of productivity at work, health services used, physicians and paraprofessionals consulted, prescription medications used, and sick leaves. In order to evaluate the first objective, descriptive statistics, independent-samples t-tests, ANOVAs, and Chi-Squares were carried out. The second objective was assessed using the non-parametric tests of Mann- Whitney U, Kruskal-Wallis H, and gamma-log-link multivariate regression analyses. When appropriate, Post-Hoc Bonferroni analyses were conducted and variables were considered as significant based on a two-tailed alpha level of .05. Results showed that the eight-month prevalence rate of probable PTSS among Canadian attorneys was of 14%. Attorneys who worked with traumatic content cases suffered from higher levels of PTSS. Specifically among attorneys exposed to traumatic content cases, the odds of suffering from probable PTSS were nine times superior for those who suffered from probable PTSS eight months earlier and they were seven times superior for people who did not have children. Attorneys who suffered from probable PTSS incurred significantly higher costs on average related to ER visits, prescription medication used, and loss of productivity at work. Private attorneys who suffered from probable PTSS also incurred on average significantly higher costs related to billable hours lost. Furthermore, attorneys who suffered from persistent PTSS engendered systematically higher costs on average than attorneys who did not suffer from probable PTSS. An overall annual loss of $688 662 056 related to probable PTSS among attorneys was found. How those alarming results mirror the values and behaviours that are promoted in the field of law is discussed. Interestingly, attorneys who did not suffer from probable PTSS also incurred costs. Other mental health disorders could influence the costs and should be investigated in future studies. Even though more refined studies assessing the economic impact of PTSS among attorneys are needed, more tailored prevention methods and treatment options should be developed and offered immediately</description><description>L’exposition à des dossiers qui contiennent des éléments traumatiques est commun pour certains avocats. Ce type d’exposition est considéré comme pouvant déclencher le développement d’un trouble de stress post-traumatique. La littérature scientifique sur cette problématique est rare, mais elle suggère que les avocats souffrent de symptômes de stress post-traumatique (SSPT) à grande échelle. À notre connaissance, aucune étude n’a examiné l’impact économique des SSPT chez les avocats. La présente étude exploratoire a évalué ces derniers aspects. Le premier objectif était d’évaluer le taux de prévalence au long terme (sur huit mois) des SSPT probables chez les avocats, ainsi que d’évaluer les facteurs qui y sont associés. Le deuxième objectif était de rapporter l’impact économique au cours de la dernière année des SSPT probables chez les avocats au Canada. Un total de 284 avocats a été invité à compléter le sondage et 159 avocats ont complété le sondage au complet. Les questionnaires ont évalué le niveau des SSPT, l’exposition passée à des événements traumatiques, la qualité de vie, la perte de productivité au travail, les services de santé utilisés, les médecins et paraprofessionnels consultés, les médicaments de prescription consommés et les congés maladie pris. Afin d’évaluer le premier objectif, des analyses descriptives ont été faites, ainsi que des tests-t indépendants, des ANOVAs et des chi- carrés. Le deuxième objectif a été évalué en performant des analyses non paramétriques, soit des Mann-Whitney U, des Kruskal-Wallis H et des analyses de régression multivariées gamma-log-link. Des analyses post-hoc de Bonferroni ont été faites lorsque nécessaire et les variables étaient considérées comme étant significatives avec un seuil alpha à deux queues de .05. Les résultats montrent que le taux de prévalence de huit mois pour les SSPT probables chez les avocats canadiens était de 14%. Les avocats qui travaillaient avec des dossiers à contenu traumatique souffraient de niveaux plus élevés de SSPT. Spécifiquement pour les avocats qui travaillent avec des dossiers à contenu traumatique, il a été trouvé que les risques de souffrir de SSPT probables étaient neuf fois supérieurs pour les personnes qui souffraient de SSPT probables huit mois plus tôt, et que les risques étaient sept fois supérieurs pour les personnes qui n’avaient pas d’enfants. Les avocats qui souffraient de SSPT probables engendraient significativement plus de coûts en moyenne par rapport aux visites aux urgences, à la consommation de médicaments de prescription et à la perte de productivité au travail. Les avocats privés qui souffraient de SSPT probables engendraient également significativement plus de coûts en moyenne liés à la perte d’heures facturables. De plus, les avocats qui souffraient de SSPT persistants engendraient des coûts systématiquement plus élevés en moyenne que ceux qui ne souffraient pas de SSPT probables. Une perte totale annuelle de 688 662 056$ liée aux SSPT probables chez les avocats a été trouvée. Comment ces résultats alarmants reflètent les valeurs et les comportements qui sont promus dans le milieu du droit est discuté. Les avocats qui souffraient de peu de SSPT ont également généré des coûts. D’autres troubles mentaux pourraient aussi influencer les coûts et ils devraient être examinés dans les études à venir. Malgré le fait que des études plus raffinées évaluant l’impact économique des SSPT chez les avocats soient nécessaires, plus de méthodes de prévention et d’options de traitements adaptés devraient être développées et offerts immédiatement</description><creator>Léonard, Marie-Jeanne</creator><contributor>Helen-Maria Vasiliadis (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Alain Brunet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Psychiatry</subject><title>The economic impact of posttraumatic stress symptoms among Canadian attorneys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jj84r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gs560</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hk965</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La douleur chronique est une condition avec une prévalence élevée dans la population pédiatrique. Plus de 10-25% des enfants et adolescents sont affectés et 5% en souffrent de façon si sévère qu’ils en sont considérés handicapés. Approximativement seulement 3% des enfants et adolescents souffrant de douleur chronique recevront un traitement efficace. Les protocoles de traitement utilisés de nos jours sont basés sur des protocoles d’anesthésie pour adultes, qui ne sont pas bien adaptés aux patients en jeune âge. Il y  a présentement un besoin impératif de d’améliorer les solutions thérapeutiques car l’échec des traitements actuels porte un impact négatif sur la santé et la vie des patients, en plus d’être un fardeau économique pour la société en termes des couts des services de santé et de perte de productivité.Les tests quantitatifs sensoriels (QST) et l’évaluation de la modulation de la douleur conditionnée (CPM) sont des outils d’évaluation somatosensorielle qui ont été développés et utilisés en recherche clinique sur la douleur depuis plus de trente ans. Les évaluations QST et CPM examinent l’intégrité des différentes fibres nerveuses et des voies neurales impliquées dans l’intégration des sensations de la douleur et du toucher à travers des méthodes cutanées. Des études suggèrent que l’utilisation des évaluations QST et CPM pourrait assister les médecins cliniciens à identifier quelle altération des voies neurales est à l’origine de la maintenance de la douleur chronique chez les patients souffrant de différentes conditions de douleur chroniques. En identifiant de tels facteurs, les évaluations QST et CPM pourraient éclairer leur choix de traitement en offrant une sélection de traitement basée sur le mécanisme de la douleur plutôt que d’utiliser une méthode essai-erreur. À ce jour, il y a une grande quantité de données scientifiques disponibles décrivant les tests QST et CPM dans diverses populations de patients souffrant de douleurs chroniques mais aussi dans des populations d’individus en santé de tous âges. Malheureusement, l’utilisation des évaluations QST et CPM demeure expérimentale et la possibilité d’une transition d’un outil de recherche à une application clinique n’a toujours pas été évaluée. L’objectif était d’évaluer si l’utilisation des évaluations QST et CPM en tant qu’outil clinique pouvait influencer la sélection du traitement dans une clinique de douleur chronique pédiatrique interdisciplinaire. L’hypothèse était que la disponibilité des résultats de l’évaluation QST et CPM changerait le choix de traitement médical (pharmacothérapie ou intervention). Une analyse rétrospective de données cliniques collectées prospectivement a révélé que l’évaluation QST et CPM a influencé le choix de traitement du médecin comparé au traitement reçu par des patients n’ayant eu que l’évaluation standard. Les données ont aussi suggéré que l’utilisation du protocole QST et CPM était sécuritaire et non-inférieure à l’évaluation standard. Cette étude supporte la prémisse selon laquelle l’évaluation QST et CPM dans le but de fournir de l’information additionnelle sur la fonction somatosensorielle des patients a une influence sur la sélection du traitement pharmacologique, et pourrait potentiellement améliorer les soins donnés aux patients dans une clinique de douleur chronique pédiatrique interdisciplinaire</description><description>Chronic pain is overwhelmingly prevalent in the paediatric population, with 10-25% of children and adolescents affected and 5% disabled by it. Approximately only 3% of the children and adolescent suffering from chronic pain will receive an effective treatment. Current treatment protocols are based on general anaesthesia protocols for adults, which are not well adapted to younger patients. There is an imperative need for better treatment solutions since failure to treat those patients bears a negative impact on their health and daily lives, in addition to being an economic burden for society through healthcare costs and loss of productivity.Quantitative sensory testing (QST) and the conditioned pain modulation (CPM) evaluation are somatosensory tools that have been developed and used in clinical research in pain over the past thirty years. QST and CPM investigate the integrity of the different nerve fibers and pathways involved in pain and touch processing through cutaneous evaluations. Research suggests that using QST and CPM could assist clinicians in identifying which pain processing mechanism is responsible for the maintenance of chronic pain. By identifying such factors, QST and CPM could assist in selecting a mechanism-based pharmacological management program to treat patients suffering from different chronic pain conditions, rather than using a trial-and-error method. Presently, there is a large amount of scientific data available describing QST and CPM results in various chronic pain patients and healthy populations of all ages. However, the use of a QST and CPM evaluation remains experimental and the translation from a research tool to a clinical application is yet to be evaluated.The objective was to evaluate if using QST and CPM assessments as a clinical tool could influence the selection of treatment in a paediatric chronic pain interdisciplinary clinic. The hypothesis was that the availability of the QST and CPM evaluations outcomes would result in a different choice of medical treatment (drug or interventional). Retrospective analysis of prospectively collected data revealed that QST and CPM evaluations had an influence on treatment choice by the physician when compared to patients receiving the standard evaluation only. The data also suggest that the QST and CPM protocol used in the study was safe and non-inferior to the standard of care assessment. This study supports the premise that using QST and CPM evaluations to provide additional information of the somatosensory function of patients has an influence on the selection of the pharmacological treatment option, and could potentially improve patient care in a paediatric chronic pain interdisciplinary clinic</description><creator>Bruneau, Alice</creator><contributor>Catherine Ferland-Legault (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Quantitative sensory testing and conditioned pain modulation evaluation  as a clinical tool in a paediatric chronic pain interdisciplinary clinic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rj830.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk965</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v6930</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:19:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il peut être utile de modéliser la compréhension du joueur des mouvements de personnagesnon-joueurs (PNJ) pour adapter un jeu vidéo à différents styles de jeu. Pour lesjeux furtifs, ce qu’un joueur sait ou soupçonne des mouvements de l’ennemi est importantpour la manière dont il ou elle va naviguer le niveau pour trouver une solution. Dans cettethèse, nous construisons une abstraction uniforme de la connaissance du trajet potentieldes joueurs en fonction de leurs observations partielles. Nous utilisons cette représentationpour calculer différentes estimations de trajets en fonction des attentes des différentsjoueurs. Nous renforçons notre recherche avec une étude qui valide les types de comportementdes PNJ auxquelles un joueur peut s’attendre et nous développons un outil qui peutcréer et explorer des trajets appropriés (et attendus).D’après notre recherche, nous avons constaté que les joueurs ont tendance à préférer lestrajets courts et simples aux trajets longs ou complexes (c’est-à-dire des trajets avec bouclesou backtrack). Nous mettons en oeuvre également nos méthodes à des situations de jeuxréelles et élaborons sur les avantages et les limites de notre méthode davantage. Nous avonseffectué des expérimentations sur des scénarios de trajets PNJ réels et créés artificiellementet avons évalué les trajets générés. Nous discutons également la simplification des trajets,ainsi que de la mesure de la similarité entre deux trajets à l’aide de la méthode Fréchetdiscret et d’une version modifiée et améliorée qui tient compte des obstacles. Nous utilisonsaire et volume pour mesurer le niveau de difficulté du jeu. Nous examinons aussi les défisde la représentation précise des observations dans le jeu, et les problèmes qu’encompasse latranslation des observations des joueurs en une représentation valable du savoir des joueurs</description><description>Modelling a player's understanding of non-player character (NPC) movements can be useful for adapting gameplay to different play styles.  For stealth games, what a player knows or suspects of enemy movements is important to how they will navigate towards a solution.  In this work, we build a uniform abstraction of potential player path knowledge based on their partial observations.  We use this representation to compute different path estimates according to different player expectations. We augment our work with a user study that validates what kinds of NPC behaviour a player may expect, and develop a tool that can build and explore appropriate (expected) paths. From the study, we found that players tend to prefer short simple paths over long or complex paths with looping or backtracking behaviour. We also apply our methods to real game situations to expand on our approach's benefits and limitations. We ran experiments on real and artificially created scenarios of NPC paths and evaluated the generated pathing behaviours and found that simple shortest paths tend to be most similar to actual NPC paths. We also discuss path simplification, as well as measuring similarity between two paths using discrete Fréchet (and a modified extended version that considers paths around obstacles). We use area and volume to measure level difficulty and we examine the challenges of accurately representing player observation and the endeavour of translating player observations into a valid representation of player knowledge</description><creator>Zhang, Mengxi</creator><contributor>Clark Verbrugge (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Modelling player understanding of non-player character paths</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r963k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v6930</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42850</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>