<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:10:02Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):30325" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz107</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The crystallites of rat incisor enamel resemble human enamel crystallites and high resolution lattice images agree with computed lattice images of theoretical hydroxyapatite. Lattice imaging revealed steps on crystallite surfaces predicted to be potential sites for growth in thickness and width. Freeze-fracture replica, isolation of individual crystallites and high resolution lattice imaging, demonstrated bending of crystallites to accommodate changes from rod to interrod positions. Apparent crystallite fusion and crystallite continuity were shown by goniometric tilting to be artifacts of overlapping. Coat-like structures attributed to crystallite-binding proteins were shown to be artifacts caused by stain adhering to the Epon space vacated by dissolved crystallites. Shark enameloid crystallites were investigated for the first time by isolation and freeze-fracture replica, and rod and interrod crystallite domains were found. Tilting the large equilateral hexagons projected octagonal shadows and confirmed the prediction that crystallite images are shadows of three dimensional solids, however, low contrast at the edges makes the octagons difficult to visualize.</description><creator>Dong, Weijia</creator><contributor>Warshawsky, Hershey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Ultrastructural studies of crystallite formation and organization in rat incisor enamel and shark enameloid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x294m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz107</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xk111</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The c-myc gene was previously shown to be regulated by a conditional block to transcription elongation and sequences from its promoter were implicated in this regulation. The objective of this project was to define the promoter elements involved in the control of transcription elongation. Using heterologous promoter constructs, the ME1a1 protein binding site located in the c-myc promoter was shown to be required for the block to transcription elongation. From mutation analysis, a correlation was established between the binding of nuclear factors to ME1a1 sites in vitro and the ability of these sites to confer block to transcription elongation in vivo, strongly implicating trans-acting factors in this process. Fractionation studies demonstrated that three nuclear factors interact with the ME1a1 site, thus generating three protein-DNA complexes termed "a", "b", and "c". These factors were characterized and a cDNA encoding the protein responsible for complex "c" was isolated. This protein was shown to represent the human homologue of the Drosophila Cut homeodomain protein (hu-Cut) and to repress expression from the c-myc promoter in transient transfection assays.</description><creator>Dufort, Daniel</creator><contributor>Nepveu, Alain (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of a protein binding site involved in the regulation of transcription elongation within the murine c-myc gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t08q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk111</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204067p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The benefits of very high resolution data from scanning and vertically pointing radars in a research and operational environment are investigated. They are used to perform research on four test topics: the study of the melting layer of precipitation, the derivation of vertical wind profiles using conventional radars, high resolution radar hydrology, and a case study of an unusual weather event. The resulting findings include a quantitative description of bright band statistics, the development of a unique wind measuring technique, the quantification of the sampling problem at high resolution, and a description of the complex interaction between stratiform precipitation and small convective cells. These results show the value of these data for research and hence operations. However, one must avoid the temptation to extract more information from these data sets than can be unambiguously retrieved.</description><creator>Fabry, Frédéric</creator><contributor>Zawadzki, Isztar (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Observations and uses of high resolution radar data from precipitation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g656f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204067p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v4555</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neonatal handling paradigm has been used to examine hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) activity under acute stress. Neonatally handled (H) animals exhibit decreased plasma levels of adrenocorticotropin (ACTH) and corticosterone (B) in response to some acute stressors relative to non-handled (NH) animals. However, relatively little is known about how animals that differ in HPA responsiveness to acute stress will respond to repeated exposure to the same stressor. We examined various aspects of HPA activity in adult, control H and NH animals (H CTL and NH CTL), and H and NH animals exposed to chronic, intermittent cold stress (4 h of 4$ sp circ$C cold a day for 21 days; H CHR and NH CHR). H CTL and NH CTL animals displayed comparable ACTH and B responses to the first exposure. H CHR animals exhibited lower levels of ACTH, but not B, during the 22nd exposure (the homotypic stressor) compared to the first exposure in H CTL. However, ACTH and B levels in NH CHR were not different from those in NH CTL. Upon exposure to restraint (the novel, heterotypic stressor), NH CHR animals hypersecreted ACTH and B compared to NH CTL more than did H CHR animals relative to H CTL animals. These endocrine responses were associated with increased basal median eminence levels of both CHR and AVP in H CHR and NH CHR relative to their control groups and with decreased GR densities in septum of both H CHR and NH CHR. Thus, the differential responses of H CHR and NH CHR to the homotypic and heterotypic stressors cannot be explained solely by changes in median eminence content of secretagogues or central GR density. We also examined three aspects of immune function. We first measured the plaque-forming cell (PFC) response, a T cell-dependent, B cell response, and plasma antibody titers to an injection of sheep red blood cells. Suppression of PFC response and antibody titers was similar in H and NH following either acute or chronic exposure to cold, but a greater suppression was seen in NH CHR than H CHR following a single re-exposure to cold. We then examined HPA responses to two doses of endotoxin and found that plasma ACTH and B responses to endotoxin depended on dose. Finally, we examined incidence of tumors in control and chronically cold stressed H and NH animals, as well as chronic intermittently restraint H and NH animals (20 min restraint a day for 21 days; H RES and NH RES) that had been injected with cells transfected with the Fujinami Sarcoma Virus. H RES animals exhibited the lowest incidence of tumors of all animals studied, and this decreased incidence was associated with adaptation of plasma B responses, decreased thymus GR levels, and decreases in some indices of sympathetic adrenomedullary activity. These data support the notion that exposure to chronic stress is associated with perturbations of immune function that may lead to the development of pathology, and that differences between H and NH animals in HPA responses to stress are relevant to the study of individual differences in the development of pathology. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Bhatnagar, Seema</creator><contributor>Meaney, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Hypothalamic pituitary adrenal and immune function in chronic intermittently cold stressed neonatally handled and non handled rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc408.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v4555</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r466x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the role of transfer of first (L1) language properties and access to knowledge of Universal Grammar in second language (L2) acquisition. Two empirical components are included: a study of the syntax of anaphora in Serbo-Croatian and an experimental study of second language acquisition of reflexive binding. Data from field work on the coreference properties of anaphors in Serbo-Croatian are discussed in terms of standard, parameterized, LF movement, and Relativized SUBJECT approaches to Binding Theory. Recent versions of the theory identify a categorial distinction between morphologically simple ($ rm X sp circ$) and complex (XP) anaphor types as a crucial factor in determining coreference relations between reflexive pronouns and their syntactic antecedents. The predictions of a morphological approach to the Binding Theory were tested in a study of the acquisition of the binding properties of English XP reflexives by native speakers of Serbo-Croatian, a language with $ rm X sp circ$ reflexives. Acquisition of the English binding pattern by this group of L2 learners requires recognition of the morphological complexity of English reflexives. Prior to reanalysis, learners are predicted to produce an incorrect L1 coreference pattern in the L2 environment. Two sentence comprehension tasks were administered to adolescent and adult Serbo-Croatian speaking L2 learners of English and similar groups of English native speaker controls. Picture identification and multiple choice comprehension tasks produced convergent results with significant differences between control (n = 47) and L2 learner (n = 73) interpretations of reflexives in complex noun phrases and object control infinitival sentences. Their pattern of interpretation shows evidence of transfer of the $ rm X sp circ$ anaphor type found in Serbo-Croatian to the target grammar and suggests L2 learners are able to apply a deductive system constrained by Universal Grammar to compute binding domains in second language acquisition.</description><creator>Bennett, Susan</creator><contributor>White, Lydia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Government-binding theory (Linguistics)</subject><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Serbo-croatian speakers.</subject><subject>Second language acquisition.</subject><subject>Serbo-Croatian language -- Anaphora.</subject><subject>Language transfer (Language learning)</subject><title>Second language acquisition of reflexive binding by native speakers of Serbo-Croatian</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr960.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r466x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p10b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of organometallic and biological systems have been investigated by infrared and Raman spectroscopy. The IR and Raman spectra of 17$ beta$-estradiol have been assigned. In pressure-tuning IR studies, hydrogen bonding of 17$ alpha$-ethinylestradiol through the 17$ alpha$-ethinyl group was detected, while in organometallic estradiol derivatives, the effect of substitution mainly affected the region near the point of substitution. In analogous pressure-tuning studies of $ alpha$- and $ beta$-(Cr(CO)$ sb3$) estradiol derivatives, differences between the two diastereomers were observed and the steric effect of the $ alpha$-diastereomer on hydrogen bonding was observed. In surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) work, two modes of binding for 17$ alpha$-ethinylestradiol were observed. In aqueous systems, the ethinyl group was deprotonated, permitting adsorption on the silver surface through $ eta sp1$-coordination, while in aqueous-CH$ sb2$Cl$ sb2$ mixtures, the 17$ alpha$-ethinyl group was bound to the silver surface via $ eta sp2$-coordination. The new technique of pressure-tuning FT-Raman spectroscopy was developed and applied in the study of Cr(CO)$ sb4$(bipy) and no breakdown in ring aromaticity was discovered. In the study of covalent and dative metal-metal bonded complexes (L)(L$ sp prime$)(OC)$ sb3$Os-M(CO)$ sb4$(L$ sp{ prime prime}$) (L = Me$ sb3$P, (MeO)$ sb3$P; L$ sp prime$ = CO, Cl, Br, I; M = Cr, W, Mo, Re; L$ sp{ prime prime}$ = CO, Cl, Br, I), the datively-bonded complexes exhibited slightly lower v(M-M) values. Permutation theory was used to illustrate that in complexes with M(CO)$ sb5$ receptor fragments, the depolarization ratios of certain carbonyl stretching modes may be indicative of dative or covalent metal-metal bonding.</description><creator>Barnett, Steven Marc</creator><contributor>Butler, I. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><title>Novel bonding interactions in organometallic and biological systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w760.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p10b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bj72f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Granulins (epithelins) are cysteine rich polypeptides with pleiotropic effects on epithelial cell growth in vitro. The human granulin cDNA predicts a 593 amino acid glycoprotein precursor containing seven and one-half granulin-like repeats arranged in tandem. The rat granulin precursor cDNA predicts a 589 residue glycoprotein with an overall identity of 75% with human progranulin. The single copy human granulin gene is located on chromosome 17. The protein coding region of the granulin gene spans 4 kilobases and contains 12 exons with each repeat encoded by two exons. The 5$ sp prime$ flanking region of the human granulin gene lacks a TATA box but has several CCAAT boxes, and exhibits heterogeneity in transcription initiation sites. The granulin precursor is processed differently depending on cell type, and secretion of the granulin gene products is both constitutive and regulated. The granulin gene is expressed in a variety of adult and fetal tissues derived from all three embryonic germ layers. In vitro, the granulin gene is expressed in cell types of diverse lineages, including epithelial cells, lymphoid and myeloid cells, and fibroblasts, whereas its expression in situ is restricted to hematopoietic and some epithelial cells.</description><creator>Bhandari, Vijay</creator><contributor>Bateman, Andrew (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Characterization of granulins, a novel family of cysteine rich growth modulating peptides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096860r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bj72f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r19r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two strains of Alcaligenes denitrificans, designated BRI 3010 and BRI 6011, were isolated from polychlorinated biphenyl (PCB) contaminated soil using 2,5-dichlorobenzoic acid (2,5-DCBA) and 2,4-DCBA, respectively, as sole carbon and energy sources. Both strains degraded 2-chlorobenzoic acid (2-CBA), 2,3-DCBA, and 2,5-DCBA. BRI 6011 alone degraded 2,4-DCBA. Metabolism of the chlorinated substrates resulted in the stoichiometric release of chloride, and degradation proceeded by intradiol cleavage of the aromatic ring. Growth of both strains on dichlorobenzoic acids induced pyrocatechase activities having catechol (catechol 1,2-dioxygenase) and chlorocatechols (chlorocatechol 1,2-dioxygenase) as substrates. Growth on 2-CBA and benzoic acid induced a pyrocatechase activity (catechol 1,2-dioxygenase) directed against catechol only. The chlorocatechol 1,2-dioxygenase from BRI 6011 was purified, characterized, and compared with the chlorocatechol 1,2-dioxygenase from Pseudomonas sp. B13 and P. putida, organisms limited with respect to their CBA degradative versatility. These enzymes appear to be very similar based on biochemical and genetic data and possess sufficient broad substrate specificity to accommodate a wide range of chlorinated catechols, hence the increased versatility for chlorobenzoic acid degradation of A. denitrificans cannot be attributed to a more specialized chlorocatechol 1,2-dioxygenase. Uptake of benzoic acid by BRI 3010 and BRI 6011 was inducible, exhibited saturation kinetics and the substrate was accumulated intracellularly against a concentration gradient by a factor of 8 and 10, respectively, indicative of active transport. Uptake of 2,4-DCBA by BRI 6011 was constitutive and saturation kinetics were not observed, suggesting passive diffusion of 2,4-DCBA and other CBAs into the cell down a concentration gradient. Based on oxygen uptake experiments with whole cells, benzoic acid dioxygenase and chlorobenzoic acid dioxygenase activity was induced by benzoic acid and ortho-substituted chlorobenzoic acids, respectively. Since 2,4-DCBA diffuses across the membrane and the expected catecholic intermediates of 2,4-DCBA metabolism are metabolizable by BRI 3010, this suggests that the major difference between BRI 3010 and BRI 6011 might be the inability of the chlorobenzoic acid dioxygenase in BRI 3010 to recognize 2,4-DCBA as a substrate.</description><creator>Miguez, Carlos B. (Carlos Barreno)</creator><date>1993</date><subject>Alcaligenes denitrificans</subject><subject>Polychlorinated biphenyls -- Biodegradation.</subject><subject>Microbial metabolism.</subject><title>Isolation and physiological characterization of two chlorobenzoic acid degrading bacteria from polychlorinated biphenyl contaminated soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c905t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r19r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vv77h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Azotobacter chroococcum the hydrogenase gene (hup) cluster spans about 14 kb of DNA. In this study about 12 kb of the hup region beginning immediately downstream of the structural genes (hupSL) were sequenced. This revealed 14 additional open reading frames (ORFs) which we designated hupZMNOQRTVABYCDE. All of them are transcribed from the same strand as hupSL and are closely linked. The polypeptides predicted from all these genes are homologous to products of the gene clusters of membrane-bound (NiFe) hydrogenases from other bacteria, including Azotobacter vinelandii, Alcaligenes eutrophus, Rhodobacter capsulatus, Rhizobium leguminosarum and Escherichia coli. The products of hupR and hupZ may be involved in hydrogenase-linked electron transport since they are similar to rubredoxins and b-type cytochromes, respectively. Site-directed mutagenesis of hupB, hupY, hupD and hupE abolished Hup activity with either O$ sb2$ or methylene blue as the electron acceptor whereas two insertions downstream of the hupE gene had no effect on Hup activity. A 10.5 kb fragment of DNA beginning in hupR was able to complement hupD and hupE mutants, supporting earlier evidence for a promoter downstream of hupSL. Mutations in hupB, hupY and hupD had little effect on $ beta$-galactosidase activity in a strain also carrying a hupL-lacZ fusion, indicating that hupB, hupY and hupD are probably not involved in regulating the transcription of hupSL. Adding nickel to the medium restored wild-type Hup activity to a hupB mutant and about half of the activity in a hupA mutant, indicating that the hupB and hupA gene products may be involved in Ni metabolism.</description><creator>Du, Lisheng</creator><contributor>Tibelius, Karl H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Azotobacter chroococcum -- Genetics</subject><subject>Hydrogenase.</subject><title>Sequences and genetic analysis of several accessory genes from the Azotobacter chroococcum hydrogenase gene cluster</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd26j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv77h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h158</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fertilizer applications of urea and triple superphosphate (TSP) suffer from low efficiency for corn production. Band or broadcast application of urea with acidic-P fertilizers may increase fertilizer efficiency. Urea and acidic-P fertilizer interactions in soil-fertilizer microsites were investigated using two Quebec soils. Adding acidic phosphates such as TSP and monoammonium phosphate (MAP) to urea reduced pH in microsites, urea hydrolysis, NH$ sb3$ volatilization, and increased soil NH$ sb4$- and NO$ sb3$-N contents. Ammonia loss decreased as P$ rm sb2O sb5$: urea-N ratios increased. Adding urea to P fertilizer increased soil pH and P sorption when using CaCl$ sb2$ as the electrolyte. Urea application increased 0.5 M NaHCO$ sb3$ extractable P. Banding urea with TSP caused dissolution of organic matter in soils, and increased P diffusion and P concentration in soil solution sampled with filter paper or in 1 M KCl extraction. Two years of field experiments demonstrated that banding urea with TSP or MAP increased soil extractable P (Mehlich-3), N and P nutrient uptake, plant growth and development of corn. Greater P fertilizer efficiencies and higher yields were achieved by banding urea-acidic P fertilizers.</description><creator>Fan, Mingxiang</creator><contributor>MacKenzie, A. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Corn -- Yields.</subject><subject>Corn -- Fertilizers.</subject><subject>Urea as fertilizer.</subject><subject>Superphosphates.</subject><title>Urea and acidic phosphate interactions in fertilizer microsites and their effect on corn (Zea mays L.) yield and nutrient use efficiency</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q558v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h158</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d27s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Long-fibre reinforced thermoplastics are one of the fastest growing segments in the composites industry. Thermoplastic pultrusion compounding is one of the techniques used to manufacture this injection mouldable material. The pultrusion compounding process used in this research consists of pulling a continuous glass roving over a series of staggered cylindrical pins immersed in a molten thermoplastic bath. This research reports on the effect of several key pultrusion compounding parameters (roving pulling speed, number and diameter of pins, melt temperature and initial roving tension) on the impregnation of nylon 6.6 melt into glass roving. The interlaminar shear strength of pultruded strands and compression moulded test bars, as well as optical microscopy, void fraction measurements and injection moulded specimen physical properties are used to quantify impregnation. Simple mathematical models have been developed to simulate the effect of processing parameters on melt impregnation. Good qualitative agreement between the model and experimental data is observed.</description><creator>Bates, Philip J.</creator><contributor>Charrier, J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Melt impregnation of glass roving in a thermoplastic pultrusion compounding process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv56d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d27s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3012840</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two major subtypes of nicotinic acetylcholine receptors (nAChRs) have been identified in the nervous system. One site is bound by $ alpha$-bungarotoxin ($ alpha$-BGT), while the other has a higher affinity for agonists and does not bind the $ alpha$-toxin. Muscle nAChRs, which also bind $ alpha$-BGT, had been reported to be sensitive to a thymus-derived polypeptide, thymopoietin (TPO). The present work was therefore done to determine whether this agent might also interact with the different nAChR populations in neuronal cells. Initial studies involved thymopentin (TP-5), a 5 amino-acid peptide which may represent the active site of TPO. TP-5 inhibited nicotinic receptor-induced release of catecholamines in bovine adrenal medullary cells in culture, a function mediated through the $ alpha$-BGT-insensitive nAChR. On the other hand, TP-5 did not inhibit either ($ sp3$H) (-)nicotine or ($ sp{125}$I) $ alpha$-BGT binding to rat brain membranes. These results suggested that TP-5 interacted in a non-competitive manner with the $ alpha$-BGT-insensitive neuronal nAChR. Studies were subsequently done with thymic preparations presumed to be purified TPO ('TPO'), the native polypeptide containing the TP-5 amino acid sequence. In contrast to the effect of TP-5, 'TPO' preparations did not alter nicotinic receptor mediated catecholamine release from neuronal cells in culture. However, 'TPO' preparations selectively decreased ($ sp{125}$I) $ alpha$-BGT binding to brain membranes suggesting an interaction between this polypeptide and $ alpha$-BGT receptors. Quantitative autoradiography revealed that 'TPO' inhibited specific ($ sp{125}$I) $ alpha$-BGT binding uniformly and with similar potency in different brain regions. As $ alpha$-BGT binding sites are highly expressed in the hippocampal formation, primary cultures of fetal rat hippocampal cells were used next to investigate regulation of the $ alpha$-BGT receptor by 'TPO'. 'TPO' caused a dose-dependent and slowly reversible decrease in the density of $ alpha$-BGT receptors. After completion of this work with 'TPO', studies by Quik and coworkers (1993) showed that $ alpha$-Naja toxin (or $ alpha$-cobratoxin) from Naja naja siamensis snake venom was present in the 'TPO' preparations; furthermore, this toxin component appeared to be responsible for the reported effects of 'TPO' on $ alpha$-BGT receptors. Therefore, the above results which had initially been interpreted to occur as a consequence of the interaction of the thymic polypeptide TPO at the nicotinic $ alpha$-BGT site, must now be attributed to the presence of $ alpha$-Naja toxin contaminant in the 'TPO' preparations. Studies were also undertaken to identify a nicotinic function for $ alpha$-BGT receptors in neuronal cells. Intracellular calcium levels were measured in response to nicotine as recent work using parasympathetic neurons showed that this may represent an $ alpha$-BGT-sensitive response. In contrast to earlier findings, the present work indicates that nAChR-mediated calcium fluxes in cultured chromaffin cells do not reveal an $ alpha$-BGT-sensitive component. These results thus suggest that nicotinic $ alpha$-BGT receptors mediate their response by altering intracellular calcium levels in some but not all neuronal preparations.</description><creator>Afar, Ronith</creator><contributor>Quik, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Regulation and function of neuronal nicotinic acetylcholine receptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk129.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3012840</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz12s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ability of two putative trophic agents, nerve growth factor (NGF) and the monosialoganglioside GM1, to induce neurochemical, morphological and behavioral recovery following injury to the adult rat basalo-cortical cholinergic pathway was studied. Treatment of unilaterally decorticated rats with these agents was shown to: attenuate deficits in holinergic markers of the nucleus basalis magnocellularis (NBM), prevent shrinkage of choline acetyltransferase (ChAT)- and p75$ sp{ rm NGFR}$-immunoreactive (IR) NBM neurons, and stimulate cortical ChAT activity and high affinity choline uptake, in a dose-dependent manner with equal efficacies but different potencies. Quantitative light and electron microscopic studies, assisted by image analysis, showed that GM1 or NGF treatment also similarly attenuated lesion-induced deficits in cortical ChAT-IR fiber length. By contrast, NGF, but not GM1, treatment caused significant synaptic remodelling in the remaining cortex of adult lesioned rats; this was reflected by increases in ChAT-IR varicosity number, presynaptic terminal size, and in the number of boutons with synaptic contacts. GM1 treatment only attenuated such lesion-induced deficits. Exogenous GM1 was also shown to potentiate NGF-reduced effects on basalo-cortical cholinergic markers and on cortical synaptic remodelling, but did not affect the affinity or number of NGF binding sites in brain membranes isolated from lesioned animals. This suggests that GM1 probably affects an alternative step of the NGF signal transduction cascade to potentiate NGF effects. Moreover, NGF or GM1 treatment were also shown to: distinctly regulate striatal cholinergic markers, differ with respect to the delay possible in treatment time onset for effective protection from retrograde regeneration, and diversely affect the behaviour of these animals in passive avoidance and Morris water maze tasks. In aged rats ($&gt;$20 months), NGF and/or GM1 treatment were also shown to effectively prevent de The work of this thesis has thus provided evidence that the injured adult rat basalo-cortical cholinergic pathway can exhibit substantial neurochemical and morphological plasticity in response to NGF and/or GM1 treatment. In particular, it has been shown that these agents cause significant alterations in cholinergic innervation.</description><creator>Garofalo, Lorella</creator><contributor>Cuello, Claudio (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Nerve growth factor- andor monosialoganglioside GM1-induced neuroplasticity in brain of decorticated adult and aged rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk510.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz12s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j700z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A risk analysis of drought and an assessment of irrigation requirements were ascertained for a wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) crop in Parana, Brazil, using 28 years of historical weather data. Two soil moisture models, The Versatile Soil Moisture Budget (VB4) and SWACROP models, were compared using data from six wheat cropping periods. The models showed good performance in predicting soil moisture contents, but SWACROP underpredicted soil evaporation and runoff, and VB4 did not separate evapotranspiration into its components. Therefore, a new soil moisture model was proposed. In the new model, a Darcy type equation was used to calculate fluxes in the soil profile, and inputs of daily rainfall and potential evapotranspiration were partitioned during the day using simple disaggregation methods. Crop growth input parameters, interacting with weather and soil inputs, were used to calculate a detailed output of the water balance components. The validation of the model showed predictions of soil water contents and evapotranspiration in close agreement with field data. A crop yield model based on the stress day index approach was selected from an evaluation of seven crop-water production functions using wheat field data. This model was combined with the soil moisture model to assess risks of drought during the establishment and development of non-irrigated wheat crops with different planting dates. Irrigation management strategies were simulated to identify net system delivery capacities and application frequencies that promote maximum yield with minimum requirements of water. Yield reductions in non-irrigated wheat due to water stress varied between 16%, for early plantings, to 50%, for late plantings. Maximum yields with minimum applied water was obtained by the use of low intensity (5 to 10 mm) and frequent (3 to 5 days) irrigations. System delivery capacity requirements varied from 1.5 to 3.0 mm/day, according to planting dates.</description><creator>Faria, Rogério Teixeira de</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Soil moisture -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Wheat -- Brazil -- Paraná (State) -- Irrigation</subject><subject>Irrigation farming -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Crop yields -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Simulation of irrigation requirements for Parana State, Brazil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w395j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j700z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th01w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA), a widely used clinical tumor marker, functions in vitro as an adhesion molecule and is the prototype for a family of glycoproteins, which includes nonspecific crossreacting antigen (NCA) and biliary glycoprotein (BGP). This study examines the control processes responsible for the overproduction of the CEA family in carcinomas and identifies the trans-acting factors which mediate CEA and BGP gene transcription. During differentiation and $ gamma$-interferon treatment, CEA and NCA are regulated at both transcriptional and post-transcriptional levels and transcriptional control is markedly different between these two corresponding genes. Characterization of the CEA gene promoter revealed both negative and positive regulatory elements and tissue-specific, differentiation-dependent interactions with USF, Sp1, Sp1-like, AP-2-like and novel silencer transcription factors. Characterization of the BGP promoter identified one positively-acting element binding both USF and HNF-4/LF-A1, thereby contributing to distinct BGP gene expression. The Sp1, Sp1-like and silencer factors are specific to CEA gene transcription.</description><creator>Hauck, Wendy</creator><contributor>Stanners, C. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Studies on the control of carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) gene family expression in a differentiating colon carcinoma cell line</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js70q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th01w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m816p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metal/ceramic composites have attracted considerable attention in the last 20 years, primarily due to the flexibility they offer when designing material with tailored properties. Melt infiltration is a popular fabricating method for such composites, as it allows the production of near-net shape components with high ceramic content. Capillaric melt infiltration is a simpler process since the liquid penetrates the preform under the action of a capillary pressure. This work deals with the fabrication and evaluation of a TiC/Al composite produced by melt infiltration. Pre-sintered preforms, having different void fraction and pore size, where infiltrated with pure Al, in an argon atmosphere, at various temperatures. The infiltration was carried out using the contact and the capillary dip methods to study the mechanical properties and infiltration behaviour, respectively. The material exhibited a wide range of properties, depending on the ceramic content. Optimum tensile strengths of up to 480MPa were obtained for composites containing between 67 and 75% TiC, and infiltrated at 1050-1200$ sp circ$C. The extent of pre-sintering of the TiC was seen to play a crucial role in the strengthening of the microstructure, as well as the fracture mechanism by which the material failed. The elastic modulus was seen to increase with increasing TiC content, from values of 120 to 290GPa. The hardness also increased with TiC content, to values as high as 800kg/mm$ sp2,$ but decreased with higher infiltration temperatures due to the breakdown of the TiC network and grain coarsening. An experimental set-up was designed to measure the rate of infiltration by continually monitoring the weight changes of the preform as a result of the penetration of Al. Infiltration profiles were generated as a function of pore size, pore volume and temperature. At low temperatures, an incubation period was evident as a result of the transient contact angle between the two phases. Moreover, infiltration was inhibited at lower pore volume fraction. Finally, the Activation energy for the system increased from 90 to 450kJ/mol, with increasing pore size, suggesting a transition from a diffusion controlled process to one activated by a surface reaction for larger pore sizes.</description><creator>Muscat, Daniel</creator><contributor>Drew, R. A. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Titanium carbidealuminum composites by melt infiltration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz207.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m816p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hk71q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The magnetic properties of amorphous Fe$ sb{ rm x}$T$ sb{ rm 100-x}$ (T = Zr, Hf, Sc; 89 $ le$ x $ le$ 93) alloys have been systematically studied mainly by Mossbauer spectroscopy and magnetization measurements. Two magnetic transitions have been observed in Fe$ sb{92.5}$Hf$ sb{7.5}$ (the only FeHf alloys studied here) and FeZr alloys with Fe content between 90 and 93 at.%. We have ruled out the cluster models which attribute the second transition either to the ordering of AFM clusters or to the freezing of FM clusters, and confirmed that the second transition is due to the homogeneous freezing of the transverse spin components as a result of exchange frustration. On varying the frustration level, the evolution process from a ferromagnetic to a spin glass ordering has been observed. Fe$ sb{89}$Zr$ sb{11}$ essentially exhibits conventional ferromagnetic behavior, while Fe$ sb{90}$Zr$ sb{10}$ shows two magnetic transitions with a noncollinear ground state. As we increase the Fe content further (and thus raise the frustration level), the second transition temperature T$ sb{xy}$ and the noncollinearity of the ground state increase, whereas the first transition temperature T$ sb{c}$ drops. T$ sb{xy}$ and T$ sb{c}$ are expected to meet at x $ simeq$ 94.5, suggesting that Fe$ sb{94.5}$Zr$ sb{5.5}$ (which can not be made by melt-spinning) would be a spin glass. Fe$ sb{91}$Sc$ sb9$ is the most frustrated system studied here and it exhibits a single transition to a spin glass. Extrapolation of the magnetic properties of all systems gives a common limit as the Fe concentration approaches 100%, and suggests that amorphous Fe is a spin glass with the spin freezing temperature about 100K and an average iron moment of $ sim$1.6$ mu sb{B}$. Below the second transition, the transverse spin components are strongly correlated on a nearest neighbor scale in Fe$ sb{92}$Zr$ sb7$Sn, while the correlation length of the longitudinal components shows no detectable change on the local scal</description><creator>Ren, Hong, 1962-</creator><contributor>Ryan, D. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Effects of exchange frustration on the magnetic properties of iron-rich amorphous alloys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs53s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hk71q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js728</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Loosely supported cylinders subjected to cross-flow may undergo fluidelastic instability in the support inactive mode resulting in cylinder/support impacting. The cylinder/support interaction forces and, in turn, the resulting cylinder wear rates are strongly dependent on the detailed dynamical response. This Thesis examines the response of a loosely supported cylinder located in the third row of an otherwise rigid rotated triangular array. The feasibility and potential of a modern nonlinear dynamics approach to the understanding of the underlying dynamics is investigated. A nonlinear quasi-steady model was formulated to model the dynamical behaviour. The steady fluid force field, required as input to the model, was measured experimentally for a cylinder within a rotated triangular array. A lither stability analysis showed the cylinder stability behaviour to be strongly dependent on cylinder position. This result serves as a possible explanation for the rare occurrence of, theoretically predicted, multiple instability regions in experimental measurements. The nonlinear analysis uncovered two important transition routes to chaos. The first, a switching mechanism prevalent at the onset of impacting. The second and most important is the intermittency route to chaos. The theoretical model showed good agreement with experiments in predicting the bifurcation sequences and transitions to chaos--comparisons were quantified via fractal dimensions and saddle orbit distributions. The identification of type I intermittency leads to a quantitative estimate of the probability distribution of the length of laminar phases. It is shown that the duration of laminar phases and the associated frequency may provide better estimates of integration time and frequency for wear-rate computation.</description><creator>Mureithi, Njuki W.</creator><contributor>Paidousis, M. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Price, S. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Nonlinear dynamics of a loosely-supported cylinder in cross-flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db494.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js728</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv992</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is arranged in two distinct parts. The first part involves the construction of a novel dynamical scheme which is capable of generating the masses of the quarks and the elements of the Kobayashi-Maskawa matrix, and which does not rely upon the Higgs mechanism. The up quarks acquire their masses by coupling to a new heavy fermion via emission and reabsorption of a new scalar boson. The down quarks, on the other hand, obtain their masses via a correction to the up mass matrix as a result of an anomalous flavour changing interaction of the $W sp pm$. Extensions of the mass generation model are proposed and discussed. The second part involves the leading-log s study of hadron-hadron elastic scattering to order $ alpha sb{s} sp3$. By introducing wave functions, it is found that there are three types of form factor for the proton, and two for the pion. These form factors turn out to cancel the infrared divergence which occurs in quark-quark scattering. To this order in $ alpha sb{s}$, the amplitude of such elastic scattering is shown to have the form $ sim$(1 + log(s)($ alpha sb{o}$ + $ alpha sp prime t$ + $O(t sp2))$ for the imaginary part and a constant $ sim alpha sb{odd}$ for the real part, where s and t are the usual Mandelstam variables, and the $ alpha$'s are constants.</description><creator>Nguyen, Phuc Bao-Uyen</creator><contributor>Margeous, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Quark mass generation and mixing; and the next-to-leading order QCD calculation for hadron-hadron elastic collisions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj740.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv992</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h1069</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores ideas about human agency and conduct as these are expressed in the Indian epic known as the Mahabharata (the "Great Bharata"). Two concepts in particular retain our attention: daiva, the power that comes from the gods, and purusakara, the power that comes from human beings (purusas). One current of thought holds that human life and the course of history are governed exclusively by external agencies ("the gods" or chance). On the other hand, the epic also carries the commanding message that the lives of individuals and societies may be changed for the better through human initiative (purusakara) in accordance with the dharma, the moral order sanctioned by religious tradition. The issue is finally reduced to the question: who is the real agent of action? The analysis concludes that the question can only be resolved in the context of epic ideas about the nature of the human being. But humanity is simply a stage in the spiritual evolution of all life towards the realization of the unity of existence as the manifestation of a Supreme Person (paramapurusa; purusottama) or a Supreme Self (paramatman). Souls (atmans) are embodied as human beings at the stage when consciousness develops into the self-consciousness of an ego (ahamkara), which arrogates to itself the notion of self-determination or "freedom." In reality, however, the soul is not free but trapped in a cycle of rebirth, which can be broken only by the abandonment of all notion of agency, action and control over the fruits of the action. The epic therefore operates at two levels. In terms of the mundane tasks and responsibilities of daily life, particularly the responsibilities of the king, the human being is regarded as enjoying a modicum of freedom and self-determination to chart the course of his or her future evolution. From the higher perspective of the unity of all life, however, this self-concept is inherently flawed. The actions of such a being spring from unconscious motives prompted by the higher purposes that govern the course of the cosmos as a whole.</description><creator>Woods, Julian F. (Julian Forster)</creator><contributor>Young, Katherine K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>Destiny and human initiative in the Mahābhārata</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x20r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h1069</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n013w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Infections with Entamoeba histolytica are associated with impaired cell mediated immunity by an unknown mechanism. Macrophages are the most important cells in host defense against invasive amebiasis. The present study investigated the effect of E. histolytica on macrophage functions. Macrophages isolated from gerbils with amebic liver abscess and naive macrophages exposed to soluble amebic proteins induced profound alteration of eicosanoid formation both in cyclooxygenase and lipoxygenase pathways by enhanced PGE$ sb2$ and LTC$ sb4$ production. TNF-$ alpha$ production by macrophages was altered locally in amebic granulomas and at systemic sites during the infection and in response to amebic proteins stimulation in vitro. PGE$ sb2$ produced by macrophages in response to amebic proteins was involved in the down-regulation of TNF-$ alpha$ production. E. histolytica-induced dysfunction of macrophage cytotoxicity against amebae and tumor cells occurred by suppressing NO and by enhancing PGE$ sb2$ production. Amebic proteins suppressed the induction. of IFN-$ gamma$-induced bone marrow macrophage class II MHC Ia molecule synthesis and I-A$ beta$ mRNA expression by stimulating PGE$ sb2$ production. Taken together, these results demonstrate that E. histolytica induced PGE$ sb2$ production plays a central role in the suppression of macrophage effector and accessory cell functions.</description><creator>Wang, Wei</creator><contributor>Chadee, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Entamoeba histolytica.</subject><subject>Amebiasis.</subject><subject>Macrophages</subject><title>The effect of Entamoeba histolytica on macrophage functions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj76j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n013w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q788g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA), an immunoglobulin (Ig) superfamily member, functions as an adhesion molecule in vitro. This thesis reports that nonspecific cross-reacting antigen (NCA), a CEA family member, can mediate Ca$ sp{++}$-independent, homotypic intercellular adhesion in vitro. Heterotypic adhesion studies demonstrate that CEA can cross-interact with NCA; however, neither NCA nor CEA can interact with other Ig superfamily members such as neural cell adhesion molecule (NCAM) and myelin-associated glycoprotein. This specificity was used to investigate the mechanism of CEA-CEA binding using CEA truncated and CEA/NCAM chimeric constructs. A novel model has been proposed in which double reciprocal interactions between the V-like domains and C-like domains of antiparallel CEA molecules result in strong binding between CEA on apposing cell surfaces. Furthermore, the specificity of a library of anti-CEA monoclonal antibodies was defined; their effects on CEA-mediated adhesion further support the CEA-binding model.</description><creator>Zhou, Hua, 1963-</creator><contributor>Stanners, Clifford P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Molecular mechanisms of intercellular adhesion mediated by carcinoembryonic antigen family members</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr99t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q788g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg097</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the fundamental assumptions made in recent continuous-time equilibrium models of the term structure of interest rates. It finds that the number and the stochastic processes of state variables are strikingly different from those assumed in the literature. It develops a three-factor empirical term structure model, based on 22 years of cross-maturity time series data. The results show that the price differences, between the well-known Vasicek, and Cox, Ingersoll and Ross models and the three-factor empirical model, for interest-rate sensitive securities are of substantial economic significance.</description><creator>Zhang, Hua, 1962-</creator><contributor>Whitmore, G. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Interest rates -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>The dynamic behaviour of the term structure of interest rates and its implication for interest-rate sensitive asset pricing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j16f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg097</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gx72c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis applies the consensus paradigm to an important problem in model-based vision, that of primitive extraction. Primitive extraction is the process of finding geometric primitives in geometric data. Such data are obtained directly by active sensors such as laser rangefinders, by processes that operate on passive sensor data to create depth information such as stereo vision, or by simple edge detection and thresholding of intensity images. A geometric primitive is a curve or surface which can be described by an implicit function. We show that the best solution to this problem is at the global optimum of a cost function which often has very many local optima. This global optimum represents the best consensus in the data with regard to the extraction problem. The consensus paradigm attempts to find this global optimum by randomly choosing small subsets of the data and evaluating the cost function for each subset. We apply the consensus paradigm to this problem by randomly sampling minimal subsets. This is a simple and general way of finding the best consensus. For primitive extraction a minimal subset is the smallest number of points necessary to define a geometric primitive. The issues of how to choose the appropriate cost function, how to decide on the number of random samples, and how to convert between a minimal subset and the parameter vector that defines the primitive are explored in detail. While effective, the consensus approach using random sampling often requires a large number of random samples, and therefore a large number of cost function evaluations. We address this problem by combining the consensus paradigm with a genetic algorithm that uses the minimal subset representation. A genetic algorithm is an optimization method based on the evolutionary metaphor. It has been successfully applied to difficult optimization problems, where the cost function is noisy, multi-dimensional, and has many local minima. In our applications the genetic algorithm is able to use local geometric information to produce a global solution in a way that usually avoids the problem of premature commitment. The resulting method often requires far fewer cost function evaluations than the random sampling approach. Some ways of implementing these algorithms on different parallel architectures are described.</description><creator>Roth, Gerhard, 1952-</creator><contributor>Levine, M. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A consensus approach to primitive extraction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h107k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gx72c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc01k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study, biochemical techniques were used with immunological techniques to dissect the specific T cell reactivities to the PG molecule. Two T cell lines and two T cell hybridomas that belong to the T helper subset TH1 were isolated. The line JY.A recognized only the human fetal PG while the other line (JY.D) and the two T cell hybridomas (TH5 and TH14) recognized PG of all the different origins tested, except the rat chondrosarcoma and the mouse PG. The three latter T cells were found to recognize immunodominant T cell epitopes on the G1 domain of PG and cross-reacted with link protein. The presence of KS chain(s) close to T cell epitopes restricted the reactivity of the two T cell hybridomas. The location of one T cell hybridoma epitope (TH5) was contained within a peptide of twenty eight amino acids in the B region of G1. T cell line JY.A can induce early pathological change characteristic of rheumatoid arthritis when injected in the knee joint of naive BALB/c mice.</description><creator>Leroux, Jean-Yves</creator><contributor>Poole, A. Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Immunological studies of T lymphocytes in the proteoglycan-induced arthritis in the mouse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc69m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc01k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):30350</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>