<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:50:09Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hz65r" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hz65r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:30:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cyclic AMP has been implicated as a mediator of the massive intestinal fluid secretion in cholera. Fluid loss as intestinal secretion contributes to the pathogenesis of irreversibility in shock. It was of interest to investigate whether cyclic AMP mediates fluid loss following ischemic in jury to the intestine or whether the fluid loss is due to changes in permeability of the intestine.  Ileal mucosal cyclic AMP levels and fluid and electrolyte fluxes were followed before and after a one-hour superior mesenteric artery occlusion (S.M.A.O.) in dogs. Acute (two-hour) and chronic (five-day) follow-up studies were performed. The intestinal permeability to radio tagged I131 serum albumen was tested immediately and three days after a one-hour S.M.A.O. Decreased fluid and electrolyte absorption and decreasing, issue levels of cyclic AMP, were observed during ischemia. Release of the S.M.A.O. was associated with increasing concentrations of cyclic AMP and secretion of fluid and electrolytes. A passive fluid filtration mechanism is in operation in the period immediately following S.M.A.O. There is massive fluid secretion coupled with permeability of the intestine to RISA, in contrast to results reported with cholera. However, at three days post S.M.A.O., copious secretion is still evident, yet the permeability of the intestine has returned to normal. It may be at this stage that elevated levels of cyclic AMP are the controlling effector of the observed continuing fluid secretion.</description><creator>Schofield, Charlotte A.</creator><contributor>McArdle, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Cyclic AMP and fluid and electrolyte fluxes across the ischemic ileal mucosa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb48t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hz65r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>