<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:00:34Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43850" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848r05s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Apoptosis is a phenomenon conserved from flies to humans,  crucial in development and in the maintenance of cellular homeostasis. Throughout  the years various molecules have been identified as critical regulators of apoptotic  signaling. Among these, the serine/threonine kinase Akt has been demonstrated to  play a pivotal role in the regulation of cell survival by phosphorylating a broad  range of effectors. This thesis looks at the regulation of anti and pro-apototic Akt  substrates, and examines the survival-promoting activity of Akt in neural tumor  cells and neurons. In the first section of this thesis I demonstrated, using a  recombinant adenovirus-based approach, that Akt is necessary for the NGF-dependent  survival of differentiated neuronal-like PC12 (pheochromocytoma) cells and  undifferentiated PC12 cells. Furthermore, I suggested that Akt possibly performs  this function via the repression of the c-jun N-terminal kinase (JNK) pathway,  upstream of JNK, as overexpression of kinase-inactive Akt activates  JNK. In the second section of this thesis, I identified mixed-lineage  kinase-3 (MLK-3) as a substrate of Akt. I showed that Akt associates with the  JIP/MLK-3/JNK scaffold complex, and that it inactivates MLK-3 by phosphorylating  T477. This study strongly suggests that in certain cellular systems, Akt represses  the JNK signaling pathway and apotosis via the inhibition of MLK-3. Finally, in the third section, we discovered that Akt  phosphorylates and interacts with the caspase inhibitor, X-linked inhibitor of  apoptosis (XIAP). The phosphorylation of XIAP occurs on serine 87. We also showed  that PI3-K/Akt synergize with XIAP to promote sympathetic neuron  survival. These studies contribute to the understanding of Akt's  anti-apoptotic mechanisms and might also help design highly specific therapeutic  approaches.</description><creator>Boudreau, Mathieu</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Substrates and biochemical mechanisms by which Akt promotes cellular survival</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd48c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r05s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gg89h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation consists of three essays each of which  considers a political economy problem. In the first essay, we study a local  government who can engage in both grabbing hand and helping hand activities with  respect to the firms under its jurisdiction. We find that there are two dynamic  paths for this economy. It can either stagnate or take off, i.e., grow without  bound. The path actually taken depends on three variables: If the initial capital  stock, tax share of the local government, or the cost of covering up corruption is  sufficiently high, the economy takes off. Otherwise it stagnates. In the second essay, we model a situation where the government  tries to help a distressed industry, but it needs to know the firms' adjustment  costs to set its level of support. We show that lobbying can help the firms credibly  reveal their adjustment costs, when the support takes the form of a subsidy or a  tariff. Furthermore, the more firms there are in the industry, the smaller is the  amount of lobbying necessary to convey information, and the higher is the social  welfare. When lobbying is effort intensive rather than expenditure intensive,  subsidies for high adjustment cost industries go up, and subsidies for low  adjustment cost industries go down with the number of firms in the  industry. The third essay considers a game between an elite with political  power and the rest of the population. Foreseeing that transition to majority rule  will lead to redistribution, the elite engages in activities that decrease the  efficiency of the public sector to discourage redistribution. We find that initial  inequality in the economy increases corruption and decreases redistribution. The  model's predictions are consistent with the empirical evidence that inequality and  corruption are correlated, and that corrupt governments are smaller.</description><creator>Dalgiç, Hüseyin Engin</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Political science</subject><subject>Economics</subject><title>Essays in political economy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t686f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gg89h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hq11t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interictal spikes are spontaneous neuronal discharges that occur  between epileptic seizures, and that constitute a specific marker of epilepsy. The  topic of our doctoral research is to localize in a noninvasive manner the regions of  the brain responsible for generating the spikes. Such information is of great  interest in the presurgical evaluation for pharmacoresistant  epilepsy. In this context, we have studied the possibility of using a  combination of two techniques, namely electroencephalography (EEG) and magnetic  resonance imaging (MRI). Specifically, we have investigated three tracks for the  combination of EEG and MRI. First, anatomical information from MRI can be used for improving  EEG source localization. Our example is the modelling of postsurgical brain and  skull defects, which affect the conductive properties of the head. Second, the EEG can be recorded inside the MR scanner and  thereby allows the investigation of spontaneous epileptic spikes with functional MRI  (fMRI). We evaluated the quality of EEG within the scanner, and measured the spatial  and temporal fMRI response to spikes. Third, the information from the two modalities can be combined  in order to benefit from both the good spatial resolution of fMRI and the excellent  temporal resolution of EEG. We have proposed to build statistical maps for EEG  source localization in order to identify common areas of activation in EEG and  fMRI.</description><creator>Bénar, Christian-George</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Combining magnetic resonance imaging and electroencephalography in the investigation of interictal epileptic spikes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z131q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq11t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f4625955</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The three essays of this thesis touch a variety of topics in  financial econometrics. The first is an empirical investigation of aspects of  transactions dynamics of currency futures. Based on the analysis of years of  transactions data, the author describes the seasonal dynamic component of trade and  price durations of futures and then analyses dynamics of durations using the  stochastic conditional duration model (SCD). The second essay develops a model for the robust analysis of  time series. Asymptotic properties of the parameter estimates of this model are  established. The model is applied to the analysis of dynamics of conditional  quantiles of the quadratic variation in currency exchange rates. Forecasting  properties of the model are also evaluated. Finally; the third essay uses recent advances in the theory of  extremal events to analyse the effects of institutional changes in financial markets  on the extremal behaviour of major stock indices, as far as this behaviour is  reflected in the evolution of Hill's estimator of the tail index.</description><creator>Zernov, Serguei</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Econometrics</subject><title>Three essays in financial econometrics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k384.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4625955</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hj58z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is interest, supported by successful field trials, in the  use of satellite communications at the Ka band (30/20 GHz) and beyond to meet  emerging demand for broadband interactive multimedia services. The key advantages of  operation at Ka band are availability of bandwidth and favorable implications for  terminal size, cost and mobility. We study two problems related to bandwidth  management of the uplink in a multibeam, CDMA-based, GEO satellite. Our focus is on  the delivery of data services with rigid constraints on bit-error rate and elastic  constraints on data rate. The first of the two problems concerns the design of the  coverage areas of the satellite beams. We were interested specifically in the  adaptation of beam shape to inhomogeneity in the geographic distribution of the user  population, and in the impact of beam shaping on the set of transmission rates that  are compatible with prescribed constraints on transmission powers and  signal-to-interference ratios. Assuming that the spatial distribution of users is  known, we construct an algorithm which computes beam coverage regions to equilibrate  the per-beam user populations. The impact on the set of feasible bit-rate  allocations is quantified through numerical experiments. Comparison with uniform  beam shapes suggests that the adaptive approach is superior in terms of the number  of concurrent transmissions that can be supported. The second problem concerns the allocation of bit rates in a  setting where user bit-rate requirements are assumed defined by averages over moving  windows of constant length. We use a frame-based channel model characterized by  fading coefficients which, though statistically variable, are assumed known to the  controller at the start of each frame. The implied temporal elasticity in  quality-of-service provides opportunity to achieve economies in transmitted power.  The value of such opportunity is quantified by comparison of two extreme cases. We  develop an approximate system model which allows optimization of the rate allocation  when the number of users is small, and a heuristic which is useful when the number  of users is not small. The associated performance results confirm the inverse  relationship between the per-bit energy required for transmission and the length of  the averaging window.</description><creator>Okello, Dorothy Kabagaju</creator><contributor>Kaplan, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Resource management in CDMA-based satellite networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q9462.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj58z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2685667</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first part of the research deals with the estimation of  extreme rainfalls for locations where rainfall records are sufficiently available  (gaged sites); the second part is concerned with cases where rainfall data are  limited (partially-gaged sites); and finally the third part involves the most  complex situation where rainfall data are unavailable (ungaged  sites). For gaged sites, two methods were developed for estimating the  annual extreme (AE) rainfalls based on the simple scaling behaviour of the first  three non-central moments (NCMs) of the AE rainfall processes and using the  Generalized Extreme Value (GEV) distribution as the parent distribution. The first  estimation method was called one-moment (OM) method since it only relied on the  first-order NCM of AE rainfall series in the computation of the rainfall quantiles,  while the second method was called three-moment (TM) procedure since it used all  first three NCMs of AE rainfalls in the estimation of the quantiles. For partially-gaged and ungaged sites, a new approach to  defining rainfall homogeneous regions has been proposed based on the similarity of  rainfall occurrences at different raingage stations. In addition, a Principal  Component Analysis technique was used to assess the similarity of raingages and to  delineate homogeneous regions. On the basis of the proposed method for identifying rainfall  homogeneous regions, two new methods (PG-1 and PG-2) were developed for estimating  annual maximum (AM) rainfalls at partially gauged sites. These methods were also  based on the scaling properties of AM rainfall series for different  durations. For ungaged sites, three methods (UG-1, UG-2, and NR) were  proposed for estimating AM rainfalls. Method UG-1 was based on the NCMs of AM  rainfalls at an ungaged site that were computed by direct interpolation of the  corresponding NCM values from the gaged sites within the same homogeneous region.  Method UG-2 used the pooled data set from all gaged sites in the homogeneous region  for this computation. On the other hand, the NR method estimated the NCMs of AM  rainfalls for an ungaged site using the regional regression between the first three  NCMs and the number of rainfall occurrence (NR) values that were interpolated from  the NR values of the gaged sites. Finally, to assess the uncertainty of extreme rainfall  estimates, two new methods (CI-1 and CI-2) were developed for computing the  confidence limits (CLs) based on these estimated values. The proposed methods were  based on the bootstrap technique and the scaling properties of the NCMs of extreme  rainfall series.</description><creator>Nguyen,Tan Danh</creator><contributor>Nguyen, Van-Thanh-Van (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Regional estimation of extreme rainfall events</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mc52v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2685667</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j71k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Whey protein isolates (WPI) have been indicated to have potent  cholesterol lowering and antioxidative properties. Such effects, however, are not  consistently observed, which could be the result of major differences in the  processing, isolation and composition of WPI. Moreover, the mechanisms of action or  the bioactive component(s) in WPI are poorly understood although the relatively high  cysteine content in WPI has been suggested to play an important role. Although high  dietary cysteine has been shown to lower plasma homocysteine concentrations, the  impact of WPI in this regard has not been investigated. The overall objective of  this thesis was to examine the antioxidative and plasma cholesterol and homocysteine  lowering properties of two WPI that were produced via different industrial  processing and isolation techniques with the milk protein, casein, used as the  control protein. We also examined for the mechanism(s) of action of WPI in terms of  possible antioxidative, and plasma cholesterol and homocysteine lowering effects. In  this regard, the intake of bovine serum albumin (BSA), a major cysteine-rich whey  protein was also studied since this protein has been implicated as a key bioactive  component for the antioxidant effects of WPI. Four studies were performed. The first  involved the characterization of a variety of commercially prepared WPI by high  performance capillary electrophoresis for identification of two WPI products that  showed major differences in protein composition for subsequent feeding trials. Most  of the WPI had similar characteristic electrophoretic profiles, however, significant  differences in protein and macronutrient (Ca, Mg, P) composition were noted in two  commercial WPI that were chosen as the test proteins in subsequent feeding trials.  In the first two feeding studies, hamsters were fed different commercial WPI or milk  protein (BSA or casein) containing diets that were either matched or unmatched in  terms of macro</description><creator>Nicodemo, Antonio</creator><contributor>Kubow, Stan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Antioxidants -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Whey.</subject><subject>Golden hamster -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Hypocholesteremia.</subject><subject>Blood lipids.</subject><title>An investigation of the hypocholesterolemic and antioxidative effects of whey protein isolates in the Golden Syrian hamster /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg238.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j71k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225b56f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>All eukaryotic mRNAs of nuclear origin are modified with a 5'  cap and a 3' poly(A) tail. These structures are recognized by translation factors,  which are responsible for the proper targeting of a ribosome to the mRNA.  Translation factors binding to the 5 ' end of mRNA are well characterized. Here, we  focus on the involvement of the 3' poly(A) tail in mediating translational control;  namely via its recruitment of the poly(A) binding protein (PABP) and its interacting  partners. PABP interacts with eIF4G, a canonical translation factor, bridging the 5'  and 3' ends of the mRNA and effectively circularizing it. Recently, two PABP  interacting proteins (Paips) were also identified in our laboratory; Paip1 and  Paip2. Paip1 is a translational stimulator, whereas Paip2, by competing with both  Paip1 and poly(A) for binding to PABP, is an inhibitor. To better understand this  mechanism of translation inhibition, we performed an in-depth characterization of  the Paip2/PABP interaction using Far Western and Surface Plasmon Resonance based  (Biacore) assays. We defined two PABP interacting motifs (PAMs) in Paip2, termed  PAM1 and PAM2, and determined the stoichiometry of the Paip2/PABP interaction to be  2:1. PAM 1 (aa 22--75) interacts with an affinity of 0.66 nM to a region encompassed  by RRMs 2 and 3 of PABP, and constitutes the Paip2 active site. PAM2 (aa 105--120)  binds to the C-terminus of PABP with a K d of 74 nM, and has no effect on the  PABP/poly(A) interaction or on translation, To elucidate the regulatory pathways  impinging on Paip2 function, we analyzed whether Paip2 undergoes phosphorylation and  ubiquitination. We detected these modifications on Paip2, but were unable to  discover their regulation and downstream effects. Lastly, we examined the importance  of circularization for translation initiation in vitro. We generated a single point  mutant of PABP (M161A) incapable of interacting with elF4G. This mutant was added to  poly(A) dependent transla</description><creator>Kahvejian, Avak</creator><contributor>Sonenberg, Nahum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Characterization of the poly(A) binding protein and its interacting partners : understanding the poly(A) tail's role in mRNA translation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v36j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b56f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h4894</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anthelmintic resistance is a major problem in livestock, and  while it has been slower to emerge in cattle, there are reports of its occurrence.  Three broad-spectrum anthelmintics are available for use, and one mechanism of  resistance that is common to all is target site alteration. Glutamate-gated chloride  channels (GluCls) are an important target for macrocyclic lactone anthelmintics  (MLs), while beta-tubulin represents the benzimidazole (BZ) target. The objectives  of this thesis were to determine whether GluCls are involved in ML resistance in the  cattle parasite Cooperia oncophora , and whether beta-tubulin is involved in BZ and  ML resistance. Two isolates of C. oncophora were used. In a fecal egg-count  reduction test, ivermectin was found to be 100% effective against one isolate (IVS),  and only 77.8% effective against the second isolate (IVR). Two full-length GluCl  cDNAs, encoding GluClalpha3 and beta subunits, were cloned. These subunits share  high sequence identity with similar GluCl subunits from Haemonchus contortus and  Caenorhabditis elegans. Genetic variability analysis of the two genes showed  significant differences in allele frequencies between IVS and IVR worms at the  GluClalpha3 gene, but not the GluClbeta gene, suggesting that the GluClalpha3 gene  is involved in ivermectin resistance. Sequencing of full-length GluCl subunit cDNAs  from IVS and IVR worms revealed the presence of mutations in the N-terminal domains.  Mutations in the GluClalpha3 caused modest but significant reductions in glutamate,  ivermectin and moxidectin sensitivity, while mutations in the GluClbeta abolished  glutamate sensitivity. Of the three mutations identified in the IVR GluClalpha3, the  L256F mutation accounted for the difference in glutamate and ivermectin response  between IVS and IVR GluClalpha3 channels. Two beta-tubulin isotypes cloned from C.  oncophora were found to share a high homology with beta-tubulin isotypes from other  trichostrongylids. Gen</description><creator>Njue, Annette Igandu</creator><contributor>Prichard, Roger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Ivermectin.</subject><subject>Anthelmintics.</subject><subject>Chloride channels.</subject><subject>Cattle -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Cooperia.</subject><subject>Drug resistance.</subject><title>Mechanisms of anthelmintic resistance in Cooperia oncophora, a nematode parasite of cattle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q52k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h4894</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t243c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oligomerization of membrane proteins in response to external  stimulation is a common event in cell signalling for generating functional  diversity. In the case of the heptahelical receptor (HHR) superfamily, the  traditional view has been that these receptors function as monomers, although a  number of recent studies have suggested that this class of membrane proteins may  exist as dimers or higher order oligomers, and play an important role in signalling.  We addressed this question using as a model the somatostatin receptor (SSTR) family,  which comprises five molecular subtypes (SSTR1--5). Receptors were expressed at  physiological levels in CHO-K1 cells and characterized pharmacologically and  physically by photobleaching fluorescence resonance energy transfer (pbFRET) in  intact cells. We first demonstrated homo-oligomerization of SSTR5 by functional  complementation of two partially active mutant receptors, whose function was rescued  by coexpression. pbFRET analysis showed that hSSTR5 exists in the basal state as a  monomer and that activation by somatostatin (SST) induces oligomerization in a  time-dependent manner. In contrast, expression of SSTR5 at higher levels in CHO-K1  cells revealed the presence of an appreciable level of preformed oligomers, although  SST could still induce dose-dependent extra-formation of receptor oligomers. Next,  we investigated SSTR heteromerization, and showed that SSTR5 forms heteromers with  some (SSTR1,2,3) but not other (SSTR4) subtypes of SSTRs. In particular, the  hSSTR1/5 oligomer displayed altered pharmacological properties such as binding  affinity and agonist-induced receptor regulation, as compared to individual  receptors. Furthermore, heteromerization between unrelated HHRs was examined using  SSTR5 and the dopamine receptor (D2R) as models. SSTR5/D2R heteromers were formed  following application of either or both agonist molecules, and displayed altered  binding and signalling properties compared to the indiv</description><creator>Rocheville, Magalie</creator><contributor>Patel, Yogesh C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Oligomerization of somatostatin receptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt36n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t243c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bc052</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this program of research was to study how  socialization agents can facilitate children's internalization of important but  uninteresting activities. Self-determination theory (SDT; Deci &amp; Ryan, 1980,  1985b, 1991, 2000) posits that autonomy is essential in fostering optimal (i.e.  integrated) internalization. It was thus hypothesized that autonomy-support would  facilitate internalization while offering rewards for compliance would thwart it. In  the present thesis, two experimental studies and one longitudinal study compared the  effects of autonomy-support and rewards on children's internalization and general  functioning. In Study 1 and 2, we asked children to perform a tedious task in an  autonomy-supportive manner or under a reward contingency. Children's affect,  perception of the task's value, and free-choice engagement served as dependent  measures. ANOVA results revealed positive effects associated with autonomy-support  whereas no effect for rewards was found. Moreover, split-group correlational  analyses showed that autonomy-support led to integrated self-regulation, whereas  rewards were associated with behaviors incongruent from affect and  value. Study 3 examined the over-time impact of maternal  autonomy-support on children's adjustment in school. Autonomy-support, rewards, and  other parenting dimensions were measured when children were 5 years old. Regression  analyses revealed that autonomy-support was positively related to teacher-rated  adjustment and reading achievement when children were 8 years old whereas the use of  rewards was unrelated to these outcomes. Supplemental analyses also revealed that  autonomy-support was associated with children's greater integration across social  and academic domains. Together, these results highlight the significance of  autonomy-support in early childhood.</description><creator>Joussemet, Mireille</creator><contributor>Koestner, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Autonomy in children.</subject><subject>Internalization.</subject><subject>Motivation (Psychology) in children.</subject><subject>Adjustment (Psychology) in children.</subject><subject>Mother and child.</subject><title>Facilitating children's integrated internalization : the differential effects of rewards and autonomy-support</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q6870.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc052</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cd66b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Translational control is an important means of regulating gene  expression. Development of the Drosophila germ line relies on translational  regulation to differentially express maternal mRNAs, allowing it to develop  distinctly from the soma. One of the critical factors required for germ cell  development and function is the conserved DEAD-box RNA helicase Vasa (Vas). The  research presented in this thesis examines the role of Vas in translational  regulation during Drosophila germ line development. A two-hybrid screen conducted  with Vas identified a translation initiation factor eIF5B (dIF2), as a direct  interactor. Mutations were created in eIF5B and were found to enhance the vas mutant  phenotypes of reduced germ cell numbers, and posterior segmentation defects,  suggesting a functional interaction between these factors in vivo. In order to  further understand the biological significance of the Vas-eIF5B interaction, the  region of Vas required for eIF5B-binding was mapped and then specifically disrupted.  Reduction of Vas-eIF5B binding using a transgenic approach, virtually eliminated  germ cell formation, while having only a moderate effect on the somatic requirement  of Vas in posterior segmentation. In addition, Vas-eIF5B interaction was found to be  required for the establishment of polarity within the egg during oogenesis, likely  through direct regulation of gurken (grk) mRNA. We concluded that through  interaction with eIF5B, Vas plays a critical role in translational regulation in the  germ line. In addition, another Drosophila DEAD-box protein, highly similar to Vas,  called Belle (Bel) was characterized. Mutations in bel were found to also affect the  germ line, leading to both female and male sterility. Like Vas, Bel is implicated in  translation initiation, however bel is an essential gene, with a requirement for  growth, whose function is not restricted to the germ line. Our data suggest that Bel  may be a nucleocytoplasmic shuttling protein,</description><creator>Johnstone, Oona</creator><contributor>Lasko, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Genetic translation.</subject><subject>Drosophila -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>Characterization of the Vasa-eIF5B interaction during Drosophila development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w0467.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cd66b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v5937</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study consisted of a series of experiments designed to test  the hypothesis that exposure to extremely low frequency (ELF) electric and magnetic  fields (EMF), similar to those generated by power transmission lines, can modify the  response to photoperiod in dairy cows. Thirty two Holstein cows, 16 pregnant and  lactating and 16 non-pregnant and non-lactating, maintained under short photoperiod  (8 h light, 16 h dark), were exposed to an electric field of 10 kV/m and a magnetic  field of 30 muTesla for 16 h/d, using cross-over experimental designs with  three-period sequences. These exposure conditions resembled those prevalent under a  735 kV line carrying an extreme current load. Feed consumption, milk yield and  composition, body weight, circulating concentrations of melatonin, prolactin, IGF-1  and growth hormone were assessed, as well as estrous cycle traits. A positive  association was found between EMF exposure and feed consumption, uncorrected milk  yield at the end of the exposure period and blood concentration of IGF-1. EMF  exposure was also associated with an increase in blood prolactin concentration and  decreased melatonin levels during the photophase in lactating pregnant cows.  Non-lactating cows exposed to EMF showed longer estrous cycles. It was concluded  that exposure to ELF EMF similar to those found under power transmission lines under  extreme conditions of load elicits a biological response in dairy cows. Some aspects  of this response are consistent with the hypothesis of a modification of the  response to photoperiod.</description><creator>Rodriguez, Maria A. (Maria Angeles), 1958-</creator><contributor>Downey, B. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Dairy cattle -- Physiology.</subject><subject>ELF electromagnetic fields -- Physiological effect.</subject><title>Physiological responses to 60 Hz electric and magnetic fields in dairy cows under short photoperiod conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v3592.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v5937</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c8032</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, resource allocation problems relevant to  multicarrier DSL environments are considered. The resources in a multicarrier DSL  environment are bandwidth (i.e., subcarriers), the power allocated, the bits loaded  and possibly the coding scheme used on each subcarrier. The major impairments in DSL  environments are crosstalk and external noise . Crosstalk (predictable and  controllable) is the interference caused by other DSL users sharing the same medium.  External Noise (unpredictable and uncontrollable) consists of relatively high energy  bursts due to electromagnetic interference from physical phenomena, electrical  switches, motors and home appliances which are invariably present in the close  vicinity of DSL modems. In current DSL applications, Crosstalk is kept in control by  specifying a fixed peakpower constraint (based on the worst-case) which each user  has to obey---a technique known as Static Spectrum Management (SSM). This simplifies  the resource allocation to a single-user optimization problem. But the worst-case  peak power constraint is overly restrictive and results in poorer rates. Recently  Dynamic Spectrum Management (DSM) techniques which dynamically vary the multiuser  power allocation for crosstalk control instead of using fixed peak power constraint  have proven to provide much better rates. This improvement however comes at the cost  of dealing with a more complicated multiuser optimization problem. On the other hand, due to its unpredictability, external noise  (and RFI pickup) has been combated with the use of a suitable safety  margin. Based on application and scenario, Resource Allocation is either  performed with the objective of Rate maximization (at a fixed margin) or Margin  maximization (at a fixed rate) since each of the quantities indirectly imposes a cap  on the other. But in both rate maximizing and margin maximizing resource  allocation algorithms available in literature the bits loaded were always  constrained to integers because most scalable modulation schemes such as QAM or PSK  support integer bit/symbol. It was initially believed that most (not all) of the  granularity losses (due to the integer bit constraint) could be recovered through  'bit-rounding' and 'energy re-scaling'. But this was observed only for the total  power constrained case. With the advent of peak power constraint, we show that the  room for optimization in the energy domain is severely restricted and granularity  losses constitute a significant percentage of the achievable data rate. To recover  these losses, we propose the Adaptive Reed Solomon aided Fine Granularity Loading  (ARSFGL) scheme---a scheme that jointly optimizes the power, bit and code  allocation. For achieving near-continuous rate adaptation, the family of Reed  Solomon (RS) codes has been used for their low redundancy, high flexibility in  correction capability and highly programmable architecture. Simulation results with  realistic VDSL-DMT systems with the currently standardized SSM framework show more  than 20% improvement in rate achieved for most cases. The extension of ARSFGL technique to multiuser (DSM) scenarios  results in a purely distributed scheme which provides rates better or equal to the  rates achieved by the centralized, optimal (much more complicated) multiuser  integer-bit loading scheme. Further in this work a multiuser margin maximization algorithm  is developed. Near-continuous rates provided by the ARSFGL scheme allow continuous  bit loading assumption for simplicity. Prior to this work, no multiuser margin  maximization algorithm existed, even though the importance of margin maximization is  well-recognized. Most existing single-user margin maximization algorithms rely on a  fixed crosstalk assumption. But in multiuser (DSM) scenarios each user's power  allocation dynamically determines other user's crosstalk. With direct extension of  single-user algorithms in multiuser (DSM) scenarios, one user's margin maximization  can lead to the failure of other users in meeting their target rates  . We begin by exploring the favorable monotonicity and fairness  properties that multi-user margin exhibits over a multiuser rate region and use them  to formulate a box-constrained non-linear least squares (NLSQ) problem that can be  solved by using a scaled gradient trust region approach with Broyden Jacobian  update. This algorithm efficiently converges to a solution providing the best common  equal margin to all users while explicitly guaranteeing that each user's target rate  requirement is satisfied. The algorithm requires only minimal coordination among  users, which makes it suitable for practical implementation.</description><creator>Panigrahi, Saswat</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Resource allocation for multicarrier DSL systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50ts18m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c8032</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p519m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Five hundred years of Christian martyrdom are represented in the  Ecclesiae militantis triumphi (1583). Engraved by Giovanni Battista Cavalieri, the  series that was bound into a book reproduces a fresco cycle in the church of San  Stefano Rotondo in Rome. While the church belonged to the Jesuit German-Hungarian  College, the book accompanied priests in their proselytizing mission in Northern  Europe. This thesis will look at the function of the book in relation to various  audiences, in different viewing contexts. Analyzed primarily in relation to the  intended Jesuit audience as an object of devotion, the book will also be inserted  within the Early Christian revival promoted by Gregory XIII (1572-1585). Finally, it  will be looked at in relation to an audience composed of individuals interested in  factual knowledge about Early Christian history and in the martyr as a historical  figure. A general endeavor of the thesis is to situate the Ecclesiae militantis  triumphi in relation to late sixteen-century representations of martyrdom, both  Catholic and Protestant, as well as in relation to other contemporary Roman printed  works.</description><creator>Tsoumis, Karine</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Christian martyrs in art</subject><subject>Cavalieri, Giovanni Battista, ca. 1525-1601. Ecclesiae militantis triumphi</subject><subject>Jesuit art -- Italy -- Rome -- History</subject><subject>Prints, Italian -- 16th century</subject><title>Giovanni Battista Cavalieri's Ecclesiae militantis triumphi : Jesuits, martyrs, print, and the counter-reformation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dm88b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p519m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860751b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this small qualitative study, the researcher explores how  four families involved in resource foster care services conceptualize concurrent  planning in the child welfare system. Analysis of the four semi-structured  transcribed interviews revealed four dominant themes: hope and optimism that  resource foster care could be a rewarding alternative to further infertility  treatment; anger and fear of disruption related to birth family visits;  identification of the foster child as their own; and uncertainty regarding resource  foster care team rules, roles, and responsibilities. Each theme was influenced by an  attachment to the child they were fostering and the fear of losing that  child. The findings suggest that resource foster parents do not fully  embrace concurrent planning as a philosophy of care that supports and works towards  the best interests of children. Practice principles central to concurrent planning  were often abandoned as a result of intense identification with adoptive parenthood  status. The researcher has included a number of recommendations with  respect to future studies, training needs, and recruitment strategies. The  conclusion states that in the best interests of children, resource foster parents  must fully embrace the concept of concurrent planning defined within child welfare  context and legislation.</description><creator>Melrose, Heather</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Adoptive parents -- Canada -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Foster home care -- Canada -- Case studies</subject><subject>Foster parents -- Canada -- Case studies.</subject><title>How do resource foster parents conceptualize concurrent planning?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dw100.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860751b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jr75w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this research is to improve the analysis of  musical sounds in comparison to traditional additive analysis, i.e. Fourier  Analysis. Namely, the focus of this study is to improve the tracking of  time-evolving partials. Traditional analysis methods assume constant amplitudes and  frequencies over each successive frame in which a signal is analyzed. Tracking the  time-evolution of these partials, however, can require the implementation of complex  probabilistic techniques. This thesis presents an alternative method in which the  Ambiguity Function, a distribution in both time and frequency, is used to create a  clearer, more accurate representation that requires fewer complex methods to track  partials. Through the use of a more accurate spectral representation and the  inclusion of a chirp rate parameter, partials may be more readily followed based  upon spectral parameters alone. This new method that is presented will build upon  the traditional methods by first employing Fourier analysis to identify partials,  and then utilizing the Analytic Signal and Ambiguity Function to improve individual  spectral parameter estimations and partial tracking. The overall intent of this work  is that through this method, one may create an improved spectral model that is more  useful to musical analysis.</description><creator>Kosek, Paul C.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Sound -- Recording and reproducing.</subject><subject>Music -- Acoustics and physics.</subject><subject>Signal processing.</subject><title>Improved analysis of musical sounds using time-frequency distributions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt224.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr75w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pw60m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Complementing field research among severely disadvantaged  minority groups, the present laboratory analogue investigates how the clarity of a  group member's cultural (collective) identity is related to positive feelings about  oneself and one's performance. Participants were assigned to a clear, conflicted, or  unclear collective identity condition, and were then faced with challenging tasks  (study 1) or a challenging social interaction (study 2). In study 1, the hypotheses  were not confirmed because participants overcame a lack of collective identity  clarity by simply applying their own familiar collective identity to the tasks. This  default alternative was removed in study 2, which resulted in a confirmation of the  hypotheses. Participants in the clear condition felt more positive and successful  than participants in the conflict and unclear conditions. Compared to participants  in the clear and unclear conditions, participants in the conflict condition found  the interaction to be the most difficult presumably because they were challenged to  resolve competing identities. Clarity of collective identity was related to feelings  of positivity, success, task difficulty, and to the expression of positive emotions,  certainty, and achievement, thereby emphasizing the importance of collective  identity clarity for the self.</description><creator>Usborne, Esther</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Group identity.</subject><subject>Self-perception.</subject><title>The importance of cultural identity clarity for the self : an experimental paradigm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405s9867.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pw60m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343s70d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Children learn from a variety of sources. One of the most  powerful pedagogical sites for kids is the consumer sphere. Marketers recognize this  and have recently carved out a new consumer niche for those between childhood and  adolescence, marking them as tweens. La Senza Corporation, which specializes in  women's lingerie, responded to this trend by opening a tween store with a name  heavily laden with meanings of sexuality: La Senza Girl. This study will apply a  textual analysis to the tween retail space, in an effort to understand the informal  pedagogy that takes place within this milieu. While La Senza Girl celebrates  girlhood by creating a space that tween girls can call their own, it is important to  take stock of the meanings of girlhood being celebrated. This study interrogates La  Senza Girl's 'pedagogies' of femininity, sexuality and girlhood.</description><creator>Koutsogianopoulos, Ralia</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Teenagers -- Social life and customs.</subject><subject>Lingerie industry -- Canada.</subject><subject>La Senza Corporation</subject><subject>Popular culture.</subject><subject>Children -- Social life and customs.</subject><subject>Consumer behavior.</subject><title>Thonging for identity : learning about girlhood, sexuality and feminity in a tween retail space</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m710t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s70d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407x82j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RHex is a cockroach-inspired hexapod robot capable of walking,  running, and climbing. This thesis presents the development of a novel, three  dimensional, bipedal running gait for RHex using only two actuated degrees of  freedom (DOF), one per compliant leg. To the author's knowledge, there are no  previous, two DOF bipeds capable of running. In this thesis it is experimentally  demonstrated that only body pitch and leg angle sensing are required. The controller  includes three levels of proportional derivative controls for balancing, forward  speed and leg tracking, as well a leg trajectory generator and a means of forward  speed estimation. With the addition of yaw angle feedback, high repeatability was  obtained. Details of a platform upgrade are also presented. Finally, a simulation  model of the robot was developed that, in conjunction with a genetic algorithm  optimization used to tune the controller and gait parameters, produced a stable gait  similar to those observed in experiment.</description><creator>Neville, Neil</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Robotics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Bipedal running with one actuator per leg</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j492.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x82j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935352z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined how medical tutors used a tool from clinical  practice known as the patient problem list to support students' clinical reasoning  in a natural internal medicine ward setting. A grounded 2 case comparative study was  conducted with 2 real patient case discussions by a tutor and 3 pre-clerkship  students and a resident and 1 clerkship level student respectively. Codes that  emerged by verbal analysis of the data were related to each other in a discourse  map. In both cases evidence of cognitive apprenticeship teaching strategies and the  patient problem list shaped and were shaped by a spiral model of increasingly  elaborate shared knowledge. The patient problem list links tutor support to student  education for practice with complex medical patients.</description><creator>Wiseman, Jeffrey</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Clinical competence.</subject><subject>Medicine -- Study and teaching.</subject><title>The patient problem list and clinical reasoning : linking education to practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q587.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935352z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xs130</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Automated Door Attendant, a multimodal interactive system  functioning as a virtual secretary for a professor, is an example of an artificial  agent deployed in a role typically assigned to humans. Accepting both speech and  touch as input, it serves as an appointment scheduler, a document browser, a  videoconferencing client, and a video answering-machine for visitors. This thesis  provides an analysis of existing multimodal kiosk systems, describes the evolution  of the current system's design, and presents the results of an empirical user  study.</description><creator>Perez, Michael Jonathan</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Redesigning the automated door attendant : a study of multimodal human-computer interaction for a public kiosk system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765371752.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs130</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999724d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The apolipoprotein E (apoE) ɛ4 is a risk factor for AD.  The mechanism by which apoE ɛ4 confers such a susceptibility to AD is  unknown. We explored whether low levels of apoE may mediate the processes leading to  neurodegeneration and cognitive decline in AD by using apoE knockout mice (apoEKO).  The complementary hypothesis was also tested to determine whether apoE could be used  as a therapeutic target in the treatment of AD. We examined the effect of apoE deficiency on the reparative  capacity and glial response following entorhinal cortex lesion (study 1), the effect  of age and apoE deficiency on the integrity of the circuitry underlying  hippocampal-dependent cognitive functioning in apoEKO mice (3 and 12 month-old)  (study 2). Given that enhanced sensitivity to stress and/or anxiety can interfere  with cognitive functioning, we assessed behavioral anxiety in apoEKO mice (12  month-old) using a battery of tests with varying degree of aversiveness and novelty  (study 3). The forth study assessed the effect of pharmacological induction of apoE  on alterations typically associated with age such as synaptic loss and glial  reactivity in aged rats (26 month old) using Probucol. The results revealed that apoE deficiency is associated with an  altered pattern of glial reactivity that coincided with impaired sprouting  responses, and with behavioral impairments (hippocampal-dependent procedural deficit  and enhanced susceptibility to stress and anxiety) that mimic some aspects of the  clinical phenotype of AD patients. Furthermore, chronic Probucol treatment in rats  led to significant increases in apoE and its receptor the low density lipoprotein  related protein receptor (LRP). In parallel, were increases in the synaptic marker  SNAP-25 along with a drastic attenuation of the age-related astroglial  reactivity. The findings show that apoE plays an important role in the  repair processes and its induction by Probucol could promote synaptic plasticity to  counteract the synaptic deterioration and glial activation associated with age or  damage. These findings are consistent with the hypothesis that part of the risk of  developing AD may be related to low levels of apoE, and suggest a novel therapy for  the treatment of AD based on apoE neurobiology.</description><creator>Champagne, Danielle</creator><contributor>Poirier, Judes (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Rochford, Joseph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Multilevel analysis of the apolipoprotein E in neuropathological, behavioral, and therapeutic challenges in rodents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pg76f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999724d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zn95s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A crucial factor to enable low-income families to participate in  the gradual development of their homes is to find a link between their building  activities and those of the large-scale building sector. Amidst technological  development and increasing demand for housing, the large-scale sector, such as  government and private groups, resorted to industrialised housing to replace  traditional and conventional building materials and methods. Industrialisation,  however, resulted not only in expensive and inappropriate dwellings but also  eliminated homeowners from the building process and management of their homes. To  bring back the homeowners in the building process, the shift was towards the  production of small components and partial prefabrication. Following the same thrust, there have been numerous innovative  building systems for housing developed in the Philippines in the last two decades.  Private entrepreneurs develop these building systems either promoting locally  invented systems or adapting imported versions. Seeing their potentials, government  and private groups are trying to employ them in housing. Despite the growing number  of the innovative building systems and the interest to use them, their integration  in low-income housing is still limited. Focusing on Metro Manila, the capital region of the Philippines,  the thesis aims to develop a selection model for the effective integration of  innovative building systems in low-income housing. The process of integration is not  simply using the building systems for mass production of houses but also enabling  homeowners to utilise, maintain and sustain them. The proposed model involves sets  of selection parameters essential at each stage of the housing delivery based on the  homeowners' progressive building process and their criteria for choosing building  materials for their homes. To facilitate progressive building and enhance the  homeowners' initiative to build, the model also includes design strategies when  employing new building systems and suggests the necessary channels to ensure the  availability of the building systems, technical assistance and  information.</description><creator>Astrand, Rachelle Navarro</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Appropriate technology -- Philippines -- Manila</subject><subject>House construction -- Philippines -- Manila</subject><subject>Low-income housing -- Philippines -- Manila</subject><subject>Self-help housing -- Philippines -- Manila</subject><title>Selection model to choose innovative building systems for progressive housing with special reference to Metro Manila, Philippines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz031.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zn95s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644s10j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:25:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Parkinson's disease (PD) is a neurodegenerative disease  characterized by progressive loss of dopaminergic neurons of the substantia nigra  pars compacta. Symptoms usually include akinesia, bradykinesia, muscle rigidity,  postural imbalance and tremor. Despite numerous studies on the physiology and  pathophysiology of tremor, its influence on voluntary motor behavior remains  unclear. Accordingly, the main objectives of the present thesis were to (a)  determine if a clinical relationship existed between tremor and performance of  voluntary movements, and (b) characterize the impact of ventrolateral (VL)  thalamotomy on tremor and voluntary motor behavior. Results indicate that  age-related change of the supraspinal component of normal physiological tremor (NPT)  has no influence on the performance of healthy elderly subjects making rapid  alternating movements (RAM). Our results also show that subsets of patients  presenting different tremor amplitudes and/or tremor power characteristics had  similar RAM performance, hence negating any direct relationship between the  supraspinal oscillator(s) generating tremor and RAM performance. Our results  demonstrate that tremor can be detected during manual-tracking movements performed  by patients with early PD, but this tremor has little consequence on the accuracy of  these patients. As for the impact of VL thalamotomy on tremor, our results show  that the thalamic lesion eliminates selectively PD tremor oscillations, in addition  to preventing a resurgence of the supraspinal component of physiological tremor. The  surgical procedure did not however improve or worsen RAM performance, suggesting  that tremor probably plays little role in bradykinesia. Accuracy during the  manual-tracking task is nonetheless greatly improved post-surgery, hence confirming  the anticipated clinical benefits of the surgical procedure. In conclusion, despite  previous evidence that tremor and RAM may share common neural networks and that  tremor may be pathophysiologically linked with bradykinesia, the aforementioned  results suggest that there is little clinical relationship between tremor and  bradykinesia observed in patients with PD making RAM.</description><creator>Duval, Christian, 1963-</creator><contributor>Sadikot, Abbas F. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Panisset, Michel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The clinical relationship between tremor and voluntary motor behavior in patients with Parkinson's disease /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w408.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644s10j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43875</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>