<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:04:27Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3750" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sz23n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Torso Rotation" (TR) is an unusual motor strategy producing an acute, reversible change in vestibular function. Following a single exposure, the signs and symptoms of motion sickness appear along with gaze and postural instability and perceptual illusions during movement. Upon repeated exposure, motion sickness susceptibility disappears and gaze instability (measured during voluntary head shaking in the light) is reduced. Whole body step rotation in the dark demonstrated that the reduction in post-TR gaze instability occurred despite a consistent daily suppression of VOR gain. To evaluate the potential role of alternate sensory inputs in this long-term change, gaze stability was measured during head shaking in the dark (i.e. no visual inputs) and during en bloc, "head-and-torso" shaking in the dark (i.e. no visual and no cervical inputs). […]</description><description>L'utilisation d'une stratégie motrice inhabituelle impliquant des rotations en bloc du torse et de la tête ("Torso Rotation", TR) crée des changements temporaires et réversibles de la fonction vestibulaire. Une fois termine, cet exercice est suivi de symptômes du mal des transports, d'instabilité visuelle et posturale ainsi que de perceptions erronées lors de mouvements normaux. Suite à plusieurs sessions impliquant TR, les symptômes du mal des transports disparaissent et l'instabilité visuelle diminue (telle que mesurée lors de mouvements rapides de la tête en présence d'une cible visuelle fixe). Cette diminution de l'instabilité visuelle a lieu malgré une réduction répétée du reflexe vestibulo-oculaire (étudie à l'aide de rotations passives du sujet dans le noir). De façon à évaluer l'apport potentiel d'autres modalités sensorielles à ce changement graduel, le niveau de stabilité visuelle rut, par la suite, mesure lors de mouvements rapides de la tête dans le noir (càd sans signaux visuels) ainsi que lors de mouvements combines du torse et de la tête (càd sans signaux visuels ni cervicaux).  […]</description><creator>Bouyer, Laurent J.G.</creator><contributor>Watt, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Torse rotation</subject><title>Neurophysiological Changes during Adaptation to Motion Sickness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg73b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz23n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064811x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse étudie le dynamique des structures en treillis flexibles qui sont articules par une installation spécifique des actuateurs. La structure est composée de plusieurs corps classifies comme treillis ou actuateur. L'actuateur, de type prismatique, se compose de deux membres; un cylindre et un piston qui sont considères rigides. […]</description><description>The dynamics of truss structures, articulated via a specific actuator arrangement, is examined in this thesis. The structure is treated as a flexible multi-body system, and sub-divided into numerous truss and actuator links. The resulting configuration becomes that of a crane-type manipulator. The prismatic actuator is modelled as a separate cylinder and piston-rod component, and considered rigid. Frame designations and kinematic expressions associated with each link-type, are established in order to evaluate the motion of the structure. Kinematic loops are introduced by the actuator installation, and the orientation angles of links dependent upon the loop are solved using the Newton-Raphson method. By virtue of the kinematic arrangement considered, only planar motion of truss cranes is examined in this thesis. The base of the structure is also considered to be fixed. […]</description><creator>Boutin, Bernard A.</creator><contributor>Misra, A. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Truss structures</subject><title>Dynamics and Vibration Control of Articulating Truss Structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k491m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064811x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515q80p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The E1A oncoproteins of adenovirus type 5 are potent inducers of apoptotic cell death. To manifest growth promoting properties, therefore, E1A requires the co-expression of a suppressor of apoptosis. During normal viral infection, this function is provided by the E1B 19kDa protein. However, the cellular suppressor Bcl-2 can substitute for 19K during infection, and both proteins can effectively cooperate with E1A to facilitate transformation of primary cells in culture. How E1A induces apoptosis and at whatpoint(s) on the pathway Bcl-2 and E1B  19K act at are not presently known. Here, we demonstrate that E1A -induced apoptosis is accompanied by specific endo-proteolytic cleavage of poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase (PARP), an event that is linked to the Ced-3/ICE apoptotic pathway in other systems. […]</description><description>Les protéines oncogéniques E1A de l'adénovirus (type 5) sont de puissants inducteurs de la mort cellulaire programmée (apoptose). Afin de promouvoir la croissance cellulaire, E1A requiert donc la présence d'une autre protéine virale, E1B-19K, permettant d'inhiber l'apoptose. Son homologue cellulaire, la protéine Bcl-2, peut se substituer à E1B-19K lors de l'infection virale et permettre la survie cellulaire. Ces protéines possèdent donc une activité similaire permettant de contrer l'apoptose médiée par E1A, l'une et I' autre pouvant également coopérer avec E1A et promouvoir la transformation de cellules primaires en culture. Le(s) mécanisme(s) responsable(s) de l'apoptose médiée par E1A de même que le(s) mode(s) d'action de E1B-19K/Bcl-2 demeurent cependant obscurs. Le pèsent travail démontre que l'apoptose médiée par E1A conduit à l'inactivation de la poly (ADP-ribose) polymérase (PARP) dans des fibroblastes en culture, un évènement lie à l'activation du sentier Ced3/Ice dans plusieurs systèmescellulaires. […]</description><creator>Boulakia, Charles Aaron</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Viral infection</subject><title>Bcl-2 and adenovirus E1B 19kDA protein prevent E1A-induced processing ofCPP32 and cleavage of poly(ADP-ribose) polymerase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk35z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q80p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676z08f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis introduces an architecture for a generic automatic speech recognition (ASR) system which is easily adapted to specific tasks. It then expands the base system to include a Vector Quantizer (VQ) preprocessor and a speaker adaptation (SA) procedure. The VQ preprocessor reduces the amount of computation which must be done on multivariant gaussian mixtures contained within hidden Markov models (HMMs) in order to achieve a realtime speedup. The SA procedure increases the accuracy of the ASR system when the same speaker uses it for a period of time. Both improvements to the base architecture are then tested and evaluated using the TIMIT test set, an Air Traffic Control task set, and a single speaker test set for speaker adaptation.</description><description>Cette thèse présente une architecture pour un système pour la Reconnaissance Automatique de la Parole (RAP) qui peut être facilement adapte à une tache spécifique. Ce système est alors agrandi pour comprendre un préprocesseur à base de quantification de vecteurs et une méthode d'adaptation à l'utilisateur. Le préprocesseur réduit le nombre de calculs nécessaire pour reconnaitre la parole, ce qui améliore la vitesse du système. L'adaptation à l'utilisateur améliore l'exactitude du système. Ces deux modifications sont évaluées avec la base de données TIMIT, con tenant des paroles de contrôleurs de trafic aérien, et une base de données d'un seul utilisateur pour vérifier l'adaptation.</description><creator>Boucher, Philippe</creator><contributor>De Mori, Renato (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Speech recognition</subject><title>Optimizations for automatic speech recognition systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs84j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676z08f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79408043f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Skeletal myogenesis is defined by a series of successive stages, each of which is characterized by dramatic changes in both gene expression and cellular behaviour. The major stages of myogenesis are schematically represented in Fig. 1-1. (Oison, 1992). The process begins with the commitment of pluripotent stem cells to the myogenic lineage. The resulting myoblasts undergo rapid proliferationto increase the mass necessary to make muscle. In response to changes in the environment such as depletion or experimental removal of various mitogens and growth factors, myoblasts withdraw from the cell cycle and initiate terminal differentiation. […]</description><creator>Blaschuk, Katharine Lynne</creator><contributor>Holland, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Muscle cells</subject><title>Regulation of Integrin Expression in Human Skeletal Muscle Cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf03b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408043f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h407z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Afin de développer un cadre conceptuel cohérent au sujet des biais de sélection dans l'évaluation des tests diagnostiques, nous avons analysé l'effet conjoint des processus de sélection et des relations entre les variables impliquées sur les stratégies analytiques traditionnelles et alternatives. Pour la situation la plus simple impliquant trois variables dichotomiques, l'étiquette diagnostique, le test et une seule covariable, nous avons envisagé la sélection basée sur le test, la covariable, le test et la covariable de façon indépendante et dépendante, et sur le diagnostic. […]</description><description>To develop a coherent conceptual framework regarding selection biases in studies evaluating diagnostic tests, we analyzed the joint impact of the selection processes and the nature of the relationships among relevant variables on traditional and alternative analytic strategies. For the simplest situation involving a dichotomous disease status and diagnostic test and a single dichotomous covariate, we considered selection based on the test, the covariate, the test and the covariate independently and non-independently, and the disease status. […]</description><creator>Blancquaert, Ingeborg</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Selection bias</subject><title>Selection Bias in Diagnostic Test Evaluation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903218j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h407z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032529v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chilean writer Gabriela Mistral (1889-1957) was awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1945. Though Mistral herself was once well established in American literary circles, her works are not well-known among English-speaking readers today. Only about a third of her published poems has so far been translated into English, partly because critics favoured Mistral's early verses about motherhood or unfulfilled love and failed to appreciate her more engage works. This thesis contains translations of 30 poems from Mistral's four volumes of poetry, as well as from the posthumous Poema de Chile (1967). Only one of these 30 poems belongs to Mistral's early phase. A total of 19 poems are here translated into English for the first time. In my introduction, I examine some of the reasons why Mistral's oeuvre has not been translated more often. I also review the works of other North-American translators and describe my own approach to the renditions contained in this volume.</description><description>Gabriela Mistral (1889-1957), du Chili, obtint le Prix Nobel de Littérature en 1945. Bien qu'elle ait été connue de l'intelligentsia américaine, peu de lecteurs de langue anglaise sont aujourd'hui familiers avec l'ensemble de son œuvre. Un tiers seulement de ses poèmes publies est en fait traduit vers l'anglais et ce, car la critique a favorisé surtout ses premiers vers, qui traitaient de maternité et d'amours malheureuses, sans bien apprécier la profondeur de sa poésie engagée. La thèse suivante contient des traductions vers l'anglais de trente poèmes tires des quatre volumes de poésie de Mistral, ainsi que de son œuvre posthume, Poema de Chile (1967). Un seul de ces trente poèmes appartient à la première phase du développement de l'auteur. En tout, dix-neuf poèmes sont ici traduits vers l'anglais pour la première fois. De plus, je m'interroge, dans mon introduction, quanta certaines des raisons qui ont fait que l'œuvre de Gabriela Mistral n'a pas été plus souvent traduite. J’effectue également un examen critique des efforts produits par les traducteurs nord-américains de l'auteur et je décris, finalement, mon approche personnelle aux versions incluses a ce volume.</description><creator>Blanc, Marie Thérèse</creator><contributor>Lindeman, Yehudi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Mistral, Gabriela, 1889-1957.</subject><title>New Selected Poems of Gabriela Mistral : A Translation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr828.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032529v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nk470</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis was to examine sources and pathways of heavy metals in lakes and their catchments. (1) A cross-system analysis was conducted which examined whole-lake metal burdens as a function of the drainage ratio (catchment area: lake area) in 21 lakes. It was found that metals follow an identical adsorption I precipitation sequence in both catchments and oceans. Sediment enrichment factors for the metals AI, Zn, Cu, Ni, Cr, and Pb are similar to their atmospheric enrichment factors demonstrating that post-depositional migration is small relative to the rate at which these metals are being accumulated and thus their historical information is not obscured. This allows these metal profiles to be interpreted in terms of their anthropogenic inputs. (2) Assumptions made in dating sediment cores with 210Pb radiochronology were examined by comparing 210Pb dated cores from much of North America and Scandinavia with three different event markers. It was found that 210Pb incorporation in the sediments is independent of the sedimentation rate which is a critical assumption when interpreting 210Pb profiles. […]</description><description>Le but de cette thèse était d'examiner les sources et les voies de pénétration des métaux lourds dans les lacs et dans leurs bassins versants. (1) On a procédé à une analyse inter système, qui a permis d'examiner la charge métallique de l'ensemble d'un lac en fonction du coefficient d'écoulement (aire du bassin versant: superficie du lac), pour 21 lacs. On a constaté que les métaux suivent une séquence identique d'adsorption et de précipitation dans les bassins versants et dans les océans. Pour I' AI, Zn, Cu, Ni, Cr et Pb, les facteurs d'enrichissement des sédiments sont semblables aux facteurs d'enrichissement atmosphériques, ce qui démontre que la migration après déposition est faible par rapport au taux d'accumulation de ces métaux et que les données historiques sur ces métaux ne sont donc pas masquées. Cela permet d'interpréter ces profils métalliques en fonction des apports humains. (2) On a examiné les hypothèses formulées quant à la datation des carottes de sédiments par radiochronologie au 210Pb; à cette fin, on a comparé des carottes datées au 210Pb provenant de la majeure partie des régions de l'Amérique du Nord et de la Scandinavie a trois majeures d'évènement différents. On a constaté que l‘intégration du 210Pb dans les sédiments se fait indépendamment du taux de sédimentation, ce qui constitue une hypothèse critique lorsqu'il s'agit d'interpréter les profils du 210Pb. […]</description><creator>Blais, Jules, M.</creator><contributor>Kalff, Jaap (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Lake sediments -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Atmospheric deposition -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Lake sediments -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>The Distribution and Dynamics of Heavy Metals in Lake Sediments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks709.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk470</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xx196</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electrical steels are soft magnetic materials used for magnetic cores in electrical machines. The magnetic properties of electrical steels may be significantly improved by a texture in such a way that magnetically preferred crystal directions are oriented parallel to those directions in the material in which theyare needed. Therefore, for technological applications, macroscopic anisotropy of magnetic properties in these materials is desirable. The correlation between texture and the magnetic properties of electrical steels is the focus of this study.  […]</description><description>Les aciers électriques font partie des matériaux magnétiques mous et sent utilisés dans les noyaux magnétiques des machines électriques. Les propriétés magnétiques des aciers électriques peuvent être significativement améliorées par une texture de façon a ce que les directions préférées de magnétisation du cristal sont parallèlement orientées avec les directions de magnétisation imposées. Donc, pour tels matériaux, l'anisotropie macroscopique des propriétés magnétiques est désirable pour les applications technologiques. La corrélation entre la texture et les propriétés magnétiques des aciers électriques représente le but de cet étude. […]</description><creator>Birsan, Marius Stefan</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Steel</subject><title>Methods of Correlating Texture and Magnetic Properties in Electrical Steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq767.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xx196</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p0524</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main purpose of the thesis is to examine cooperation between the Gulf states. It will look at the exisiting literature on cooperation and will inquire into the dynamics of integration in the Gulf region which led up to the creation of the Gulf Cooperation Council in 1981. After examining a number of external and regional threats to the Gulf security, the thesis will conclude that although external international threats appeared to be the main reason behind cooperation, internal domestic similarities also played a role. The GCC states are now part of an organization that benefits them in more than just the military and security field. Indeed it is by economic integration and the development of communication that the Gulf states will be able to progress. Such solid bases for cooperation suggest an optimistic future for the GCC.</description><description>L'objectif de la thèse est d'examiner le phénoménal de coopération entre les pays du Golfe Arabe. Seront inclus dans la thèse, une révision de la littérature sur le phénoménal de coopération ainsi qu'une étude du processus d'intégration aboutissant à la formation du Conseil de Coopération du Golfe en 1981. Après avoir examiné certains dangers internationaux et régionaux menaçant la sécurité de la région du Golfe, il apparait que malgré l'importance des dangers internationaux, les similarités domestiques existantes entre les pays du Golfe jouèrent aussi un rôle significatif et de grande envergure dans l'accomplissement de la coopération. Les états membres du CCG font aujourd'hui partie d'une organisation qui leur offre des bénéfices allant au delà des domaines militaires et sécuritaires. En effet le progrès des états du Golfe est fortement lié à l'intégration économique ainsi que le développement de la communication. Cette base solide pour la coopération suggère un future positif pour le CCG.</description><creator>Bikhazi, Rania</creator><contributor>Brawley, Mark R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Gulf Cooperation Council.</subject><subject>Persian Gulf States -- Foreign relations.</subject><title>Gulf Cooperation Council: A Sincere Effort Aimed at Coordinating and Developing Cooperation between the Gulf States</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f53t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p0524</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr14q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le protectorat Britannique des iles Ioniennes fut établit en 1815 par le Traite de Paris. Les deux principales raisons de la Grande Bretagne justifiant cette acquisition étaient, dans un premier lieu, d'empêcher la Russie de s'installer dans le bassin Méditerranée. Aussi, cela donnait à la Grande Bretagne une base à l'est de la Méditerranée de laquelle elle pouvait assurer un équilibre des forces, réaffirmant les intérêts qu'elle avait au Levant. De 1815 à 1831, la guerre d'Independence en Grèce remit en question ces objectifs. Ce mémoire couvre cette période, a fin d'exposer en détail le façon dont la Grande Bretagne a relevé ce défi et a protège ses intérêts stratégiques.</description><description>In 1815, the British protectorate of the Ionian Islands was established by the Treaty of Paris. Great Britain acquired the islands for two purposes: First, to prevent Russia from establishing itself in the Mediterranean; Second, to provide a base in the eastern Mediterranean from which Britain could promote a balance of power favourable to its Levantine interests. From 1815 to 1831, those purposes were threatened by the outbreak of the Greek War for Independence. This thesis examines that period, so as to illustrate how Britain met this challenge, and protected its strategic interest.</description><creator>Bhamjee, David</creator><contributor>Senior, Hereward (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Ionian Islands (British protectorate)</subject><subject>Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- Mediterranean Region.</subject><title>The British Administration of the Ionian Islands: 1815-1831</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fk30w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr14q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074x392</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lower vertebrates such as teleost fish contain numerous biologically active factors which have often only been studied superficially. The corticostatins have recently been discovered in mammalian tissues and shown to have significant effects upon steroidogenesis of adrenal cells in vitro. We have examined the possible existence of similar bioactive peptides in tissue extracts of teleost fish and the rat in order to gain insight into important structure/function relationships. Using high performance liquid chromatography fractionation of acidic extracts of heart and hematopoietic tissues of teleost fish and the bone marrow of the rat, we have structurally and biologically characterized two families of cystine-rich polypeptides. [...]</description><description>Plusieurs facteurs peptidiques que l'on retrouve chez les poissons téléostéens sont plus souvent étudies superficiellement. Certains facteurs tels les corticostatins ont récemment été caractérises comme ayant certains effets sur la stéroidogénèse au niveau de la glande surrénale chez les mammifères. La possibilité de retrouver ces facteurs peptidiques chez les poissons téléostéens (carpe) et le rat et d'étudier les structures primaires importantes pour leurs activités a été entreprise. À cette fin, nous avons utilise la chromatographie liquide a haute pression pour l'isolation et la caractérisation de deux familles de facteurs peptidiques ayant un haut pourcentage de cystéine. […]</description><creator>Belcourt, Daniel Richard</creator><contributor>Bennett, Hugh (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Fish</subject><title>Characterization of the Granules and Corticostatins, Two Classes of Cystine-rich Peptides Found in the Hematopoietic Tissues of a Teleost Fist, Cyprinus Carpio, and the Rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268750r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x392</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc13q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>These investigations examined the relationship between inspiratory muscle function and ventilatory failure in clinical situations and during mechanical loading with and without chemostimulation by C02 rebreathing. This work proposes a conceptual framework that links alveolar ventilation to the level of inspiratory effort, taking into account the limits of muscle function (force, flow and volume displacement). […]</description><description>Ces investigations examinent la relation entre la fonction des muscles inspiratoires et l'hypoventilation alveolaire en situation clinique stable et lors de la mise en charge des muscles inspiratoires. […]</description><creator>Bégin, Paul</creator><contributor>Grassino, Alejandro E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Hyperventilation</subject><title>Role of respiratory muscles in chronic alveolar hypoventilation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fr150.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc13q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j1254</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rooted in the psychophysical approaches to landscape evaluation, this thesis focuses on a quantitative examination of the public's assessments of the aesthetic quality of the landscape at a recreational lake in southern Quebec. A sample of 430 local cottagers and day-visitors to the area was surveyed on-site through personal structured interviews during the summer of 1995. Each respondent was asked to provide information about his or her recreational activities, permanent residence, access to a cottage, ownership of boats, and other socio-economic data, and to rate a set of computer-generated photographs, or "photo-cards" of the lake with various combinations of boating activities. […]</description><description>Cette thèse est basée sur les approches psychophysiques de I'évaluation du paysage. Celle-ci est une examination quantitative d'une évaluation publique concernant la qualité esthétique du paysage au bord d'un lac au sud du Québec. Des entrevues individuelles et structurées avec 430 résidents saisonniers, ainsi que des visiteurs journaliers ont eu lieu sur place durant l'été 1995. Chaque personne interrogée a fourni des informations de ses activités récréatives, de son adresse permanente, de son accès a un chalet, de sa possession d'embarquations, et d'autres questions socio-économiques. De plus, les individus interviewes ont évalué, selon leurs préférences esthétiques, des photographies informatisées du lac (les "cartesphotos") sur lesquelles sont représentées plusieurs activités à bord d'embarquations. […]</description><creator>Bardati, Darren Robert</creator><contributor>Ewing, Gordon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Boating</subject><title>The View from the Shore : The Impact of Boating on Lakescape Aesthetics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tf321.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j1254</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881p34k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Astroglial reactivity is a prominent universal event following trauma and inflammation to the adult central nervous system. In contrast, injury inflicted during early postnatal life produces minimal astroglial reactivity. This divergent response is dictated by the nature of the complex cascade of cellular events that follow anisomorphic injuries. In the adult animal, an inflammatory phase which involves the activation of intrinsic resident microglia and the infiltration of extrinsic blood-borne monocytes occurs prior to astroglial reactivity. The central hypothesis of this thesis therefore states that immunoregulatory cytokines from these intrinsic and extrinsic inflammatory cells contribute towards astroglial reactivity. […]</description><description>La réactivité des astrocytes est un phénomène universel important consécutif à un traumatisme et à une inflammation du système nerveux central de l'adulte. Au contraire de l'adulte, une lésion induite durant la période post-natale précoce produit une réactivité minime des astrocytes. La différence de réponse est due à la nature de la cascade complexe des évènements cellulaires résultant des lésions anisomorphes. Chez l’animal adulte la réactivité des astrocytes est précédée par une phase inflammatoire qui entraine l'activation de la microglie intrinsèque locale et l’infiltration des monocytes extrinsèques d’origine sanguine. En conséquence, l'hypothèse principale de cette thèse est que les cytokines immunrégulatrices provenant des cellules inflammatoires endogènes et exogènes contribuent à la réactivité des astrocytes. […]</description><creator>Balasingam, Vijayabalan</creator><contributor>Yong, Voon Wee (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Cytokines</subject><title>Cytokines and Astroglial Reactivity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634599q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881p34k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t1494</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La recristallisation de neufs aciers de différentes teneurs en Mo, Nb et B a été étudiée pour différentes conditions de refroidissement continu. Des tests de torsion a chaud ont été effectues comportant 17 passes de déformation et des temps d'interpasses de 0.05 à 150 secondes, pour des vitesses de déformation de 0.2 à 10 s-1. Après un recuit à 1250°C ou 1200°C, la première déformation est effectuée a 1180°C et la dernière autour de 700°C. En traçant la contrainte d'écoulement en fonction de 1000/T, la température de non recristallisation (T nr) a été déterminée, et les effets de la composition chimique et des conditions de déformation estimes. Des équations empiriques distinctes pour des temps d'interpasse courts ou longs ont alors été obtenues pour Tnr à partir des données expérimentales. Ces relations décrivent l'influence de la composition chimique, du chemin de déformation, de la vitesse de déformation et du temps d'interpasse pendant le refroidissement. […]</description><description>The recrystallization behaviour of nine steels containing various combinations of Mo, Nb and B was investigated under continuous cooling conditions. Hot torsion tests were performed using a 17 pass deformation schedule at strain rates of 0.2 to 10 s-1, and interpass times of 0.05 to 150 seconds. After reheating at 1250 or 1200 °C, the first deformation was applied at 1180°C and the last one at about 700 °C. By plotting the mean flow stress vs. 1000/T, the no-recrystallization temperatures (Tnr) were determined, and the effects of chemical composition and the deformation conditions were assessed. Separate empirical equations for the Tm were derived from the data for short and long interpass times. These relations describe the influence of chemical composition and of the pass strain, strain rate, and interpass time under continuous cooling conditions. […]</description><creator>Bai, Deng Qi</creator><contributor>Jonas, John J.  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Recrystallization</subject><title>Recrystallization and Transformation in Low Carbon Nb and Nb-B Steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h200.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t1494</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676z09q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the past ten years, three dimensional radiation dosimetry techniques based on the dose response of the Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) spin relaxation of the water protons in gels have been developed. The studies in this work focus on 1) the dose response of the spin-lattice relaxation rate, R1, of the ferrous sulfate-doped gelatin dosimeter and 2) the dose response of the spin-spin relaxation rate, R2, of the BANG (Bis Acrylamide Nitrogen Gelatin) polymer gel dosimeter. […]</description><description>Depuis les dix dernières années, des techniques de radiodosimetrie en trois dimensions ont été développées. Les techniques sont basées sur l'effet de la dose sur la relaxation Résonance Magnétique Nucléaire (RMN) des protons d'eau trouves dans les dosimètres de gels radiosensibles. Les études présentées regardent 1) la relation dose-effet du taud de relaxation spin-réseau, R1, du dosimètre contenant des ions ferreux et de la gélatine et 2) la relation dose-effet du taud de relaxation spin-spin, R2, du dosimètres polymérique BANG (Bis Acrylamide Nitrogen Gelatin). […]</description><creator>Audet, Chantal</creator><contributor>Schreiner, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>3-D radiation</subject><title>NMR-Dose Response Studies of the Gels Used for 3-D Radiation Dosimetry by Magnetic Resonance Imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc70r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676z09q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj55v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La formation des pyrazines et leur contribution à la saveur du sirop d'érable a été étudiée. À cet effet, du sirop d'érable a été préparé au laboratoire. Le pH de la sève en ébullition passait d'une valeur initiale de pH 7.2 a une valeur de pH 9.2, puis diminuait jusqu'à une valeur de pH 7.7. La diminution de pH coïncidait avec une hausse de la teneur en solides dissouts. L'analyse chromatographique en phase gazeuse et la spectrométrie de masse d'extraits de sirops d'érable authentiques, de sirops ne provenant pas de l'érable, et d'échantillons d'arôme artificiel d'érable ont démontré la présence de 2-methylpyrazine, 2,5-dimethylpyrazine, 2,6-dimethylpyrazine, 2-ethylpyrazine, 2,3-dimethylpyrazine, trimethylpyrazine, 2-ethyl-3-methylpyrazine, tetramethylpyrazine, 2-ethyl-5-methylpyrazine, 2-ethyl-6-methylpyrazine, 2- ethyl-3,5-dimethylpyrazine et 3-ethyl-2,5-dimethylpyrazine. […]</description><description>The formation of pyrazines and their contribution to maple syrup flavor were investigated. Maple syrup was prepared in laboratory conditions. The pH of boiling sap increased from 7.2 to 9.2 followed by a decrease to a final pH 7.3. The decrease pH coincided with an increase of total dissolved solids. Gas chromatography/mass spectrometry analysis of extracts from commercial maple syrups, laboratory prepared maple syrup, commercial non-maple syrups, and artificial maple flavorings revealed the presence of 2-methylpyrazine, 2,5- dimethylpyrazine, 2,6-dimethylpyrazine, 2-ethylpyrazine, 2,3-dimethylpyrazine, trimethylpyrazine, 2-ethyl-3-methylpyrazine, tetramethypyrazine, 2-ethyl-5- methylpyrazine, 2-ethyl-6-methylpyrazine, 2-ethyl-3,5-dimethylpyrazine and 3- ethyl-2,5-imethylpyrazine. […]</description><creator>Akochi-Koblé, Emmanuel</creator><contributor>Alli, Inteaz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Maple syrup.</subject><subject>Pyridazines.</subject><subject>Flavor.</subject><title>The Formation of Pyrazine Compounds and their Contribution to Maple Syrup Flavor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t742.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj55v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nb08z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:06:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'anti-addition électrochimique des chlorures de sulfényl sur des doubles liaisons carbone-carbone a été utilisée pour la synthèse d'une nouvelle classe de composes soufres comportant deux ou trois soufres en faisant réagir, en une étape, un chlorure de triphénylméthanesulfenyl 65 (ou son homologue soufre 61 et di-soufre 70) avec différents types d'oléfines. Nous avons commencé l'étude de ce type d'addition et nous espérons développer une voie vers la synthèse de dithiétanes, comme par example 77, qui pourraient être des intermédiaires stables et/ ou des précurseurs de soufre diatomique. La stéréochimie de ce type d'addition a été déterminée par analyse cristallographique. La structure cristalline des réactifs di-et tri-soufres 68, 69, 75 et 76 est rapportée pour la première fois. L'identification de ces réactifs a être confirmée par RMN du proton et du carbone ainsi que par analyse élémentaire. […]</description><description>The electrophilic anti-addition of sulfenyl chlorides to carbon-carbon double bonds by a one pot reaction of triphenylmethanesulfenyl chloride 65 (or its thio 61 and dithio 70 homolog) with various types of olefins is used for the synthesis of a new series of di- and trithio compounds. We have initiated a study of some of the chemistry of this type of addition hoping to develop a useful pathway to dithietanes like 77 as potentially stable intermediates and/or diatomic sulfur precursors. The stereochemistry of addition has been determined by x-ray analysis. The x-ray crystal structures of di- and trithio reagents 68, 69, 75 and 76 are reported for the first time. The identity of these reagents was confirmed by 1 H and 13C NMR as well as by elemental analysis. […]</description><creator>Abu-Yousef, Imad</creator><contributor>Harpp, David N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Sulfur</subject><title>Precursors for Diatomic Sulfur (1S2) and Sulfur Monoxide (SO) Formation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv24d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nb08z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397b54m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:07:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse fait l'examen des actes d'intervention illicite dans le domaine de l'aviation civile internationale ainsi que de l'analyse critique du régime légal et régulateur qui s'applique, ceci dans le but de recommander des mesures réfléchies afin d'insuffler une nouvelle approche à ce problème. Tout au long du travail l 'emphase est mise sur les mesures à prendre afin de régler le problème des actes d'intervention illicite. La conclusion de ce travail comprend plusieurs dispositions pouvant être prises afin de rencontrer cet objectif. […]</description><description>This thesis examines the offence of unlawful interference with international civil aviation and analyses critically the legal and regulatory regime that applies thereto, with a view to recommending measures that are calculated to infuse a new approach to the problem. Emphasis is laid throughout the work on action which may be taken to alleviate the problem of unlawful interference. The conclusion of this work incorporates various steps that can be taken towards achieving this objective. […]</description><creator>Abeyratne, R. I. R. </creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>Legal and regulatory aspects of unlawful interference with civil aviation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c878.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b54m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977x22m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:07:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans la plupart des pays en développement, la productivité agricole détermine le revenu familial, le niveau de la consommation et le seuil de pauvreté. En Éthiopie, les technologies agricoles vétustes et la croissance démographique ont affecté le niveau de productivité agricole de façon marquante. Se référant a un échantillon de données chronologiques et multidimensionnelles, cette thèse démontre comment la croissance démographique a provoqué une diminution de la productivité agricole à long terme et illustre ses effets sur l'efficience de la distribution des ressources en Éthiopie. La pauvreté étant définie comme une insuffisance en calories, la thèse évalue l'impact et l'étendue de la pauvreté, d'une part sur les plans régional et national, d'autre part sur les groupes socio-économiques. Elle fait l'inventaire des variables déterminant le seuil de la pauvreté familiale en Éthiopie et met en lumière les implications des solutions politiques développées pour atténuer la pauvreté. […]</description><description>In Ethiopia, as in most developing countries, agricultural productivity determines household income, consumption, and poverty status. Agricultural productivity in Ethiopia, however, has declined because of population growth and the lack of improvement in the traditional technology of farming. On the basis of time-series and cross-sectional data, the thesis demonstrates how population growth has resulted in the long-term decline of agricultural productivity and how it has affected the allocative efficiency of resources in Ethiopia. Taking a calorie-deficiency definition of poverty, the thesis estimates the incidence and magnitude of poverty nationally, regionally, and by socio-economic groups; it investigates the variables determining the poverty status of households in Ethiopia, and highlights the policy implications for poverty alleviation.  […]</description><creator>Aberra, Worku</creator><contributor>Frankman, Myron (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Rowley, Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Ethiopia -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Agricultural productivity -- Ethiopia.</subject><subject>Ethiopia -- Rural conditions.</subject><title>Poverty and Agricultural Productivity Among Rural Households in Ethiopia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw72v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977x22m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nk488</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:07:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several novels of the 19th century depict marriage in a pessimistic manner. Some examples include Le Rouge et le noir by Stendhal, La Femme de trente ans by Balzac, Indiana by George Sand. The personal opinions of these authors reflect the conception that society had of women during that era. At the beginning of the 19th century (1804), the Napoleonic Code made important restrictions on the liberty of the married woman. Later in the century (1872), in the article "Femme" published in Le Grand Dictionnaire de Pierre Larousse, women are portrayed as being too weak and incapable of assuming their independence. […]</description><description>Plusieurs romans du XIXe siècle présentent l'institution du mariage de façon pessimiste. Le Rouge et le noir de Stendhal, La Femme de trente ans de Balzac, Indiana de George Sand en sont des exemples. Ces visions personnelles d'auteurs offrent aussi un reflet de la société de l'époque. Le Code Napoléon au début du siècle (1804) apporte des restrictions importantes a la liberté de la femme mariée. Plus tard dans le siècle, en 1872, dans l'article "Femme" publie dans Le Grand Dictionnaire de Pierre Larousse, on peut constater à quel point la femme est perçue comme un être faible et inapte à assumer sa liberté. […]</description><creator>Tabet, Karen</creator><contributor>Pascal, Gabrielle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Sand, George, 1804-1876. Mauprat.</subject><subject>Marriage in literature.</subject><subject>Maupassant, Guy de, 1850-1893. Vie.</subject><title>La Thématique du Mariage dans une Vie de Maupassant et Mauprat de Sand</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n635.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk488</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935526r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:07:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis adopts a two pronged approach in examining the hypothesis that legal aid operates as a method of social control, more amenable to upholding the status quo than to promoting social change.Firstly, it analyzes the existing structures for legal aid delivery in Quebec and in Ireland, to show how their mandate and operation exclude certain classes of individuals de facto from the benefit of legal aid. On a second level of analysis it highlights the existence of entrenched institutional bias within the legal aid system itself which effectively prevents the use of legal aid to challenge dominant meanings. […]</description><description>C'est à travers une approche bi-polaire que l'hypothèse de l'aide juridique en tant qu'instrument du contrôle social, mieux apte au maintien du statu quo qu'à l'avènement d'un changement social significatif, est examinée. Nous analyserons d’abord les structures existantes au service de l'aide juridique, tant au Québec qu'en Irlande, afin de démontrer comment son mandat et son exécution excluent de fait certains groupes d’individus du bénéfice de celle-ci. Une analyse approfondie révèle les préjuges intègres dans l'institution même de l'aide juridique. Cette dernière contient donc son propre obstacle à la remise en cause des conceptions prédétermines et dominantes. […]</description><creator>Phelan, Siobhán</creator><contributor>Macdonald, Rod (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Legal assistance to the poor -- Ireland.</subject><subject>Legal assistance to the poor -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Legal aid -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Legal Aid – The Master’s Tool?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq56k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935526r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s4772</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:07:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Deux études furent entreprises pour déterminer les préférences alimentaires des porcelets pré- et post-sevrage lorsque donne le choix entre des diètes similaires différant seulement dans l'ingrédient expérimental. Dans une première étude, 25 portées Landrace de porcelets nourrissons et 15 portées Landrace de porcelets sevrés hâtivement (21 jours) furent affectées à un test de préférence et une combinaison de 2 diètes contenant 70% de mais (M), de blé (B), d'orge (0), ou C d'avoine (A) ainsi que 30% d'un pré-mélange, selon un modèle entièrement aléatoire. La préférence relative maximale des porcelets nourrissons fut obtenue avec la diète à base de B (60%a) suivie du M (56%ab) de l’O (47%ab), et finalement de I'A (36%b). Les préférences alimentaires relatives des porcelets sevres furent similaires, le B (74%") étant encore une fois l'ingrédient le plus apprécié, suivit du M (58%ab), de l’O (50%ab) et finalement de I'A (17%b) qui fut nettement rejetée (p&lt;0.05). […]</description><description>Two experiments were carried out to assess the dietary preferences of nursing and early-weaned piglets when offered a choice between similar diets differing only in one experimental ingredient. In experiment 1, 25 nursing and 15 early-weaned (21 days) Landrace litters were assigned to a preference test and a combination of two diets containing 70% of corn (C), wheat (W), barley (8), or oats (O) and 30% of a basal mix in a completely randomized design. Maximum percent of relative preference and highest average daily intake per piglet were obtained, for the nursing piglets, with diets containing W (60%a), followed by C (56%ab), B (52%ab), and finally O (31%b). Only the difference between W and O was significant (p&lt;0.05). The preferences expressed by the weaned piglets were similar, with W being again the most preferred (74%a), followed by C (58%ab), B (50%ab) and finally O (17%b) which was clearly disliked (p&lt;0.05). […]</description><creator>Bruneau, Christian D.</creator><contributor>Chavez, Eduardo R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Swine -- Feeding and feeds.</subject><title>Assessment of Feed Ingredient Preferences by Piglets during the Nursing and Post-Weaning Age</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f85b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s4772</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sz256</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:07:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prokaryotic and eukaryotic cells respond to potentially damaging stimuli such as elevated temperature by the rapid, vigorous and transient acceleration in the rate of expression of a small number of specific genes, known as heat shock genes. Consequently the products of these genes collectively known as heatshock proteins (HSPs) or stress proteins increase and accumulate in cells to reach fairly large concentrations. Several of the major heat shock proteins are members of gene families that include proteins normally present in the cell and, in most cases, essential for cell function. […]</description><creator>Wang, Ying</creator><contributor>Morgan, William D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Heat shock proteins</subject><title>Interaction of human heat shock factor-1 transcription with promotor DNA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r460.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz256</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3775</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>