<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:50:16Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd58p" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd58p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:30:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the rapid development of technology and society, inactivity has become a main challenge in modern lives. As the basic units for living, communities and cities should be planned to incorporate physical activity into daily errands and encourage residents to be more active. A healthy community should improve the quality of residents’ physical health, mental well-being, and social contacts.This report analyzes the planning strategies to design communities for active living from two aspects, transportation and land use. Planning principles for better walking and cycling environments are studied. Designing guidelines of mixed land use and vibrant public space are examined. Three precedents are selected to illustrate the implementation of the strategies. The Western Harbor in Sweden is chosen to show how to build dense and mix-used communities with vibrant public space in suburbs. The Manhattan Borough of New York, US is selected to show how to plan a metropolitan with a high walkability. Copenhagen, the city of cyclists, is chosen to show how to offer equipped cycling facilities and environments to encourage more cycling. The study shows that the planning of communities for active living cannot be easily achieved by a single planning strategy. To increase physical activity, an organization of fine urban structures, decent walking facilities, safe cycling infrastructures, and convenient access to daily errands should be achieved with the efforts from urban planners, neighborhood committees and municipalities.</description><description>Avec le développement rapide de la technologie et de la société, l'inactivité est devenue un défi majeur dans la vie moderne. Comme les unités de base pour la vie, les communautés et les villes doivent être planifiées à intégrer l'activité physique dans les courses quotidiennes et encourager les résidents à être plus actifs.Ce rapport analyse les stratégies de planification pour concevoir les communautés de vie active de deux aspects, le transport et l'utilisation des terres. Les principes de planification pour le meilleur environement de marche et cyclisme sont étudiés. Les lignes directrices de conception d'utilisation mixte des terres et de l'espace public dynamique sont examinées. Trois précédents sont choisis pour illustrer la mise en œuvre des stratégies. Le Port de l'Ouest en Suède est choisi pour montrer comment construire des communautés denses et à usage mixte avec un espace public vivant dans les banlieues. Le Manhattan Borough de New York est choisie pour montrer comment planifier une métropole avec une grande accessibilité piétonne. Copenhague, la ville des cyclistes, est choisi pour montrer la façon d'offrir des installations et des environnements de cyclisme équipés pour encourager le cyclisme.L'étude montre que une organisation de bonnes structures en milieu urbain, desinstallationsde marche décent, des infrastructures cyclables sécuritaires et desaccès pratiquesaux courses quotidiennes devrait être atteint avec les efforts de planificateurs urbains, des comités de quartier et les municipalités.</description><creator>Lu, Mingyu</creator><contributor>Friedman, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Architecture</subject><title>Communities for active living: planning strategies on transportation and land use</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vp06m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd58p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>