<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:58:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc85v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An optical technique for monitoring the solidification of thermoplastics in an injection moulding machine was implemented. The technique uses a He-Ne laser that illuminates the mould cavity, and a photomultiplier to measure the intensity of reflected light during the moulding cycle. Data from the sensor allows tracking the injection moulding cycle development. The measured light intensity is mainly influenced by refraction and reflection phenomena at the melt-solid interfaces during solidification. Reflection occurs primarily from the opposite mould wall but the reflection intensity is a complex composite of reflective scattering and refraction from crystallites, the mould wall and as many as six interfaces. The scattering caused by the opposite mould wall roughness also affects the light intensity. Plots of reflection intensity during the injection moulding cycle obtained for the three materials tested show similar patterns. Polystyrene, polypropylene and high-density polyethylene resins were used. The higher scattering power of semi-crystalline polyethylene and polypropylene reduces the reflection intensity values compared to the polystyrene plots. Further experimental and analytical work is required to use this technique for process control purposes.</description><creator>Ramírez Domínguez, Edgar C.</creator><contributor>Patterson, W. I. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><title>Optical sensing of thermoplastics solidification in an injection moulding machine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x3490.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc85v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881p21h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Potable water for some regions of the world is difficult or even impossible to find. However, some of these locations have salt water or brackish water and desalination can make this water potable. Currently, reverse osmosis, evaporators, and solar stills are used for this purpose. In this study, membrane distillation was examined and deemed to be a potential alternative. In this thesis, two polypropylene tubular membrane units were compared; they differed in membrane tube length and number of tubes. The system was configured for direct contact membrane distillation. The feed passed through the membrane lumen, while the cooling water passed counter current on the shell side. The stream temperatures (feed: 35°C--47°C, cooling: 15°C--26°C), concentration of the feed solution (0--5 wt% NaCl), and the flow rates (feed Reynolds number: 750--4500) were varied. The feed flow rate, feed temperature, and the difference between the stream temperatures had the largest effect on the permeate flux. Within the range examined, feed salt concentration had no observable effect. A semi-empirical lumped parameter model of the membrane distillation process was validated with both the 0.036 m2 and 1 m 2 tubular membrane units. The model predictions were consistent with the experimental data. It was concluded that when using the same type of membranes in a similar configuration and only increasing the number of tubes or the length, the permeate rate is a function of area.</description><creator>Prasanna, Praveen Ram Menta.</creator><contributor>Simandl, Jana (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>A study and scale-up of desalination via membrane distillation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd875.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881p21h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j329b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Under open access, market driven transactions have become the new independent decision variables defining the behaviour of electric power systems. Understanding the impact of these bilateral transactions on system losses and line loading is important for the secure operation of the network and for establishing equitable tariffs corresponding to actual network use. The theory presented here is based on the argument that it is always possible to compute the exact loss and line loading allocation corresponding to an infinitesimal variation in a bilateral transaction. This leads to a set of governing differential equations whose solution yields the exact allocation. Numerical examples illustrate the properties of both the exact and approximate solutions of the allocation equations, as well as their dependence on the path of integration. The exact solutions are also compared with those obtained using pro-rata methods, DC power flow formulations, and contract paths. Lastly, practical applications of the allocation algorithm are suggested and discussed.</description><creator>Phelan, Mark.</creator><contributor>Galiana, Francisco. D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Business Administration, Accounting.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Energy.</subject><title>Loss and line flow allocation in a competitive environment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b1044.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j329b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k021c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Geons are simple 3-D geometric primitives proposed by Biederman for object representation. The idea is to segment objects into an arrangement of simple geometric shapes. Objects represented by geons can be identified more easily since the many-to-one mapping of object recognition is reduced to the recognition of a small number of geons. In this project, a vision system is implemented for the search and recognition of geons. The vision system is composed of a colour camera and a laser range finder, and is mounted on a pan-tilt unit. The entire setup is mounted on a mobile robot. The task of the system can be divided into two phases: The first phase is focus of attention. Our focus of attention algorithm is based on colour. The geons are painted with a pre-determined colour, and the colour camera searches for objects with that colour. Upon detection of a geon, the mobile robot moves towards it in preparation for the next phase. The second phase is object recognition. With the robot in the proximity of the geon, the laser range finder is used to obtain range data of the geon for recognition. Since only a small number of geons (N = 7) is considered in this project, very sparse range data is sufficient for successful recognition.</description><creator>Ng, Romney K. H.</creator><contributor>Levine, Martin D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Geon recognition using a mobile robot vision system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945t03w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k021c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r770k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The response of closed-cell polyethylene foams to blast loading was studied by systematically exposing foam sheets to blasts from explosive charges. It has been found that depending on the blast strength, foam type, and foam sample thickness, that the transmitted pressure felt beneath the foam could be either attenuated or amplified. A distinctive feature of the foams' response, when impacted by a relatively strong blast, is a pressure plateau. To compliment the experiments, a model of the foams under blast loading has been developed. This was achieved by first characterizing the stress-strain behavior of the foams over a range of strain rates, using both a hydraulic testing machine and a drop weight impact tester. The results of this testing was then used to create a rate-dependent constitutive model of the foams. In order to simulate blast loading, the model was implemented into a finite difference wave propagation code. Simulations show many of the features apparent in the experiments, including the amplification and attenuation of the transmitted pressures and the observed pressure plateau.</description><creator>Nerenberg, Jeffery G.</creator><contributor>Nemes, James A. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Frost, David L. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Blast wave loading of polymeric foams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r99d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r770k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n328t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis research addresses the challenges involved in the design of WITS, the Welding Intelligent Tutoring System. The project was motivated by the desire of providing a realistic training environment for maintenance workers involved in the repair of grounding fixtures on electrical power station equipment. The thesis elaborates on each of WITS' three subcomponents: the user interface and peripherals, the expert system, and the 3D virtual environment. The research focuses on the creation of a 3D representation of the operator and his tools. This virtual operator is built to have basic interaction capabilities namely touch and grasp and is made capable of communicating with the expert system which contains the task expertise and thus provides the necessary coaching. Keyboard and voice command interfaces were also developed so that users with no access to a graphical virtual environment can still take full advantage of the expert system.</description><creator>Mourad, Atallah.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><subject>Education, Technology.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Education, Industrial.</subject><title>Human interface and interaction in the WITS training system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd30m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n328t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375z582</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As digital processors continue to reach new performance limits, the pressure on the interface between the analog world and these processors, formed by A/D and D/A converters, continues to mount. Also, to reduce fabrication costs, the trend has been to integrate both the analog and digital components of mixed-signal systems on a single chip. Thus, there is a need for high-performing converters, capable of coexisting with the digital circuitry. This thesis is concerned with the design and implementation of high-performance, monolithic A/D converters based on DeltaSigma modulation for various applications ranging from speech and audio to digital radio. High performance implies many qualities, such as high-speed, high resolution, wide bandwidth, low power and/or low voltage. In this work, the emphasis is placed on resolution, speed, and bandwidth. Two approaches are considered in order to meet those goals: high-order, single-bit bandpass modulators, and multi-bit implementations. The Switched Capacitor (SC) technique is used to implement the various modulators described due to its mature design state and its well-known capability of providing high resolution at fairly high speeds. The various designs are fabricated through the Canadian Microelectronics Corporation (CMC) in Northern Telecom's 0.8 mum BiCMOS process, and experimental results are given for all the modulators discussed. Therefore, this work contributes by examining the applicability of high-performance BP modulators for digital radio, and by investigating new possible multi-bit DeltaSigma implementation methods.</description><creator>Louis, Loai.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A study of delta-sigma modulators for analog-to-digital conversion /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000223q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z582</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bk35h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Log-domain filters have recently received considerable research attention as an intriguing alternative to the existing continuous-time filter implementations. Log-domain filtering explicitly employs the diode nature of bipolar transistors, resulting in a class of frequency-shaping translinear circuits. It demonstrates potential in high-speed and low-power applications. Most interesting of all, it opens the door to elegantly realizing a linear system with inherently non-linear (logarithmic-exponential) circuit building blocks, and may benefit from the advantages offered by companding signal processing. However, log-domain filters suffer directly from transistor-level nonidealities. This thesis will study the filter response deviations due to major transistor imperfections, which include parasitic emitter and base resistances, finite beta, Early effect, and area mismatches. SPICE simulations, both large and small-signal analysis, are performed to verify the results. By understanding the underlying deviation mechanisms, very natural and simple electronic compensation methods are proposed. The analysis will cover both biquadratic and high-order ladder log-domain filters.</description><creator>Leung, Vincent W.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Analysis and compensation of log-domain filter deviations due to transistor nonidealities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g7187.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bk35h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g468</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Through exhaustive simulations and experimental work, this thesis investigates and develops practical solutions to efficiently perform bandpass digital-to-analog conversion using sigma-delta (SigmaDelta) techniques. Due to the robust VLSI CMOS technology, these techniques are widely used nowadays to realize high quality data converters. In particular, a novel and modular structure is proposed to implement high-order bandpass digital SigmaDelta modulators with variable bandwidth and arbitrary resolution. Using this structure, near-optimum noise suppression is achieved even after coefficient quantization errors are introduced. In addition, high speed operation is now attained independent of the modulator order. A synthesis method is also provided which is straightforward and easy to automate. As such, the new SigmaDelta modulator was entered into the Delta-Sigma Modulator and Oscillator Design program called DSMOD. Because of the use of Sigma modulation, the signal band is surrounded by noise which requires post-filtering. In the second part of this thesis, a high frequency filtering approach using active inductors is examined as a potential solution to extracting the encoded information from the Sigma output bitstream. A novel floating active inductor was created. To illustrate the operation of this floating inductor, a sixth-order bandpass LC reconstruction filter was designed, built and tested on the bench. All designs in this thesis were implemented with programmable gate arrays and/or custom-layout integrated circuits (IC) in a 0.8 mum BiCMOS process. Experimental results and measurements of these ICs will be provided.</description><creator>Leong, Choon-Haw.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>New architectures for high-order bandpass sigma-delta modulation in digital-to-analog converters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x92r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g468</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xd88f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Besides the need to have generally available power system test networks with parameters that closely match those of realistic power systems, the continuously increasing sizes of practical power systems also dictates a growing requirement for larger and larger test networks. A new method is proposed for the development of artificial, but reasonably realistic, power system networks of arbitrary size and complexity, suitable for full load-flow analysis (having feasible load-flow solution). It is based on an iterative procedure to expand an initial network by adding a new bus and/or line at each iterative step, until the system of the desired size and complexity is reached. The method is implemented using a new "backwards" approach, which maintains the network determined in the previous iterative step the same everywhere, except at the bus (or buses) where the new network element is added. Five different sample networks, together with all the data necessary for full load-flow calculations have been computed to illustrate the performance of the new method. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kockar, Ivana.</creator><contributor>McFee, S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Iterative generation of synthetic power system networks for load flow studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j110h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd88f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999876c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The onset of a 'late' rotating vortex over an off-centre drain nozzle at 2/3 radius was studied in an 1160-mm diameter tank. It was found that using a sloped bottom ladle could be beneficial in terms of steel yield, provided the exit nozzle is located 'centrically'. Miner modification of the nozzle (skewed nozzle) to impart a radial component of velocity to the spinning vortex core was found to be effective in making AMEPA system sensitive to early slag entrainment phenomena by diverting the core away from the central vertical axis of the nozzle. A 0.75 scale water model was constructed to simulate the flow of liquid steel through a ladle shroud in the presence of gas infiltration. It was found that the ladle shroud slag detector could be temporarily 'blinded' by gas bubbles or permanently blinded by a standing submerged gas jet.</description><creator>Kim, Hyoungbae, 1969-</creator><contributor>Guthrie, R. I. L. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Physical modelling of two phase flows in ladle-shroud systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r054w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999876c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n503</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ever increasing demand of communication bandwidth places more stringent demands on the electronic systems. Optical interconnects can help satisfy these requirements. In order for an optical interconnect to be successful, a number of factors must be considered. These include the actual integration of the opto-electronic devices with silicon, the packaging of the opto-electronic chip, power and noise considerations. Of particular interest at present are the Hybrid/SEED devices implemented as Smart Pixel Arrays (SPA) to encode the electronic data (using intensity modulation) onto an array of constant power beams of light. The migration from modulator based systems to emitter based systems is also becoming critical. This document deals with some aspects of a photonic backplane technology. It deals with the design of opto-electronic chips as well as considering power consumption reduction and noise in these chips. It also deals with the packaging of the chips with considerations of bandwidth and thermal issues. The packaging must deal with the space constraints defined by the optical interconnect as well the provide the electrical connectivity required by the opto-electronic chip. The issues involved in the testing and characterization of the opto-electronic chips as well as the package are also addressed. It contains some preliminary data for driving Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Lasers (VCSEL) arrays with emphasis on modulation bandwidth. This is for characterizing VCSELs as high modulation bandwidth optical sources. A small signal model for the VCSELs was also developed to calculate the modulation bandwidth of the VCSELs.</description><creator>Khurana, Pritha.</creator><contributor>Tooley, F. A. P. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Plant, D. V. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Optoelectronic circuit design, packaging and characterization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d637b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n503</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sc46p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The utilization of ultrasound in diagnostic medicine has increased since the 1950's. Ultrasound is a non-invasive two dimensional (2D) imaging technique that provides useful information about underlying soft tissue anatomical structures. Developed recently, three dimensional (3D) reconstruction algorithms convert a series of sequential 2D ultrasound images into 3D data sets. 3D reconstruction is one phase in a pipeline for 3D ultrasound volume visualization that typically takes upwards of 2 minutes to complete. The objective of this research focuses on high speed 3D ultrasound reconstruction by comparing reconstruction speeds on parallel and sequential processors. To decrease reconstruction times, optimizations such as; conversion from floating point to fixed point, multithreading, in-line coding, and mathematical analysis were performed. Optimizations achieved a 15%--50% performance increase. Although parallel processors are not a requirement for 3D reconstruction, they will be necessary to achieve the ultimate goal of real-time 3D ultrasound volume visualization.</description><creator>Karnick, Amol S.</creator><contributor>Watkin, K. L. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>High speed 3D ultrasound reconstruction : a comparative study between parallel and sequential processors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf132.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc46p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm57h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of WITS Welding Intelligent Tutoring System is to provide a realistic and safe virtual reality environment to train electrical workers in performing standard alumino-thermal ground welding procedures on equipment in an electrical switching station yard. The WITS training system allows users to practice a variety of welding scenarios which satisfy company practices and provides help, feedback, and a performance evaluation. The Virtual Reality Interface, Expert System, Virtual Environment, and Monitoring modules of WITS are presented. This thesis focuses on the monitoring of human interactions in the WITS Welding Intelligent Tutoring System. The Monitoring module design includes welding task, manipulation, physics, scheduling, and weather agents. Implementation test results show the feasibility of this approach for monitoring the user's manual interactions in this training environment.</description><creator>Kaddoura, Mohamad Khaled.</creator><contributor>Malowany, Alfert (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Education, Technology.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Education, Industrial.</subject><title>Monitoring human interaction in the WITS virtual reality training environment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b549q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm57h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375z59b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines rock mass characteristics of the Bousquet 2 mine, and reviews ground reinforcement practices applied to tunnel and stope hanging-wall support. The effectiveness and suitability of the installed support elements is examined through numerical modelling techniques and instrumentation. The second part of the thesis examines mechanisms influencing stope hanging-wall stability. Through a case study incorporating hanging-wall instrumentation, numerical modelling, and laser survey of the mined stope profiles, the extent of hanging-wall over-break in both primary and secondary stopes is studied.</description><creator>Henning, John G.</creator><contributor>Mitri, H. S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Ground control strategies at the Bousquet 2 mine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd89q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z59b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn816</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An analytical model for computing the supply current, delay, and power of a submicron CMOS inverter is presented. The effect of the Miller capacitance is also modeled. A modified version of the n-th power law MOSFET model [25] is proposed and used to relate the terminal voltages to the drain current in submicron transistors. By first computing definable reference points on the output voltage waveform and then using linear approximations through these points to find the actual points of interest, the desired speed and accuracy of the inverter model is achieved. The most important part of the analysis is a three-step process for computing the time and output voltage when the short-circuit transistor changes its mode of operation. The time and output voltage when the charging/discharging current reaches its maximum are also calculated and then used to evaluate the propagation delay and characterize the output voltage waveform. The model, implemented in MATLAB, has been validated with a wide range of inverters under various conditions of input transition time and capacitive load: it can predict the delay, peak supply current, and power dissipation to within a few percent of ELDO simulation results, while offering about two orders of magnitude gains in CPU time over ELDO simulator. Hence, its use in CAD tools supporting low power design is justified.</description><creator>Hamoui, Anas.</creator><contributor>Rumin, Nicholas (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Current, delay, and power analysis of submicron CMOS circuits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms04b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn816</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt406</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An accurate and efficient method is presented for computing the supply current pulse and delay in a CMOS inverter with an RC load. It is based on the technique presented in [11] for solving this problem for the case of a capacitive load, but any similar method can be used. An iterative procedure computes the effective capacitance that approximates the RC load's driving point impedance. This is done be equating the charge associated with this capacitance to that due to the RC load over the time interval ending when the charging/discharging transistor leaves saturation. The supply current peak and its time of occurrence are then obtained using the method in [11]. A simple yet accurate analytical approach is finally used to compute the complete output voltage and supply current waveforms. Since the effective capacitance iteration converges in only two to three steps, the resulting model is computationally efficient, and the two to three order of magnitude speedup over Spice achieved in [11] is preserved.</description><creator>Hafed, Mohamed M.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>CMOS inverter current and delay models incorporating interconnect effects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk749.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt406</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032515h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A bolometer for infrared detection and imaging, operating at room temperature, is presented. The detector consists of a metal thin film deposited over a suspended SiO2 membrane using thermal evaporation. The suspended membrane increases responsitivity by minimizing thermal conductance and is fabricated by employing an isotropic etch to remove the underlying Si substrate from the front-side of the wafer. The membrane size is 100 mum x 12 mum x 0.8 mum. Extensive characterization was performed including measurements of film resistivity and temperature coefficient of resistance as a function of thickness. As well, various metals were explored including Ni, Bi, Au and Cr and Hall measurements were carried out on the Bi thin films since these films show the most preferable characteristics. For optimal devices, the responsitivity is close to 10 V/W and the time response is 130 mus. To specifically demonstrate the effect of the SiO2 suspended membrane on thermal conductance, bolometers fabricated with conventional bulk substrates are also presented. These devices have a thermal conductance three orders of magnitude larger than the devices made using the suspended membrane. Moreover, the responsitivity is 10-5 V/W. A novel micromachining procedure is presented for the fabrication of suspended single crystal silicon membranes on (111) Si. The thickness of the membrane and the vertical separation from the substrate are both easily controlled through the process. Typical values for both parameters lie in the range of 0.1 to 20 microns. Such a structure has many applications including the mechanical support for high-Tc bolometers.</description><creator>Greenspan, Jonathan</creator><contributor>Shih, Ishiang (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>The fabrication and characterization of metal thin film bolometers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z546.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032515h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784n86w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Current research has focused on visual feedback for the development of virtual surgery. However, little is known about the haptic feedback required for realistic simulation. The forces necessary for the cutting of anatomical tissues were investigated for three surgical scissors: the Mayo dissection scissor, the Metzenbaum dissection scissor and the Iris scissor. Several experiments were completed in conjunction with a surgical doctor to acquire force data for analysis. This work aimed to establish the force-position relationship, find any invariant properties for tissues or scissors, and determine the frequency components present in the force signal as well as the significance of the cutting rate. General trends in the data were discovered, and necessary improvements to the experimental method for the determination of more exact quantitative measures were identified. In general, both the measurable force magnitude and "texture" differences contribute to the difference in tactile perception between a blank run and a tissue cutting run. This is a low frequency texture, as 99% of the frequency components of the signal are below 5Hz. The force measurements were determined to be independent of the cutting speed for the Mayo and Metzenbaum scissor runs, whereas results for the Iris scissors were inconclusive. The scissor sensitivity while cutting the tissue longitudinally or transversally appears to be a function of both the tissue and the scissor. To further determine the tactile feedback required for simulation, future experiments should account for the "user grip", tissue thickness, tissue moisture content, hand orientation, and innate scissor dynamics. A database of the collected force and position data has been created on the Internet (Site:http://www.cim.mcgill.ca/~haptic/tissue/data.html). This data allows current force feedback devices, such as the Freedom-7, to determine the feasibility of realistic haptic simulation.</description><creator>Greenish, Stephanie.</creator><contributor>Steffen, Thomas (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Hayward, Vincent (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Acquisition and analysis of cutting forces of surgical instruments for haptic simulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h35c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784n86w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn68d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Schottky junctions were fabricated by evaporating Al on Bridgman-grown monocrystalline p-type CuInSe2 substrates. The effect of single crystal surface preparation on the electrical behavior of the devices was studied. Crystals were mechanically polished and then etched in a bromine/methanol solution. In addition, a group of crystals received a 350°C heat treatment in argon. Devices that received the substrate anneal showed a substantial reduction of junction current. Capacitance-voltage measurements performed at different frequencies indicated the presence of a large density of defect states. The frequency dependence of the capacitance was much more pronounced in non-heat treated devices. The substrate anneal can improve the near-surface quality by reducing defect states created by the mechanical polishing/chemical etching step. Deep level transient spectroscopy (DLTS) revealed a majority carrier trap at 0.18 eV above the valence band in both heat-treated and non-heat treated crystals. A clear relationship between the density of this trap and the CuInSe 2 substrate anneal step could not be established. Electron beam induced current (EBIC) measurements revealed that a buried homojunction was not present in the Schottky junctions. The CuInSe2 minority carrier diffusion length as well as the surface recombination velocity of both cleaved and polished CuInSe2 surfaces was measured by EBIC.</description><creator>Garanzotis, Theodoros.</creator><contributor>Shih, I. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Electrical characterization of CuInSe2 crystals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk34x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn68d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd82c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the major quality problems encountered in continuous casting is the formation of transverse cracks, which is partly due to the poor hot ductility of the cast steel. In this work, high temperature tensile testing is used to determine the hot ductility of a Nb-Ti and Ti-B microllayed steels. The influence of reheat treatment on hot ductility of the alloys is studied. In order to accomplish this task, steel specimens were reheated near the incipient melting temperature, and subsequently tensile tested to fracture at a strain rate typical of the unbending operation over a range of temperatures, in order to obtain hot ductility data. The results are compared to those obtained after melting and solidification prior to high temperature tensile testing. As well, tensile specimens were subjected to thermal histories typical of continuously cast billet surface up to the unbending operation, and then subjected to a tensile test to fracture. In other words, physical simulations of the continuous casting procedure were performed. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>El-Wazri, Abdelbaset M.</creator><contributor>Yue, S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Effect of thermal history on hot ductility of steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k935g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd82c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vq60b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The steeply dipping vein orebody of Bousquet 2 mine is extracted by sublevel open stope method. The presence of structural discontinuities, high induced stress distribution, and narrow stope widths are major factors which can seriously affect ore dilution. Therefore, strict ore dilution control is necessary in order to keep the mine competitive. The thesis describes the selective mining method adapted to this type of orebody, and subsequent measures taken to minimize ore dilution. For this study, the locations of stress relaxation are taken as failures zones. Therefore, these zones are more important since they are subjected to very low stresses which can provoke rock block sliding or local wall caving (tension failure). Tracing the zone of tensile stress in the stope wall gives reasonable prediction of dilution and permits to calibrate the numerical model using the field data obtained from the cavity Monitoring System (CMS). Stope mining is made in several cuts according to the width of the ore zone. For an improved recovery, some stopes are mined using primary and secondary stoping. Blasthole pattern and mining sequences are closely linked to the ore zone configuration. The main causes of ore dilution are summarized. They are a combination of several factors such as ground conditions, blasting damage, state of stresses around the stope, and stope design. In order to minimize ore dilution from hanging-wall and foot-wall, cable support is installed. Numerical modelling is carried out for a typical cable bolt pattern. The results of modelling have demonstrated that the cable bolts were necessary to control hanging wall caving. This is accompanied by a reduction of ore dilution. Consequently the study has shown the effectiveness of cables bolt as pre-support of the schistose walls in Bousquet sublevel stoping environment.</description><creator>Diakité, Oumar.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Ore dilution in sublevel stoping</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n997n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq60b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j38609033</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over half of the earth's dry surface is inaccessible to wheeled or tracked vehicles. Even relatively structured indoor or urban environments with steps, stairs, or narrow hallways, are challenging for most wheeled or tracked systems. This is one of the primary motivations for the study of mobile robots with legs. We propose a new type of quadruped robot with maximum mechanical simplicity---the SCOUT class. Most robots built to date possess many actuated degrees of freedom (DOF) (three or four per leg) thus making them too expensive for practical use. SCOUT robots, on the other hand, feature only one actuated degree of freedom per leg. SCOUT dynamics, while still non-trivial, is greatly simplified compared to that of higher degree of freedom robots. In our analysis, we assume instantaneous plastic impacts occur when a leg touches the ground, and consequently, a momentum transfer occurs that causes step changes in the linear and angular velocities. The calculations of these changes are based on the principle of conservation of angular momentum with respect to the impact toe, since it is that point which acts as pivot, or a free pin joint. A set of walking algorithms based on the controlled momentum transfer have been developed, and validated, using numerical simulations. These algorithms have subsequently been implemented on our walking robots, SCOUT I and SCOUT II. This thesis will show that, with very simple mechanical design and control strategies stable walking is achievable. However, it is important to note that research currently being undertaken in the ARL group will establish that, with only minimal structural changes, SCOUT will have the ability to run and climb stairs.</description><creator>Cocosco, Anca Elena.</creator><contributor>Buehler, Martin (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Control of walking in a quadruped robot with stiff legs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj18f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38609033</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg57s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Speech coding at bit rates near 4 kbps is expected to be widely deployed in applications such as visual telephony, mobile and personal communications. This research focuses on developing a speech coder based on the waveform interpolation (WI) scheme, with an attempt to deliver near toll-quality speech at rates around 4 kbps. A WI coder has been simulated in floating-point using the C programming language. The high performance of the WI model has been confirmed by subjective listening tests in which the unquantized coder outperforms the 32 kbps G.726 standard (ADPCM) 98% of the time under clean input speech conditions; the reconstructed speech is perceived to be essentially indistinguishable from the original. When fully quantized, the speech quality of the WI coder at 4.25 kbps has been judged to be equivalent to or better than that of G.729 (the ITU-T toll-quality 8 kbps standard) for 45% of the test sentences. Further refinements of the quantization techniques are warranted to bring the coder closer to the toll-quality benchmark. Yet, the existing implementation has produced good quality coded speech with a high degree of intelligibility and naturalness when compared to the conventional coding schemes operating in the neighbourhood of 4 kbps.</description><creator>Choy, Eddie L. T.</creator><contributor>Kabal, Peter (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Waveform interpolation speech coder at 4 kbs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b387.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg57s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r5265</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>System identification techniques were used to obtain a parametric description of the mechanical stiffness of the ankle, which was then used to assess the effect of four weeks of stretching the ankle flexors and extensors. The ankle musculo-articular system was described in terms of elastic stiffness, viscosity and inertia. This description of the mechanical behaviour of the ankle joint provided an objective basis for evaluating the effects of a long-term stretching program that utilized proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation (PNF). PNF, preceded by a warm-up, was performed daily on the soleus, tibialis anterior and gastrocnemius of six healthy subjects, for four weeks. The question that we asked in this study was: "Does stretching have an effect on the dynamic stiffness of the ankle joint?" A significant increase in ankle range of motion (p &lt; 0.02) was observed. However, the intrinsic stiffness of the ankle joint did not change. We concluded that the gains in joint range of motion achieved by long-term stretching were due to an increase in the subjects' tolerance to stretching and not to changes in the dynamic stiffness of the joint.</description><creator>Barrett, Christopher, 1970-</creator><contributor>Kearney, Robert E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>The effect of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation with warm-up on ankle joint dynamics /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gg151.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r5265</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>