<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-30T21:51:06Z</responseDate><request identifier="oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rj60p" metadataPrefix="oai_etdms" verb="GetRecord">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><GetRecord><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rj60p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:00:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fusarium head blight (FHB) of barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) is a devastating disease, caused by Fusarium graminearum (teleomorph: Gibberella zea), resulting in reduced yield and quality of grain by producing mycotoxins. The resistance in barley to FHB is quantitative and controlled by several genes, thus making it difficult to breed for resistance. In wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) and barley more than 100 quantitative trait loci (QTL) for resistance have been reported against FHB, but the mechanisms of resistance controlled by these QTL are unknown. Metabolic profiling technology was applied to better understand the mechanisms of resistance and to phenotype resistance in barley genotypes against FHB. The current study aimed to: 1) identified the resistance related (RR) metabolites by comparing resistance in barley cultivars Chevron and Stander against FHB, and determined antimicrobial properties of selected RR metabolites under in vitro conditions; 2)determined the effects of selected RR metabolites on inhibition of trichothecene biosynthesis by F. graminearum under in vitro conditions; 3) identified biomarker metabolites, in six barley genotypes ('Chevron', H5277-44, H5277-164, M92-513,M122, and 'Stander') varying in resistance to FHB, for potential biomarker selection to screen barley genotypes for resistance. Barley genotypes were mock-inoculated or pathogen-inoculated under greenhouse conditions; metabolites were extracted using aqueous methanol and analyzed using LCESI-LTQ-Orbitrap. XCMS and CAMERA algorithms were used to process the LC/MS output. Significant metabolites were classified as RR constitutive, and RR induced based on their greater abundance in resistant genotypes. Deoxynivalenol (DON) and its detoxified metabolite DON-3-O-glucoside (D3G), designated here as resistance indicator metabolites, were detected in both resistant and susceptible genotypes. The resistant cultivar Chevron had the least DON accumulation and high level of DON conversion to D3G. The selected RR metabolites varied in their ability to inhibit mycelial biomass and trichothecene synthesis by F. graminearum in vitro. The major potential biomarkers selected were: p-coumaric acid, sinapic acid, naringenin, naringenin-glucoside, kaempferol-glucosides, jasmonic acid, methyl jasmonate, and linolenic acid.     In conclusion, we have demonstrated here that the mass spectrometry tool can be used to better understand the mechanisms of quantitative resistance in barley against biotic stress and to select potential biomarkers to screen for FHB resistance.</description><description>La fusariose de l'épi (FE) de l'orge est une maladie dévastatrice causée par Fusarium graminearum (Gibberella zea) et résultant en pertes de rendement et de qualité du grain dû à la production de mycotoxines. La résistance à la FE chez l'orge peut être quantifiée et est généralement contrôlée par plusieurs gènes, ce qui limite l'amélioration de ce trait par de simples croisements. Plus de 100 loci de caractères quantitatifs (LCQ) de résistance contre la FE ont été rapportés chez le blé et l'orge, mais les mécanismes de résistance contrôlés par ces LCQ sont inconnus. La technologie de profilage métabolique a été appliquée afin de mieux comprendre les mécanismes de résistance contre la FE et de 'phénotyper' la résistance de certains génotypes d'orge. Les objectifs de cette étude sont : 1) d'identifier les métabolites reliés à la résistance (RR) en comparant la résistance contre la FE descultivars Chevron et Stander et de déterminer les propriétés antimicrobiennes des métabolites RR sélectionnés in vitro; 2) de déterminer l'effet des métabolites RR sélectionnés sur l'inhibition de la biosynthèse du trichothécène par F. graminearum invitro; et 3) d'identifier des métabolites biomarqueurs chez six génotypes ('Chevron', H5277-44, H5277-164, M92-513, 'M122' et 'Stander') avec une résistance différente à la FE, afin de sélectionner des biomarqueurs permettant d'évaluer la résistance chez les génotypes d'orge. Les génotypes d'orge ont été inoculés avec de l'eau ou un pathogène enconditions de serre. Les métabolites ont été extraits avec du méthanol aqueux et analysés avec LC-ESI-LTQ-Orbitrap. Les algorithmes XCMS et CAMERA ont été utilisés pourtraiter le produit LC/MS. Des métabolites significatifs ont été classifiés en fonction de leur lien avec la résistance constitutive et exprimés en fonction de leur abondance qui est plus importante chez les génotypes résistants. Le déoxynivalénol (DON) et le glucoside DON-3-O, son métabolite détoxifié (D3G), désignés ici comme des métabolites indicateurs la résistance, ont été détectés dans les génotypes résistants et sensibles. Le cultivar résistant Chevron a produit le plus bas niveau de DON total et la plus grande proportion de DON converti en D3G. Les métabolites RR sélectionnés ont varié dans leur habileté à inhibiter la biomasse de mycélium et la synthèse du trichothécène par G. zeaein vitro. Les biomarqueurs potentiels qui ont été sélectionnés sont : l'acide p-coumarique, l'acide sinapique, la naringinine, le glucoside de naringinine, les glucosides de kaempférol, l'acide jasmonique, le jasmonate de méthyl et l'acide linolénique. En conclusion, nous avons démontré que la spectrométrie de masse peut être utilisée afin demieux comprendre les mécanismes de résistance quantitative chez l'orge contre le stress biotique et pour sélectionner des biomarqueurs potentiels permettant d'évaluer la résistance FE.</description><creator>Bollina, Venkatesh</creator><contributor>Kushalappa Ajjamada (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Agriculture - Plant Pathology</subject><title>Mass spectrometry based metabolic profiling of six-row barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) genotypes varying in resistance to Fusarium graminearum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042z269.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rj60p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record></GetRecord></OAI-PMH>