<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:41:00Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sc18h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Basu, Sudhamay.</creator><date>1975</date><subject>Deformations (Mechanics)</subject><subject>Solids.</subject><title>On a general deformation theory of structured solids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw471.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc18h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526f25n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the use of English in Quebec offices; it further examined the knowledge and strategies used by francophones as they perform various business-related tasks in English. A sample of 26 offices located in a primarily francophone community were surveyed regarding what tasks employees were required to perform in English. Results showed that all but one required some level of English proficiency. It is to be noted that 46% of the offices surveyed conducted all of their business within Quebec's borders. These findings led to the conclusion that English is a requirement in the majority of offices and therefore should be taught in Quebec's secretarial and accounting programmes. In the second phase of this research, concurrent and retrospective verbal reports were used to examine two of the tasks frequently reported as being performed in English in the offices surveyed. Six volunteers (3 experienced and 3 inexperienced) performed role plays of each task and the strategies they used in the preparation and execution of the role plays were coded into previously determined categories which were based on the work of Bachman and Palmer (1996) as well as that of Tarone (1980). All participants showed evidence of having used Bachman and Palmer's goal setting, assessment and planning strategies in preparation of their role play performances, and they all used at least some of Tarone's compensatory strategies in the actual execution of the role plays. Further research is suggested in the area of strategy-based English second language instruction within the business programmes offered by the Quebec Ministry of Education.</description><creator>Irving, Patricia M.</creator><contributor>Turner, Carolyn E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>English language -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>English language -- Business English.</subject><title>Business English proficiency and its related strategies in the Quebec context</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pj286.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526f25n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g935q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I analyze the Germanophone reception of Gustav Meyrink's The Golem (Der Golem) between 1916 and 1996 with respect to its treatment as light fiction (Trivialliteratur). I examine a representative selection of literary criticism concerning the dominant themes and narrative structures of the novel. Since The Golem could not be ascribed to a distinct genre or period within the canon, its reception has been characterized by profound dichotomies. Meyrink's novel can be seen as a blank screen upon which critics have projected their respective ideological agendas. By applying new historicist and genre studies, I contextualize the trends across eighty years of critical response to The Golem and the dialectical conflict between 'high' literature and popular fiction. I thus demonstrate that the novel's reception is symptomatic of the debate about art and popular fiction concerning works of early modern surrealism.</description><creator>Jabs, Stefanie.</creator><contributor>Schmidt, Josef (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Meyrink, Gustav, 1868-1932. Golem.</subject><title>Die Rezeption von Gustav Meyrinks Roman Der Golem als Werk der Trivialliteratur</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr83s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g935q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sr93x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates a type of infinitival complement previously analyzed as a relative clause construction. The unique properties of this construction, namely, a Specificity Effect on the logical object of the embedded verb and a semantic restriction on the matrix verb, stem from the syntactic structure of the complement. The complement's T (Tense) node is specified [-Tense]. A T that is specified [-Tense] fails to select an Asp (Aspect) projection. The lack of an AspP projection has significant consequences: The embedded verb cannot assign an external theta role and accusative Case cannot be checked. The distinction of infinitival complements on the basis of their Tense specification will be shown to account for a difference in behaviour with respect to VP-deletion, temporal interpretation and the licensing of PRO. Furthermore, the arguments and evidence presented suggest that the functional projection responsible for checking accusative Case features is AspP, not AGRoP.</description><creator>Howatt, Mary.</creator><contributor>Duffield, Nigel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Infinitive.</subject><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Complement.</subject><title>Object infinitival complements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s6742.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr93x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418q090</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From the late nineteenth century to the mid-twentieth century, the experiences of predominantly male Chinese migrants in Canada, their relationship with each other, and their interactions with Chinese and Canadian society were influenced by each society's patriarchal nature. Each society had a culturally-specific patriarchal system that perpetuated the interests of a few elite men over other groups and cultures, and each portrayed this group as the masculine ideal. Since each viewed events through this lens, racism frequently took on a gendered language. The construction of culturally-specific notions of gender helped maintain each community's culturally-specific patriarchal system. Furthermore, racialized gender constructs and gendered constructs of race legitimized existing patterns of domination both within each group and in these groups' interactions with each other. This thesis shows that the categories of race and gender were linked and that a feminist approach is useful for the study of immigration history.</description><creator>Huang, Belinda.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Masculinity.</subject><subject>Sex discrimination against women -- China.</subject><subject>Chinese Canadians -- Attitudes.</subject><subject>Sex discrimination against women -- Canada.</subject><title>Gender, race, and power : the Chinese in Canada, 1920-1950</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t393s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q090</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c4604</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In his Roman de la Rose, Guillaume de Lorris promises several times the revelation of the significance of his work, the senefiance. If the use of allegory by Guillaume does not elucidate the mystery of this senefiance, symbolic interpretation opens a gate in accordance with the time and the text. The dream as a framework signals a symbolic content and provides unity. In an orchard of geometrical proportions, truly edenic garden, the fountain of Narcisus, transformed in a fountain of Love by Cupido, is a mirror perilous, where the Rose will appear. It will confront the dreamer, the future Lover who happens to be the poet himself, to the myth of self-knowledge, sparing him, however, the faith of Narcisus. After a kiss stolen from the Rose too soon by the Lover, Jealousy will command the construction of a castle and a tower to protect the Rose. All these adventures, in this magical setting, will confirm a highly symbolic content and will contribute in enhancing and throwing light on the work of Guillaume de Lorris, although never exhausting its senefiance. The symbolism and the senefiance we deduce from it, will help in understanding the didactic reach of this work, its universal character and in refuting the incompletion of the poem while accepting the incompletion of a quest always renewed.</description><creator>Dicaire, Francine.</creator><contributor>Di Stefano, Giuseppe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Guillaume, de Lorris, fl. 1230. Roman de la Rose.</subject><title>Symbolisme et senefiance dans le Roman de la Rose de G. de Lorris</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m3776.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c4604</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg361</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Shifting cultures of recycled style: a history of second-hand clothing markets in Montreal draws a cultural history of the evolving circuits through which discards of the fashion system pass. The focus is on three manifestations of the market: the female-dominated charity circuits of the nineteenth-century into which the flow of used goods was redirected following the introduction of mass-produced garments; the revival of cast-off clothing's stylish potential by punk and grunge subcultures in their respective creations of a poverty aesthetic; and the more heterogeneously mainstream market of the late 1980s and 1990s operating within a consumer environment seeped in nostalgia. The second-hand market is a facet of the fashion system receiving scant attention by the academic community. This study aims to redress the oversight by demonstrating how much of a given society is revealed through the ways in which its members manage the matter of sartorial waste.</description><creator>Diggins, Kimberly A.</creator><contributor>Marchessault, Janine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Used clothing industry -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Fashion -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Vintage clothing -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Shifting cultures of recycled style : a history of second-hand clothing markets in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm88s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg361</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c459c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The legend of Shambhala incorporated in the Tibetan Canon, has been one of the favourite motives of Tibetan Buddhism throughout the centuries. High lamas and laity alike venerated the legend connecting their innermost aspirations with it. For some it represents a mystical millennial country revealing itself only to the chosen ones, while others perceive it as a symbol of the hidden treasures of the mind. This way or the other, the legend of Shambhala remains a living belief for many. The present hardships of Tibet made the legend with its leitmotif of future victory of Buddhism, especially viable. When the legend reached the West in the beginning of this century, it inspired many westerners including political leaders, and acquired diverse and innovative interpretations. Conveying the ever cherished human dream of a better world beyond ours, the legend of Shambhala proved to be a ubiquitous symbol surpassing its original Buddhist framework.</description><creator>Dmitrieva, Victoria.</creator><contributor>Hayes, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Civilization, Western -- Chinese influences.</subject><subject>Shambhala.</subject><subject>Buddhist mythology.</subject><title>The legend of Shambhala in Eastern and Western interpretations /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tn94f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c459c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h54z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Midrash is a genre of rabbinic Bible exegesis, composed by various authors and compiled in anthologies during the first seven centuries of the Common Era. This thesis explores the reading of Midrash and its possible influence on early artistic activity. Examples of early Jewish and Christian biblical representations that display some degree of midrashic impact, are presented in order to establish the existence of a relationship between Midrash and art. Finally, by a systematic reading of the corpus of midrashic literature found in Midrash Rabbah, Midrashim that suggest graphic representation, but which have not yet to been found among early art forms, are categorized and analyzed.</description><creator>Dascal, Elana.</creator><contributor>Levy, B. Barry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Art, Early Christian.</subject><subject>Jewish art and symbolism.</subject><title>Reading Midrash as graphic artistic activity : the compilation of Midrash Rabbah as possible influences on early Jewish and Christian art</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc433.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h54z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h152d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis attempts a critical examination of the theory of war under Islamic and public international law, in an effort to demonstrate that jihad is a just, defensive, and exceptional form of warfare, geared to the maintenance of peace, and the protection of human rights for all people, whether those rights be exercised alone or in association with others, without distinction as to race, sex, language or religious belief. Through an examination of the norms of Islamic and public international law on armed conflict, this thesis argues that Islamic law, which governs the doctrine of jihad, is realistic and practical. Further, it made a great contribution to international humanitarian law more than a millennium before the codification of the four Geneva Conventions of 1949, and eight centuries before the appearance of Hugo Grotius treatise "De jure belli ac pacis libri tres" in 1625. Furthermore, this comparative study reveals that the word jihad might be one of the most misunderstood terms in the history of Islamic legal discourse. This analysis also claims that the division of the world into dar al-Islam (territory of Islam) and dar al-harb (territory of war), which is not predicated on a state of mutual hostility, was dictated by particular events, and was not imposed by scripture. Moreover, this discussion provides that Islamic humanitarian law regulates conduct during a jihad on the basis of certain humane principles, compatible with those upon which modern international conventions are based. Finally, this thesis concludes that there is a unique relationship between jihad and the notion of just war, a matter which qualifies it as the bellum justum of Islam.</description><creator>Zawātī, Ḥilmī.</creator><contributor>Hallaq, Wael (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Cotler, Irwin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>War (International law)</subject><subject>Jihad.</subject><subject>Just war doctrine.</subject><subject>War (Islamic law)</subject><title>Just war, peace and human rights under Islamic and international law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd64v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h152d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k460m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Martin Amis remains on the outer fringes of the modern literary canon because his novels have not been appreciated in the context within which they were written. This is, basically, a postmodernist experimental mode which self-consciously tests (but does not abandon) the boundaries of form and content in the traditional English novel. The principal contention here is that Amis "challenges" but does not "change" the human subject as it exists in literature. Hyper-self-consciousness, the signature mark of postmodernism, does not mean simply that Amis's characters are just one-dimensional pawns of literary gamesmanship, even though this is a valid point of inquiry (examined in Chapter One). Rather, the presentation of subjectivity allows for a polyphonous critique and affirmation of literary and moral value. Such critiques and affirmations can be analysed when one examines Amis's inscription and parody of past value systems (such as modernism, described in Chapter Two), and those of the present, nuclear age (described in Chapter Three). As these three inquiries show, Amis does offer a portrait of the human subject, but it is bruised and abused by both the author and the world. Value, in other words, exists here, but its packaging is distinctly different. Amis is therefore not an immoral pop-cultural icon, but a serious postmodernist writer that deserves to be judged accordingly.</description><creator>Allison, Ryan.</creator><contributor>de Monchey, Marika Finley (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Amis, Martin -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Style is entertainment, style is morality : contradiction and subjectivity in the postmodern novels of Martin Amis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w4295.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k460m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn68n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Free space optical interconnects are a viable candidate to meet the intensive bandwidth requirements for interconnecting the future high performance digital computing systems and switching fabrics. Transceivers for the optoelectronic VLSI are key components of such systems. The design constraints of such transceivers (especially receivers) are quite different from the transceivers used for telecommunication links. Besides the requirement for availability in large arrays (and associated constraints such as small area, low complexity and low power dissipation), it is desirable that the transceivers contribute to making the optical design easy for the system. With the above objectives in mind, the various issues of transmitter and receiver design are considered in this thesis. BICMOS drivers are proposed as transmitter drivers instead of conventional CMOS. Time-differential receiver, a new mode of receiver operation, is introduced. Current-mode operation of receiver is discussed to enhance tolerance to optical misalignment. Future areas for research and development are then considered.</description><creator>Sinha, Pritam.</creator><contributor>Tooley, Frank A. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Transceiver design for optical interconnects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz64b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn68n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g29m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the historical development of the Japanese comic performance genre of manzai, and its contemporary manifestations. The first chapter examines manzai's ritual origins in the Heian court and its subsequent expansion throughout Japan as an established performance style. The chapter also describes the genre of 'classical manzai' and discusses its present status. The second chapter examines how 'stage manzai' emerged in Osaka from a panoply of popular entertainment forms, and particularly from niwaka stage comedy. The third chapter describes the emergence of the genre of 'modern manzai,' details its adaptation to radio and discusses the impact of the Second World War. The fourth chapter examines modern manzai's post-war development and focuses on its representation through television. The fifth chapter provides excerpts of modern manzai performance in its various stages of evolution. Finally, the sixth chapter discusses the challenges facing modern manzai today and contemplates possibilities for its future.</description><creator>Bensky, Xavier Benjamin.</creator><contributor>Lamarre, Thomas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Manzai (Comedy) -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Manzai : metamorphoses of a Japanese comic performance genre</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb28x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g29m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m1372</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A combination of technical innovations, system cost reductions, and post-1970's tourism industry restructuring has led to the development and diffusion of a variety of sophisticated computer reservation systems, or CRSs. Questions remain as to the extent to which tourism suppliers and destinations have achieved CRS links. In this case study of two urban destinations, Montreal and Toronto, tourism supplier relationships with CRS technology are examined. Drawing on results from the accommodation and attraction sectors of each city, the varying degrees of CRS adoption and impact are illustrated. CRS adoption by firms is shown to be constrained by a variety of management market, and tourism product-oriented barriers. Strategies employed by tourism suppliers to counter and overcome these barriers are identified. Following a review of tourism and information technology policies within Canada, some regulatory initiatives that may assist in facilitating successful technology adoption and use among the various components of the urban tourism product are proposed. The constantly evolving 'technological' channels and networks of tourism marketing and distribution are shown to be important influences on tourism destination policy. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Gill, Kara M.</creator><contributor>Milne, Simon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Tourism -- Data processing.</subject><subject>Reservation systems -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Reservation systems -- Ontario -- Toronto -- Case studies.</subject><title>Computer reservations systems in the Montreal and Toronto tourism industries : adoption and use trends</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c81s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m1372</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m8739</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis will investigate the significance of the Eastern Orthodox perspective of theosis, for the bioethical principle of autonomy, specifically with regard to its respect for the elderly. Theosis is a central doctrine of the Orthodox Church which pertains to the salvation of human persons and their free and cooperative response to God's grace, and as such, has an intimate relationship with the Eastern Orthodox understanding of personhood. On the one hand there are a number of areas of mutual concern or overlap between the concept of respect for autonomy and the Orthodox understanding of personhood and the goal of theosis. There are, however, significant differences which prevent them from being viewed as synonymous or even as totally compatible. There are complementary aspects, some of which will be identified in this initial study. It is hoped that such an investigation can help to further develop Eastern Orthodox thinking with regard to bioethical issues and be of value when dealing with the complex issues related to the elderly. This topic will also be of interest to a wider audience involved in bioethical reflection from both Christian and secular perspectives.</description><creator>Frank, Barbara, 1951-</creator><contributor>Keyserlingk, Edward W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Theological anthropology -- Christianity.</subject><subject>Orthodox Eastern Church -- Doctrines.</subject><subject>Autonomy (Psychology) in old age.</subject><subject>Aging -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.</subject><title>Respect for the autonomy of the elderly : an Orthodox perspective of theosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3061.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m8739</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj20q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the relationship between the Children's Depression Inventory (CDI; Kovacs, 1983) factor scores and the longitudinal outcomes of depressive symptomatology in a non-clinical sample of children (mean age = 10.67 years). The CDI was administered to measure depressive symptomatology at three intervals: twice within a two-week period to verify that clinical levels of depressive symptoms had persisted, and once at a seven month follow-up to measure the outcome of those depressive symptoms. Results suggested that recovery from depressive symptoms was comparable to recovery rates of depression in adult and child clinical populations. There was little empirical support for the hypothesis that Kovacs' CDI factors could discriminate between children with a good outcome of recovering from their depressive symptomatology and those with a poor outcome. An unexpected result was the lack of significant correlations among the factors in the depressed sample. The implications for these findings are discussed.</description><creator>Gerstein, Stephanie Hannah.</creator><contributor>Heath, Nancy Lee (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Depression in children -- Testing.</subject><subject>Psychological tests for children.</subject><title>Examining the Children's Depression Inventory Factors' ability to predict outcomes of depression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qn97h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj20q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w98r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an historical examination of the most radical antireligious policy in Eastern Europe under Communism. It will document the Albanian government's religious policy during the Communist period between 1944--1991, devoting special attention to the policy initiated during the Albanian Cultural Revolution (1967) which outlawed all religious practice of Islam and Christianity, public and private, for a period of twenty-three years. Historical factors which had bearing on the Albanian regime's militant atheism will be surveyed. The ideology of the Albanian Communist Party, the main component of which is nationalism, will be cited as the foundation of the "World's First Atheist State." This research will further address the he vulnerabilities of Albanian religious institutions, making possible their vulnerabilities of Albanian religious institutions, making possible their abolition by the state, as well as the significant amount of popular resistance to the state's official atheism, ensuring the return of Islam and Christianity to Albanian society.</description><creator>Gallagher, Amelia.</creator><contributor>Turgay, A Uner (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Furcha, Edward (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Religion and politics -- Albania.</subject><subject>Communism and religion.</subject><subject>Albania -- Politics and government -- 1944-1990.</subject><subject>Albania -- Religion.</subject><title>The Albanian atheist state, 1967-1991 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182n14g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w98r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sx781</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Quebec, between 1914 and 1939, women were portrayed as keepers of the hearth, roles established since the mid-19th century, and further reinforced in the early 20th century when the Western World was threatened with drops in population, high infant mortality and the general ill-health of society. French Canadian physicians were one of the self-proclaimed leaders and experts who maintained they possessed all the knowledge to cure society's ills. Their attention fell principally on the elimination of infant mortality on the one hand, and the promotion of multiple births on the other. To succeed, physicians maintained that while they held the knowledge, women and mothers were ultimately responsible for applying it. Training for motherhood began as early as childhood and would continue until maturity. Medical prescriptions for francophone mothers relied heavily on religion and patriotism to convince them that quality motherhood was necessary if the French Canadian "race" were to survive in an increasing changing landscape.</description><creator>Taylor, Nadine.</creator><contributor>Levesque, Andree (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Women -- Québec (Province) -- Social conditions.</subject><subject>Medicine -- Québec (Province) -- History.</subject><subject>Women -- Health and hygiene -- Québec (Province) -- History.</subject><title>The road to sainted motherhood : women in the medical discourse in Québec, 1914-1939</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m343.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sx781</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz52b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vapour-liquid equilibrium is the driving force behind many separation processes such as distillation. Previous studies have shown that the vapour-liquid equilibria of many mixtures can be altered when the vapour-liquid interface is modified by capillary systems. This thesis studied the effects of capillary actions due to modified vapour-liquid interfaces on the vapour composition of ethanol-water and 1-propanol-water systems. A method was developed to measure and compare the vapour compositions of systems with a planar vapour-liquid interface and systems with capillary plates. Experiments were conducted to investigate the effects of interface materials, pore sizes and liquid compositions. Significant differences in vapour composition between capillary systems and systems with a planar interface were observed. This difference was much larger than that predicted by the Kelvin equation. The mechanism of the capillary actions and the factors causing the increase in vapour composition were investigated.</description><creator>Wong, Nga Sze Judy, 1972-</creator><contributor>Simandl, Jana (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical</subject><title>The effects of capillary plates on vapour-liquid equilibrium in aqueous alcohol systems /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm15k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz52b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx82c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De azufre y sal--which can be translated as "From sulphur and salt"--is a composition for orchestra with an approximate duration of 12' 30". This piece is mainly concerned with nuances of instrumental colour, registral space and tuning. The idea of exploring and working with these parameters was inspired by the work of Theophrastus Paracelsus (1493-1541) and by other texts about alchemy from different periods. The idea of conducting slow empirical work in laboratories in attempts to find the formula to create gold and the Philosopheris Stone suggested to me certain ideas about this piece, for example, the notion that the piece should always turn back on itself in order to proceed in a certain direction, while simultaneously accumulating the desirable features of each stage. The title is purely symbolic and should in no way be read as programmatic.</description><creator>Gaviola, Natalia.</creator><contributor>Cherney, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Orchestral music -- Scores.</subject><title>De azufre y sal : for orchestra</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv08b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx82c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fz66w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Souvenirs du vent is a composition for soprano and chamber orchestra with a duration of approximately 16'.30". The piece consists of three movements, a prelude, two interludes and a postlude. The poems set in the three movements were chosen for their similar subject matter, the wind. This common subject is emphasized by a music in which both the large-scale and small-scale formal divisions are blurred through structural counterpoint. The poets of the three poems are all from the Montreal area; they are: Emile Nelligan, Claude Brouille and Remi-Paul Forgues.</description><creator>Frehner, Paul (Paul Anton)</creator><contributor>Cherney, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Songs (High voice) with chamber orchestra -- Scores</subject><title>Souvenirs du vent : pour soprano et orchestre de chambre = for soprano and chamber for orchestra</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb79m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz66w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719p235</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is devoted to the optimal commitment of generation units in a power system, a problem known as a Unit Commitment (UC). This optimization is a difficult nonlinear mixed-integer task with various constraints whose exact solution can be found only through explicit enumeration. However, this technique requires impossibly long computational time and is impractical for most industrial applications. Various optimization techniques are proposed in the literature to solve the UC problem. In the present thesis, the Lagrangian Relaxation technique has been chosen for study. First, the Lagrangian Relaxation technique is applied to the static UC problem (SUC), that is, one whose optimum solution does not depend on the previous conditions of the power system. The proposed algorithm to find a "close to optimum" SUC solution is based on the concept of Switching Curves derived from the Lagrangian Relaxation. Then, a more general optimization problem over a planning horizon, called the dynamic unit commitment (DUC) is considered. Dynamic programming is assumed to yield the most exact solution. However, this method suffers from the "curse of dimensionality" and is becomes difficult to apply for a large number of generators. Thus, in the present thesis, the hypothesis is made and tested that a solution to the DUC problem can be obtained by solving a sequence of modified SUC problems together with some heuristics that permit the final schedule to satisfy all problem constraints. Simulations indicate that the proposed method yields solutions very close to those found through dynamic programming with the advantage that the computational effort is not exponential. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Radinskaia, Elene.</creator><contributor>Galiana, F. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>An investigation into the use of switching curves for unit commitment /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s2076.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719p235</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr518</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the appraisal of the economics of underground conversion in surface limestone mining operations. Software that predicts the time at which an open pit operation should be converted to underground extraction has been developed. The software is based on estimates of capital expenditures required for the underground conversion and for future equipment acquisitions and replacements under both open pit and underground operating alternatives, as well as long-term operating cost estimates for both alternatives. Open pit and underground cost estimates can be entered either directly, or estimated using O'Hara and Suboleski's (1992) cost estimation equations. It is assumed that an underground source of limestone is accessible and that its extraction is technically feasible. The program determines the cost-flow profile of each alternative and compares their present worth equivalents at yearly intervals over a pre-determined period of analysis. The program reports the optimum time for the conversion, if indeed it exists. The report starts with a review of limestone and dolomite as mineral commodities. This is followed by a brief literature review relating to underground conversion of surface mining operations. Mining methods and costs related to industrial minerals are then described and discussed. The thesis concludes with a detailed description of the software and a hypothetical case study.</description><creator>Shinobe, Alexandre.</creator><contributor>Bilodeau, Michel L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Economics, Commerce-Business.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Economics of underground conversion in an operating limestone mine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j061.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr518</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pf91v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Typically, when a robotic manipulator undergoes rapid acceleration, there is a commensurate loss in end-effector positional accuracy. To achieve high accuracy of the working end, massive links are usually required. Conversely, to achieve high accelerations, thin and flimsy links have to be employed, only to be plagued by large end-effector vibrations and long settling times. However, this traditional tradeoff can be circumvented through the application of high-performance materials such as graphite/epoxy which exhibits high stiffness-to-weight and strength-to-weight ratios as well as good damping properties. This thesis describes the process of designing and fabricating the three principal mechanisms of an anthropomorphic lightweight robotic arm: the shoulder joint, elbow joint and wrist. Each mechanism comprises various components which were individually optimized for strength stiffness and weight by finite element analysis. The components were then synthesized into shoulder, elbow and wrist mechanisms that exhibited excellent workspace, low backlash and low friction. This lightweight composite manipulator was developed as a multi-purpose arm for possible applications in the remote repair of hydroelectric power lines, minesweeping and the handling of hazardous materials.</description><creator>Roy, Matthew MacGregor.</creator><contributor>Lessard, Larry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Design and fabrication of a lightweight robotic manipulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v7468.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pf91v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f5486</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sludge combustion experiments were performed using a computer-controlled thermogravimeteric system. Microscopy and spectometry techniques were used to determine ash morphologies and structures, metals distribution inside ash particles and leachability of toxic metals from ash. Parameters examined included temperature, residence time, heating rate and cooling rate. The combustion process consisted of four stages: initial burning, transition, sintering and melting. It was found that temperature has the greatest effect on ash morphologies and metals distribution in the ash particle. It was observed that light metals predominated in the surface layers of the ash particle while heavy metals were mostly partitioned in the core area. As the temperature increased, leaching of heavy metals from ash decreased significantly. At temperatures above 1200$ sp circ$C, no toxic metals were leached out. Such ash particles could be safely disposed of and reused.</description><creator>Zheng, Guohui, 1962-</creator><contributor>Kozinski, Janusz A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Ash morphology and metals distribution during combustion of de-inking sludge</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806183d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f5486</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>