<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:25:00Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21625" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nc34h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent years have witnessed a growing concern among foreign investors about the laws and policies concerning foreign investment in Quebec and Canada. This thesis focuses on the laws that affect non Canadians doing business in Canada and Quebec. The introduction deals with the history of the policies concerning foreign ownership in Quebec and Canada. Section two analyzes the juridical personality of foreigners. Thereafter, this thesis will study the different implications for aliens acquiring moveables or immoveables in Quebec. This writer will analyze the legislative provisions and policies concerning foreign investment that are enacted by the federal government and the provincial government. A survey of the extraterritoriality of Antitrust laws and the international approach of settling the problems of confiscation, expropriation and nationalization follows. This thesis will briefly examine the Provincial legislation in immigration. Finally, the conclusion attempts to offer an alternative to the solutions arrived at by the federal and the provincial government of Quebec. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Bissonnette, Marc.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Legal aspects of foreign investment in Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Marc Bissonnette, 1985</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tq409.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc34h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806090m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two distinct patterns of neurological disease have been identified among Cree Indian children in Chisasibi, Nouveau Quebec and among Native Indian infants in Northern Manitoba. Both affect the cerebral white matter. The fifteen patients in the first group may suffer from an autosomal recessive defect causing defective development of cerebral myelin. The eleven patients in the second group have systemic immune dysfunction and meningoencephalitis. Together, these diseases are responsible for over half the deaths of infants and young children in Chisasibi. Inbreeding, and the familial occurrence of cases, suggest a genetic cause in both groups, in whom no gestational or perinatal causes can be identified. The first disease pattern may be due to hypomyelination of the central nervous system. The etiology of the second group may be a genetic susceptibility to viral infection.</description><creator>Black, Deborah Naomi.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Familial leukoencephalopathy in Chisasibi, Nouveau Québec : clinical epidemiological, and genetic aspects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk129.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806090m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848r703</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An internal combustion engine was instrumented in view of developing automatic diagnosis methods based on the analysis of PV diagrams. The pressure signal is unstable over successive cycles. Consequently, pressure must be averaged over several consecutive cycles to produce valid data. Due to instrumentation problems the data obtained was insufficient to allow the development of diagnostics. The investigation reported in this work is thus limited to the development of a microprocessor-based system for the acquisition of pressure-volume data on high speed, spark ignition internal combustion engines. Several instrumentation problems were identified and solutions applied or proposed. The information presented here can form the basis for further research on the original project.</description><creator>Boulanger, Yves</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>A microprocessor system for internal combustion engine PV diagram analysis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj08v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r703</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m289s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It was hypothesized that skeletal muscle (SKM) satellite cells multiplied in vitro could be used to repair injured heart muscle. The purpose of this study was to test this hypothesis by auto-transplanting SKM satellite cells to a myocardial injury site. Fourteen dogs underwent explanation of the anterior tibialis muscle. Satellite cells were multiplied in vitro and their nuclei were labelled with tritiated thymidine 24 hours prior to implantation. The same dogs were then subjected to a myocardial injury by the application of a cryoprobe. The cells were suspended in serum free growth medium and implanted within the damaged muscle. There was persistence of the implantation channels in the experimental sites when compared to the controls. Macroscopically, muscle tissue completely surrounded by scar could be seen. Masson trichrome staining showed homogeneous scar in the control site, but not in the test site where a patch of muscle fibres containing intercalated discs (characteristic of myocardial tissue) was observed. In 2 dogs, specimens were taken at 14 weeks post-implantation. Muscle tissue could not be found. Electrically stimulated skeletal muscle regenerates did not show histological evidence of cardiac transformation. These results support the hypothesis that SKM satellite cells can form neo-myocardium within an appropriate environment. The specimens failed to demonstrate the presence of myocyte nuclei. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Marelli, Daniel</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Cell transplantation for myocardial repair</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pr42p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m289s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20st79z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pre-operatively (pre-op) and following arthroscopic partial meniscectomy (every 2 weeks for 12 weeks), bilateral knee extensor and flexor peak torques (PT) were evaluated at the Sports Medicine Lab (SML) and Sacre Coeur Hospital (SCH) via Cybex II or II+, in 22 subjects. Three submaximal contractions were followed by 3 maximal contractions at 60, 120, 180 and 240 deg/sec, with a 2 minute rest between sets. For both groups, the quadriceps had a significant deficit in PT at pre-op, except at 180 and 240 deg/sec at the SML, whereas the hamstrings only had a significant deficit at 60 deg/sec. Despite significant differences in PT (SML $&gt;$ SCH) and percent deficit (SCH $&gt;$ SML) the recovery pattern was similar in both groups. Extensor PT dropped significantly at 2 and 4 weeks post-op, returned to pre-op values by 6 weeks post-op and plateaued at this level until and including 12 weeks post-op. Flexor PT dropped significantly at 2 weeks post-op, except at the faster speeds, and was fully recovered 2 weeks later. These results indicate that while the hamstrings were minimally involved, the extensors were not able to recover beyond their pre-op level of strength within 3 months, without training. The differences between the SML and SCH may be attributed to differences in Cybex machines, thigh muscle cross sectional area and tourniquet time.</description><creator>Matthews, Paula</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>The time course of passive recovery following arthroscopic partial meniscectomy /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc19d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20st79z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988m13g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cerebral palsy is a non-progressive disorder associated with brain injury, defect, or disease, of early onset. Emphasis is placed on the more easily observable motor deficits, with any underlying sensory deficits often being overlooked. Existing sensory assessments have either been standardized on an adult population or for a paediatric population without significant neuromotor impairment. Thus, there is a need to formulate a standardized sensory assessment battery that may be used to evaluate physically handicapped children. A review of the literature highlights the necessity to evaluate the presence and extent or sensory dysfunction in school-age hemiplegic children, using a standardized clinical sensory assessment battery, as well as somatosensory evoked potentials. A reliable sensory battery, which assesses 5 sensory modalities, was formulated and normative data for school-age children was derived. Sensory function was evaluated in 9 hemiplegic children (4-19 years) and 18 healthy age-matched controls. Significant bilateral sensory deficits were documented in hemiplegic children. Thus a sensory assessment should be an integral part of the evaluation of a child with hemiplegia.</description><creator>Cooper, Jasmine</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The determination of sensory deficits in children with hemiplegic cerebral palsy /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354g422.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m13g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289k234</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis considers the phenomenon of flow-rate enhancement of polymer solutions in a pipe due to pulsating pressure gradients. It presents an historical review of the problem. The unexplained experimental dependence of enhancement on pulsation frequency reported by Barnes et al is examined, as are later theoretical attempts to reproduce their results. We find that the results can be reproduced only by omitting the important inertial term. The Modified Moment Method is applied to the problem. The results confirm the predictions of other models. The enhancement is of second order in the pulsation amplitude, exhibits a maximum when the pressure gradient is varied, and declines with increasing pulsation frequency. An expansion in powers of the pulsation amplitude gives a satisfactory approximation. Less power is consumed at the same rate of flow if the pressure gradient is constant and not pulsated.</description><creator>Hausner, Alejo</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Fluid and Plasma.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Non-linear effects in pulsating pipe flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h066j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289k234</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021g380</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several studies claim to have demonstrated an increased frequency of Down syndrome (DS) dermatoglyphics and other DS characteristics in parents of DS children, which could be explained by unrecognized parental mosaicism for trisomy 21. The goal of this study was to test the following hypothesis: In some cases of DS the cause will be parental gonadal mosaicism for trisomy 21. These parents will also be mosaic in tissues other than the gonads and will therefore have quantitative deviations in the direction of the DS phenotype. Upon examination of such traits in 162 parents with one DS child it was found that 22 parents had dermatoglyphic characteristics within the DS distribution of the Preus diagnostic index (no significant increase), 6 had DS quantitative phenotypic traits, and 1 had both. There was no evidence of bimodality in the distribution of these traits, or of a correlation between these traits with one another or with the Preus dermatoglyphic index for DS. There were no trisomy 21 cells in 200 lymphoblast cells counted for each of the 5 subjects with the most DS-like dermatoglyphic characteristics. The one subject who has both DS dermatoglyphics and a trend toward DS phenotype had 1/300 trisomy 21 cells in lymphoblast culture and 0/100 cells in fibroblast culture. Neither these data nor these from the literature, provide support for the suggestion that parental mosaicism for trisomy 21 is associated with an increase in DS-like physical characteristics.</description><creator>Gilbert, Adel Dorothy</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Down syndrome -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Dermatoglyphics, phenotype, and mosaicism in parents of trisomy 21 (down syndrome) children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj094.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g380</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322f373</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The number of lesions increased with increasing temperatures over the range of wet periods except at 30$ sp circ$C, where their number decreased with increasing wetness duration. Cultivars were evaluated for partial resistance under field and greenhouse conditions. In the field ranking was based on cluster analysis of the standard area under the disease progress curve (SAUDPC) for intervals between sampling dates. In the greenhouse, the cultivars were evaluated on the basis of their response relative to five components of partial resistance: the SAUDPC, mean lesion area (MLA), pycnidial density (PCD), spore density (SPD), and the latency period defined as the time from inoculation to 50% and 75% disease (T$ sb{50}$ and T$ sb{75}$). In the greenhouse, overall ranking was based on cluster and principal component analysis of responses to SAUDPC, MLA, PCD and SPD. T$ sb{50}$ and T$ sb{75}$ were not significant. Three cultivars, Golden Plume, Superdora and Summit, were rated as moderately resistant in both field and greenhouse trials. The others ranged from moderately susceptible to very susceptible. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Mathieu, Danielle</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Celery -- Disease and pest resistance.</subject><subject>Septoria apiicola</subject><subject>Celery -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>Leaves -- Temperature.</subject><title>Effects of temperature and duration of leaf wetness on infection of celery by Septoria apiicola, and cultivar screening for partial resistance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st80q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322f373</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s00v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Heparan sulfate proteoglycan (HSPG) was isolated from the mouse Engelbreth-Holm-Swarm (EHS) tumor. Polyclonal antibodies against the isolated HSPG were raised by two separate techniques, both producing highly reactive antisera. The antisera were found to be reactive against epithelial basement membrane of the mouse foot pad, glomerular basement membrane of the kidney and the EHS tumor matrix using the techniques of light microscopic immunoperoxidase on frozen sections and electron microscopic immunogold labelling on ultrathin Lowicryl K4M sections. At high magnification of the EHS tumor matrix, the gold particles were found over 5 nm wide sets of parallel lines, referred to as "double tracks" (Inoue et al., 1989). When HSPG was incubated in 50 mM Tris buffer, pH 7.4, at 35$ sp circ$C for either 5 min or 1 hr, a precipitate resulted which was made up of 5-6 nm wide sets of parallel lines, similar to double track structures. Together these studies demonstrate that HSPG of the EHS tumor matrix is made up of double track structures, and that in vitro incubation of HSPG produces double track structures in as short a time as 5 min.</description><creator>Shima, Thomas Brent</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Isolation, structural and immunohistochemical characterization of basement membrane heparan sulfate proteoglycan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n10s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s00v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn14h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The calibration and quality control measurements of the ZEUS forward and rear calorimeters made using movable $ sp{60} Co$ sources are described. The types of assembly faults discovered from the runs taken first at CERN and then later at DESY from mid 1990 to early 1991 are presented. The WLS attenuation length as well as changes in the attenuation length of the scintillators can be monitored by the cobalt scans.</description><creator>Hung, Ling-Wai</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Physics, General.</subject><title>The 60Co calibration of the ZEUS calorimeters /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g398m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn14h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n450</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fertilizer P fixation and fertilizer N losses in soils may be reduced through additions of polyphenolic compounds. The influence of ammonium lignosulfonate (NH$ sb4 sp+$-LS) on triple superphosphate (TSP) efficiency was investigated in a soil incubation study using three Quebec soils and in a growth bench study using one soil. For the incubation study, soils were analyzed for pH and P extractability, as a function of NH$ sb4 sp+$-LS rate and time. In the growth bench study, TSP and NH$ sb4 sp+$-LS were applied at varying rates and corn (Zea mays L.) dry matter yields and nutrient compositions analyzed. Similar studies were conducted in subsequent growth bench studies, to evaluate combinations of NH$ sb4 sp+$-LS, diammonium phosphate (DAP), and urea on two soils. Ammonium LS increased soluble P levels when applied with TSP. The effect was most significant in fine textured soils, and increased with time. This improved P availability to plants, without affecting growth. The optimum NH$ sb4 sp+$-LS:P$ sb2$O$ sb5$ application ratio was approximately 2.8:1. Ammonium LS did not improve availability of DAP-P in either of the subsequent experiments, nor did it improve urea fertilizer efficiency. Some NH$ sb4 sp+$-LS-urea-DAP formulations did, however, improve corn growth beyond that obtained when only urea and DAP were applied in combination. In nutrient amended soils, applying NH$ sb4 sp+$-LS DAP was detrimental to growth and, for some application rates, reduced nutrient uptake.</description><creator>Russell, Elizabeth F. (Elizabeth Fiona)</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Ammonium compounds.</subject><subject>Factory and trade waste as fertilizer.</subject><subject>Corn -- Fertilizers.</subject><subject>Pulpwood industry -- By-products.</subject><subject>Corn -- Growth.</subject><title>Influence of ammonium lignosulfonate fertilizer mixtures on corn (Zea mays L.) growth and nutrient composition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602193b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n450</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397941b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The research pursued relates to the establishment of interrelationship between various factors affecting chitin extraction, and combination of optimum levels of factors required to maximize the yield of chitin extraction. Optimization of chitin extraction was carried out using crab, lobster, and shrimp solid wastes. The study was divided into two stages: (a) optimization of chitin extractability with respect to particle size; (b) optimization of demineralization and deproteinization stages in lobster chitin extraction using Response Surface Methodology. Particle size had a significant effect on crab and lobster chitin extractability; a particle size of 2.0mm gave the highest yield in chitin extraction. The mean yield of chitin from crab and lobster at particle size of 2.0mm were 28.8% and 23.2%, respectively. Shrimp chitin extractability was not affected by particle size with the mean yield being 25.2%. Response Surface Methodology was used to determine simultaneous effects of (a) concentration of extractant; (b) shell:extractant ratio; (c) temperature of extraction; and (d) time of extraction on deproteinization and demineralization stages of chitin extraction and hence yield of chitin. All variables had an effect on demineralization and deproteinization yields. Maximum demineralization was predictable by a multi-factor model consisting of a combination of concentration of HCl, shell:extractant ratio, temperature and time of extraction. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Tetteh, Antonia Yarbeh</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Fishery processing industries -- By-products.</subject><subject>Extraction (Chemistry)</subject><subject>Chitin.</subject><subject>Lobster industry -- By-products.</subject><title>Optimization studies on chitin extraction from crustacean solid wastes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418p33v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397941b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g8614</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ricoeur advances a theory of metaphor as discourse. The notion of metaphor as event and as meaning is complicated by the form of written discourse and the distanciation which inscription engenders. By specifying the autonomy of the text in relation to the author's intention, the original audience, and the original context, Ricoeur argues that metaphor refers to its own world. Suggesting that the metaphorical arises from a "seeing-as" which contains a non-verbal element, he contends metaphors indicate a extra-linguistic mode of existence. The possibility of conceptualization lies for Ricoeur, at the core of the dynamism of the metaphorical. It is proposed in this thesis that Ricoeur's defence of the autonomy of speculative discourse is inadequate.</description><creator>Mehta, R. (Rajesh)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Ricœur, Paul -- Contributions in hermeneutics.</subject><title>Metaphor in Ricoeur's hermeneutics of poetic language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k8251.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g8614</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707958851</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abstract Not Available.</description><creator>Korell, Ulrich</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Electrochemistry at organic conducting salt electrodes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz42x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707958851</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv13m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of chronic exercise on the frequency and intensity of positive and negative affect in Chinese students and to examine the effects of chronic exercise on indicators of fatigue and health. No differences in maximal oxygen uptake between groups or across time were observed. Significantly higher heart rates were noted as a function of participation in the exercise program. Positive affect increased for the male exercise group from Pre-training to Post-training while the female exercise group did not significantly increase over time periods. Positive affect of the control group remained stable throughout. Negative affect in males and females in the control group did not change over time. In the exercise group the females' negative affect decreased from Pre-training to Post-training while the males did not significantly decrease from Pre-training to Post-training. The men and women in the exercise group reported significantly greater daily indicators of fatigue than the control group of subjects. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Fei, Xia-Wen</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Mood (Psychology)</subject><subject>Exercise -- Psychological aspects</subject><title>The effects of chronic exercise on the frequency and intensity of positive and negative affect in Chinese students /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t9626.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv13m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rm501</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De architectura libri decim, the oldest extant treatise on Architecture in the Greco-Latin tradition, has historically constituted the archetype of architectural discourse, if its specific content would now seem largely irrelevant. And yet to the extent that we still distinguish theoretical activity and practice, we remain de-limited by the essential terms of the Vitruvian text, and the rational order which they prescribe, an order of the logos. But within the prescription itself we find the traces of a diversity and richness largely repressed, traces of an other logos, another understanding of the traditional world of artifice--including the artifice of writing--that undermines the structure and space of the logos which Vitruvius has attempted to erect, and which we still inhabit. If Architecture is The Ten Books ..., it is also a writing, a multiple, palimpsestic writing in which the play of artifice will leave its trace in the stratification of the inscription.</description><creator>Fisher, Matt, 1959-</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Vitruvius Pollio. De architectura.</subject><title>Erasing Vitruvius ...</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rx81r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rm501</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pr43z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anna Akhmatova's poetical works have been heard of a lot in the past few years, mainly because of the celebration in 1989 of her 100th birthday. But if literary analyses of her works can be counted by the hundreds, to find something written about her in, let's say, a more semantical fashion can prove very difficult. A writer is nothing without his words, and among these words, the verbs play an important role, since their mission is to convey the action of a sentence. If one can dispose of all the verbs of a given writer, one is in a better position to analyse this writer. Furthermore, if this list of verbs comprises all the conjugated forms of these verbs, then one has a fantastic data base with illimited possibilities. A frequency dictionnary is a first rate tool in order to establish comparisons, and this is what I attempted to do in this work.</description><creator>Girard, Steve</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Akhmatova, Anna Andreevna, 1889-1966 -- Language</subject><title>Les formes verbales dans la poésie d'Anna Akhmatova /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf138.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pr43z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kk77k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>By analogy with the Makkai duality for first order logic, we develop a duality theory for $ kappa$-exact categories in which the structure on the model categories is that induced by $ kappa$-reduced products. The main theorem, a strong completeness result, states that for any small $ kappa$-exact category $F$, the functor $F { buildrel{e sb F} over longrightarrow} hom({ bf Mod}F,{ bf Sets})$ defined by evaluation is an equivalence of categories, where $hom({ bf Mod}F,{ bf Sets})$ is the category of functors from ${ bf Mod}F$ to Sets which preserve the reduced product structure.</description><creator>Boshuck, William H.</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Reduced products and strong completeness of regular logic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2040298.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kk77k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903109c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis I examine the initial stage of Paul Ricoeur's hermeneutics of the "I am," focusing particularly on the question of method. In Chapter 1 I analyze how psychoanalysis opens a space for Ricoeur's hermeneutics of "I am" by redirecting doubt towards the origins of meaning. I will try to show that the premises of this hermeneutics--the analogy between subjective manifestations and texts--preclude strong methodological commitments. The Second Chapter focuses on the main argument Ricoeur makes in favor of method. His attempt to set in motion a dialectic between phenomenology of subjectivity and structuralism will be questioned with respect to the power this dialectic has to capture the "I" as the generative moment of the interpreted series of subjective manifestations. Finally, with the analysis of Heidegger in Chapter 3, it will become apparent that the very framework of discussion in terms of subject-object, structure-event, signifier-signified has to be replaced by an ontological approach and that from this perspective subjectivity is ultimately beyond the grasp of any methodology. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Cristian, Alin</creator><contributor>Fisher, Linda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1991</date><subject>Hermeneutics</subject><subject>Ricœur, Paul -- Contributions in hermeneutics.</subject><title>Perspectives on Ricoeur's early hermeneutics of subjectivity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bq48k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903109c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn15s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The quasi-steady analytical approach was used to develop a mathematical model for investigating instability using a rotatable five cylinder cluster with one "movable" cylinder. In this model, the important time retardation factor is taken into account. First, the equations of motion for the "movable" cylinder were written in dimensional form, and then non-dimensionalized and written in the final matrix form. Secondly, the force coefficients and their spacial derivatives with respect to cross-flow and in-flow displacements were measured on the "movable" cylinder. Also, the current direction was measured and the approach velocity was calculated. Finally, using this model and the experimental input data, the critical flow velocity for the onset of fluidelastic instability was calculated using a computer program developed for this purpose. It is shown that, depending on the current direction, riser clusters may suffer from fluidelastic instability. The theoretical findings are in good agreement with experimental data. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Al-Jabir, A. A. (Abdul-Malik)</creator><contributor>Price, S. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Paidoussis, M. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Fluidelastic instability in multi-tube risers subjected to cross-flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580n726.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn15s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gp44k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The most common and generally best performing replacement algorithm in modern caches is LRU. Despite LRU's superiority, it is still possible that other feasible and implementable replacement policies could yield better performance. (34) found that an optimal replacement policy (OPT) would often have a miss rate 70% that of LRU. If better replacement policies exist, they may not be obvious. One way to find better policies is to study a large number of address traces for common patterns. Such an undertaking involves such a large amount of data, that some automated method of generating and evaluating policies is required. Genetic Algorithms provide such a method, and have been used successfully on a wide variety of tasks (21). The best replacement policy found using this approach had a mean improvement in overall hit rate of 0.6% over LRU for the benchmarks used. This corresponds to 27% of the 2.2% mean difference between LRU and OPT. Performance of the best of these replacement policies was found to be generally superior to shadow cache (33), an enhanced replacement policy similar to some of those used here.</description><creator>Altman, Erik R. (Erik Richter)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Genetic algorithms and cache replacement policy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8965.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gp44k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763807r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Joseph Gould was an important figure in the musical life of late nineteenth-century Montreal. His activities as a church musician, piano and organ dealer, and journalist made a considerable impact on artistic life in the city. But it was as the founder and conductor of the Montreal Mendelssohn Choir that Gould's influence was most keenly felt. Founded in 1864, the Mendelssohn Choir enjoyed a thirty-year lifespan and became famous for its high standard of performance. The library of the Choir, housed at the Marvin Duchow Music Library of McGill University, is an important collection, not only because of the presence of a number of interesting pieces of Canadiana within it, but as a basis for further study of nineteenth-century choral music. Included in this thesis is a catalogue of this collection as well as a list of Gould's known compositions.</description><creator>Rice, Kelly S. (Kelly Stanley)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Montreal Mendelssohn Choir</subject><subject>Gould, Joseph, 1833-1913</subject><subject>Marvin Duchow Music Library</subject><title>Joseph Gould and the Montreal Mendelssohn Choir</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm140.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763807r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3012395</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Within the framework of generative grammar, it is assumed that children are endowed with an innate language faculty called Universal Grammar (UG). Children learn their native language on the basis of the interaction of positive evidence in the input with the principles and parameters of UG. In terms of parameter setting, positive evidence consistent with just one value of a parameter causes the preemption of any incorrect settings hypothesized by the child, in accordance with the Uniqueness Principle (Pinker 1984, Wexler and Culicover 1980) which ensures that only one parameter setting can be held at a time in the child's grammar (Berwick 1985). This thesis investigates the operation of preemption in parameter setting in second language (L2) acquisition in cases where the learner initially adopts the L1 value of a parameter. Focussing on a parametric difference between French and English, namely, the verb movement parameter (Pollock 1989) which relates to (among other things) the placement of adverbs, 58 grade 5 francophone students learning English as a second language in intensive programmes in Quebec schools were exposed over a two week period to a flood of positive evidence on adverb placement in English--input which was consistent with only the English value of the parameter. The results indicate that the subjects did not reset the verb movement parameter to the English value, suggesting that preemption does not function in L2 as in L1 acquisition. Possible explanations for these results and their implications for theories of L2 learnability are developed.</description><creator>Trahey, Martha</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Second language acquisition</subject><title>Positive evidence, preemption and parameter resetting in second language acquisition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx57h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3012395</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2686302</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rural development is a serious problem in Bangladesh, and so is the situation of women. This thesis assesses the programmes offered by a particular non-governmental organization, the Bangladesh Rural Advancement Committee (BRAC), which simultaneously promote rural development and improve the status of women. This assessment is achieved by examining the functioning and impact of these programmes in a single village. The study is exploratory and uses qualitative methods, employing principally unstructured but in-depth interviews. Results indicate that most village women were aware of the need for improvement in the position of women, but interest, and thus active participation, was greater among those who were widowed or divorced. For these women, the programmes did succeed in raising their income through better technical knowledge, and in some ways improved their position in the family and society. They did not, however, succeed in raising their administrative knowledge, confining them to "women's only" projects, and did little to increase political empowerment.</description><creator>Halim, Sadeka</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Rural women -- Bangladesh -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Rural development projects -- Bangladesh</subject><subject>Rural development -- Bangladesh</subject><title>Rural development programmes : their impact on women : a Bangladesh study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc52p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2686302</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21650</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>