<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:02:08Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15575" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514np85s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is an analysis of thirty-one interviews held in 1952, with men who were residing at the Meurling Refuge, a municipal shelter in the city of Montreal. It is undertaken with a view to learn of the factors that might have some bearing on why these particular men have become dependent on an institution of this nature. In addition, the writer will survey other existing services available in Canada for the homeless and consider how these services meet the needs of these men. As described in this study, a "homeless man" will denote one who is not attached to a family group in the community in which he is residing, even though members of his family might be living in the same area. Seldom is he willing or able to sustain regular employment, with the result that he has either a marginal income or a complete lack of funds.</description><creator>Abugov, Albert.</creator><contributor>Younge, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1954</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>Factors contributing to homelessness.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd22m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np85s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qg70w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>1959, the year of the opening of the St. Lawrence Seaway, marked the end of an era for the port of Montreal. For the first time in the history of navigation on the St. Lawrence River large ocean vessels gained access to the Great Lakes, and the port of Montreal was no longer the head of ocean navigation for large ocean ships. This study analyses the impact of these recent changes on the port of Montreal, and examines the new role of the port in changed patterns of navigation on the St. Lawrence River. It is a study of one of the most dynamic and important periods in the history of the port of Montreal. It is still too early to attempt to discover the full impact of the Seaway on the port of Montreal.</description><creator>Slack, Brian.</creator><contributor>Lundgren, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Geography.</subject><title>The impact of the St. Lawrence Seaway on the port of Montreal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m7509.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg70w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602449d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electric contacts, both stationary and moving, with lead contact members separated by an oxide layer are examined. The stationary contact results are consistent with earlier work and are used as preliminary data for the moving contact case. All stationary contacts were superconducting at low currents when the members themselves were superconducting. Two types of contacts were found; one whose abrupt resistance transition is accompanied by hysteresis, and the other whose transition is gradual. The difference may be connected with the properties of the contact surface. Moving contacts between superconducting lead brushes and a rotating lead cylinder exhibited resistance whose magnitude was 10^-3 of the normal conduction resistance. The speed of rotation, current and temperature were varied. Consideration of effects which could cause the resistance led to the conclusion that the contact resistance is small because only a thin layer of oxide becomes normal as a result of mechanical deformation of the contact surfaces.</description><creator>Simons, John. H.</creator><contributor>Farnell, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>Properties of superconducting electric contacts.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v204j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602449d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c178h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is evidence that humans have been afflicted with arteriosclerotic vascular diseases for more than 4000 years. Shattock (1908-1909), for example, recorded finding arteriosclerotic changes in an aortic segment removed from the mummy of King Menephtah, allegedly the pharaoh of the Hebrew Exodus. Ruffer (1911) also described arteriosclerotic lesions in the aortae and peripheral arteries taken from a group of mummies thought buried during a 2000-year period ending in 500 B.C. The majority of the lesions in the peripheral arteries of the mummies were undoubtedly of the type now known to be due to Mönckeberg’s sclerosis. Others, particularly those in the aortae, were of a different nature.</description><creator>Silver, Malcolm. D.</creator><contributor>McMillan, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Inflammation and repair in rabbits fed atherogenic diets.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429d94m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c178h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977z53t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The solvolysis of a given compound I, where G is the neighbouring group and X a group which readily departs with the electron pair, thereby generating a carbonium ion, brings into play varying effects. The neighbouring group can compete with the solvent or other dissolved nucleophilic agents sufficiently well to determine partially or wholly the nature of the final products. Neighbouring groups are classified as functional, for example bromide, iodide, methoxy and acetoxy, or non-functional, e.g., alkyl, vinyl, aryl and hydrogen. In the case of neighbouring carbon, the amount of activation energy involved in the rearrangement must be small for it often competes favourably with the collapse of the solvated carbonium ion to give solvolysis products, a process which inherently does not require high activation energy.</description><creator>Shortland, Frederick. E.</creator><contributor>Just, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The solvolysis of methylated steroids and the free sterols of dermatophytes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j320.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977z53t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623h10p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The earliest description of cancer has been traced back to records on Egyptian papyri of the fifteenth century B.C. Following this, in the era of Hippocrates, in the fourth century B. C., the nature of cancer was described as the presence of a tumour, and the absence of any tendency towards healing. Hippocrates used the term “kapkivos” , "carcinos”, for all indolent ulcers, and “kapkivwua”, "carcinoma” for progressive malignant tumours. In spite of many descriptions, and many personal views as to the origin of cancer in the following centuries, little came but mere speculation. Perhaps, the one of the most notable events in the history of cancer research was the essay by Bernard Peyrihle (1735-1804) of Lyon, “Qu’est ce que le cancer?”.</description><creator>Shinozuka, Hisashi.</creator><contributor>Ritchie, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Studies of initiating stage of epidermal carcinogenesis in mice.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tj96n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623h10p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qw34v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the past three decades, following the isolation of ascorbic acid from bovine adrenal glands (1), there have been many investigations concerning the possible role of this vitamin in adrenal function. The elucidation of the mechanism and significance of ACTH (adrenocorticotrophic hormone) induced depletion of ascorbic acid is still a major problem in adrenocortical physiology. Ascorbic acid occurs in two forms, one being the oxidation product of the ether. Both forms are biologically active. They are water soluble, insoluble in organic solvents, and unstable when exposed to oxygen, light, alkalies and certain metals. The most prominent chemical property of ascorbic acid is its ready oxidation to dehydroascorbic acid, which is catalyzed by small concentrations of metal ions.</description><creator>Sharma, Shail. K.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Uptake of ascorbic acid by adrenals and brain and the action of steroid hormones and ACTH.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m73c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qw34v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jc42q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In southwestern Quebec, eight species of grasshopper (Melanoplus femurrubrum, M. bivittatus, M. borealis, Orphulella specicosa, Chorthippus curtipennis, Encoptolophus sordidus, Chortophaga viridifasciata and Metrioptera roeseli) were studied during 1962, in relation to the following parasites: Mermis nigrescens (Nematoda), Eutrombidium trigonum (Acarina) and Sarcophagidae (Diptera). Mermis parasitism, in the situation studied, made little contribution to controlling the Acridid grasshopper populations in nature, with the probable regulation of nymphs of M. femurrubrum. In M. roeseli (Tettigoniidae), however, parasitism by this species appeared to have restricted both abundance of nymphs and adults and spatial distribution.</description><creator>Sharma, Ravindra. N.</creator><contributor>Kevan, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>A preliminary study of parasitism in grasshoppers in southwestern Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w326c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jc42q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gr82d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glycine was the first amino acid shown by isolation to be present in a protein hydrolysate (Braconnot, 1820). Besides incorporation into proteins, peptide hormones and glutathione, the carbon atoms of glycine appear in other amino acids like serine and creatine, glycocholic acid, hippuric acid, purine and porphyrin rings. The methylene carbon atom of the glycine molecule also contributes significantly to the one carbon pool. Thus, although structurally the simplest amino acid, the metabolism of glycine presents a complex picture. If carbohydrate and lipids are considered as fuels for the metabolic furnace, proteins may be regarded as forming not only the structural frame work, but also the gears and leavers of the machinery.</description><creator>Selvaraj, Ratnam. J.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the intermediary metabolism of glycine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n204b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gr82d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z168n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Knob Lake Ridge is located near Schefferville townsite, three hundred and seventy miles north of Seven Islands; the Knob Lake Ridge defines the New-Quebec-Newfoundland-Labrador boundary adjacent to the critical ore zone. The Labrador trough represents a structural depression seven hundred miles long and twenty to sixty miles in width running southeast-northwest and extending south from the Payne River situated at the 60° parallel on the western shores of Ungava Bay to the fifty first degree parallel. This trough represents a geosyncline that was partially filled by a succession of sedimentary strata.</description><creator>Seguin, Maurice.</creator><contributor>Stevenson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Geology of Knob Lake Ridge, Schefferville, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dz782.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z168n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wt98x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>According to a historical survey of immunology by Grabar (1), the phenomenon of immunity was known to the ancient Greeks. A major breakthrough in the understanding of its physical basis was made in the latter part of the nineteenth century when Kraus (2) discovered that resistance to disease could be developed not only to intact bacteria, but also to their extracts or toxins. Von Behring and Kitasato (3) observed that this resistance was associated with the presence of some factor in immune serum, and subsequently it was shown that the introduction of a foreign substance into an animal induced the formation of globular serum proteins which possessed the unique property of reacting specifically with the foreign substance.</description><creator>Schneider, Henry.</creator><contributor>Sehon, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies of antibody-hapten reactions by polarography.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vx50h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wt98x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524js388</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the Soviet Union the relationship between social and economic conditions on the one hand and Constitutional law on the other is closer than in other states, and of a peculiar nature. The relationship is specifically dictated by Marxist doctrine. The totality of productive social relationships, wrote Marx, constituted the "real basis upon which is built the juridical and political superstructure.” Since it was a basic tenet of the Marxian dialectic that the nexus of substructural, economic relationships underwent periodic change, it followed logically that the juridical superstructure would also change from time to time.</description><creator>Schlieper, Heinrich. C.</creator><contributor>Mladenovic, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>History.</subject><title>The historical background of the Soviet constitutions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd52v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524js388</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bx88g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the results or an attempt to isolate and give an axiomatic basis for the pure-implication fragment or each or several logical systems. C. I. Lewis points out that exact logic may be taken as a canon or deductive inference, and that the chief business of a canon or deduction is to delineate correctly the properties of the relation of 'implication’. It seems clear, then, that criticism or any logical calculus must include consideration of just what properties are imputed to the relation of ‘implication' by that calculus.</description><creator>Schindler, Patrick. F.</creator><contributor>McCall, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Philosophy.</subject><title>The formalization of implication in propositional logic.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd23w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bx88g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mq96w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Measurements of spin-lattice relaxation times in potassium chromicyanide diluted with potassium cobalticyanide have been made on crystals of nominal concentration of chromium varying from 5% to 0.1%. Crystals were grown in the laboratory and studied using saturation method. The relaxation times were measured for forbidden transitions at 9.4 KMc/s which occur at low magnetic fields. Spin-lattice relaxation times are of the same order of magnitude as for allowed lines. Spin-spin interaction time increases with decreasing concentration for the range of the concentration used. All measurements were made at a constant temperature of 4.2° K.</description><creator>Saxena, Govind. P.</creator><contributor>Woonton, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Paramagnetic relaxation on forbidden lines in K3Cr(CN)6.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n464w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq96w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999b18w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following work is based on the study of some nematodes collected in Formosa from two hosts, Suncus murinus and Bandicota nemorivaga. It deals with the taxonomy of the nematodes, with their hosts and with their geographical distribution range.</description><creator>Sapong, Debra.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>Nematodes parasitic in Suncus murinus and Bandicota nemorivaga from Formosa.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k8674.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999b18w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd99x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Homovanillic acid has been shown by several investigators to be a constituent of normal human urine. In certain disease states, the urinary level of homovanillic acid is altered. This tact may be used as a criterion for clinical diagnosis of these diseases. Several method are available for measuring homovanillic acid, but they are relatively involved and costly procedures. The purpose of this study was to determine a rapid method which could be used routinely for the clinical measurement of homovanillic acid. Dopamine and its metabolite, 3, 4-dihydroxyphenylacetic acid, have been shown in Dr. Sourkes' laboratory to be abnormal in certain diseases. Another metabolite of these substances, homovanillic acid, has also been found in elevated amounts in some diseases.</description><creator>Sankoff, Irwin.</creator><contributor>Blackwood, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Measurement of homovanillic acid in human urine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx990.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd99x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322j24n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interest in acetylcholine (ACh) as a chemical transmitter in the central nervous system was developed many years ago when attempts were made to determine the mechanism of transmission of impulses occurring (a) across ganglionic synapses and (b) from motor nerve endings to the motor endplates of skeletal muscle. Although ACh was synthesized in 1867 (1) and Elliott in 1904 (2) firmly suggested the concept of humoral transmission when he found marked functional similarities between the effects of sympathetic nervous stimulation and that of adrenaline action, it was not until 1906, that Hunt and Taveau (3) proved ACh to be a nerve depressor.</description><creator>Samad, Roushan. A.</creator><contributor>Hosein, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The influence of narcotic and convulsant drugs on acetylcholine-like substances in brain.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f957r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j24n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988p455</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It was not until the year 1839 that Theodor Schwann, a professor of anatomy and physiology at Louvain, Germany, advanced his cell theory in which he postulated that all living matter is made up of cells. Modem biochemistry has no quarrel with this concept and accepts the cell as the fundamental organized unit of all living matter. The living cell is composed of a number of intracellularly located elements which are surrounded by an extremely thin and delicate membrane. This membrane is a complex and fragile structure which is and must be considered an integral part of the cell as a living unit. Cellular architecture or structural compartmentation within the cell is also achieved almost entirely by means of individual membranes surrounding each of the intracellularly located parts.</description><creator>Sahagian, Benjamin.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Absorption and metabolism of carbohydrates by the small intestine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m74n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p455</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wk651</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The distributions of daily maximum and minimum temperatures recorded at McGill Observatory during the 88 year period from August 1874 to July 1962 have been analysed. The following main features emerge: 1) The frequency distributions (as judged by plots on arithmetic probability paper) fall into four well defined categories. A summer type corresponds to a normal distribution of temperatures. A winter type corresponds to a skew distribution, and transition types occur in the spring and the fall. 2) The interquartile range for both the maximum and minimum temperatures is highest in mid-winter and lowest in mid-summer, with secondary minima occurring in the spring and the fall.</description><creator>Sabourin, Georges.</creator><contributor>Marshall, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Meteorology.</subject><title>Maximum and minimum temperatures at McGill observatory.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hg637.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk651</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z444d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Text-books of history usually divide recorded history into three, sometimes four periods: antiquity (ca. 1000 B.C. to ca. 500 A.D., the end of the Roman Empire), the Middle Ages (ca. 500 to ca. 1500 A.D.), and modern times (from the Reformation onwards). Sometimes the French Revolution is used to demarcate the beginning of a fourth period, that of recent history. Whatever the merits or demerit of this classification may be, it is convenient for us to use it, because it coincides nicely with a division which we wish to make in the history of thought. The end of the Middle Ages and the beginning of modern times saw the emergence of a force, the concept of which has played an important role in the theology of the last forty years or so.</description><creator>Rumscheidt, Hans. M.</creator><contributor>McLelland, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Divinity.</subject><title>The concept of the Kingdom of God in the thought of Hegel and Marx.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494c827.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z444d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Sacred Theology</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Religion</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430814p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is the objective of this thesis first to indicate the present position of the United States domestic air freight industry, in relation to the whole U.S. domestic freight transportation system, and then to examine the ways in which this particular segment of the system is likely to develop. An analysis of the air freight industry made in the context of the total domestic freight transportation system, such as the analysis contained in this thesis, has, to my best belief, not been undertaken before. In order to achieve the first of the two objectives of the thesis - that of indicating the present position of the air freight industry - all United states domestic surface media of transportation are examined, so that their major characteristics may be understood.</description><creator>Rickards, Anthony. E.</creator><contributor>Armstrong, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>The role of aviation in the domestic freight transportation system of the United States.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj377.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430814p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zc21q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this thesis is to explore the concept of the 'National Interest' as seen through the writings and speeches of China’s leaders, Chiang Kai-shek and Mao Tse-tung. The definition of the 'National Interest varies among Western theorists. Generally speaking, the 'National Interest’ may be termed the driving force of international politics, the essential framework for the definition of state objectives and the conduct of policy. A leading theorist, Hans J. Morgenthau, explains that the controversy which surrounds the concept of the 'National Interest' has its; roots in the two different schools of thought, “utopianism” and "realism”.</description><creator>Richardson, Ann. B.</creator><contributor>Brecher, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Economics and Political Science.</subject><title>China’s national interest: a comparison of nationalist and communist views.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dw88g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zc21q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics and Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p169h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Solvolysis of 3 B-cholesteryl derivatives have been known to result in the formation of derivatives of 3 A, 5-cyclo-cholestan-6 B-ol. By analogy with the cholesteryl series one might expect that solvolysis of 4, 4-dimethylcholesteryl 3 B-esters would yield the corresponding 3 A, 5-cyclo steroids of similar configuration at C6. The existence of such a compound, however, still awaits positive confirmation. Because of our interest in 4-alkylated steroids and especially on account of recent investigations on the solvolysis of 4, 4-dimethylcholesteryl tosylate, it was considered essential to synthesize the 3 A,5-cyclo-4, 4- dimethylcholestan-6 B-ol in an unambiguous fashion.</description><creator>Richardson, Keith. S.</creator><contributor>Just, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Synthesis and reactions of 4, 4-dialkylated steroids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9677148.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p169h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hk09t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of the work is to determine the effects of electron interactions on the power absorbed by a dense electron gas under the conditions of cyclotron resonance. This is accomplished by computing the transverse, complex conductivities within self-consistent field theory. A relaxation time is used to express the effects of scattering on the conductivities. The validity of this assumption is discussed fully. The power absorption is calculated for the propagation of microwaves along the direction of the uniform magnetic field in a finite sample of the gas. The result is round to be much more dependent on the shape of the body than in the weak field case as calculated by Dresselhaus, Kip and Kittel. The resulting magnetic-plasma resonance is investigated.</description><creator>Richardson, John. R.</creator><contributor>Wallace, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Effect of electron interactions on cyclotron resonance.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b195.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk09t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f4799</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:50:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The recent increase in interest in the biology of field crickets has prompted the author to attempt a revision of the subfamily Gryllinae. The description of new species of field crickets has for the past thirty years been based at least in part on the structure of the male genitalia and most of the new species have had at least the epiphallic portion of their genitalia figured. This practice, unfortunately, has not included the type species of the various genera and furthermore has not been universally applied to the genera in the subfamily. The logical beginning for a revision would thus be a survey of the genitalia of the type species of the various genera.</description><creator>Randell, Robert. L.</creator><contributor>Kevan, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>A study of the male genitalia of the crickets belonging to the subfamily Gryllinae (Orthoptera: Ensifera: Grylloidea) and its relationship to taxonomy.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w327n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f4799</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15600</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>