<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:20:28Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32950" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xk27x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In most instances, translation is regulated at the initiation phase, when a ribosome is recruited to the 5' end of an mRNA. The eIF4E-binding proteins (4E-BPs) interdict cap-dependent translation initiation by binding to the translation factor eIF4E, and preventing recruitment of the translation machinery to mRNA. The 4E-BPs do not inhibit cap-independent translation, such as that driven by picornavirus IRESes. The 4E-BPs inhibit translation in a reversible manner. Hypophosphorylated 4E-BPs interact avidly with eIF4E, whereas 4E-BP hyperphosphorylation, elicited by stimulation of cells with hormones, cytokines, or growth factors, results in an abrogation of eIF4E binding activity. Here I show that upon infection of cells with encephalomyocarditis virus (EMCV) or poliovirus, 4E-BP1 becomes dephosphorylated, and binds more strongly to eIF4E. This dephosphorylation could play a role in the shutoff induced by EMCV. Conversely, infection with adenovirus results in hyperphosphorylation of 4E-BPI and 4E-BP2 early in infection, at a time when viral protein synthesis proceeds via a cap-dependent mechanism. I also showed that the pathway leading to 4E-BP1 phosphorylation is dependent upon the activity of PI3 kinase, Akt/PKB and FRAP/mTOR. I then analyzed the phosphorylation of individual phosphorylation sites. Thr37 and Thr46 are phosphorylated by FRAP/mTOR immunoprecipitates. In vivo, a high stoichiometry of phosphorylation on these sites is observed in conditions of serum deprivation, or following treatment of cells with PI3K or FRAP/mTOR inhibitors. Phosphorylation on these sites is, however, required for the subsequent phosphorylation of the serum-sensitive sites, which I identified as Ser65 and Thr70. Phosphorylation of 4E-BP1 can be further ordered: phosphorylation of Thr37 and Thr46 precedes that of Thr70, which occurs prior to Ser65 phosphorylation. Phosphorylation of a combination of sites is required to mediate release from eIF4E, as phosphorylation of either Thr</description><creator>Gingras, Anne-Claude.</creator><contributor>Sonenberg, Nahum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Regulation of the translational inhibitor 4E-BP1 by phosphorylation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f293q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk27x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz156</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The release of vasopressin and oxytocin from the nerve terminals of magnocellular neurosecretory cells (MNCs) is optimised by increases in firing frequency and the adoption of a phasic pattern of firing in the soma. The temporal summation of post-spike depolarising afterpotentials (DAPs) of consecutive action potentials has been proposed to contribute to the generation of phasic firing. There has not been, however, any experimental evidence to support this hypothesis. In this study, a direct blocker of the DAP is introduced as being Cs +. Using this blocker, it is shown that the DAP plays an important role in the generation of phasic firing. Furthermore, these experiments reveal that external Cs+ causes depolarisation of MNCs when the membrane potential is held between action potential threshold and near -80 mV. External Cs+, however, is also known as a classical blocker of the hyperpolarisation activated inward current (IH). If I H is present in rat MNCs, the blockade of the IH by external Cs+ should lead to hyperpolarisation rather than the observed depolarisation. Using a recently introduced blocker of IH, ZD 7288, I show that IH is indeed expressed in rat MNCs, and that it also plays an important role in excitability and phasic firing of these cells. Finally, the ionic basis for the depolarising effects of external Cs + in rat MNCs is investigated. It is concluded in that extracellular Cs+ blocks both IH and a leakage K+ current that contributes significantly to the resting potential.</description><creator>Ghamari Langroudi, Masoud.</creator><contributor>Bourque, Charles W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Analysis of caesium sensitive membrane conductances in neurones of supraoptic nucleus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g9068.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz156</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666620n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chronic myelogenous leukemia (CML) is a disease arising from a reciprocal translocation between chromosome 9 and 22. Chromosome 22 encodes the Bcr gene, while chromosome 9 gives rise to the proto-oncogene, c-abl. In CML, these two genes form a fusion protein known as Bcr/Abl, which contains a constitutively activated protein tyrosine kinase. The focus of my research has been to address genomic instability as it relates to CML. Initially, I addressed genomic instability by utilizing Inter Simple Sequence Repeat Polymerase Chain Reaction (Inter-SSR PCR), in combination with primers which consist of a set of eight CA repeats. Using Inter-SSR PCR, I compared P190Bcr/Abl pre-leukemic mice (about 100 days, before onset of leukemia) and P190Bcr/Abl leukemic mice to control mice (BL6/CBA), and found an increased number of insertions and deletions in the pre-leukemic and leukemic mice compared to control. Next, I decided to again address genomic instability by utilizing the P190Bcr/Abl transgenic mice (line 623) and the Big Blue assay system (Stratagene). My results demonstrated a two to three fold increase in point mutation rate observed in P190Bcr/Abl x Big Blue pre-leukemic mice as compared to control mice (C57/BL6). These mice were then injected with the c-Abl specific kinase inhibitor, STI571 for ten consecutive days, to see if these mutation frequencies could be reversed. I observed a decrease in mutation frequencies upon injection with the inhibitor, in both the kidney and the spleen. I again utilized the InterSSR PCR system to address genomic instability in a P210 Bcr/Abl transgenic mouse with a tetracycline repressible system. My results showed an increase in insertions and deletions when the tetracycline is withdrawn from the P210Bcr/Abl transgenic mice and therefore Bcr/Abl is expressed. I examined genomic instability one last time by utilizing cDNA expression arrays to compare the P190Bcr/Abl pre-leukemic mice to the control mice (BL6/CBA). Using this system I noted an increase in several genes in the pre-leukemic mice, including several genes involved two genes involved in DNA repair, XPC and RAD23B . These experiments demonstrate that Bcr/Abl is inducing a mutator phenotype, seen as an increase in altered bands and point mutations, and that this can be reversed with the inhibitor ST1571. The results from the P210 Bcr/Abl inducible mice confirm previous results seen in the P190 Bcr/AbI transgenic mice and
reconfirm that Bcr/Abl is required for the induction and maintenance of disease. Finally,
these results suggest that BcrlAbl causes genomic instability seen upon disease
progression and that Ber/Abl induces genomic instability potentially through defects in
DNA repair pathways.</description><creator>Brain-Holcomb, Julia M.</creator><contributor>Laneuville, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Genomic instability in chronic myelogenous leukemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh68f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666620n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171z85m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Focusing on the entire literary works of Fernand Ouellette, that is to say all the writings published in collections from 1953 to 2000, the present thesis studies the evolution of his poetical writing in comparison with his writing of the essay, from a perspective both philosophical (development and evolution of concepts) and rhetorical (poetics and the form of thought). A chronological approach allows to draw three stages within the evolution of his works: (1) the period of lightning (1955--1973), which is linked to the poetics of revelation; (2) the period of wandering (1974--1986), when the poetics of relation is developed; (3) the mask of the augur (1987--2000), when occurs the meeting of the poetics of revelation and relation. Fernand Ouellette is one of the most important writers of his generation (the so-called generation of l'Hexagone) as well as of Quebec's literary history. Owing to romanticism and existentialism, he belongs to a humanistic and idealistic movement which advocates the total commitment of the artist. Alternately poet, essayist, autobiographer, biographer, literary critic and novelist, his production is remarkable not only because of its literary quality but also because of its intellectual and spiritual requirements. His works foster a filiation relationship with many artists and philosophers, mostly European. Centered between the desire of unity which sees an absolute in poetry, and the need of uniqueness which commands to take part in history, Ouellette's literary production, from the very first titles, is articulated on a dynamics, initially dual and then dialogical, establishing a relation between the lyrical subject, literally poetic, and the dialectical subject, corresponding to the figure of the essayist. By his commitment to fiction and self-portrait, two forms that are both privileged not only in autobiography but also within the novel and literary criticism, a dialectic is gradually developed, putting side by side poetry and essay without confusing them; it is through this dialectic that the figure of the subject is allowed to take shape. The result is an open literary production in which the function of the essay is essential to the poetical drive forward, while writing, based on movement, is both present to the World and oriented towards a mystical quest.</description><creator>Brassard, Denise, 1963-</creator><contributor>Rivard, Yvon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Ouellette, Fernand -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>La fonction de l'essai dans la demarche poetique de Fernand Ouellette /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps04g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z85m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns0647430</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research examines the changing relationships of gender, place and identity wrought by women's entrance into Montreal's financial service sector between 1900 and 1930. I seek to answer two related questions. First, what kinds of identities were enabled in the new spaces created by the feminization of clerical work? In particular, how was gender, sexual, and ethno-linguistic difference constructed within the mixed-sex clerical workspace? Second, what effect did women's entrance into corporate workspaces in the financial district have on prevailing notions about gender, class and urban space? How did this change in labour markets affect representations of women in public more generally? I make three arguments about women's entrance into Montreal's white-collar workforce. First, I argue that this process created a new kind of "contact zone" within and beyond the white-collar workplace. In these spaces, people came together across cleaves of difference, and ideas about nationalism, class, religion, and language were negotiated in new ways. Secondly, I argue that women's entrance into this sector of the labour market was marked by contradiction. On the one hand, women were held responsible for bringing sexuality into the white-collar workplace, and were sexualized within corporate culture. On the other hand, ideas about "respectability" defined through sexual propriety and corporeal restraint were central to the corporate image as well as media representations of female clerical workers. Finally, I argue that the feminization of clerical work re-mapped relations of gender, class and space. In the highly modernized offices of the financial district, ideas about public womanhood competed. I argue that this change in labour helped legitimize representations of modern womanhood which were consummately urban in nature.</description><creator>Boyer, Laura Kate.</creator><contributor>Olson, Sherry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Sex role in the work environment.</subject><subject>Women -- Employment -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Women clerks -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>The feminization of clerical work in early twentieth-century Montreal /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66345487.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647430</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj78j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Lame polynomials naturally arise when separating variables in Laplace's equation in elliptic-spherical coordinates. The products of these polynomials form a class of spherical harmonics, which are the joint eigenfunctions of a quantum completely integrable system of commuting, second-order differential operators P0 = DSN , P2,..., PN -1 acting on Cinfinity( SN ). These operators depend on parameters and thus constitute an ensemble. In the main result presented in this thesis, we compute the limiting mean level spacings distribution for the zeroes of Lame polynomials in various thermodynamic, asymptotic regimes. We give results both in the mean and pointwise, for an asymptotically full set of values of the parameters. As an application, we compute the limiting level spacings distribution of the zeroes of Van Vleck polynomials.</description><creator>Bourget, Alain.</creator><contributor>Toth, John A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Nodal statistics for the Lame ensemble</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks07j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj78j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf67k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation addresses the impact of principles of soft law on the development of international regimes for environmental protection. It focuses on three such principles that have attracted a certain degree of consensus in international environmental law and are therefore influential in international environmental regimes: namely, the principle of common but differentiated obligations; the principle of common heritage of mankind and its corollary, the principle of common concern of humankind; and the precautionary principle. The regimes analysed are the Antarctic regime, the regime for control of trade in endangered species, the regime for protection of the stratospheric ozone layer, and the emerging regime governing conservation and management of straddling fish stocks. It is argued that these principles influence normative development in international environmental regimes through processes of discourse in which participants, both state and non-state actors, seek to determine the rules by which their mutual relations will be governed and their common interests protected. Such discourse also connects the evolution of legal rules with a broader set of concerns relating to the interest of human communities in achieving a certain level of environmental protection. In this respect, the legal rules may be contemplated within a moral framework in which members of international society seek to determine what they ought to do with respect to global environmental protection.</description><creator>Ellis, Jaye.</creator><contributor>Toope, Stephen J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Environmental protection.</subject><subject>Environmental law, International.</subject><subject>Environmental protection -- International cooperation.</subject><subject>International law.</subject><subject>Environmental policy.</subject><title>Soft law as topos : the role of principles of soft law in the development of international environmental law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw114.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf67k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw67n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Organized in the nineteenth century, the General Conference of German Baptists was primarily a North American denominational body that adopted the polity of the American Baptists to build religious communities of converts of German ethnic background. From 1851 to 1920, the General Conference of German Baptists resisted institutional unity with the larger English-speaking bodies. Instead, it developed an ethnic mission with the financial aid of the American Baptist Home Mission Society. With time the German church membership became more Americanized in language and habits. The external pressure to assimilate increased. Yet, the German Baptist leadership moved away from complete Americanization of the churches and sought to preserve the distinct Pietist theological basis and ethnic mission of the Conference. The General Conference of German Baptists embraced institutional independence beginning in 1920 with the dissolution of the Cooperative Agreement that bound the mission of the German Baptists, the ABHMS, and the Baptist Union of Western Canada.</description><creator>Wesley, Cindy K.</creator><contributor>Kirby, Torrance (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>German Baptist Conference (U.S.) -- History</subject><subject>German Americans -- Ethnic identity.</subject><subject>Pietism.</subject><subject>German Americans -- Religion.</subject><subject>German Baptist Conference (U.S.) -- Doctrines -- History</subject><title>The Pietist theology and ethnic mission of the General Conference German Baptists in North America, 1851-1920 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w87h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw67n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr36w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to contribute to the research on school dropout by exploring the manner in which school policies and practices affect students' behavior. Four groups, each composed of 12 (6 male, 6 female) secondary students were interviewed. These involved an engaged group, an at-risk group, a group enrolled in alternative programs, and a group who had dropped out of school. The study had two goals. The first was to determine how these participants differed in their perceptions of their scholastic experiences. The second was to compare how males and females perceived their experiences. Significant differences were found by group and gender in perceptions of scholastic abilities. Clear distinctions were also found by group and gender in how the participants made sense of their academic experiences. Suggestions for preventative and remedial programming are offered. Implications for counselling psychology, in general, and school counselling, in particular, are discussed.</description><creator>MacDonald, G. Alexander (Gerard Alexander)</creator><contributor>Talley, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Dropouts -- Attitudes.</subject><subject>Problem children -- Attitudes.</subject><title>Perceptions of school experiences of dropouts and at-risk students</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt357.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr36w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x0694</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a study of stable perturbations in convex programming models. Stability of a general model is introduced as lower semicontinuity of the feasible set mapping. This stability is shown to be equivalent to the Robinson notion of stability and regularity. In the convex case, it is also equivalent to the full-rank Slater condition. Then, the relationships between various point-to-set mappings are studied for convex models and new implications between these mappings are established. Also, local and global optimality of parameters is studied. A new result here is a characterization of locally optimal parameters that does not require stable perturbations. This result is valid, in particular, for convex models with LFS constraints. The value of the model can be improved by one of several new formulations of the marginal value formula. The results on stability are applied for bilevel convex models and an algorithm for solving these models, based on a marginal value formula, is suggested and then applied to a real-life problem in the petroleum industry.</description><creator>Trujillo-Cortez, Refugio.</creator><contributor>Zlobec, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Stable convex parametric programming and applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k883x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x0694</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q317h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Infectious diseases continue to be one of the leading causes of morbidity and mortality in the world. Infection of mice with Salmonella typhimurium causes a systemic disease reminiscent of human typhoid fever and constitutes one of the best-described models of infectious disease. We show that wild-derived Mus musculus molossinus (MOLF/Ei) mice are extremely susceptible to infection with S. typhimurium, despite resistance alleles at known Salmonella-susceptibility loci. To identify the genes responsible for the innate susceptibility of MOLF/Ei mice, we performed a genome-wide scan using a panel of (C57BL/6J x MOLF/Ei)F2 mice. Salmonella-resistance was linked to Nramp1 with a LOD score of 18.8 and to mouse chromosome 11 with peak LOD score of 7.0 at D11Mit5. One recessive, susceptibility QTL (quantitative trait loci) was identified on distal chromosome 1 with a maximal LOD score of 4.8 at D1Mit100. In parallel, we undertook a functional dissection of the response of MOLF/Ei mice to infection with S. typhimurium. Kinetics of bacterial proliferation within the reticuloendothelial organs and histological evaluation of tissue sections suggest that MOLF/Ei mice do not succumb to infection following an overwhelming bacterial growth or massive tissue necrosis. We also demonstrate that, in spite of a normal response to Lipopolysaccharide and high expression of IL-1alpha and IL-1beta mRNA during infection, MOLF/Ei do not upregulate Nos2 mRNA expression and have a reduced capacity to release nitrite in vitro. We examined the candidacy of several genes located within the chromosomal interval defined by our genetic analysis and thought to be involved in resistance to Salmonella infection. The newly described role of Toll-like receptors in innate immunity and the location of human TLR5 in a region homologous to the interval containing the mouse chromosome 1 Salmonella-susceptibility QTL prompted us to clone mouse Tlr5. Mouse Tlr5 mRNA encodes for an 859 amino acid protein predominantly expressed in the liver. As expected, Tlr5 maps to the distal chromosome 1. The decreased expression of Tlr5 mRNA in the liver of susceptible MOLF/Ei mice, as compared to other strains, suggests the possibility that Tlr5 may play a role in host response to Gram-negative infection in wild-derived mice. We examined four candidate genes (Il12b, Csfgm, Nos2 and Mpo) within the Salmonella-resistance QTL on mouse chromosome 11. Although sequence analysis and mRNA expression studies reveal differences between the MOLF/Ei and C57BL/6J alleles, no definite conclusions can be drawn as to the roles of these genes in S. typhimurium infection. We created a series of B6.MOLF-Nramp1Gly169/chr11 congenic strains that collectively overlap the entire chromosome 11 QTL to define more precisely the chromosomal interval involved and, ultimately, to identify the causative gene(s). Preliminary testing of these strains confirms the presence of the MOLF/Ei-resistance locus and allows us to exclude the genomic area encompassing D11Mit84 and D11Mit141 from the QTL interval, thus eliminating Il12b as a candidate gene. Further characterisation of these strains will help elucidate which of the candidate genes on chromosome 11 confers resistance to infection with S. typhimurium.</description><creator>Sebastiani, Giovanna.</creator><contributor>Gros, Philippe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Genetic and functional dissection of resistance to gram-negative infection in wild-derived mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z702z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q317h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bg729</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The spoilage pattern of carp (Cyprinus carpio) fillets was investigated. The studies were aimed at evaluating the potential use of pressure-shift freezing to reduce quality deterioration during frozen storage. The effects of pressure treatment at low temperature on fish carp fillets were evaluated and conditions were chosen to reduce any adverse effect on the quality of fish fillet. Pressure-shift freezing treatment was applied to carp fillets and biochemical properties were evaluated and correlated with objective measurement of texture, drip loss and the size of ice crystals formed. Changes in these properties were monitored during frozen storage for a period of 75 days. Results indicated that proteolityc changes due to endogenous enzymes in fish muscle play an important role in quality deterioration of carp fillets during ice storage. No changes were observed in Ca2+-ATPase, Mg2+-ATPase or Mg2+-EGTA-ATPase activity of actomyosin from carp fillets during iced storage (p &gt; 0.05). In contrast, Mg2+-Ca2+-ATPase and Ca2+ sensitivity of actomyosin decreased during ice storage of fish fillets. No changes were found in the SH content of actomyosin throughout the ice storage of carp fillets (p &gt; 0.05). The surface hydrophobicity of actomyosin and auto-degradation products increased during the storage period (p &lt; 0.05). Response surface methodology (RSM) was used to study the effect of high-pressure treatment on some physico-chemical properties (actomyosin extractability, Ca2+-ATPase activity, surface hydrophobicity, TBA value, liquid loss and firmness) of intact fish fillets. Balancing the benefits of low temperature pressurization with the denaturing effects of pressure on fish proteins, it is evident that there is a region in which the responses of the factors (protein extractability, Ca2+-ATPase activity and protein hydrophobicity) to the processing variables (time and pressure) seemed to be adequate to keep protein denaturation to a minimum. This region lies between 140--175 MPa and 16--18 min. However, it was observed that high-pressure treatment induced changes in colour on fish fillets. The L*, a* and b* values increased as pressure and time treatment increased. The application of pressure-shift freezing or air-blast freezing resulted in decrease in myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic protein extractability, and reduced actomyosin Ca2+-ATPase activity during frozen storage. However, actomyosin Ca2+-ATPase activity in pressure-shift frozen samples remained relatively higher than that of air-blast frozen samples. On the other hand, levels of thiobarbituric acid and free fatty acids were relatively lower in samples frozen by PSF. The freezing procedure did not seem to have a significant effect (p &gt; 0.05) on the texture of carp fillets. The ice crystals found in PSF fish samples were mainly intracellular, smaller and more regular shaped than those found in the ABF samples, which were mainly extracellular. Differential scanning calorimetry showed that PSF treatment appeared to be more effective in preventing protein denaturation in post-rigor fish fillets than in the pre-rigor fish fillets.</description><creator>Sequeira-Munoz, Amaral.</creator><contributor>Simpson, Benjamin Kofi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>High pressure (Technology)</subject><subject>Fish fillets -- Preservation.</subject><title>Use of high pressure for improving the quality and shelf life of frozen fish</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw12d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg729</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q3167</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Discordant physician-patient perceptions on health-related information have been related to less favourable health outcomes and increased use of health services. Objectives. To develop a psychometrically-sound measure of physician-patient discordance that could be used by clinicians and researchers working with patients with various chronic diseases. To investigate the relationship between physician-patient discordance and patient adherence to self-care in inflammatory bowel disease. Study design and population. A prospective cohort study with follow-ups at 2-weeks and 4-months was conducted between February and November 1999 at three gastroenterology clinics affiliated with the McGill University Health Centre. Ten physicians and 200 patients with inflammatory bowel disease participated in the study. Methods. A 10-item visual analog scale questionnaire was developed which assessed perceptions of the patient's health status and of the clinical visit. Questionnaires were completed independently by physicians and patients following the index clinical visit. Discordance was calculated within physician-patient pairs. Demographic, clinical and psychosocial data were obtained prior to the visit. Patient adherence data were obtained at 2-weeks using a telephone interview and mail-back survey. General adherence was assessed with a visual analog scale; medication adherence was determined with a validated questionnaire. Medication data were obtained by chart review at 4-months. Multivariable generalized estimating equations models and mixed models for unbalanced repeated measures analysis of variance were used to determine associations between discordance and patient adherence. Results. Satisfactory psychometric properties were obtained for discordance scores. Higher psychological distress was the most important determinant of higher discordance. Higher distress was correlated with active disease, less time since diagnosis, greater number and impact of negative life events. Higher satisfaction with social support reduced psychological distress by buffering the negative impact of perceived stress. Higher discordance on symptoms and treatment increased the risk of general nonadherence in patients with higher social support satisfaction. Medication adherence was associated with active disease, greater disease duration and scheduling another appointment. Higher discordance on well-being decreased the probability of medication adherence in non-distressed patients. Conclusion. Preliminary evidence has been provided to support the validity of the new measure of physician-patient discordance. Higher discordance was associated with an increased risk of nonadherence in patients with healthy psychosocial characteristics.</description><creator>Sewitch, Maida.</creator><contributor>Abrahmowicz, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Dobkin, P. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Effect of discordant physician-patient perceptions on patient adherence in inflammatory bowel disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg207.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q3167</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc80m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The diagnostic utility of tympanometry with respect to distinguishing healthy and otosclerotic ears was investigated in four studies. This issue was examined with respect to alternative measures of static immittance (SI), tympanometric shape, resonant frequency (RF), and frequency corresponding to admittance phase angle of 45 degree (F45°) obtained from 68 healthy ears and 36 ears with surgically confirmed otosclerosis. Study 1 served to replicate previous findings that otosclerotic and healthy ears differ with respect to F45° and RF but not SI and TW measured at 226 Hz, thus confirming the advantage of multifrequency measures over standard low frequency tympanometric measures in differentiating healthy and otosclerotic ears. Studies 2 and 3 examined the effect of probe tone frequency on the diagnostic utility of SI and tympanometric shape. Group differences were evident for SI measured using a probe tone near the frequency corresponding to F45°, in the present study the optimal probe frequency was 630 Hz. Group differences were not evident for tympanometric width (TW) at 226 Hz, 350, and 450 Hz whereas the two groups differed in distribution of Vanhuyse patterns of 1B1G and 3B1G observed at frequencies between 800 Hz and 1250 Hz. In study 4 the diagnostic performance of five different tympanometric parameters was assessed using test performance and receiver operating characteristic (ROC) analysis. Results showed that F45° was the best single measure to distinguish healthy ears from otosclerotic ears; RF and SI measured at 630 Hz were the next best measures followed by Vanhuyse patterns; TW was the least useful measure. However, when compared using optimal decision criterion (derived from ROC analysis) differences in test performance for F45° and SI measured at 630 Hz were small suggesting that their clinical utility is comparable. Correlations and patterns of individual performance also confirm the presence of two independent signs of otoscle</description><creator>Shahnaz, Navid.</creator><contributor>Polka, Linda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Audiology.</subject><title>Distinguishing otosclerotic ears from healthy ears using multifrequency and multicomponent tympanometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nj80t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc80m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860860h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Myelin and axonal debris are cleared very slowly after injury to the adult mammalian central nervous system (CNS). This process of degeneration distal to the site of axon injury, called Wallerian degeneration, can take several weeks to months to complete in the CNS, and is thought to be due to a slow immune cell response. However, rapid myelin phagocytosis can occur in the CNS under certain conditions such as during lysophosphatidylcholine (LPC)-induced demyelination. To understand the factors that regulate and control the immune cell responses that lead to rapid myelin phagocytosis, I first studied the cellular and molecular changes that underlie LPC-mediated demyelination in the adult mouse spinal cord. I showed that LPC induced rapid recruitment of T cells, neutrophils and monocytes, and activation of macrophages that phagocytosed myelin by two days. A substantial degree of demyelination was established by 4 days. Recruitment of the immune cells was accompanied by significant increases in expression of the cell adhesion molecules VCAM-1 and ICAM-1 in blood vessels, as well as widespread disruption of the blood-brain barrier. I then carried out studies to assess the involvement of chemokines and cytokines in mediating the rapid immune cell responses and demyelination induced by LPC. The expression of GM-CSF, MIP-1alpha, MCP-1, and TNF-alpha mRNA was found to be increased in the mouse spinal cord early after LPC injections. To provide more direct evidence for their involvement in the immune cell response, the activity of these molecules was blocked singly or in combination using neutralizing antibodies. All four molecules were found to play a role in promoting recruitment of T cells and neutrophils, and recruitment and activation of macrophages, as well as myelin phagocytosis. In addition, MCP-1 and MIP-1alpha together were found to contribute significantly to these effects. I then compared the expression of these two chemokines in the hemisected mouse spinal cord and cut sciatic nerve, two regions of the nervous system that have differing rates of Wallerian degeneration. The expression of MCP-1 and MIP-1alpha mRNA was upregulated in the distal segments of the peripheral nerve. In contrast, there was little if any increase in expression in regions of the spinal cord undergoing Wallerian degeneration. Direct injections of recombinant MCP-1 and MIP-1alpha into the dorsal columns of the spinal cord undergoing Wallerian degeneration resulted in rapid phagocytosis of axonal and myelin debris. These studies demonstrate that MCP-1 and MIP-1alpha play a significant role in mediating the immune cell changes needed for rapid phagocytosis and clearance of myelin from the injured adult mammalian CNS. This work will have implications for stimulating rapid Wallerian degeneration in the CNS, as well as understanding some of the factors that may be involved in inflammatory demyelinating diseases such as multiple sclerosis.</description><creator>Ousman, Shalina S.</creator><contributor>David, Samuel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Immune cell responses involved in rapid clearance of myelin in the adult mamalian central nervous system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb53p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860860h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322f968</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ceruloplasmin oxidizes the toxic ferrous (Fe(II)) form of iron to the ferric (Fe(III)) form, and promotes iron loading onto transferrin. It is produced by the liver and secreted into the plasma. My work has shown that a novel membrane-anchored form of ceruloplasmin is the major form of this enzyme in the rat brain. The membrane-anchored form of ceruloplasmin was identified using a monoclonal antibody (mAb 1A1) that specifically labels the surface of astrocytes. Using mAb 1A1 immunoaffinity chromatography, the antigen was purified from detergent extracts of rat C6 glioma cells. Amino acid microsequencing, and additional experiments, revealed that this antigen was highly similar to ceruloplasmin. Further experiments revealed that this form of ceruloplasmin was directly anchored to the surface of astrocytes and C6 glioma cells by a glycosylphosphatidylinositol (GPI) anchor. Screening of a C6 glioma cDNA library identified a novel alternatively-spliced transcript that codes for this GPI-anchored form of ceruloplasmin. HEK293T cells transfected with the novel full-length cDNA expressed ceruloplasmin on the cell surface. Treating these transfected cells with phosphatidylinositol-specific phospholipase C (PI-PLC), an enzyme that specifically cleaves GPI anchors, eliminated the cell surface localization of ceruloplasmin, confirming that the novel cDNA codes for the GPI-anchored form of the protein. RNase protections on rat brain and liver RNA revealed that GPI-anchored ceruloplasmin is the major form in the brain, whereas the liver expresses predominantly the secreted form. To better understand the role of ceruloplasmin in vivo, a ceruloplasmin gene knockout mouse was generated. The knockout mice accumulate large amounts of iron in the liver and have reduced serum iron levels. Older knockout mice (15--17 months) have increased iron accumulation in different parts of the CNS, including the cerebellum, spinal cord, and retina. Increased lipid peroxidation is also observed in some regions of the CNS. These biochemical changes were accompanied by deficits in motor skills. Furthermore, dissociated cell cultures of the cerebellum from knockout mice were more susceptible to free radical injury when treated with hydrogen peroxide. These data suggest that ceruloplasmin plays an important role in iron metabolism in the CNS and provides protection against free radical injury.</description><creator>Patel, Bharatkumar N.</creator><contributor>David, Samuel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Ceruloplasmin : novel form and function in the central nervous system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064745j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322f968</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xn32x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) is the prototypic member of a large family of highly related cell surface glycoproteins that includes CEACAM6 (formerly NCA) and CEACAM1 (formerly BGP). The extracellular domains of CEA/CEACAM6 are bound to the external surface of the plasma membrane through a glycosylphosphatidyl inositol (GPI) anchor and are over-expressed in more than 50% of all human cancers. In contrast, CEACAM1 contains extracellular, transmembrane and cytoplasmic domains, and its level of expression is down-regulated in human tumors of the colon and prostate. When over-expressed on the surface of various cell types in model systems, CEA/CEACAM6, but not CEACAM1, function as pan-inhibitors of cell differentiation and cell polarization and cause a distortion of tissue architecture. Anoikis is a quality control mechanism that must be inhibited in cancer cells for such a distortion to persist. This thesis presents data demonstrating that CEA/CEACAM6 over-expression on the surface of a variety of cell lines inhibited anoikis. The molecular basis for the inhibitory effects of CEA/CEACAM6 on both anoikis and differentiation is shown to be correlated with perturbation of the function of certain integrins. In contrast to CEA/CEACAM6, the expression of the CEACAM1 glycoprotein neither perturbed integrin function nor prevented anoikis and, consistent with this, inhibited tumor growth. As a conclusion, we propose that CEA/CEACAM6, but not CEACAM1, over-expression on the surface of cancer cells inhibits cell differentiation and anoikis through perturbation of integrin functions. These inhibitory effects could instrumentally contribute to tumor formation and progression.</description><creator>Ordoñez, Cosme.</creator><contributor>Stanners, Clifford (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Role of the human carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) family in the regulation of cell differentiation and apoptosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v257.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn32x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz80x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The proposed thesis comprises three essays on the design of financial securities in the presence of frictions. The first essay develops a dynamic model of the impact of security designs on investment behavior and examines the adverse incentives created by debt and by equity when information is ex ante symmetric, inside agents cannot engage in perquisite consumption, and when there are no corporate taxes. A dynamic precommitment equilibrium is constructed and the choice between using risky debt and equity to raise capital is investigated. The second essay extends the above dynamic precommitment equilibrium approach to examine the behavior of the term structure of risky debt and characterizes the agency cost of adverse incentives as a spread. Assuming a fixed economic life of assets, the optimal maturity for debt is then investigated. The third essay develops a general equilibrium stochastic volatility framework and seeks to understand the structure of volatility risk. With a notion to develop tools to manage such risk, it considers the proper specification of the volatility of stocks, and the valuation of options written directly on this volatility.</description><creator>Osakwe, Carlton-James U.</creator><contributor>Jacobs, Kris (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Detemple, Jerome (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Securities.</subject><title>Essays on security design</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h25h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz80x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h26s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A 186-bp fragment of ors8, a mammalian DNA replication origin, was previously identified as the minimal sequence required for origin function in vivo and in vitro. The 186-bp origin contains, among other features, an octamer motif, serving as the binding site for the transcription factor Oct-1, and an A3/4-homologous region, serving as the binding site for the origin binding protein, OBA. The research objective of this thesis is to investigate the role of Oct-1 and OBA in mammalian in vitro DNA replication. Depletion of the Oct-1 protein inhibited in vitro DNA replication to basal levels. The inhibition was partially reversed upon the exogenous addition of Oct-1 POU protein. Site-directed mutagenesis of the octamer motif in the origin resulted in a mutant clone that lacked Oct-1 binding but replicated efficiently. The results suggest that Oct-1 is an enhancing component in DNA replication but its effect is not caused through direct DNA binding, but rather through protein-protein interactions. OBA was purified from HeLa cells through its ability to interact with the 186-bp origin. OBA binds to A3/4, a 36-bp mammalian origin sequence. The DNA binding subunit of OBA is identical to the 86 kDa subunit of Ku antigen. Depletion of OBA/Ku, by inclusion of anti-Ku antibodies to the in vitro replication reaction of p186, inhibited DNA replication. Furthermore, addition of the A3/4 oligonucleotide to the replication reaction of mammalian origin-containing plasmids (p186, pors12, and pX24) inhibited replication. This inhibition was reversed upon addition of OBA. In contrast, SV40 in vitro replication remained unaffected. OBA also possessed DNA helicase activity. By co-immunoprecipitation analyses, OBA was found to associate with DNA polymerases delta and epsilon, PCNA, topoisomerase II, RF-C, RP-A, DNA-PKcs, and Oct-1. The replication activity of xrs-5, a derivative of Chinese hamster ovary (CHO) K1 cell line defective in Ku86, was also examined. Total and cytoplasmic extracts from xrs-5 cells replicated p186 DNA as efficiently as CHO K1 extracts. In contrast, xrs-5 nuclear cell extracts lacked DNA replication activity, which was restored upon addition of OBA. The data implicate OBA/Ku in a direct role in the initiation of mammalian DNA replication as an origin-specific binding protein with helicase activity. The physical association of OBA/Ku with Oct-1 and the replication machinery reveals a possible mechanism by which these proteins are recruited to DNA replication origins. A cytoplasmic Ku-like origin-specific binding protein likely compensates for the absence of the endogenous OBA/Ku in xrs -5 cells. These studies provide a better understanding of the proteins that bind to mammalian origins, thereby aiding in understanding the mechanisms that regulate the initiation of DNA replication.</description><creator>Matheos, Diamanto.</creator><contributor>Zannis-Hadjopoulos, Maria (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Origin binding proteins and their rose in mammalian DNA replication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp995.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h26s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73px66g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vitruvius dedicated his, the only work on architecture to have survived from classical antiquity, to Augustus Caesar, the first Roman emperor, and claimed repeatedly that he was "writing the body of architecture (corpus architecturae)." A detailed examination of meaning of this claim, read in the specific imperial context that brought De architectura to light in ca. 25 B.C., is the principal focus of this study, which has been undertaken less as an effort to come to positive terms with the relevance (or irrelevance) of Vitruvius' normative prescriptions for Roman building practice than in the attempt to try to understand what he was trying to say about architecture and why. The exegesis is developed in four parts. The first deals with the corporeal identity of the book itself: a ten-scroll "angelic" messenger, whose written form proves to be as significant an index of its meaning as its content. The second part assesses Vitruvius' presentation of his treatise to Augustus in the preface to Book 2 of his treatise as the emperor's Herculean body: at once the agent and proof of Roman conquest and, like Hercules, the philanthropic purveyor of the benefits of civilisation to conquered peoples. The third unravels what Vitruvius meant when he said that buildings, temples especially, were to be put together in the same way that nature puts together the bodies of beautiful men. The fourth part concludes that the beautiful body, in question is the body of the king: that of the emperor himself, whose body---corpus imperii---was, at that historical juncture, imagined as congruent with the body of the Roman world. For Vitruvius, through architecture---as architecture---this kingly body was to be the chief agent of the empire's enduring coherence. That the project of Roman world dominion so consistently shaped this first self-conscious attempt to give a comprehensive account of architecture raises troubling questions about the discipline itself. It is in raising such questions that Vitruvius' De architectura acquires more than antiquarian interest.</description><creator>McEwen, Indra Kagis.</creator><contributor>Boker, Hans J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Vitruvius Pollio. De architectura.</subject><subject>Vitruvius Pollio.</subject><title>Vitruvius : writing the body of architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333398f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px66g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806153p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The term structure of interest rates shows the relationship between yields of zero-coupon bonds and their maturities. The empirical performance of the single-factor model of the affine term structure models, such as Vasicek (1977) and Cox, Ingersoll, and Ross (1985), has not been entirely satisfactory. The curve fitting methods, and particularly the spline method, used in practice to estimate the term structure are ad hoc and thus subject to arbitrage opportunities. Guo (1998) used the fundamental Partial Differential Equation (PDE) for bond pricing to derive a linear discount function, which is consistent with no-arbitrage. He showed that this is the unique linear solution to the PDE. This solution, the exponential-polynomial model or EP model for short, has n unobserved state factors that drive a stochastic discount process for pricing bonds so as to rule out arbitrage opportunities. In this thesis, we conduct an extensive cross-sectional analysis of the EP model on two different data sets: prices for daily Treasury bills, notes and bonds from the New York Federal Reserve Bank quotation sheets from July 1989 to October 1996, and daily Canadian bills, notes and bonds prices for the time period from June 1992 to May 1995. We estimate the model by applying a minimization criterion. The cross-sectional analysis shows that the EP model is able to describe adequately the term structure of interest rates. For the US data, we find that every term structure from the sampling period can be fully represented by either nine or ten state factors. Eigenvalue analysis indicates that the first three principal components are underlying the term structure movements. We conduct a time series analysis on the three principal components. They are found to be best described by ARMA/GARCH processes. We form two types of GARCH forecasts of the three principal components and test their out-of-sample performance. We conclude that the three principal components are predictable in a statis</description><creator>Mazigh, Monia.</creator><contributor>Whitmore, G. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Interest rates -- Econometric models.</subject><title>A linear model for the term structure of interest rates /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq42f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806153p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n028h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies the notion of knowledge in business firms, and in particular the concept of knowledge mobilization, understood as the mechanisms used by organizations to apply, transfer and retain knowledge about cause and effect relationships. As a theoretical framework, we use here a derivative of the resource based view of the firm called the knowledge based view. This theory is used to understand and analyze how service organizations in international strategic alliances developed and refined their knowledge base. Methodologically, this thesis utilizes a qualitative, longitudinal perspective, based on several cases of organizations in similar structural context but whose results after a few years of operation show large variances. The findings of this work show that the usefulness of knowledge for business firm (its value), is highly dependent on the life-cycle of the organization. Also, the types of knowledge mobilized varied also according to position in the life-cycle. Whereas younger, inexperienced organizations sought to transfer and develop knowledge, older organizations tried to prevent knowledge from dissipating. All these findings contribute to the creation of a contingent, evolutionary view of knowledge in business firms. In addition, the notion of knowledge consolidation (or effortful activities needed to maintain a piece of knowledge in the organization) is developed, and evidence is presented to support it.</description><creator>Martin de Holan, Pablo.</creator><contributor>Mintzberg, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Phillips, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Knowledge management.</subject><subject>International business enterprises.</subject><subject>Hotel management -- Cuba.</subject><subject>Organizational change.</subject><title>The dynamics of knowledge in international strategic alliances : a longitudinal study of service firms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000177t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n028h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z255h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Topic of this dissertation is the fast placement of hypergraph nodes into multi-dimensional grids. Hypergraphs can be used to model electronic circuits and network topologies, and grids can model the underlying architectures of electronic integrated circuits and optical systems. Thus, placement of hypergraphs into grids is an important problem as it may serve, for example, to reduce interconnection wire length in integrated circuits, or to minimize communication delays incurred in optical networks by routing around unnecessary bends. Fast placement techniques that complete in near-linear run time are desirable as circuit and network topologies are expected to continue to grow in size exponentially. The term "fast placement" thus refers to (a) the run time of the placement algorithm, and (b) the lower transmission delays in the resulting placement. Original research contributions are provided in chapters 1, 4, and 5. In chapter 1, the extension of relevant combinatorial grid placement problems to hypergraphs and multi-dimensional grids constitute a modest original contribution. Entirely original work is presented in chapter 4, where we introduce a novel force-directed iterative placement algorithm for two- and three-dimensional placements. This algorithm is designed to produce good minimum-wire-length placements for large circuits, for which no comparison results exist. The three-dimensional implementation of our placement algorithm pioneers the 3-D placement field in which previously no efficient algorithms had been published. In order to avoid operating in a vacuum, we were forced to create a comparison algorithm based on an accepted standard placement technique. With this reference placer, we generated the first published 3-D placement results, and 2-D placement results for large benchmark circuits for which no published comparison results exist. Our placement algorithm out-performs the reference placer substantially in both run time and wire-length. Further, we use our algorithm to present some experimental evidence of the estimated wire-length savings when utilizing the third dimension. Our final original contribution is a method presented in chapter 5 for efficiently placing a modern network topology, the star graph, into multi-dimensional grids such that all star graph neighbours are joined by a common grid line. The basic placement technique, originally published in [Obe95], is made efficient by compacting and contracting the bendless embedding in an effective manner.</description><creator>Obenaus, Stefan Thomas Henning.</creator><contributor>Szymanski, Ted (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Fast placement algorithms for grids in two and three dimensions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg15f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z255h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw279</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ubiquitin dependent protein degradation is now emerging as an important mechanism of cellular regulation. Specificity for the multitude of different substrate proteins is provided by a series of E2, E3 and deubiquitinating enzymes. The structural basis by which ubiquitin (Ub) conjugating enzymes (E2s, UBCs) and deubiquitinating enzymes determine substrate specificity remains unclear. We cloned rabbit reticulocyte E217k, and identified it as a homologue of S. cerevisiae UBC7. UBC7 differs from other class I E2 enzymes in possessing an insertion of 13 amino acids distal to the active site cysteine. Yeast UBC7 crystal structure indicates that this insertion forms a loop out of the otherwise conserved folding structure. By deletion of the loop in UBC7 and insertion of the loop in a typical class I E2 enzyme, E214K, we found that the loop interferes with the ability of E2 to bind to E1 charged with Ub as well as with E3s or substrates. We also identified two isoforms of a novel testis specific ubiquitin specific processing protease, UBP-t1 and UBP-t2, which contain identical core regions but different N-termini. Both isoforms were germ cell specific and developmentally regulated. UBP-t1 was induced in step 16--19 spermatids and primarily in the nucleus while UBP-t2 was expressed only in step 18--19 spermatids and located extra-nuclearly and in residual bodies. By expressing UBP-t1, UBP-t2 and UBP-core with myc tag, and fusions of the two distinct amino terminal ends with green fluorescent protein in COS-7 cells, we found that the N-terminus of UBP-t2 targets the protein to the centrosome and N-terminus of UBP-t1 targets the protein to nucleur. The N-termini also play a critical role in recognition of specific substrates. These findings indicate that divergent sequences, sometimes quite small, within conserved families of E2s or deubiquitinating enzymes can determine specificity of ubiquitination by influencing their subcellular location, and their abilities to recogni</description><creator>Lin, Haijiang.</creator><contributor>Wing, Simon S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Structure-function relationships of enzymes involved in ubiquitination</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w913.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw279</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx106</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work thermal dilepton production from a hot medium created in heavy ion collision is studied. Using an effective Lagrangian technique for particle decays and annihilations, a complete method for calculation of the lepton pair production rate is developed. The importance of axial vector meson contributions to the dilepton spectrum is analyzed. Different effective Lagrangians for the a1rhopi interaction are considered, and a new form of b1o(ϕ)pi effective Lagrangian is introduced. A systematic study of light meson contributions is performed. The most significant decay and reaction contributions are calculated and summed for low and intermediate invariant mass dileptons. The calculated dilepton rate is compared to that obtained using spectral functions extracted from data, and it is shown that the chosen set of mesonic reactions and decays accounts for all significant contributions to the thermal dilepton emission. A hydrodynamic approach to the space-time evolution of the hot medium formed as a result of a central heavy ion collision at ultra-relativistic energies is considered. A theoretical curve of intermediate invariant mass dilepton spectrum is computed and compared to the NA50 data from central Pb(158 AGeV)+Pb collisions. Experimental acceptance cuts are accounted for. Drell-Yan processes are considered as well. We find that our thermal dileptons account for the intermediate mass excess observed by the NA50 Collaboration. We see no need to invoke charm enhancement. Predictions for the future experiments at RHIC and are made.</description><creator>Kvasnikova, Ioulia.</creator><contributor>Gale, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Mesonic sources of dileptons in ultrarelativistic nuclear collisions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3012947.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx106</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):32975</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>