<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:13:27Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):31175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d1415</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A frequently reported disorder affecting mostly women, dyspareunia (pain with penile-vaginal intercourse) has been under-investigated in comparison to other sexual dysfunctions and pain syndromes. After presenting a critical review of the literature, delineating the history of description, classification, prevalence, etiology, and treatment, this thesis reports two sets of results from a clinical study of over 100 women who suffer pain with intercourse and 100 matched controls. A biopsychosocial protocol was used to assess both groups. Results from the two sets of analyses showed that (1) dyspareunia may be a heterogeneous disorder with, at least, three sub-types based on physical findings, (2) pain classification variables account for more of the variance in dyspareunia than the sexual dysfunction classification system currently in use, (3) higher levels of physical pathology, psychological distress and relational maladjustment are associated with dyspareunia in general, (4) biopsychosocial differences between the pain group and matched controls vary depending on the dyspareunia sub-type. The implications of this study underline the need for a research and clinical effort that integrates psychology and gynecology to address the heterogeneity of this complex disorder.</description><creator>Meana, Marta.</creator><contributor>Binik, Irving (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Dyspareunia.</subject><title>Deconstructing dyspareunia : description, classification and biopsychosocial correlates of a pain disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk74j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d1415</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526d90r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermolysis was investigated as a process to convert waste olefin-based polymers into value-added products at a moderate temperature. Virgin, linear low density polyethylene was used for the majority of the experiments. The thermolysis of virgin polystyrene, recycled polyethylene and 3:2 mixtures of polyethylene and polystyrene were also investigated. The final process that was developed employed the reactive distillation of polyolefins under an inert atmosphere and at moderate reaction temperatures, ranging from 375 to 450$ sp circ$C. The major products from thermolysis of polyethylene were a distribution of low-molecular-weight straight chain alkanes and $ alpha$-olefins ranging from C$ sb6$ to C$ sb{25}.$ Overall volatile product yields up to 90% were obtained from the starting polymer. The initial molecular structure of the polyethylene was found to have a large effect on the rate of molecular weight reduction. A significantly enhanced rate of thermolysis was also observed when polyethylene was processed as a mixture with polystyrene. The mechanisms of thermolysis of polyethylene, polystyrene and mixtures of the two polymers were elucidated. Furthermore, the mechanism of dimer production from polystyrene was found to be different than what has been reported previously.</description><creator>McCaffrey, William Chessleigh.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Thermolysis of polyethylene and polyethylenepolystyrene mixtures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v511.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d90r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d29b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The separation of the boundary layer at the trailing edge of sails is considered in the present work. This problem was identified as one of the major reasons for the disagreement between existing theories and experimental results. The separation of the flow on flexible surfaces is a complex phenomenon because of the interdependence between the shape of the sail, the pressure distribution and the separation position. The problem is simplified by considering the flow over a two-dimensional sail set at design incidence to isolate the effect of the separation of the flow. A theoretical model predicting the pressure distribution around a rigid aerofoil with trailing edge separation has been developed. The model uses a point source in potential flow to simulate the effect of the separated region on the flow. The separation position is determined using a turbulent boundary layer development calculation based on an integral method. The source strength and its position are modified iteratively until a set of closure conditions is satisfied. The model is first tested on circular-arc aerofoils and validated against experimental results of obtained on five different circular-arc aerofoils of camber ratio ranging from 10% to 27%. The theoretical results are also compared with other experimental results found in the literature. The agreement between the viscous theory and the experimental results is satisfactory up to camber ratios of approximately 23%. The theoretical model is then extended to simulate the flexibility of a two-dimensional sail. The shape of a rigid aerofoil is modified iteratively using the pressure distribution obtained from the flow separation model and the sail equation until convergence. The results of the viscous theory for two-dimensional sails are compared with a new set of experimental results obtained on four different two-dimensional sails of excess-length ratios ranging from 0.097 to 0.167. The predictions of the theory for a lower range of excess-length ratios are compared with experimental results from other authors. For the two-dimensional sails the viscous theory is generally in good agreement with experimental measurements up to excess-length ratios of 0.167. The theory presented in the present thesis demonstrates that a single source can simulate the essential effect that separation of the boundary layer near the trailing edge has on a thin cambered aerofoil. The integration of the separation model in an iterative scheme made it possible to determine the effect of trailing edge separation on the aerodynamic performance of a two-dimensional sails at design incidence.</description><creator>Cyr, Stéphane.</creator><contributor>Newman, B. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Prediction of flow separation over rigid and flexible aerofoils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306351.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d29b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b773z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polyomavirus large T antigen binds to four adjacent sites on viral DNA, denoted 1/2, A, B and C. Binding to site 1/2 leads to the initiation of viral DNA replication. RNA polymerases transcribing the late strand of the circular, 5.3 kb viral DNA are blocked just upstream of the replication origin and stalled RNA polymerases accumulate in that region (Skarnes et al., J. Mol. Biol. 203: 153-171, 1988). This accumulation of stalled RNA polymerases depends on binding of large T antigen to site A but not B or C (Bertin et al., J. Virol. 67:5766-5775, 1993). To investigate whether this accumulation depends on sequences other than site A, we cloned an insert containing sites A and 1/2, and the adjacent enhancer region, in the small T antigen intron or between two polyadenylation signals of a polyomavirus mutant. Most of the insertion mutants located in the small T antigen intron were nonviable. However, those located between the two polyadenylation signals were viable. Although stalling did not occur within the inserts, a major transcript within the replication origin was found while examining runon RNAs with viral transcription complexes isolated from cells infected with insertion mutants. Labelled RNA was hybridized with a single-stranded DNA, complementary to late-strand RNA, that extends through the replication origin; a major 80-nt RNA species was protected against nuclease treatment. Hybridization with two other DNAs that extend 18 and 41 nt farther in the direction of late transcription protected 98- and 121-nt RNAs, respectively. These results place the 5$ sp prime$ end of this transcript near the early side of site 1/2. Control experiments were carried out in which labelled RNAs synthesized in vitro were hybridized with the same DNAs; no RNAs with these 5$ sp prime$ ends were detected. S1 mapping of nuclear RNA from virus-infected cells detected no such transcript. The RNA polymerases that synthesize this RNA could terminate in vivo shortly downstream of the initiation site, or the RNA could be unstable. This "ori-RNA" is sensitive to $ alpha$-amanitin, resistant to aphidicolin, and independent of functional large T antigen. Ori-RNA synthesis could help stabilize the unwinding of DNA at the replication origin and enhance initiation of replication.</description><creator>Cherng, Jaw-Ming</creator><contributor>Acheson, Nicholas H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Transcription within the replication origin of polyomavirus DNA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v77d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b773z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bz83s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One major trajectory of early 'aql traditions is scrutinized: the Aqbil! Adbir! creation narrative "lamma khalaqa llahu l-'aqla (When god had created the intelligence ...)". In Part I early Sunni and Shii transmission and reception of the varying texts dominates the discussion, with analysis of chief motifs. Then successive transformations are traced, with attention devoted to ideas of 'first creation'. The original context of the Aqbil! reports is convincingly explained within the thought forms of 1st &amp; 2nd century theological ideas of voluntarism or predestination, without recourse to Goldziher's "new-Platonic element". The late neo-Platonising form "awwalu ma khalaqa llahu l-'aqlu, (The first (thing) God created is the intellect ...)", is shown to be not earlier than the mid-3rd/9th century. In a related class of narratives, 'aql pre-exists in the realm of the divine Throne. The focus is the notion of the divinely provisioned innate trait of 'intelligence' or 'wisdom' as a "light in the heart" inequitably apportioned among humanity. Part II examines the creative manner in which the sixth Shi'iimam Ja'far al-Sadiq (d.148/765) transforms the Aqbil! tradition by integrating this heavenly sapiential 'aql with the 'Adam-Iblis' conflict into a binary listing of the character traits (akhlaq, khisal). His myth of the creation, empowerment, and opposition between 'aql and jahl (intelligence &amp; ignorance, or wisdom &amp; folly) propounds a psycho-ethical scheme for the inner purgative struggle, wherein 'aql operates as chief of the character traits, Ja'far stresses the cognitive function (ma'rifah) in the perfection of 'aql peculiar to the inner circles of humanity (prophets, saints$ $ Imams, the faithful). An assessment is given of the repercussions of al-Sadiq's contribution for continuing Shii and Sufi enrichments of the 'aql creation narratives (eg. with al-Hakim al-Tirmidhi).</description><creator>Crow, Douglas Sloan.</creator><contributor>Landalt, Hermann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Islam and reason.</subject><subject>Jaʻfar al-Ṣādiq, 702?-765 or 6.</subject><title>The role of al-ʻAql in early Islamic wisdom with reference to Imam Jaʻfar al-Ṣādiq</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v13f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bz83s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz15m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three studies examined the relation of intimacy motivation as a social motive to interpersonal functioning. In Study 1, a self-report measure of intimacy motivation (san Int) was first constructed and then compared to the existing thematic measure (n Int; McAdams, 1992). The two motive measures were uncorrelated and associated with different quantitative and qualitative dimensions of social interactions. Nonetheless, both were independent predictors of the valence of interpersonal interaction. In Study 2, n Int and san Int were again found to be uncorrelated and to independently predict the valence of social interactions. In addition, the results indicated that although n Int and san Int were somewhat differently related to the sources and form of social support, both contributed independently as well as interactively to the perception of social support. In Study 3, the two forms of intimacy motivation were considered along with interpersonal skill and values in the prediction of rapport in a specific close relationship. The results showed that n Int and san Int independently predicted dyadic rapport as well as interacted with levels of interpersonal skill and values. Interestingly, there was also a negative interaction between n Int and san Int. Taken together, this series of studies provides strong support for distinguishing between motives assessed via self-report and thematic analysis as tapping two qualitatively different kinds of motivation. In addition these studies clearly indicate that the best prediction of interpersonal functioning is accomplished through the assessment of both kinds of motivation along with measures of interpersonal skills and values.</description><creator>Craig, Judy-Anne.</creator><contributor>Koestner, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Intimacy (Psychology)</subject><subject>Interpersonal relations</subject><title>The relation of implicit and self-attributed intimacy motivation to interpersonal functioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q504.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz15m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq71j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An immunocytochemical procedure for the human glucocorticoid receptor (GR) was developed herein in order to assess its level and subcellular distribution in a well-studied system of childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia cells (CEM), in which sensitive and resistant subclones have been established, and in different tissue preparations (lymph node biopsies, bone marrow aspirates and peripheral blood) from patients with various forms of leukemia or lymphoma. In the absence of preincubation with steroid, the GR was localized predominantly in the cell cytoplasm and to a weaker extent in the nucleus of CEM cells. Following incubation with glucocorticoid, an increase in nuclear GR was observed in the steroid-sensitive CEM-C7 and C7E$ sb2$A cell lines but not in the resistant C7 subclones (4R4, 3R43 and ICR27). Incubation of human peripheral mononuclear cells with 10$ sp{-6}$M dexamethasone for 30 or 60 minutes in vitro resulted in a marked increase in nuclear GR immunoreactivity. Since nuclear translocation of GR is a critical step in glucocorticoid hormone action on target cells, assessment of the subcellular distribution of GR may provide functional tests for steroid responsiveness. Furthermore, the effect of glucocorticoids on the regulation of GR and its mRNA was studied by immunocytochemistry, RIA and in situ hybridization.</description><creator>O'Donnell, Dajan J. (Dajan James)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Localization and regulation of the glucocorticoid receptor in human leukemic cells using immunocytochemistry, in Situ hybridization and radioimmunoassay</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc83v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq71j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w0324230</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Soybean growth with respect to N fertilizer rates, plant population densities and two cultivars was investigated on three Quebec soils at four sites. Soybean nodulation, growth, grain yields and nutrient uptake at three developmental stages were investigated. Soil nitrate levels after harvest were also studied. N fertilizer application depressed soybean nodulation consistently, but improved soybean growth where initial soil nitrate levels were low. Grain yield was increased at one site with added N, where soybean growth was stressed by low initial soil nitrate levels (below 17 kg N/ha) and severe summer drought. Soybean N and K uptake were increased with increased N fertilizer but P uptake was not affected. Residual soil nitrate content in the 0-50 cm depth in the fall of the crop year increased linearly and this effect carried over to the following spring. Plant population had little effect on individual plant nodulation but increased fresh nodule mass per unit area. Plant biomass, grain yield and nutrient uptake were increased with increased population densities. The cultivar Apache had better nodulation potential and grain yield potential and was better adapted to intensive management practices with high plant populations than the cultivar Maple-Arrow.</description><creator>Chen, Zhengqi, 1959-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Soybean -- Varieties.</subject><subject>Soybean -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Nitrogen fertilizers.</subject><title>Soybean (Glycine max L. Merrill) nodulation, growth and grain yield as influenced by N fertilizer, population density and cultivar in southern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv00g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0324230</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r06d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The interaction of naloxonazine, a putative long lasting or "irreversible" mu$ sb1$ receptor antagonist, with morphine, morphine-6-glucuronide (M6G) and sufentanil was studied in two nociceptive tests using rats, the formalin test and the tail-immersion test. Also, the displacement of ($ sp3$H) naloxone binding by selective opioid agonists in the rat brain membrane was performed after naloxonazine pretreatment in vivo. The specificity of naloxonazine was dependant on the nociceptive test used. In the tail-immersion test, intracranial naloxonazine (1 ug 4 hours before testing) produced a nonparallel right shift of the dose effect relations of all three agonists studied, consistent with long lasting "irreversible" antagonist properties of naloxonazine. In the formalin test, the same naloxonazine pretreatment regimen produced parallel right shift of the morphine dose effect relation but failed to alter the effects of M6G and sufentanil, suggesting either "reversible" antagonist properties or a more complex mechanism. Displacement binding assays suggest that naloxonazine interacts with mu and delta opioid receptor sites. The data imply that naloxonazine interacts in a long lasting manner with more than one opioid receptor subtype. An allosteric interaction between opioid receptor subtypes is proposed to explain the effects in the formalin test.</description><creator>Chen, Lei, 1961-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Effects of naloxonazine on opioid analgesia in the formalin and the tail-immersion tests</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz48k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r06d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j217b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In an effort to attain a quantitative understanding of the temporal and spatial variability of the tropical radiation budgets and the cloud-radiative forcing, a complete annual cycle of measurements by the Earth Radiation Budget Satellite scanning radiometer is analyzed. Results show the existence of strong diurnal variation in the longwave emission over land and desert scenes and in the reflected shortwave radiation for all scenes. A bias in the Earth Radiation Budget Experiment scene identification algorithm against clear tropical scenes at night is evident in the longwave diurnal variation results. Substantial east-west variation is exhibited in the radiation and the cloud forcing components for some latitude zones. The largest seasonal changes in the radiation and the cloud forcing components are associated with the Asian summer monsoon and the migration of the Intertropical Convergence Zone. Cloud forcing results show a strong dependence of net forcing on cloud type, with small values for convective clouds and large negative values for stratiform clouds.</description><creator>Chang, Tin Yee</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Remote Sensing.</subject><title>Tropical radiation budget from ERBS scanner measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f247m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j217b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d776x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous reports of the effects of tetrodotoxin (TTX)-induced muscular disuse have demonstrated alterations in muscle force, speed, and fatiguability that might suggest changes in the quality of contractile proteins. These studies were extended to the effects of TTX-induced disuse on the Ca$ sp{2+}$-activation characteristics of myofibrillar ATPase of the rat gastrocnemius. Atrophic responses after TTX treatment were as previously reported with a significant decrease in left gastrocnemius weight (g) compared to the control-pump (C) group (1.25 $ pm$ 0.04 for C vs 0.72 $ pm$ 0.04 for TTX, X $ pm$ SEM, p $ leq$ 0.01). Myofibrillar protein yield (mg$ cdot$g$ sp{-1}$ wet weight) was also depressed (92.8 $ pm$ 4.6 for C vs 70.3 $ pm$ 3.7 for TTX; p $ leq$ 0.01). Maximum ATPase of myofibrils (nmol Pi$ cdot$mg$ sp{-1} cdot$min$ sp{-1}$) was decreased (424 $ pm$ 46 for C vs 199 $ pm$ 27 for TTX, p $ leq$ 0.01). Furthermore, the Hill n which reflects the cooperative aspects of Ca$ sp{2+}$-activation of the myofibrillar ATPase was significantly depressed (1.58 $ pm$ 0.07 for C vs 1.29 $ pm$ 0.09 for TTX; p $ leq$ 0.05) after TTX treatment. The results of the present study suggest that muscle perturbations that result from TTX-induced disuse are at least partially related to changes in the myofibrillar fraction.</description><creator>Panenic, Robert</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Muscles</subject><subject>Tetrodotoxin</subject><subject>Rats -- Physiology</subject><title>TTX-induced disuse of mammalian skeletal muscle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9354215.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d776x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w66344901</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alkali-rich pyroxenite and sovitic carbonatite intruded amphibolite grade metamorphic rocks of the Bancroft terrane, Grenville province, in the Eganville-Pembroke region, Ontario, between 1090 and 1038 Ma ago. Intrusive field relationships, metastable feldspar mineralogy and oxygen isotope geothermometry indicate temperatures of emplacement above 650$ sp circ$C and locally rapid cooling rates. Clinopyroxene compositions from pyroxenites, carbonatites and fenites show identical sodium and iron enrichment trends. REE and C and O isotope ratios in carbonate dikes are typical of carbonatites. The presence in nearby carbonate metasediments of diopside- and apatite-rich skarn zones resulting from regional metamorphism explains the confused state of literature concerning the intrusive suite. Previously recognized resetting of radiogenic isotope systems may have resulted from a regional fenitization event associated with the emplacement of this suite.</description><creator>Mungall, James E.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Geochemistry of carbonatite and alkali pyroxenite, Bancroft Terrane, Grenville Province, Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66344919.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66344901</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m531p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In what follows I will examine problems surrounding Hilary Putnam's defense of 'internal' realism. I will begin by considering his motivations for rejecting what he calls 'metaphysical realism' and the theory of truth that this leads him to adopt. This theory, idealized rational acceptability, in turn raises doubts that 'internal' realism could be an undesirable form of 'relativism'. Putnam tries to show that his position is distinct from relativism, giving several specific arguments that the latter is inconsistent in various ways in which 'internal' realism is not. These arguments will constitute the main focus of this work. I shall argue that the arguments only succeed against a very narrow and naive class of relativist positions. I will then consider a more careful formulation of a sophisticated relativism offered by Chris Swoyer. From this it will be seen that other relativist doubts can be eliminated and I will then briefly consider what other resources the 'internal' realist position can make use of to deal with some remaining difficulties.</description><creator>Parisien, Aurèle</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Relativity</subject><subject>Realism</subject><title>Between realism and relativism : Putnam's narrow path</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935420w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m531p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w66344898</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A family of sets S = (S$ sb1$,S$ sb2$,...,S$ sb{m}$) is a k-fold cover for set T if each element of T is contained in at least k members of S. This thesis examines partitions of S such that each part is a cover for T. It is mainly concerned with extremal problems of the type "find the smallest k such that every k-fold cover can be partitioned into two 1-fold covers". In general, no such k exists. If elements of T are points in the plane and sets of S are straight lines then k is at least 4. If T is the interior of a simple polygon and S a family of convex or star-shaped sets then there does not always exist a "perfect" partition of the cover. This shows that computing a minimum size k-fold cover for a polygon does not reduce to combining minimum size thinner covers.</description><creator>Pesant, Gilles</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Factorizations of covers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935422f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66344898</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fc91n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The western portion of the hinterland zone in the northern Labrador Trough is characterized by four NW trending en echelon Archean basement bodies. From south to north the bodies are: the Scattered, the Moyer, the Renia and the Boulder. The Scattered and Renia have synformal geometries whereas the Moyer and Boulder have antiformal ones. These bodies are overlain by a cover sequence consisting, from the base upwards, of: various calcareous units, pelitic and semi-pelitic schists, an iron formation, a basalt horizon and a thick assemblage of coarse siliciclastic rocks. The sequence up to the basalt horizon can be correlated with the Kaniapiskau Supergroup of the Labrador Trough. The overlying sediments, the Thevenet Formation, are thought to correlate with the more extensive Laporte Group found in the hinterland of the central trough. Facies changes indicate an eastern provenance for the Thevenet Formation and the upper portion of the sediments underlying the basalts. The uplifted source region would include siliciclastic sediments, minor mafic volcanics and granitoid basement rocks.</description><creator>Moorhead, James</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Stratigraphy, structure and metamorphism of the renia basement gneiss body and the adjacent cover succession in the western Hinterland zone of the northern Labrador Rrough, west of Kuujjuaq, Northern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph565.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fc91n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz317</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The inclusive production of neutral pions has been measured in reactions of 95 MeV/nucleon $ sp{16}$O+$ sp{27}$Al, $ sp{58}$Ni, $ sp{208}$Pb, using a setup of 8 lead-glass Cherenkov counter telescopes to detect in coincidence the two photons resulting from pion decays. The differential distributions of interest: d$ sigma$/dT$ sb{ pi}$, d$ sigma$/d$ Omega$, d$ sigma$/dy and d$ sigma$/dp$ sb{ rm t}$ are obtained from the experimental invariant cross section of the pions. The transverse momentum, kinetic energy, and angular distributions, are discussed in the framework of the moving thermal source model. The shape of d$ sigma$/dp$ sb{ rm t}$ and d$ sigma$/dT$ sb{ pi}$ is reproduced by a single source having a temperature close to 20 MeV and moving with a velocity between that of the nucleus-nucleus and the nucleon-nucleon center of mass rest frames. Relevant signatures of the energy and angular dependences of pion reabsorption have been extracted from the data. The deviations of the energy distributions from the thermal model predictions are consistent with the deduced behavior of reabsorption. It is also shown that the absorption can explain the evolution of the anisotropy of the angular distributions with the target mass.</description><creator>Moisan, Christian</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><subject>Physics, Atomic.</subject><title>Neutral pion production in the reactions 160+27Al, 58Ni, 208Pb at 95 MeVu</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n9198.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz317</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289k31t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine the influence of self-efficacy on attentional deployment in a coincidence timing (CT) task. Hypotheses stating that high self-efficacy would incur less performance error than low self-efficacy and that increasing task difficulty, or stimulus speed, would increase CT error as a result of decreased reserve attentional capacity were tested. MANOVA procedures were used to compare CT error scores over three experimental conditions, two levels of task condition (single/dual) and two speeds (15/25 mph). Alpha was set at the.10 probability level for all statistical comparisons. As predicted, the positive feedback group reported significantly higher levels of self-efficacy than did the control and negative feedback groups, who were statistically similar in self-efficacy. Less variable, absolute, and total error was incurred by positive feedback than by the negative and no feedback treatments. A significant difference between the negative and no feedback groups was also noted in reserve attentional capacity.</description><creator>Koppel, Piret</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Performance</subject><subject>Sports -- Psychological aspects</subject><subject>Attention -- Testing</subject><title>Effects of self-efficacy on attention and error in coincidence timing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j9276.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289k31t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m297g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the urchin Strongylocentrotus purpuratus, the expression of the Spec3 gene is associated with the growth of cilia, one of the first morphogenetic events during development. The product of this gene was characterized using an antiserum raised against a peptide corresponding to the predicted amino-terminal portion of the protein. This thesis describes the localization of the Spec3 protein at different stages during embryonic development. Immunocytochemistry indicated that the protein is associated with cilia and Golgi complexes of ectodermal cells. Agents that inhibit protein synthesis and Golgi secretion also altered its normal distribution. Fractionation of cilia and immunoblotting indicate that the protein is associated with the ciliary axoneme and that it behaves as a large aggregate.</description><creator>Montpetit, Isabelle</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Strongylocentrotus purpuratus.</subject><subject>Sea urchins -- Embryos.</subject><subject>Developmental genetics.</subject><title>Localization and characterization of an ectodermal protein of sea urchin embryos</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h19w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m297g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r680m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The celebrated 'veil-of-ideas' argument is a skeptical argument that moves from a certain epistemological doctrine about perception to a general negative conclusion concerning our thoughts about external material objects. Indeed, the argument concludes not only that we do not know, but that neither could we know nor even reasonably believe, any of the thoughts that we may possibly entertain concerning external material objects. The epistemological doctrine about perception referred to in the argument has been in fashion since Descartes and states that the nature of perceptual knowledge in general is inferential. In this thesis, we will attempt to defuse this argument by calling into question the epistemological doctrine upon which it relies. This method of defusing the argument appeals to some of the reasoning to be found in the writings of J. L. Austin and, more recently, John McDowell. The following is a rough outline of how we will proceed. First, we will briefly look at the skeptical argument in question. Second, we will examine the mainstay of the epistemological doctrine, the Argument from Illusion, and argue that without the appeal to a certain view about the nature of appearance, this argument is ineffective. Third, we will adduce reasons for rejecting this view of appearance and put forward an alternative. This alternative requires us to construe knowledge in fallibilist rather than infallibilist terms. Thus, finally, we will examine the fallibilist and infallibilist conceptions of knowledge.</description><creator>Jung, Darryl</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Knowledge, Theory of</subject><subject>Perception (Philosophy)</subject><title>The problem of the external world : a fallibilist vindication of our claim to knowledge</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c024.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r680m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hw58x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:24:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research examined the influence of ability, prior knowledge and knowledge of text structure on expository history text corpora comprehension using a quasi-representative research paradigm. Sixty grade eight students participated in two history units. Hypotheses that ability, prior knowledge and knowledge of text structure would significantly influence performance in terms of the amount and organization of information presented on various measures were supported for the Ancient Man unit only. No interactions between the independent variables arose. The lack of significant findings for the Ancient Egypt unit is explained by poor text corpus organization and weak text structure. The findings suggest that teachers can facilitate students' comprehension of an expository text corpus by providing appropriate background knowledge of content and strategies for recognizing and utilizing text structure. Further, teachers should consider the organization of a textbook or corpus, and when necessary manipulate the materials to improve their structure and comprehensibility.</description><creator>Klein, Carolyn</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Learning, Psychology of</subject><subject>Social sciences -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</subject><subject>Reading comprehension</subject><title>The effects of ability and prior knowledge on recall in social studies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m38v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hw58x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t205</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:24:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The arrangements of lines stand at the heart of many problems in Computational Geometry, and the topological plane sweep algorithm (EG 86) permits to visit these structures in optimal time and space. This algorithm already improved the resolution of several older problems. In this thesis we present new applications where visiting an arrangement plays a major role. In the first we resolve the problem of finding the points contained on a line from each of k sets of n lines in O(kn$ sp2$) time and O(kn) space. In the second the task is to find the lines that can intersect (or stab) one element from each of k sets. The sets contain line segments or polygons, and the algorithm uses O(k$ sp2$n$ sp2$) time and O(k$ sp2$n) space, where n is the total size of the elements in each set. Minor modifications to the algorithm published in (EG 86) are also described. They allow the handling of degeneracies without recourse to a perturbation technique.</description><creator>Leblanc, Alain, 1964-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Some applications of the topological plane sweep algorithm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w854g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t205</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz32h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:24:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an analysis of the political thought and activities of an Iranian 'alim, SAYYID HASAN MUDARRIS (1870-1938). It demonstrates the continuation of the Iranian 'ulama's struggle, started in late 19th century, against colonialism and despotism during the years after the Persian Constitutional Revolution. This study investigates the deep causes of conflict between Mudarris and Riza Shah, the founder of the Pahlavi regime. Mudarris was a man of God as well as a man of his people. He was a mujtahid with high degree of patriotic sentiments. He devoted his life to Iran and to the dignity of his people for whose freedom from the yoke of Imperialism and despotism he lost his life.</description><creator>Jahanbakhsh, Forough</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Mudarris, Ḥasan, 1870 or 71-1937.</subject><subject>Ulama -- Iran -- Biography</subject><title>Sayyid Ḥasan Mudarris (1870-1938)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch839.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz32h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb038</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:24:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the nonbreeding season (July), three groups of five Dorset x Leicester x Suffolk rams were assessed over a period of 5 days. One group of rams (control) was implanted (sc) with five 5cm empty Silastic capsules (i.d. 3.4mm, o.d. 4.6mm); two other groups, designated as Low-E$ sb2$ and High-E$ sb2$, received five estradiol filled capsules of either 5cm or 10cm, respectively for 4 days. Estradiol treatment elevated serum estradiol concentration about 150% in the Low-E$ sb2$ groups (15.7 $ pm$ 1.3 pg/ml) and 300% in the High-E$ sb2$ groups (26.6 $ pm$ 2.4 pg/ml) compared with controls (6.3 $ pm$ 0.8 pg/ml). In the absence of LH pulsing, mean LH, FSH and testosterone concentrations were all decreased significantly (P $&lt;$.05) with increasing estradiol concentration, while PRL concentration was increased (P $&lt;$.05) by as much as 105%. In the LH-pulsed groups, LH-peak height on day 4 was comparable for all three groups of rams and peak frequency was, as expected, consistently increased to 4 peaks per 6 hours. The increase in mean testosterone concentration (P $&lt;$.05) in all three groups was due to an increase in testosterone baseline concentration and testosterone peak frequency.</description><creator>Melnyk, Peter M. (Peter Michael)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Sheep -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Estradiol.</subject><subject>Reproduction -- Endocrine aspects</subject><title>Estrogen regulation of testicular function in the adult ram</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v276.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb038</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623d73b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:24:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The deep seabed until the late sixties was a largely unknown part of the sea and represented nothing more than an academic curiosity. With technology making hitherto hidden depths of the ocean accessible for exploitation, it became known in the late sixties that the deep seabed contained precious minerals. In a world used to shrinking resources, this shot the deep seabed into the centre stage of world politics, becoming perhaps the most controversial issue in any United Nations Conference. The controversy centered around the legal status of the deep seabed. This work contends that there is not in place any viable international legal regime for supervising and regulating resource development in the deep seabed outside national jurisdiction; that whatever regulations there are, are geared towards facilitating exploitation of the area; that such lacunae would be at an environmental cost that could negate whatever short-term benefits are derivable therefrom. This work therefore examines the potential environmental impact of deep seabed mining and proposes a legal regime for preventing and minimizing same.</description><creator>Izedonmwen, Osaretin Ernest</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>The environmental impact of deep seabed mining /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x514r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623d73b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pt82h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:24:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A reversed micellar phase was studied using infrared spectroscopy and surface tension analysis. The effect of the organic phase composition and the type and concentration of salt were investigated. Two parameters were measured, the surfactant partition between the organic and aqueous phases and the amount of water solubilized. The organic phase consisted of a mixture of hexane and hexadecane containing dissolved Aerosol OT. The aqueous phase contained a postassium salt in a buffer solution. The Aerosol OT partitioned essentially completely to the organic phase under conditions of high salt concentration or high hexane concentration. As the hexane:hexadecane ratio increased, the amount of water solubilized decreased. For all salts, except those of lanthanum, the water solubilized decreased considerably as the salt concentrations increased.</description><creator>Miletti, George</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Surfactant partition and water solubilization in reversed micellar systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv63p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pt82h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):31200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>