<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:25:04Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21650" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801ph522</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyses Thomas Bernhard's partially autobiographical but at the same time critical works on society as well as on contemporary issues. The mendacity of the Austrian society and the related catastrophical consequences of it for the intellectual individual forms the central theme. The inability of the Austrian people to overcome their past is above all concentrated on. In the year 1988, the commemorative year of the fifty years since Austrian Annexation with Nazi-Germany, Bernhard made with Heldenplatz an essential contribution to the positive incorporation of history. The careful study of Bernhard's works with particular references made to Beton and Heldenplatz, demonstrates his recognition of the symptoms of the neurotic behaviour of the Austrians. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Summer, Jacqueline</creator><contributor>Schmidt, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Bernhard, Thomas -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Gesellschaftskritik und Selbstmord im Werk Thomas Bernhards mit Bbesonderer bezugnahme auf Heldenplatz und Beton</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n12b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801ph522</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j96021965</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA was microencapsulated by emulsification/interfacial polymerization within semi-permeable cross-linked chitosan membranes. Polar solvents and pH extremes were avoided during microencapsulation by using vegetable or mineral oil as the continuous phase and chitosan as the polymeric backbone. The membrane was cross-linked with glutaraldehyde or hexamethylene diisocyanate and microcapsules varied in diameter from 95 to 325 $ mu$m. DNA was visualized within the microcapsules with ethidium bromide stain. Binding of ($ sp{14}$C) methyl iodide and ($ sp{14}$C) benzo (a) pyrene by microcapsules was demonstrated in vitro and in vivo, respectively, although binding was mostly evident in the chitosan membranes. Magnetic recovery of the microcapsules from rat faeces following GI transit was facilitated by co-encapsulating magnetite. The microcapsule diameter decreased by 60-70% during GI transit due to dehydration in the colon and the recovery was approximately 10%.</description><creator>Alexakis, Theodora</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Microencapsulation of DNA within cross-linked chitosan membranes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v408s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96021965</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537232g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The chelating effect on regio- and stereochemical control of the homoallyl alcohol synthesis and electrophilic substitution of allylsilane was studied, using 2,2-dimethyl-1-$ {$1- ((S)-2-(2-methoxyethoxy)methyl) pyrrolidinyl$ }$-2-sila-4-pentene (S1) and 2,2-Dimethyl-1-$ {$1- ((S)-2-hydroxymethyl) pyrrolidinyl$ !$-2-sila-4-pentene (S2), with S1 synthesized from L-Prolinol. The synthesis of homoallyl alcohol was carried out by allyl transformation from S1 and S2 to a Lewis acid activated aldehyde. Chelation between the allylsilyl ligand and the Lewis acid:aldehyde complex was found to favor the cyclic syn-clinal over the acyclic anti-periplanar transition state, in the asymmetric synthesis of the alcohol 1-dodecen-4-ol (P1). The bulky, remote and weak chelating ligand resulted in only modest selectivity and average chemical yield. Regio- and stereochemical control of the electrophilic alkylation of allylsilanes S1 were achieved due to chelating effect that favored $ alpha$-alkylation. The chiral chelating ligand also resulted in enhanced stereochemical control electrophilic alkylation. Steric effect, due to a large electrophile, and solvent effect that causes disruption of the chelated complex, decrease $ alpha$-selectivity.</description><creator>Nguyen, Thi-Ngoc Dieu</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Allylsilanes in organic synthesis homoallylic alcohol synthesis and electrophilic alkylation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st828.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537232g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000001138</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The predictors of birthweight (scBWT) in normal pregnancy are well established. The objectives of this study were to characterize and determine predictors of scBWT among women diagnosed with scGDM. A cohort of 436 scGDM full-term pregnancies (followed 1978-1989) were examined using data abstracted from the Royal Victoria Hospital Antenatal Diabetic Clinic charts and McGill Obstetric and Neonatal Database. Women were treated with insulin and/or diet. Dietary treatment (mean 2047 kcal/d) significantly decreased the rate of weight gain and mean fasting plasma glucose (scFPG). Regression analysis identified several predictors of scBWT (mean 3520 g): prepregnancy body mass, height, smoking, pre-diagnostic rate of weight gain, scFPG, gestational age, infant gender, and length of treatment. Stratification by body mass indicated that among non-obese women with scGDM, scFPG and length of treatment were not significant predictors of scBWT. In conclusion, since women with normal pregravid mass and prediagnostic weight gain are at lower risk of high scBWT, these require consideration, in addition to plasma glucose criteria, when treating scGDM.</description><creator>Snyder, Jennifer</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Birth weight.</subject><subject>Diabetes in pregnancy.</subject><title>Nutritional predictors of infant birthweight in gestational diabetes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v907q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000001138</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892b94n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following is a case study of the Northeast Fisheries Project, in Northeast Thailand, carried out jointly by the Canadian International Development Agency, its implementing agency and the Thai Department of Fisheries from 1986 to 1990. The formulation and events surrounding the project will be reviewed, with special emphasis on an experimental extension program which was pivotal to the project's success. Overall, the project did not succeed in meeting its objectives, and the purpose of this study is to examine the role of Thai values, social structure and bureaucracy, in contributing to this failure. Specifically, we will consider Thailand as a 'bureaucratic polity', the history and dynamics of patron-client relationships, and how these factors interact in the context of development projects and programs.</description><creator>Thomas, Virginia</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Thailand -- Economic policy</subject><subject>Fisheries -- Thailand</subject><subject>Fisheries -- Government policy -- Thailand</subject><title>Obstacles to development in a 'bureaucratic polity' : a case study of the Northeast Fisheries Project</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430590w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b94n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9997811</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I have measured the metabolism of tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$ in Friend cells undergoing erythroid differentiation, using an assay exploiting the tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$ gene's ability to specifically hybridize tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$. The concentrations of tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$ measured as a proportion of the total tRNA population (relative concentration) decreased until day 3 post-induction, and then increased on day 4. The relative concentrations of tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$ are influenced by tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$ having lower turnover rate in comparison to the total tRNA population, and by the relative rate that labelled, newly synthesized tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$ accumulates in vivo. The rate of tRNA$ sp{ rm Asn}$ synthesis in nuclei isolated from Friend cells at different times during differentiation also fluctuates. This fluctuation may reflect changes in RNA polymerase III activity in these isolated nuclei.</description><creator>Miller, Harvey</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Transfer RNA.</subject><title>The metabolism of tRNAAspargine in the friend erthroleukemia cell /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn30c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9997811</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xg18m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experimental investigations and theoretical considerations of long acoustic cladded buffer rods are presented and theory superiority over uncladded rods is shown. These rods consist of a core and a cladding which are so designed to confine acoustic energy in the core, giving rise to a perfect guidance. Different rods with different core dopant material, concentration and profile were designed and their acoustic performance was studied by ultrasonic pulse-echo experiment. Tapered rods are also introduced. A cladded silica rod of a large diameter is tapered gradually to a rod of a small diameter and gives it the ability to be used where tiny features or openings are dealt with. Novel metalic acoustic rods both cladded and uncladded are presented and a comparison is made between these rods and conventional metal rods. Acoustic lenses are fabricated at the end of a few rods including cladded silica tapered silica and cladded metalic rods and ultrasonic focus and unfocus measurements carried out at 5 and 10MHz are presented for all the rods. Finally, the application of our unique rods at elevated temperatures is discussed. Ultrasonic measurements are performed at medium temperatures (up to 270$ sp circ C$) on a high viscosity liquid and at high temperatures (around 750$ sp circ C$) on molten aluminum. It is shown that our cladded acoustic rods are proper candidates for use at high temperatures to monitor the properties of molten metals specially good for molten aluminum or low melting point temperature (below 1000$ sp circ C$) metals.</description><creator>Miri, Amir Masoud</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Long acoustic cladded buffer rods</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k323.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg18m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fx890</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two series of experiments were conducted to investigate the heat transfer processes from open channel flow to an ice block and an array of ice blocks. The first series of twelve tests were conducted to determine the heat transfer rate from the open channel crossflow to a single isolated ice block. During the experiment the ice block was gradually lowered into the crossflow while maintaining a constant volume of submergence. The ice block which initially had the shape of a circular cylinder, changed gradually to the shape of a cone yielding to the thermal erosion by the crossflow. The heat-transfer rate from the crossflow to the ice cone was greater than the rate to a hemisphere and also the rate to a circular cylinder. This higher heat transfer rate associated with the cone is explained by a 'heat-transfer concentration' phenomenon associated with the tip of the ice cone. In the second series of experiments, a packed array of ice blocks in the tightest arrangement was used to simulate a brash ice cover in the open channel flow. Six tests were conducted. The heat transfer rate from the open-channel flow to the brash ice cover was significantly higher than the rate to a smooth surface. The increase in heat transfer rate due to the 'roughness effect' was as high as 300 percent. However, due to the 'sheltering effect', the heat transfer rate from the flow to each of the ice cone in the array was only 35 percent of the rate to a single isolated ice cone with the same volume of submergence.</description><creator>Wang, Yaohua, 1959-</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Heat transfer from open channel flow to an ice block and an array of ice blocks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq12z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx890</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jc547</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The brook trout population in a 4.7 hectare subarctic lake was sampled in 1986 and intensively fished in 1987, 1988 and 1989 in order to study the effect of stock depletion on fish parasite transmission. Population density was originally high, with slow individual growth rates, and small maximum size. Brook trout bore infections of Eubothrium salvelini, Phyllodistomum umblae, Crepidostomum farionis and Diplostomum sp. as well as some rare parasites. After intensive fishing the growth rates and size of the remaining fish increased. In 1987 all parasites increased in abundance. E. salvelini decreased in 1988 whereas the abundance of the other parasites remained high. In 1989 two new parasites, Echinorhynchus lateralis and Philonema sp. appeared. Parasite community changes and improves fish growth were related to trout diets and the pattern of intermediate host consumption. In 1987 zooplankton feeding increased. It then declined in 1988 and 1989 as populations of large benthic invertebrate prey increased. Feeding shifts may also have been mediated in part by intraspecific competition and aggression.</description><creator>Wright, Bernard James</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Brook trout -- Parasites -- Québec (Province) -- Schefferville Region.</subject><title>Effects of intensive stock reduction on a brook trout population and its parasite community</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m2923.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jc547</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333332b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents accurate and efficient transistor-level delay modeling techniques for the worst-case delay estimation of digital MOS circuits. A number of timing analysis tools already rely on transistor-level delay models which use relaxation-based electrical simulation techniques to accurately model the propagation delay of MOS logic gates. For worst-case delay estimation, efficient application of relaxation-based electrical simulation techniques can be performed by using multiple-transition delay modeling methods and by minimizing the number of node equations to be solved. The worst-case delay estimates produced by accurate transistor-level delay models can be inaccurate if logic dependencies within MOS logic gates are ignored. A class of transistor-level delay estimators, which is based on the enumeration of worst-case conduction subnetworks, is introduced to handle these logic dependencies. A comparative study of multiple-transition worst-case delay estimation methods is also presented.</description><creator>Gaiotti, Serge</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Worst-case delay estimation of digital MOS circuits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc35s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333332b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s132b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A field lysimeter experiment was conducted on a sandy loam soil during the growing seasons of 1989 and 1990. The experiment tested the effects of four water table treatments on soybean (Glycine max) yields. The water table depths were 40, 60, 80, and 100 cm in depth. Yields were measured in terms of: total seed mass per plant, number of seeds per plant, number of pods per plant, number of seeds per pod, and speed protein content at harvest. The water management simulation model DRAINMOD, was used to develop irrigation and drainage strategies for soybean production. Three water table management methods were tested with each of three water table depths. The methods were conventional drainage, controlled drainage, and subirrigation, and the water table depths were 40, 60, 80, and 100 cm. It was shown that for the driest year highest yields are obtained with subsurface irrigation and a weir setting of 40 cm. For the average year, highest yields are obtained with subirrigation and a 60 cm weir setting. For the wet years, best results are found when controlled drainage is used with 80 cm weir setting. It was found that in all but the driest and wettest years controlled drainage improved yields by 10% or more.</description><creator>Broughton, Stephen R. (Stephen Russell)</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Irrigation -- Management.</subject><subject>Soybean -- Irrigation.</subject><subject>Water table.</subject><title>Water table management strategies for soybean production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d096j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s132b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73px14q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chicken strains divergently selected for either abdominal fat deposition, avian leukosis (ALV) resistance or Marek's disease (MD) resistance were analyzed for restriction fragment length polymorphism (RFLP) in the growth hormone gene (GH). A total of four polymorphisms were identified, one at a SacI restriction site (PS1) and three at MspI restriction sites (PM1-PM3). Restriction mapping indicated that all polymorphisms were in exons and/or introns and not in flanking regions of the gene. Selection for abdominal fat composition significantly affected the frequency of polymorphisms at PM2, but not at the other restriction sites (p $&lt;$ 0.0004). The PM2$ sp{+}$ allele (presence of a restriction site) was fixed in the fat line and occurred at a frequency of 63% in the lean line. Selection for ALV-resistance resulted in significant differences in the frequency of polymorphisms at PS1 and PM3. Selection for MD resistance also affected the frequency of polymorphisms at PS1 and PM3.</description><creator>Fotouhi Ardakani, Nasser, 1959-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Somatotropin.</subject><subject>Poultry -- Genetics</subject><title>Incidence of growth hormone gene polymorphisms in strains of chicken selected for abdominal fat content or resistance to avian leukosis virus or Marek's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c167p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px14q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741s96c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A thorough literature review of cloud algorithm validation strategies is presented, with particular emphasis on the problems of detecting cirrus clouds. To further advance our cirrus detection capabilities, a new cloud detection technique is proposed for the Multi-angle Imaging Spectro-Radiometer (MISR), which is scheduled to be on the first platform of the Earth Observing System. Radiative Transfer simulations have been used to develop a Band-Differenced Angular Signature technique. This new technique takes the difference between two solar spectral reflectances as a function of view angle. The resulting angular signature is used to discriminate between high- and low-level clouds and surface reflectance anomalies. This technique, coupled with a Predetermined Clear Sky Threshold developed in this study for MISR, can detect cirrus clouds of visible optical thickness $&gt;$0.5 without any a priori knowledge of atmospheric conditions. Other techniques that can be used with MISR (i.e. stereo) are also discussed.</description><creator>Di Girolamo, Larry</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>On the detection of cirrus clouds from satellite measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc801.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s96c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm80q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phonotactic steering behavior of tethered flying crickets (Teleogryllus oceanicus) was examined as a measure of the insect's attraction to temporal patterns of calling song at different frequencies and intensities. A stimulus with a 5 kHz carrier becomes less attractive the further its pulse repetition rate deviates from 16 pulses/s. Increasing the intensity increases selectivity for temporal pattern. At sufficiently high intensity level crickets cease to respond to stimuli with altered temporal patterns. High frequency neurons were suspected to be behind cessation of responsiveness to stimuli with altered temporal features. This hypothesis predicts that the effect on selectivity of increasing the intensity of the 5 kHz stimulus might be mimicked by adding a high frequency to the stimulus. My results contradict this hypothesis. The response to a 30 kHz carrier demonstrates a dependency on the duration and pulse repetition rate of the stimulus.</description><creator>El-Feghaly, Edmond M.</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Oceanic field cricket -- Behavior</subject><subject>Insect sounds.</subject><title>The influence of sound spectrum on recognition of temporal pattern of cricket (Teleogryllus oceanicus) song /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf908.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm80q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547s61s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Cloud of Unknowing is in a very real sense a treatise on epistemology, and on the practical aspect of the communication which we call rhetoric. The Cloud draws upon the Platonic rhetorical tradition, which asserts that grasp of abstract truth gives value to human understanding and communication. Reality is above all transcendent, as mirrored in the kataphatic mystical tradition to which the Cloud belongs. The problem is that, if this "vertical" mode of knowing be set against the "horizontal" mode of knowing which in literary theory is generally labelled "metaphor", the existence of metaphoric approaches to reality in the Christian faith (which the Cloud author professes) seems inconsistent with the mystical tradition and Platonic rhetoric. However, a reconciliation of vertical and horizontal modes of knowing--of metonymy and metaphor--is effected, in theological terms, by an Incarnational dynamic involving creation and grace, and, in critical terms, by paradox and analogy.</description><creator>Burgess, Andrew</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Mysticism</subject><title>Incarnational epistemologies : metaphor and metonymy in the mystical tradition of the Cloud of unknowing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f462t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s61s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs03k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is about attempted suicides and is based on open and in-depth interviews of 31 individuals who have attempted suicide once or several times. The phenomenon is presented through the concept of "career" and from the subject's point of view. Its first objective is to reconstruct the sequence of events that marks the experience of individuals who had decided to commit suicide but have failed in their project. This sequence starts with the decision to commit suicide, the choice of method, followed by the act itself; it is characterized by an interruption that triggers different forms of intervention: physical treatment in a hospital and psychiatric evaluation; it continues with the return of the individual to his/her familiar circle, facing the life conditions he/she had wanted to leave. Reconstructing this experience emphasizes the solitary, the physical and the uncertain nature of the suicidal act. It also shows how individuals who do not complete their suicide will be caught in disconcerting and compromising situations, and that their act will force them to justify themselves to different audiences and will taint their relationships with others. Finally, the analysis indicates that the terms in which individuals envisage suicide are transformed in the course of their experience.</description><creator>Camarra, Josée</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Suicide</subject><subject>Suicidal behavior</subject><title>"Partir revenir" : compte rendu de tentatives de suicide</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1393067.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs03k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579t358</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The subjects of the study were kindergarten and first grade speakers of Czech and English. The Czech language contains a considerably higher frequency and variety of complex syllabic onsets than English. Hence, it was hypothesized that if linguistic input affects children's phonological awareness development, Czech children should show higher levels of ability on the tasks. These differences were expected to appear in preliterate kindergarten children if linguistic input, more than literacy and/or general cognitive factors, impacts significantly on phonological awareness. The finding that preliterate Czech children were more advanced in the ability to manipulate complex syllable onsets suggests that oral language input has an important effect on developing phonological awareness skills. Furthermore, its effect appears to be independent of the effects of literacy.</description><creator>Caravolas, Marketa</creator><date>1991</date><subject>English language -- Phonology</subject><subject>Language acquisition</subject><subject>Czech language -- Phonology</subject><title>The effect of linguistic input on children's phonological awareness : a cross-linguistic study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z897f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579t358</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff3656199</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a study of Chava Shapiro, a woman writer, born in 1876 in the Ukraine, who died in 1943 in Nazi Czechoslovakia. It describes her conventional Hasidic upbringing, her successful rebellion against it and her subsequent studies in Switzerland which led to a career in Hebrew journalism. It follows her return to Russia in 1914, her escape to Czechoslovakia after the pogroms of 1919 and 24 years later her tragic end in Terezin. Dominating the study is the well-known Hebrew writer, Reuven Brainin, 1862-1939, with whom Chava Shapiro fell in love and who exerted an extraordinary influence on her life. Using original, never before published materials from the Jewish Public Library Archives in Montreal, the study seeks to define the woman as a feminist and a Hebrew writer.</description><creator>Caruso, Naomi</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Shapiro, Chava, 1876-1943 -- Correspondence</subject><subject>Authors, Hebrew -- Correspondence</subject><subject>Hebrew literature, Modern -- History and criticism</subject><subject>Brainin, Reuven, 1862-1939 -- Correspondence</subject><subject>Hebrew literature -- Women authors</subject><title>Chava Shapiro : a woman before her time</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t7487.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3656199</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547s622</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is a great interest in the treatment of spent autocatalyst because, due to large amounts of PGM used by catalytic converters, the autocatalyst scrap is the largest and constantly growing source of PGM available for recycling. A hydrometallurgical method of PGM extraction from honeycomb type catalyst containing platinum (800-1200 ppm) and rhodium (50-60 ppm) using HCl-AlCl$ sb3$-HNO$ sb3$ or HCl-HNO$ sb3$ mixtures was studied. Experimental results of the leaches performed in a bench scale tubular reaction with recycled continuous flow of the leaching solution as well as 1000 cc stirred reactor are presented. The results suggest that Cl$ sp-$ single ion activity plays a decisive role in controlling the PGM dissolution. The extent of PGM recovery increased not by increasing HCl concentration to very high levels, but by keeping a relatively low total Cl$ sp-$ level (2.5 M) with a significant proportion present as AlCl$ sb3$. Rhodium extraction was always 5-10% lower than platinum, and it appears that increasing the AlCl$ sb3$/HCl ratio tends to increase rhodium recovery. High temperature (85-95$ sp circ$C) and an HNO$ sb3$ concentration around 3-3.5 M play very important roles in effectiveness of PGM extraction. The presented method of HCl-AlCl$ sb3$-HNO$ sb3$ tubular reactor leaching supplemented by solvent extraction (Kelex 100) of PGM from pregnant solution appears to be very attractive for small size (5-20 tonnes of catalyst/day) installations.</description><creator>Boliński, Lech</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Platinum and rhodium recovery from scrapped automotive catalyst by oxidative acid chloride leaching</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g6245.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s622</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827c86h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this research project has been to evaluate the feasibility of improving the impact properties of polypropylene (PP)/ethylene vinyl alcohol copolymer (EVOH) laminar blends by the incorporation of a rubber phase. The impact modifier was poly (ethylene-propylene) rubber (EPR). The study was conducted initially with a batch mixer, and then continued with an extruder. Furthermore, it was decided to evaluate the improvement in impact toughness of the blends upon addition of a polyethylene (PE) phase. The batch mixing studies showed that it is possible to bring the impact properties of maleated PP (MAPP)-based blends to the range of those exhibited by MAPP, by incorporation of both EPR and PE. The sequence of addition of EPR and PE is very important. The products obtained exhibited good adhesion at the interface between the dispersed phase and the matrix. The presence of EPR and PE did not affect the final oxygen permeabilities of the blends. The extrusion studies showed that the morphology of the blends, and therefore their final properties, depend on the method of compounding. Different MAPP resins were used as the major phase. The best impact properties were found in the case of addition of the EPR-PE phase in a twin screw extruder. The oxygen permeabilities were disappointing, and appeared to be only slightly influence by compositional or processing parameters. One possible explanation is that moisture might have contaminated the EVOH phase, inhibiting its effectiveness as an oxygen barrier.</description><creator>Arghyris, Laurent</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Modification of the impact properties of blends of polypropylene and poly(ethylene-vinyl alcohol)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz21r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827c86h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt26r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents two algorithms to solve nonlinear seismic problems in generalized coordinates, one that uses a set of vectors computed from initial properties, the Pseudo-Force Method (PFM), and another that continuously updates the vector basis to represent the nonlinear behaviour, the Tangent Spectrum Method (TSM). Both methods can use either exact eigenvectors or load dependent vectors as vector basis. Parametric analyses are carried out on a series of multistory buildings idealized as shear beam structures with bilinear hysteretic behaviour. The effects of the truncation of the vector basis on the stability and the quality of the nonlinear solutions are investigated using nonlinear response parameters such as ductility, energy balance, and dissipation. The algorithms are then used to make a comparative study on the effects of different mathematical representations of viscous damping based either on initial elastic, or tangent modal, properties of MDOF structures. For a flexible 25-story structure, the solution is much more sensitive to the truncation of the vector basis when the PFM is used instead of the TSM.</description><creator>Dussault, Serge</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Nonlinear seismic analysis using vector superposition methods</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s97n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt26r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kk80w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the corpus of Chekhov's prose there is a perceptible evolution in his use of irony. This study involves an examination of the use of irony in the initial, middle and final phases of his artistic career. It will demonstrate that in the initial phase, Chekhov's use of irony was direct and overt; in the middle phase, it was more deliberate and covert; and in the final phase, it was subdued, more transparent and transcendent. Selected stories taken from all three periods will illustrate this evolution.</description><creator>Lemieux, Martha</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Chekhov, Anton Pavlovich, 1860-1904 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Chekhov, Anton Pavlovich, 1860-1904 -- Technique</subject><title>The evolution of irony in the short stories of Chekhov /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch775.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kk80w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b231z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Changes to 5-HT$ sb2$ receptors in rat brain following antidepressant and anxiolytic treatment were investigated. The B$ sb{ rm max}$ of ($ sp{125}$I) AMIK was found to be decreased significantly in rat fronto-parietal cortex after 21 days administration of antidepressant drugs including desmethylimipramine (30%), buspirone (47%) and adinazolam (17%). The anxiolytic drug, diazepam, which is devoid of intrinsic antidepressant action, did not significantly change the binding parameters. In comparison to 5-HT$ sb2$ receptors, the beta-adrenoceptors labelled by ($ sp{125}$I) cyanopindolol in membrane binding were decreased only by desmethylimipramine, with a 17% reduction in B$ sb{ rm max}$. Data from in-vitro quantitative autoradiography suggests that ($ sp{125}$I) AMIK binding to 5-HT$ sb2$ receptors is decreased in frontal and parietal cortices following 21 days administration of DMI, amitryptiline, gepirone and adinazolam. The results from the present study strongly suggest that the 5-HT$ sb2$ receptor is involved in depressive disorders. Since some of the antidepressant drugs tested possess anxiolytic activity after prolonged administration, 5-HT$ sb2$ receptors may also be important in anxiety disorders.</description><creator>Lafaille, Francine</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Characterization of [125I]7-amino-8-iodo-ketanserin binding and comparative effects of long-term treatment with anxiolytic and antidepressant drugs on serotonin type 2 and beta-adrenergic receptors in rat brain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c168z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b231z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bv70m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis proposes the exploration of three architectural sources that are narrative in nature: the Renaissance Entry of a Monarch as a public event in the city, the Surrealist novel as a critical medium, and the Teatro del Mondo project by Aldo Rossi for the Venice Biennale of 1979-80, in order to address the making of architecture in the contemporary city. The royal entry and the modern novel are forms that provide for possible interpretation of the city and reflect the difference between the modern and the pre-modern eras. Aldo Rossi's Teatro del Mondo as a work of architecture that was both ephemeral and a place of narrative, was a project that addressed the difficult problems of the architecture of the city. Architecture no longer participates in the realization of ritualistic narrative, as when the festival gave permanence to urban institutions by revealing the order of the Cosmos. However, there remains the necessity for architecture to engage imagination and the narratives implicit in the world.</description><creator>Livesey, Graham</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Architecture and literature</subject><subject>Architecture and society</subject><subject>Architecture -- Philosophy</subject><title>Narrative, ephemerality and the architecture of the contemporary city</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386k54c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bv70m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zx721</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:51:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using chronic disease registers, a list of physician-diagnosed diabetics was drawn up for the 8 James Bay Cree communities (total population 8840). Medical records were then consulted to ascertain the clinical histories of the patients. The World Health Organization definition of diabetes was applied to diagnosed cases and those not meeting the biochemical criteria were eliminated. A total of 235 persons with diabetes were found, giving a total prevalence of 2.7%. Prevalence of type II was 5.2% in the 20 years and older age group. Prevalence varied from 1.9% in the northernmost village to 9.0% in the southernmost Cree community. The Cree diabetic population is characterized by high levels of obesity and low rates of macrovascular diseases. Duration of disease and poor glycemic control (as reflected by the type of medication needed) influences the presence of microangiopathies.</description><creator>Brassard, Paul</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Diabetes in the James Bay Cree communities of Québec, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096817g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx721</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21675</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>