<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:17:06Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):47225" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k0998</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Water may be held by various bodies' in such a way and with such a degree of firmness that it fails to exhibit certain of the properties characteristic of water in the ordinary free state. The term 'bound' water may be loosely applied to describe water which is so held in any system. The binding of water by a solid material is especially characteristic of lyophilic colloids of which the protein gelatin is a typical example. A number of heat capacity measurements have been made on gelatin gels with the object of obtaining some evidence of the amount of water bound, the intensity of the binding forces and the mechanism of the binding of the water by the gelatin. Previous measurements of this kind have been made in the range of temperatures below zero with the object of determining the amount of water frozen in the gel. The present work involves measurements of the heat capacity of gelatin gels between 0° and 80°C. and an attempt to elucidate the heat effects accompanying changes in the gelatin water relationship which occur within that range of temperatures. It was considered that similar measurements on a different type of system involving 'bound' water might aid in throwing light on the mechanism of water binding by gelatin. Consequently a calorimetric investigation has been made of the properties of the water Borbed by activated charcoal.</description><creator>Horn, Wallace Randolph</creator><contributor>Mennie, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Calorimetric measurements on gels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd3760575.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k0998</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg835</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our concern, here is with his critical treatment of Shakespeare. Opinion on Johnson's performance in this field has fluctuated from his day to our own. Even today the estimates vary. The purpose we have in view is to assemble and record these opinions, as they were issued, from Johnson's time to the present. The method by which we shall proceed will be based on a fivefold division of the subject. The first chapter will serve to indicate the successive stages of Johnson's interest in Shakespeare, up to the publication of his edition of the plays. The second chapter will contain an analysis of the Preface. The third will record the opinions on Johnson's performance expressed in the eighteenth century. Chapter four will consider the attitude of the nineteenth century writers towards Johnson. Chapter five will bring the record down to the present day.</description><creator>Klein, Jenny</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784.</subject><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>The history of Johnson’s Preface to Shakespeare: 1765-1934</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xp634.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg835</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m978w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is a strange anomaly, and yet it is a fact of great importance, that at a time when poetry is being least read, (or if read, least understood and appreciated), America has come into its most poetic period. It seems to be adequate refutation of Whitman's dictum that "to have great poets, we must have great audiences." The fact that there has been a tremendous amount of poetry written in the past twenty-five years, and that poets ply their art in every state in the Union, does not of course prove that America has come into its most poetic era. One of the purposes of this thesis is to show to what extent that poetic output is of genuine worth.</description><creator>Hamilton, Robert Alexander</creator><contributor>Latham, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>American poetry -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>American poetry from 1910 to 1935</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064888j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m978w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jr83w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Thesis endeavours to determine: first, the English conception of Spain and Spanish literature at the end of the Eighteenth century; second, the extent to which these opinions prevailed throughout the English Romantic Period; third, what influence these conceptions had upon English literature during this period; and, fourth, how, if at all, these conceptions were modified.</description><creator>Hetherington, Elizabeth Mabel</creator><contributor>Noad, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>Spanish literature -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Comparative literature -- English and Spanish.</subject><title>Spain and the English romanticists : a study in comparative literature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150m949.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jr83w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72pb281</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>the enunciation of the "neurone theory" by His and Forel (1886-1887) attention has been focussed on the nature of interneuronal connections. Max Schültze, the discoverer of neurofibrils (1871), surmised a discontinuity between the units of the nervous system. The subsequent discoveries of Cajal, Held, Auerbach, etc. have done much to explain on a structural basis many facts concerning the synapse long known to neurophysiologists. In the present work studies have been made of the "boutons terminaux" as they occur in synapses in the spinal cord, cerebellum, and cerebrum, both in the normal state and after axonal section. The early manifestations of degeneration have been carefully recorded, in order that the tracing of fibre tracts by the "bouton" method may be placed on a sound basis. Evidence is produced in favour of the conception of "contact" rather than "continuity" at interneuronal junctions, as implied in the "neurone theory".</description><creator>Gibson, Willam Carleton</creator><contributor>Penfield, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>Neurology.</subject><title>A Morphological study of interneuronal connections</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p3249.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pb281</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pt52b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our greatest wheat growing areas are in Western Canada, hence it necessarily follows that most wheat breeding programmes have as their primary object, the producing of more suitable varieties for that part of the country. A new variety, unless it be early is of doubtful value to Western Agriculture since late maturing sorts are periodically damaged by late summer frosts. The losses due to a reduction of grain yield and grade of wheat as a result of untimely frosts may often total millions of dollars. The inheritance studies of the earliness character in different wheat varieties become of great importance in view of those facts. The number of factors responsible for the expression of 'earliness' in wheat may vary with different varieties, but most investigators report a complex factorial inheritance.</description><creator>Gfeller, Frederick</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>Genetics.</subject><title>Inheritance studies of earliness, bunt resistance, awns and phenol colour reactions in a spring wheat cross</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473036n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt52b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s7837</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been known for some time that Grignard reagents may give both 1,2- and 1,4- addition to α, β -unsaturated ketones. More recently it has been shown that, when there is a sufficient amount of substitution, an aromatic ring might provide the α, β -unsaturation for such a 1,4- addition. Some quinones are like α, β -unsaturated ketones but have been found to give 1,2- addition with Grignard reagents in most cases. A partial list of the quinones that have been investigated 1s given in Table I. This list is only intended to bring up to date and supplement a similar one incorporated in a previous thesis presented at this University.</description><creator>Gilman, Lucius</creator><contributor>Allen, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Action of the Grignard reagent on polynuclear ketones</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042w916.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s7837</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s320z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper deals with the effect on shrinkage and residual stress longitudinally in an electrically welded butt joint of preheating plates at temperatures of about 200°F., 300°F., and 400°F., by comparison with a plate welded at room temperature. Weld and plate metal are also tested in tension for Modulus of Elasticity and Yield Point, as well as by micro-examination and for checical composition.</description><creator>Hamilton, Donald</creator><contributor>Jamieson, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1936</date><subject>Civil engineering and applied mechanics.</subject><title>Preheating effects on residual stresses in arc-welded steel plates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193c803.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s320z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cd88n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>       Le suivi de la composition corporelle des joueurs de hockey universitaires peut faire ressortir certaines de leurs caractéristiques physiques et peut aider les joueurs, comme les entraîneurs en préparation physique à optimiser les gains physiologiques durant l’entre-saison tout en évitant une diminution des performances durant la saison. Deux études distinctes ont pris place lors de cette grande recherche. La première étude avait pour but d’observer les changements de la composition corporelle du corps en entier, puis par région spécifique du joueur de hockey élite universitaire prenant en considération les tissus adipeux et maigres durant l’entre-saison et la première moitié de saison. Le but de la deuxième étude était de voir si les athlètes universitaires pouvaient précisément déterminer les changements de leur composition corporelle.        Dans la première étude, le profil de la composition corporelle de dix-neuf joueurs élites de hockey universitaire canadien a été évalué utilisant l’absorption de l’énergie double des rayons-x à trois différents moments (fin de la saison, pré-saison et mi-saison). La répétition de mesures d’anova a été utilisée pour comparer le changement de composition corporelle des joueurs à différents moments. Des changements signifiants de la composition corporelle ont été observés, alors que les joueurs ont montré différent gains/pertes de tissus tout dépendant de la région évaluer. Globalement, les joueurs ont gagné (1.38kg, p &lt; .01) de tissus adipeux durant l’entre-saison et perdu (.79kg, p &lt; .01) durant la saison. Les joueurs ont aussi montré des gains signifiant au niveau des tissus maigres des jambes (.29 kg, p = .02) et des pertes au niveau de la masse des tissus des bras (-.25 kg, p = .02) durant la première moitié de la saison régulière. Plusieurs corrélations émergent ce qui donnent un aperçu des tendances potentielles qui pourraient être davantage prononcées durant une plus longue et plus demandant cédule.          Dans la deuxième étude, un total de 24 joueurs a complété les évaluations de pré-saison et de mi-saison. Immédiatement avant  le scan, les joueurs ont répondu à un questionnaire sur leurs entraînements durant la saison ainsi qu’hors-saison sur comment ils évaluaient l’évolution de leur composition corporelle et de leur force par rapport aux régions spécifiques désignées. Le deux tiers des joueurs on précisément perçue les changements dans leurs tissus maigres des bras et la moitié pour leurs tissus adipeux. Les deux tiers des joueurs n’ont pas précisément perçue les gains ou les pertes de leurs tissus maigres ou adipeux de leurs jambes et de leur corps en entier.           Les résultats de chacune des études peuvent avoir d’importantes implications pour la performance et le développement des athlètes universitaires. La précision des joueurs à percevoir les changements de leur composition corporelle peut affecter leur acceptation et leur adhésion à une diète ou à un programme d’entraînement. Globalement, la compréhension d’un profile de la composition corporelle, des variations et des autres variables potentiels qui peuvent influencer la composition corporelle des joueurs de hockey universitaires peut aider les entraîneurs et les programmes sportifs à adapter les entraînement d’équipe, la nutrition, le mode de vie et les sources d’informations de leurs joueurs de manière à mieux supporter leurs athlètes. </description><description>       The monitoring of a collegiate hockey player’s body composition can reflect fitness characteristics, and may help players, coaches or strength &amp; conditioning professionals optimize physiologic gains during an off-season, while simultaneously preventing performance decrements in-season.  Two separate studies took place in this investigation.  The first study’s purpose was to examine changes in the whole-body, and regional-body composition profiles of elite collegiate hockey players in regards to fat and lean tissue mass during an off-season and the first half of a competitive season.  The purpose of the second study was to evaluate if collegiate players could accurately perceive their fluctuations in body composition.        In the first study, the body composition profiles of nineteen elite Canadian collegiate hockey players were assessed using dual energy x-ray absorptiometry at three different time-points (i.e. end of season, pre-season and mid-season).  A repeated measures anova was used to compare the player’s changes in body composition at the different time-points.  Statistically significant changes in body composition profiles were observed as players showed various tissue gains/losses depending on the region assessed.  Overall, players gained (1.38kg, p &lt; .01) and lost (.79kg, p &lt; .01) fat tissue during the off-season and in-season, respectively.  Players also showed a significant gain of leg lean tissue (.29 kg, p = .02) and loss of arm tissue mass (-.25 kg, p = .02) during the first-half of the competitive season.  Several correlations emerged that may provide insight into potential trends that could be more pronounced during longer and more demanding schedules.       In the second study, a total of 24 players completed pre-season and mid-season assessments. Immediately before each scan, players answered questionnaires regarding their off-season and in-season training, and perceived change in their body composition and strength of particular regions during the 3-month time period.  Two thirds of players and one-half of players accurately detected changes in arm-lean and arm-fat tissue respectively. Approximately two-thirds of players did not accurately perceive gains or losses of lean or fat tissue within their leg and overall body region.        The findings from each study can have important implications for the performance and development of collegiate athletes.  The accuracy of a player’s perceived change in body composition may affect their acceptance and adherence to a dietary or training intervention.  Overall, the understanding of body composition profiles, body composition fluctuations, and potential variables that may influence the composition of collegiate hockey players can help coaches and athletic programs tailor their team’s training, nutrition, lifestyle and informative resources to further support their athletes. </description><creator>Prokop, Neal</creator><contributor>Ross Andersen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>Seasonal changes in whole body, and regional body composition profiles of elite collegiate hockey players</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v51f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cd88n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365812s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Soil pollution due to anthropogenic petroleum hydrocarbon (PHC) spills has become a major environmental hazard. The eco-toxicological indicators used to evaluate soil quality complement physico-chemical criteria employed in contaminated site remediation. But their cost, time consumption, sophisticated analytical methods and in-situ inapplicability pose a major challenge to the rapid detection and mapping of the extent of the soil contamination. This research describes a sensor based approach for measuring potential (substrate-induced) microbial respiration in PHC-contaminated and non-contaminated soil and hence, indirectly evaluates their microbial activity. A simple CO2 sensing system was developed using an inexpensive non-dispersive infrared (NDIR) CO2 sensor and was successfully deployed to differentiate between the control and diesel-contaminated soils in terms of CO2 emission after glucose addition. Glucose was used as a substrate at an optimal concentration of 25 mg g-1, dissolved in deionized water to adjust the soil moisture to 80% of water holding capacity (WHC) and sprayed over 20 g soil samples to trigger microbial respiration and hence, CO2 emission. The sensor was able to distinguish glucose-induced CO2 emission from sterile and control soil samples (p ≤ 0.0001). Acetone was used as an organic solvent to spike soil samples with phenanthrene and was found to suppress CO2 emission from phenanthrene-contaminated soil samples after incubation. Significant effects of diesel contamination (p ≤ 0.0001) and soil type (p ≤ 0.0001) on glucose-induced CO2 emission were found. The sensing system can provide in-situ evaluation of soil microbial activity, an indicator of soil quality and is a promising tool for the initial screening of contaminated environmental sites and for creating high spatial density maps at a relatively low cost. </description><description>La pollution du sol causée par des déversements d’hydrocarbures pétroliers (PHC) anthropiques est devenue une menace environnementale majeure. Les indicateurs éco-toxicologiques, utilisés pour évaluer la qualité des sols, complémentent les critères physico-chimiques utilisés lors de l’assainissement de sites contaminés. Par contre, les coûts, les délais, les méthodes analytiques sophistiquées et l’inapplicabilité in-situ présentent des défis majeurs pour la détection rapide et la cartographie de l’étendue de la contamination du sol. Cette recherche présente une approche basée sur des capteurs servant à mesurer le potentiel de respiration microbienne (induite par un substrat) pour des sols contaminés et non contaminées aux HCP, et par conséquent à évaluer indirectement leur activité microbienne. Un système simple de détection du CO2 a été développé en utilisant un capteur de CO2 infrarouge non dispersif (NDIR) peu coûteux et est parvenu à différencier les sols contaminés au diesel de ceux de références en matière d’émissions de CO2 après l’ajout de glucose. Ce dernier a été utilisé comme substrat à une concentration optimale de 25 mg g-1, dissous dans l’eau déminéralisée, pour ajuster l’humidité du sol à 80% de sa capacité de rétention de l’eau (WHC), et pulvérisé sur des échantillons de 20 g de sol pour déclencher la respiration bactérienne et donc les émissions de CO2. Le capteur a pu distinguer les émissions de CO2 induites par le glucose de celles des échantillons de sol stérile et de référence (p ≤ 0.0001). De l’acétone a été utilisée comme solvant organique pour charger de phénanthrène les échantillons de sol et s’est avérée éliminer les émissions de CO2 de ces échantillons de sol contaminés aux phénanthrènes après l’incubation. La contamination au diesel (p ≤ 0.0001) et le type de sol (p ≤ 0.0001) ont démontré avoir des effets significatifs sur les émissions de CO2 induites par le glucose. Le système de détection peut fournir une évaluation in-situ de l’activité microbienne du sol, un indicateur de sa qualité, et est un outil prometteur pour effectuer l’examen préliminaire de sites environnementaux contaminés et pour créer des cartes à haute densité spatiale à des coûts relativement bas.</description><creator>Kaur, Jasmeen</creator><contributor>Viacheslav Adamchuk (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Agriculture - Soil Science</subject><title>Development of a non-dispersive infrared carbon dioxide sensor-based system for assessing soil toxicity using substrate-induced respiration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qm79n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365812s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tc23x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Public health issues of the 21st century continue to grow, change and increase in complexity as they affect western populations. With this change and growth, we have come to realize that patient and health education as a fundamental right, and is a direct contributing factor to the betterment of society's health overall. While most would agree that patient and health education already exists, further study shows a lack of governing mandate that holds healthcare professionals and institutions accountable for the administration of said education and information. Furthermore, this lack of accountability often times denies individuals a 'right' to patient education, does not allow the patient to become fully knowledgeable or aware of their diagnosis and prognosis, which in turn makes them bystanders of their health and healthcare rather than active participants. This philosophical examination takes a deeper look at the status quo and current state of patient education in the West. It also offers analysis on what is currently being done across western countries, and offers new and practical approaches to bettering the creation, delivery, follow through and follow-up of patient and health education materials and outreach.</description><description>Les problèmes de santé publique continuent de croître au 21e siècle, changeant et gagnant en complexité à mesure qu'ils affectent les populations occidentales. Du fait de ces mutations et développements, nous sommes venus a considérer le patient et son éducation à la santé comme un droit fondamental, comme un facteur contribuant directement à l'amélioration générale du système de santé. Alors qu'il serait généralement accepté que la considération des patients et leur éducation à la santé existent déjà, des plus poussées montrent un manque de détermination politique à faire appliquer ces mesures par les professionnels de la santé et les institutions responsables de la transmission de cette éducation et de ces informations. En outre, ce manque de responsabilité prive souvent les individus d'un « droit » à l'éducation, en ne leur permettant pas d'accéder à l'ensemble des connaissances pour comprendre leurs diagnostiques et prognostiques, les transformant en observateurs de leurs soins plutôt que d'en être des participants actifs. Cette analyse philosophique examine le statut quo et l'état courrant de l'éducation des patient en occident. Elle offre également un exposé sur ce qui est pratiqué dans plusieurs états occidentaux et présente de nouvelles approches pratiques pour améliorer la réalisation, transmission et visibilité des matériaux éducatifs, ainsi que le suivi des patents dans leurs éducation à la santé.</description><creator>Fora, Abraham</creator><contributor>Kevin Michael McDonough (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Education - Philosophy of</subject><title>The right to patient education: a philosophical examination of the right to education in healthcare</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117r95p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc23x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wn27r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La disparition forcée constitue une violation complexe de droits de l'homme et un crime international sérieux. Ce phénomène, synonyme de violence et souvent d’impunité, a des répercussions envahissantes dans la société. Il génère également une attitude de peur et de méfiance à l’égard des institutions, tant aux points de vues individuel que collectif. Cette thèse propose d'étudier la tragédie humaine de la disparition forcée à partir d'une variété de perspectives, afin d'aborder le spectre des conséquences qui en découlent.  Octroyer une réparation appropriée aux victimes est une tâche difficile et problématique vu la difficulté de quantifier les dommages causés. Cette étude offrira une analyse comparative de la jurisprudence de la Cour Européenne et de la Cour Interaméricaine des Droits de l’Homme, deux cours chargées de la protection des droits humains dans deux différentes régions touchées par le fléau des disparitions forcées. L'originalité et le pivot de cette thèse résident dans le dialogue qu'elle établit entre les différentes disciplines. L’objectif est d'évaluer les multiples dimensions humaines affectées par cette violation et qui méritent une réparation appropriée et efficace. La pratique des disparitions forcées frappe et détruit l'identité et la dignité d'une personne, de même que ses cadres familial et social. Pour cette raison, des réponses globales et holistiques sont nécessaires et impératives.</description><description>Enforced disappearance is a multiple and complex human rights violation and a serious international crime. This phenomenon has pervasive implications on individuals and society as a whole, leaving behind a legacy of violence, fear, impunity and overall distrust in the institution of law. The purpose of this thesis is to investigate the human tragedy of enforced disappearance from a range of perspectives in order to address the variety of complications arising from this phenomenon. One such challenge is the provision of redress to victims, a problematic task for international human rights courts. This study will offer a comparative analysis of the remedial jurisprudence of the most prominent regional courts entrusted with the protection of human rights in two different regions affected by the prevalence of enforced disappearance. The originality and core contribution of this thesis lies in the dialogue it establishes between different disciplines in order to gauge the distinct human dimensions affected by this violation, which in turn merit their own appropriate redress.  The practice of enforced disappearance strikes at the very identity and dignity of a person, their family and their social infrastructure, and therefore requires a comprehensive and holistic response.</description><creator>Raimondo, Giulia</creator><contributor>Evan Fox-Decent (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Redress for victims of enforced disappearances: a comparative perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042w93r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wn27r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246v82c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pour la planification de l’extraction d’une mine à ciel ouvert, le gisement est discrétisé en blocs d’extraction dont la taille est définie par la capacité et la sélectivité des équipements utilisés. Les blocs sont extraits du gisement à différentes périodes et sont envoyés vers divers destinations, pour être traités, stockés ou jetés. La planification de la production minière à long terme avec multiples destinations est utilisée dans l’industrie minière pour fournir les lignes directrices reliées aux décisions lors du processus d’extraction de la mine, ainsi qu’aux décisions reliées à la politique de destination pour chaque bloc. La politique de destination a pour but d’optimiser la destination où le minerai est transporté une fois extrait, afin de maximiser les flux de trésorerie actualisés selon les capacités du système. La planification de la production minière à long terme, sous incertitude, inclut la présence de l’incertitude reliée à la teneur en minerai des matériaux durant le processus d’optimisation, par la maximisation de la valeur actuelle nette, tout en minimisant les déviations de production associées aux différentes destinations. Pour des gisements contenant un grand nombre de blocs, les modèles de programmation mathématiques associés aux problèmes d’optimisation sont souvent très larges et peuvent ne pas être résolubles en un temps raisonnable, en utilisant des méthodes exactes. Dans ce mémoire, des formulations stochastiques en nombre entiers sont utilisées pour intégrer l’incertitude directement dans la modélisation de la planification de la production minière et des algorithmes de type métaheuristiques parallèles sont utilisés comme approches pour générer des solutions proches de l’optimalité en un temps raisonnable. Deux approches différentes sont présentées  pour la politique de destination, la première basée sur la teneur en minerai et la seconde, basée sur la valeur économique de chaque bloc. La première approche utilise une destination fixe qui est définie par la destination qui maximise le revenu pour chaque bloc avant l’optimisation, tandis que la seconde considère l’optimisation simultanée de la politique de destination durant le processus d’optimisation de la séquence de la planification minière.La première partie de ce mémoire présente trois implémentations d’algorithmes de recherches taboues parallèles différentes, afin de résoudre une formulation stochastique en nombre entiers de la planification minière sous incertitude avec multiples destinations basée sur une destination préétablie pour chaque bloc, en produisant une solution qui est proche de l’optimum en un temps pratique. Les deux premières méthodes permettre une recherche étendue de l’espace des solutions. La première méthode utilise plusieurs recherches tabou indépendantes en parallèle, tandis que la seconde utilise aussi plusieurs recherches tabou en parallèle mais permet la communication d’informations entre les différentes recherches. La troisième méthode intensifie la recherche locale autour de régions prometteuses en explorant divers régions locales simultanées, en partant de la même solution de départ. Une application des méthodes à un gisement d’environ 70 000 blocs est présentée afin d’évaluer la capacité des méthodes à générer des calendriers d’extraction avec des déviations minimisées, dans un temps raisonnable.En seconde partie, un modèle mathématique stochastique en nombre entier qui maximise simultanément la destination et la période d’extraction de chaque bloc est formulé. Avec cette formulation, un algorithme parallèle de recherche tabou avec multiples voisinages est présenté pour générer une solution qui est proche de l’optimum. Une étude de cas utilisant un gisement d’environ 100 000 blocs est présentée afin de montrer en pratique la capacité de la méthode à générer un calendrier de production où les cibles de production sont réalisées, et la valeur actuelle nette est maximisée, en un temps pratique. </description><description>In open pit mine planning, the mine deposit is discretized into mining blocks, where the size of these mining blocks is defined by the mine’s extracting equipment capacity and selectivity. Mining blocks are removed from the ground at different periods and sent to various destinations to be processed, stockpiled or dumped. Long-term production scheduling with multiple destinations is used in the mining industry, to provide guidelines for this extraction process, deciding the mining period and the destination policy that should apply for each mining block. The destination policy aims to optimize where to send the extracted material, in order to maximize the discounted cash flow according to the system capacity. Stochastic long-term production scheduling with multiple destinations includes the uncertainty associated with the grade’s material in the optimization process, by maximizing the net present value, while reducing the risk of not meeting the different production targets at each destination. For deposits represented by a large number of mining blocks, the optimization leads to very complex and large mathematical programs, this cannot be solved to optimality using exact methods such as Branch and Bound. In this thesis, stochastic integer programming formulations are used to integrate the uncertainty directly into the optimization of the long-term production scheduling problem, and Parallel Tabu Search metaheuristics are presented as an approach to provide nearby optimal solution, in a reasonable amount of time. Two different approaches are presented here for the destination policy during the optimization process, based on the economic value of each block. The first approach uses a fixed destination policy, which sends each block to its more profitable destination before the optimization, whereas the second one considers optimizing the policy simultaneously within the optimization process of a life-of-mine schedule.The first part of this thesis, Chapter 3, presents three different implementations of parallel Tabu Search metaheuristics to solve a previously existing stochastic integer program, designed to provide optimal solution for the life-of-mine production schedule with multiples destinations, under geological uncertainty and under a fix destination policy. The first two methods allow a more extensive search of the solution space, the first using several independent Tabu Searches, whereas the second allows communication between the different Tabu Searches to broadcast information. The third method aims to provide a more intensive search by exploring different local area simultaneously, starting from a single solution. An application to a deposit of about 70,000 mining blocks is shown to assess the ability of all methods to generate a schedule with minimized deviations in practical amount of time.In the second part, Chapter 4, a stochastic integer program that jointly optimizes the destination and the year of extraction for each mining block is presented. A parallel multi-neighbourhood Tabu Search implementation is used to approximate the optimal solution of this formulation. The approach considers optimizing simultaneously both the destination and the period of extraction of each mining block by defining different types of neighbour solutions to explore. The computational complexity added by considering simultaneously extraction and destination variables is reduced by the use of a load balancing strategy to distribute the work equally among the different processors. An application at a deposit of about 100,000 mining blocks is made to show the ability of the method to generate a schedule where the production targets are met and the NPV is maximized in a practical amount of time.</description><creator>Senecal, Renaud</creator><contributor>Roussos G Dimitrakopoulos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Engineering - Mining</subject><title>Applications of tabu search parallel metaheuristic for stochastic long-term production scheduling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473037x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246v82c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82kb245</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Montreal is home to three music education programs inspired by the internationally renownedVenezuelan program known as El Sistema. The Garage à musique (est. 2009) is part of theFondation Dr Julien, and features classical and popular music as part of their work in socialpediatrics in the Hochelaga-Maisonneuve borough. Share the Warmth is a communityorganization in Pointe-Saint-Charles that started out collecting food and clothes for those in need(1989), expanding to include youth programming and music lessons (2007) and a “SistemaIntensive Music Program” (2012). Finally, Viva! Sistema serves both Pointe-Saint-Charles andthe Kahnawà:ke reserve with a string orchestra program. In this study, I address two majorquestions. First, how does media coverage of these programs reflect their aims as well as publicunderstanding of El Sistema and Sistema-inspired programming? Second, why were these siteschosen for Sistema programs, and what does that imply about the role of Western classical musicin these communities, as perceived by music educators and the general public?For my study I analyze newspaper articles from the four major Montreal Newspapers in bothFrench (Le Devoir, La Presse, Le Journal de Montréal) and English (The Montreal Gazette) aswell as music industry publication La Scena Musicale, all from January 2011 to August 2014.Through this I gauge public perception of the programs, supplementing this analysis withprimary sources such as program brochures and websites. I explore the themes that arise fromthis analysis, including issues of language (particularly important in Quebec), immigration,indigeneity, race, culture, and class as they operate in Montreal, engaging theoretical workincluding Simpson (2014), Haque (2012), Chan (2010), Thobani (2007), Razack (2007) andFreire (1970). I also draw on music education literature such as Bowman (2005) and Campbell(2004). The North American scholarly literature discussing El Sistema programs is growingrapidly, including books by Tunstall (2012) and Baker (2014) as well as several studies anddissertations, for example Mauskapf (2012), Shoemaker (2012), Silberman (2013); Rossi (2011);Cline (2012). By investigating Montreal media coverage of Sistema-inspired programming, Iwill supplement the existing literature regarding various North American projects. Theconnections I will make between social issues and Sistema-inspired music education make itpossible to apply this research well beyond the boundaries of the communities in this study.</description><description>Montréal compte trois programmes d’éducation musicale inspirées par le programmevénézuélien de renommée mondiale connu sous le nom d’El Sistema. Le Garage à musique (est.2009) fait partie de la Fondation du Dr. Julien, et figure les musiques classique et populaire dansle cadre de leurs projets de «pédiatrie sociale» dans l’arrondissement Hochelaga-Maisonneuve.Partageons l’espoir est un organisme communautaire à Pointe-Saint-Charles qui a vu ses débutsdans la collecte de vêtements et de nourriture pour les sans-abris (1989), s’agrandissant pourinclure des divers programmes destinés aux jeunes et des leçons de musique (2007) et enfin unprogramme de musique intensif inspiré du El Sistema (2012). Enfin, Viva! Sistema sertl’arrondissement de Pointe-Saint-Charles ainsi que la réserve Kahnawà:ke avec son programmed’orchestre à cordes. Dans cette étude, j’adresserai deux questions majeures. Premièrement,comment la couverture médiatique de ces programmes reflète-t-elle les buts et la compréhensionpar le public de la programmation El Sistema? Deuxièmement, pourquoi ces sites furent-ilschoisis, et qu’est-ce que cela peut impliquer en ce qui concerne le rôle de la musique classiquetraditionnelle dans ces communautés, telle qu’elle est perçue par les éducateurs en musique etpar le public en général?Dans le cadre de mon étude, j’analyserai des articles provenant des quatre journaux importantsmontréalais, dont trois francophones (Le Devoir, La Presse, et Le Journal de Montréal) et unanglophone (The Montreal Gazette) ainsi que le magazine de l’industrie de la musique La ScenaMusicale, tous datant de janvier 2011 à août 2014. Au travers, j’évaluerai la perception desprogrammes au sein de la population, complétant cette analyse avec des sources primaires tellesque les brochures et les sites web de ces programmes. J’explorerai les thèmes émanant de cetteanalyse, y inclus les questions de langue (particulièrement important au Québec), d’immigration,d’appartenance autochtone, de race, de culture et de classe telles qu’elles évoluent à Montréal,engageant les travaux théoriques de Simpson (2014), Haque (2012), Chan (2010), Thobani(2007), Razack (2007) et Freire (1970). Je ferai également appel à la littérature surl’enseignement de la musique telles que celles de Bowman (2005) et de Campbell (2004). Lalittérature savante s’intéressant aux programmes El Sistema s’accroît rapidement dansl’Amérique du Nord, et comprends les livres par Tunstall (2012) et Baker (2014) ainsi queplusieurs études et dissertations, comme par exemple celles de Mauskapft (2012), Shoemaker(2012), Silberman (2013), Rossi (2011), et Cline (2012). Ce projet augmentera cette littérature enadressant divers projets dans l’Amérique du Nord, et en enquêtant la couverture médiatique d’ElSistema et de la musique classique dans la société. Les connections que je ferai entre les enjeuxsociaux et l’éducation musicale inspirée par El Sistema rendront possible l’application de marecherche au-delà des frontières des communautés évoquées dans cette étude.</description><creator>Hopkins, Emily</creator><contributor>Roe-Min Kok (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Sistema in the news: exploring media coverage of Sistema-inspired programs in Montreal and Kahnawà:ke</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q003s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kb245</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fp70w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le trafic Internet sans cesse croissant, stimulé par l'expansion en continu des services infonuagiques offerts par les centres informatiques, ainsi que la demande croissante en matière de bande passante favorisée par les applications et les services médias basés sur le Web, ont accru le besoin en solutions optiques de courte portée, plus rapides et peu coûteuses. Avec la commercialisation et le déploiement de technologies à 100 Go/s et le développement de systèmes à 400 Go/s, il existe un besoin évident en éléments constitutifs à faible consommation énergétique et à coût abordable. Actuellement, la transmission à 100 Go/s des trames Ethernet par fibre optique monomode est réalisée au moyen d'un système multiplexage par répartition en longueur d'onde à quatre couleurs dans un format 4 × 25 Go/s. Il est cependant largement admis que les systèmes à 400 Go/s seront réalisés à l’aide d’une configuration 4 ×  100 Go/s, ce qui nécessite l’opération   à 100 Go/s sur une longueur d'onde unique. Pour atteindre une transmission de données à débit supérieur, des formats de modulation optiques avancés, de concert avec à la fois multiplexage en polarisation et multiplexage par division des longueurs d'onde sont nécessaires. La modulation d'impulsions en amplitude (pulse amplitude modulation, PAM) permet une plus grande efficacité spectrale par le biais de l'utilisation d'amplitudes multiniveaux. L'utilisation d'un format de modulation PAM-4 double l'efficacité spectrale de la liaison optique. La génération de PAM a récemment pu être prouvée à l’aide de modulateurs d'intensité SiP. Dans cette thèse, je présente un modulateur à ondes progressives Mach-Zehnder (TW-MZM) de type push-pull en silicium, de 4,2 mm de longueur et à bande passante de 35 GHz. Le modulateur est basé sur une jonction PN latérale utilisant des longueurs d'onde de près de 1550 nm. Un débit binaire de 112 Go/s est obtenu à l’aide de modulation PAM-4 à 56 Gbaud après 2 km de fibre optique monomode (SMF), en dessous du seuil de décision ferme Pré-FEC de 3,8 x 10-3, pour fournir un taux d'erreur binaire final inférieur à 10-15. Au moment de la rédaction de cette thèse, ce modulateur surpasse la bande passante la plus élevée rapportée pour un modulateur SiP de 5 GHz. </description><description>The ever increasing internet traffic driven by the constant spread of cloud services offered by data centers and the increasing demand for higher bandwidth driven by web-based media applications and services have increased the need for faster and inexpensive short reach optic solutions. With the commercialization and deployment of 100 Gb/s technologies, and the development of 400 Gb/s systems, there is a clear need for inexpensive and power efficient building blocks. Currently 100 Gb/s transmission of Ethernet frames over single mode fiber (SMF) is realized using a four color wavelength division multiplexing (WDM) setting in a 4 × 25 Gb/s format. However, it is widely agreed that the 400 Gb/s systems will be realized using 4 × 100 Gb/s configuration, which necessitates the need for a single wavelength operation at 100 Gb/s. To achieve higher data rate transmission, advance optical modulation formats together with polarization and wavelength division multiplexing are required. Pulse amplitude modulation (PAM) enables higher spectral efficiency by using multi-level amplitudes. Using PAM-4 modulation format doubles the spectral efficiency of the optical link. Recently PAM generation has been demonstrated using Silicon Photonics (SiP) intensity modulators. In this thesis, we present a 4.2 mm long, 35 GHz bandwidth single drive series push pull silicon travelling wave Mach-Zehnder modulator (TW-MZM) based on lateral PN junction operating near 1550 nm wavelength.  A bit-rate of 112 Gb/s is achieved using PAM-4 modulation scheme at 56 Gbaud after 2 km of single mode fiber (SMF) below the hard decision pre forward error correction (Pre-FEC) threshold of 3.8 × 10-3 to provide a final bit error rate under 10-15. To the best of our knowledge this modulator surpasses the highest bandwidth reported for a SiP modulator by 5 GHz. </description><creator>Samani, Alireza</creator><contributor>David V Plant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Design and characterization of 35 GHz silicon photonic travelling wave modulator for next generation short reach communication links</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w5283.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fp70w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pw73z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Augmenter la résistance des dents d'engrenages est une éxigeance récurrente dans les industries. Dans cette thèse, une nouvelle approche à la conception de la racine des profils de dents des engrenages planaires et coniques, en utilisant des courbes spline cubiques non-paramétriques, afin d'augmenter la résistance des engrenages, est proposée. Des engrenages coniques, générés en utilisant l'approximation de Tredgold ou le profil à développante sphérique exacte, ont été étudiés. La forme du profil de la racine de la dent est assouplie de telle sorte à ajouter une continuité de classe G2, ainsi réduisant la concentration des contraintes aux points critiques. Une procédure itérative de co-simulation consistant en la synthèse de la racine des profils de dents, par programmation non-linéaire et analyse par éléments finis,  fut mise en place. Les conceptions ainsi proposées permirent de réduire la concentration des contraintes de 20% pour les engrenages planaires, ainsi que, respectivement, 15.9% et 19.3% dans le cas de l'utilisation de l'approximation de Tredgold et dans le cas du profil à développante sphérique exacte, pour des engrenages coniques.</description><description>Increasing the strength of the gear tooth is a recurrent demand from industry. In this thesis a novel approach to the design of the tooth-root profile of spur and bevel gears using non-parametric cubic splines, with the aim of increasing the gear strength, is introduced. Bevel gears generated using the Tredgold approximation and the exact spherical involute were considered. The shape of the root profile was smoothed so as to endow it with G2-continuity, thereby reducing the stress concentration at the critical blending points. An iterative co-simulation procedure consisting of tooth-root profile shape synthesis via non-linear programming and finite element analysis was conducted. The proposed designs are capable of reducing the stress concentration by 20.0% in spur gears, 15.9% and 19.3% in the Tredgold approximation and the exact spherical involute bevel gears, respectively.</description><creator>Shaker, Mathew</creator><contributor>Jorge Angeles (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Optimization of tooth-root profile for maximum load-carrying capacity: spur and bevel gears</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz483.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pw73z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z381b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il y a divers sortes de fibres de bois et de nombreuses applications peuvent être proposées pour ce matériel. Pendant la procédé de mise en pâte, la morphologie des fibres de bois est altérée. Après la mise en pâte et l'assèchement, les gouttelettes d'eau peuvent ou bien adsorbées sur les parties amorphes des parois cellulaires ou bien absorbées dans les cavités. Dans le premier cas où les gouttelettes d'eau sont adsorbées, l'assèchement des parois cause le rétrécissement du lumen ce qui affecte la structure submicroscopique. Dans le deuxième cas où l'eau est absorbée dans les cavités, un effondrement se produit et altère la forme cellulaire. Une meilleure connaissance du phénomène est essentielle quant à la commercialisation et le développement puisque ce domaine de la science est encore mal compris. À un taux d'humidité plus élevé que le point de saturation d'un fibre (PSF), l'eau s'évapore des larges pores au lieu que de rester sur la surface céllulosique. À un taux d'humidité inférieur au PSF, les molécules d'eau sont immobilisées dans les pores nanoscopiques et ceux-ci interagissent directement avec les groupes hydroxyles. Le rétrécissement est causé par la contraction non-uniforme des couches dans la paroi cellulaire et provoque un changement dans les propriétés mécaniques, l'épaisseur de la paroi et la nature du lumen pendant que l'eau s'évapore. L'effondrement se produit par l'énergie élastique de la paroi et la tension superficielle. Ces facteurs causent le rapprochement des parois lorsque la diminution du volume d'eau initie le rétrécissement des fibres. Dans cette thèse, le modèle de l'élasto-capillarité est développé afin d'étudier la déformation causée par l'assèchement lorsque le taux d'humidité est supérieur au PSF et lorsque les conditions favorisent l'effondrement. Le modèle en question est une membrane élastique et circulaire en forme de tube. Celui-ci interagit avec des ménisques simples (bulles) ou doubles (ponts) à une interface entre l'air et l'eau. La conformation à l'état sec est déterminée par la stabilité des branches d'équilibre à un volume de liquide fixe à partir d'un état complètement saturé jusqu'à l'état effondré. La stabilité des ponts liquides avec la ligne de contact est déterminée avec une perturbation aléatoire. Les régions de volume et de pression constantes sont construites dans le diagramme indiquant la relation entre le volume cylindrique et l'élancement. Si on compare ces régions avec les ponts liquides pris entre deux disques, les symétries équatoriales et réflectives sont brisées par la ligne de contact. Ce  phénomène change les caractéristiques de la bifurcation à la limite inférieure. Les bifurcations en forme de fourche deviennent des embranchements et les perturbations graves n'ont aucune symétrie. Les prédictions théoriques à propos de la limite de stabilité sont expérimentalement vérifiées sous flottabilité nulle. De plus, l'effet déstabilisant des lignes de contact a été théoriquement et expérimentalement démontré. En utilisant des méthodes spectrales et variantes, la stabilité du modèle élasto-capillaire est associée à la forme des branches d'équilibres. Cette stabilité démontre le principe de l'échange de stabilité dans la théorie des catastrophes. Un chiffre élasto-capillaire est établi; ceci quantifie la rigidité de la membrane axiale par rapport à la tension superficielle. Les limites supérieures du chiffre élasto-capillaire sont liées au rayon et à l'angle de contact. Ces limites donnent une fourchette de valeurs pour les paramètres géométriques et mécaniques où la forme à l'état sec est ouverte. Les caractéristiques dimensionnelles des épinettes norvégiennes ont été utilisées pour cette œuvre. L'effondrement capillaire sur une échelle de longueur de diamètre d'un lumen de fibre ne contribue pas intégralement au rétrécissement volumétrique.</description><description>Wood fibres are diverse in application and abundant in species. They are isolated from parent wood by pulping, where their morphological features appreciably change. Upon drying, adsorbed water is removed from amorphous parts of the cell wall, whereas absorbed water evaporates from wood cavities (e.g., cell lumen and micropores). The former results in shrinkage, affecting the submicroscopic structure, and the latter causes collapse, affecting the cell shape. A comprehensive understanding of wood-fibre interaction with water is crucial to product development and is lacking in the literature. Water evaporates from large pores where it is held in wood tissues by capillary forces at moisture contents above the fibre saturation point (FSP). However, below the FSP, water is trapped in nanometer-sized pores where water molecules are directly bound to the hydroxyl groups. Shrinkage is caused by non-uniform contractions of the cell-wall layers, altering the effective mechanical properties, wall thickness, and lumen conformation as moisture content decreases. Collapse occurs through the coupling of the wall-elastic and water-surface-tension energies, bringing the walls into close contact as the air-water interface recedes into cavities. The overall volumetric shrinkage can be obtained by superimposing collapse and shrinkage deformations. In this thesis, an elastocapillary model is developed to study drying deformations in wood fibres above the FSP in the collapse regime. The model comprises a circular elastic membrane with a hole at the center, interacting with simply connected (bubble) and doubly connected (bridge) menisci at the air-water interface. The dry-state conformation is determined from the stability of equilibrium branches at fixed liquid volume from the fully-saturated to collapse states. First, the stability of liquid bridges with a free contact line is determined with respect to arbitrary perturbations. Constant-volume and constant-pressure stability regions are constructed in the cylindrical volume versus slenderness diagram. Compared with liquid bridges pinned at two equal discs, equatorial and reflective symmetries are broken by the free contact line, altering the characteristics of bifurcations along the lower boundary. Here, pitchfork bifurcations unfold into turning points, and critical perturbations have no symmetry. Theoretical predictions of the stability limits are experimentally verified under neutral buoyancy. Moreover, the destabilizing effect of free contact lines is theoretically and experimentally demonstrated. Next, using spectral and variational methods, the stability of the elastocapillary model is rigorously related to the shape of equilibrium branches, supporting the principle of stability exchange in the catastrophe theory. An elastocapillary number is introduced, measuring the membrane axial rigidity relative to the water surface tension. Upper bounds on the critical elastocapillary number are determined as functions of the scaled hole radius and contact angle, providing ranges of geometrical and mechanical parameters in which the dry-state conformation is open. Estimating the model characteristic length scales from the structural features of Norway spruce fibres, it is shown that capillary-induced collapse over the length scales of pit-holes and the cell lumen is unlikely to contribute to the overall volumetric shrinkage.</description><creator>Akbari, Amir</creator><contributor>Reghan James Hill (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Theodorus G Van de Ven (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Wood-fibre collapse upon drying</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk19f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z381b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397c243</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’agriculture de précision utilise les technologies de l’information pour améliorer les aspects économiques, environnementaux et sociaux de l’agriculture moderne. Parmi différentes innovations, la capacité de prendre en considération la variabilité spatiale des conditions de croissances des cultures a été particulièrement ambitieuse. La principale contrainte à l’adoption massive de ces technologies a été le manque de données économiquement viables révélant l’hétérogénéité des propriétés du sol et se rapportant aux besoins locaux de fertilisants.Des équipements et méthodes avancés servant à l’obtention de mesures de haute densité des propriétés physiques et chimiques du sol à des coûts relativement bas sont essentiels pour augmenter l’utilisation de la technologie. Pour améliorer la qualité des données requises par les algorithmes de prise de décision, une plateforme de détection automatisée, semblable aux robots déployés sur Mars, doit être développée pour mesurer le sol in situ. Le projet se concentre sur ce défi. La thèse a abordé trois aspects clés du développement de la technologie : 1) la conception d’un analyseur de sol sur place automatisé, 2) l’évaluation du potentiel de déploiement de différents systèmes de capteurs hyper-spectraux et 3) le développement d’un algorithme pour regrouper des données spatiales multicouches de haute densités pour maximiser la valeur des mesures par points recommandées.Un nouvel analyser sur place (OSA) a été développé pour effectuer des mesures souterraines des propriétés chimiques du sol en utilisant un ensemble d’électrodes sélectives. Ces électrodes peuvent simultanément déterminer de manière automatisée l’acidité et nitrate. Le système peut aisément être élargi à d’autres capteurs, comme des capteurs hyper-spectraux actifs. Un ensemble d’instruments de terrain prêts-à-déployer pour des mesures de réflectance du sol hyperspectrales a été testé en termes de répétabilité (précision) et de prévisibilité (exactitude) des mesures. Ces capteurs ont été évalués en termes de leur capacité à prédire la distribution de la taille des particules de sol, le carbone du sol, la matière organique et le contenu en phosphore extrait. Cette recherche était centrée sur des instruments fonctionnant dans le visible, l’infrarouge proche et l’infrarouge moyen du spectre électromagnétique. Finalement, un nouvel algorithme a été développé pour utiliser des données traditionnelles de détection du sol à proximité, comme la conductivité électrique apparente du sol (ECa) et l’élévation des champs. Des tests préliminaires ont été effectué pour six terrains de production. Les résultats ont confirmé la robustesse de l’algorithme lors de la délimitation des zones de terrain avec différentes élévations et mesures ECa. Cet algorithme a le potentiel d’optimiser la valeur des mesures par points en utilisant l’OSA, d’autres systèmes de capteurs in situ, ou l’échantillonnage du sol.Six activités individuelles de recherche ont résulté en six différents manuscrits qui constituent le corps de cette thèse.</description><description>Precision agriculture uses information technologies to improve the economic, environmental and social aspects of modern farming. Among other innovations, the ability to account for spatial variability in the crop growing environment has been the most challenging. The main limitation to the widespread adoption of these technologies has been the lack of economically feasible spatial data to reveal the heterogeneity of soil properties related to local fertilization needs. To increase the implementation of this technology, advanced equipment and methods to obtain high density measurements of the physical and chemical properties of soil at a relatively low cost are essential. The quality of data needed by decision-making algorithms must be improved; this needs the development of, an automated sensing platform for in situ soil measurements, similar to the rovers deployed on Mars. The project focuses on this challenge. The thesis addressed three key aspects of the development of the technology: 1) design of an automated on the-spot soil analyser, 2) evaluation of the potential for deploying different hyperspectral sensor systems, and 3) development of an algorithm to cluster multilayer high density spatial data to maximize the value of prescribed point-based measurements. A new automated, on-the-spot soil analyser (OSA) was developed to perform subsurface measurements of soil chemical properties. It used an array of ion-selective electrodes and could simultaneously determine pH and nitrate, on-the-spot, in an automated manner. The system can be easily extended to use other sensors, such as active, hyperspectral sensors. A set of field deployment-ready instruments for active hyperspectral measurements of soil reflectance were tested in terms of both their reproducibility (precision) and predictability (accuracy) of the measurements and evaluated in terms of their ability to predict soil particle size distribution, soil carbon, soil organic matter, and total soil phosphorous content. This research focused on instruments operating in the visible, near-infrared and mid-infrared parts of the electromagnetic spectrum. Finally, a new algorithm was developed to process traditional high-density proximal soil sensing data, such as apparent soil electrical conductivity (ECa) and field elevation. Preliminary tests of the algorithm using six production fields illustrated the algorithm’s robustness when delineating field areas with different field elevations and ECa measurements. This algorithm has the potential to optimize the number of point-based measurements with OSA, other in situ sensing systems, or conventional soil sampling. Six individual research activities resulted in six different manuscripts that constitute the main body of this thesis. </description><creator>Dhawale, Nandkishor</creator><contributor>Viacheslav Adamchuk (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Shiv Prasher (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Agriculture - General</subject><title>Advances in proximal soil sensing through integrated systems approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064890k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c243</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qg17c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il n'est pas bien compris quel type d'anévrisme de l'aorte ascendant entraîne les complications. La biomécanique pourrait nous offrir des données pour prédire les risque; et de ne pas se fier seulement sur la grandeur de l'anévrisme. La perte d’énergie mécanique représente la quantité relative de l’énergie absorbée par l’aorte au cours du cycle cardiaque. Nous avons ainsi cherché à en étudier la corrélation avec l’anévrisme de l’aorte ascendante et l’histopathologie, afin de déterminer la pathophysiologie des complications liées à cette dilatation artérielle.Les échantillons sont obtenus suite à des opérations chirurgicales sur des patients et les témoins proviennent d’autopsies ou de dons d’organes. Des essais de traction biaxiale sont réalisés au niveau des quatre quadrants de l’anneau aortique, permettant ainsi de calculer la perte d’énergie à travers l’intégrale de la courbe de contrainte-déformation, lors du chargement et déchargement de l’échantillon. Un travail de comparaison est ensuite effectué en tenant compte de la taille et de la rigidité du tissu via son module d’élasticité apparent, un élément prépondérant dans le domaine de la biomécanique. L’élastine, le collagène et la mucopolysaccharide, quant à eux, sont quantifiées par la technique de « pentachrome de Movat » sur des lames d’histologie.Quarante-et-une aortes sont analysées (trente-quatre cas d’anévrismes et sept témoins) et des augmentations de rigidité (p&lt;0.0001), ainsi que de perte d’énergie (p&lt;0.0001) sont constatées. La perte d’énergie a une corrélation significative avec le diamètre de l’aorte (p&lt;0.0001, r2=0.60). Or, lorsque ce dernier est supérieur à 5.5cm, la perte d’énergie augmente rapidement. Elle présente également une relation linéaire pour une taille de l’aorte indexée à l’air de sa surface (p&lt;0.0001, r2=0.78). Enfin, la perte d’énergie corrèle avec l’histopathologie, en particulier avec le rapport entre le collagène et l’élastine (p=0.0002, r2=0.49).Les variations de pertes d’énergie permettent de distinguer des patients aux histologies pathologiques à d’autres personnes saines pouvant présenter des diamètres de mêmes dimensions. Lors de la dilatation de l’aorte ascendante, la perte d’énergie est également plus importante pour des diamètres supérieurs à 5.5cm, démontrant ainsi la complexité du comportement de cette artère en fonction de ses dimensions. Pour finir, la perte d’énergie corrèle avec les répartitions uniformes d’élastine et de collagène, ce qui pourrait amener à une relation impliquant l’histopathologie et la biomécanique du tissu.</description><description>It is not well understood which ascending aortas will develop complications. Biomechanics may provide insights beyond the consideration of size alone, and improve risk prediction. Energy loss is a biomechanical parameter describing the relative amount of energy absorbed by the aorta during the cardiac cycle. We aim to correlate energy loss with ascending aortic aneurysm size and histopathology to elucidate the pathophysiology of aneurysm complications.Aneurysmal ascending aortic specimens were obtained during surgery. Controls were obtained from autopsy and organ donors. Biaxial tensile tests were performed on the four quadrants of the aortic ring. Energy loss was calculated using the integral of the stress-strain curve during loading and unloading. It was compared to size and the traditional biomechanical parameter, stiffness (apparent modulus of elasticity). Elastin, collagen and mucopolysaccharide content was quantified using Movat pentachrome staining of histology slides. Forty-one aortas were collected (34 aneurysmal, 7 control). Aneurysms exhibited increased stiffness (p&lt;0.0001) and energy loss (p&lt;0.0001) compared to control. Energy loss correlated significantly with aortic size (p&lt;0.0001, r2=0.60). A hinge point was noted at a diameter of 5.5cm, after which energy loss rose rapidly. The relationship between energy loss and size became strongly linear once size was indexed to body surface area (p&lt;0.0001, r2=0.78). Energy loss correlated with histopathology, especially the collagen to elastin ratio (p=0.0002, r2=0.49). High energy loss distinguished patients with pathological histology from others of similar diameters.As ascending aortas dilate, they exhibit greater energy loss, rapidly rising after 5.5cm. This mirrors the rise in complications at this size. Energy loss correlates with imbalances in elastin and collagen composition, suggesting a measurable link between histopathology and mechanical function. </description><creator>Chung, Jennifer</creator><contributor>Richard L Leask (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kevin J Lachapelle (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Energy loss, a novel biomechanical parameter, correlates with aortic aneurysm size and histopathology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085p178.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qg17c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fv52f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Avec l’avènement du séquençage à haut débit, il a été révélé que les gênes codeurs de protéines constituent seulement une minorité du génome. Généralement vu comme de l’ADN «égoïste» ou «camelote», les éléments transposables (ETs) comptent pour une large portion du génome. Les recherches effectuées sur le déchiffrage des régions non codantes sont un domaine de recherche plus récent. Il a été démontré que les ETs ont contribués à l’évolution du génome.L’activité des ETs peut être déclenchée par des facteurs de population et environnementaux dans divers organismes. Dans le cadre du projet VEGI, des dépistages de stress abiotique ont été réalisé sur un échantillon méticuleusement sélectionné de T-ADN de mutagénèse insertionnelle afin d’identifier les gènes d’éléments transposables domestiques (ETDs) avec des fonctions putatives. Dans ces dépistages, un ETD non caractérisé que nous avons nommé TOPHAT, a démontré des phénotypes dans plusieurs tests de tolérance abiotique (sel, efficacité d’utilisation de l’azote, congélation). Les lignes de surexpressions de TOPHAT ont été créées dans une plante de type sauvage afin de caractériser ce gène ETD. Dans une expérience parallèle portant sur un séquençage d’ARN, l’analyse de l’expression confirme le phénotype du stress osmotique dans la ligne du knock-out. L’analyse révèle également un groupe nombreux de gènes de défense contre les pathogènes qui s’expriment constitutivement dans la surexpression du génotype. Les protéines encodées par ces gênes jouent un rôle critique dans l’identification des pathogènes et l’activation des réponses de défense.Nous proposons que TOPHAT soit un ETD qui provoque des changements dans l’expression d’une variété de gênes à travers une co-régulation synergique avec d’autres gênes de la même famille. Parmi ces gênes, plusieurs sont associés avec des résistances et des réponses abiotiques et biotiques. TOPHAT et ses gênes SLEEPER apparentés peuvent agir collectivement pour réprimer une suite de gênes liés au stress afin de s’assurer de maintenir une expression transitoire. J’espère que mon étude caractérisant les nouveaux ETD pourra approfondir nos connaissances sur l’importance des ETDs dans l’évolution des gênes.  </description><description>With the advent of high-throughput sequencing, it has been revealed that protein-coding genes constitute only a small portion of the genome. Comprising a large segment of the genome are transposons, or transposable elements (TEs), which have been classically regarded as “selfish” or “junk” DNA. Research on deciphering the non-coding regions has been a more recent area of focus, and TEs have been shown to be a contributing factor in genome evolution.The activity of TEs can be induced by environmental and population factors in various organisms. As part of the VEGI project, abiotic stress screens were performed on a curated set of T-DNA insertional mutagenesis lines to identify domesticated transposable element (DTE) genes with putative functions. In this screen, one uncharacterized DTE, which we have named TOPHAT, showed significant phenotypes in multiple abiotic tolerance screens (salt, nitrogen use efficiency, freezing). TOPHAT overexpression lines were created in a wild-type background to further characterize this DTE gene. In a parallel RNA-sequencing experiment, expression analyses confirmed the osmotic stress phenotype in the knockout line and identified a large group of pathogen defence genes that are expressed constitutively in the overexpression genotype. Proteins encoded by these genes play critical roles in pathogen recognition and the activation of defence responses. We propose that TOPHAT is a DTE that causes changes in the expression of a host of genes through a synergistic co-regulation with other genes in its gene family. Among those are genes which are associated with abiotic and biotic resistance and response. TOPHAT and the closely related SLEEPER genes may be acting collectively to repress a suite of stress-related genes to ensure and maintain transiency of expression. We hope our study characterizing this novel DTE can further our knowledge of the importance of DTEs in genome evolution.</description><creator>Leung, Danny Ka Ming</creator><contributor>Thomas E Bureau (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Characterization of TOPHAT, a novel domesticated transposable element gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sw76j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv52f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mz540</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Genes coding for epigenetic modifying enzymes are highly mutated in hematological malignancies, suggesting that epigenetic regulation is an important factor for pathogenesis and a potential target for therapy. Overall, blood cancers have increased expression of histone deacetylases (HDACs) and genetic aberrations leading to inactivation of histone acetyltransferases. Thus, inhibitors of HDACs (HDACi) hold promise for the treatment of hematological malignancies. Nonetheless, actual clinical experiences have not met this promise and HDACi therapy remains unapproved for DLBCL and AML. Appropriate design of an optimal clinical trial with HDACi is complex, as a plethora of anti-cancer mechanisms have been suggested. These mechanisms essentially rely on HDACi’s ability to induce acetylation of numerous proteins, which are part of various targetable pathways. Fine-tuning of HDACi therapy will be obtained by a better understanding of the cellular and molecular effects of HDACi. The aim of the work presented in this thesis was to understand the molecular effects of HDACi in hematological malignancies to better target patients likely to respond and to design improved combination regimens. We developed hematological cancer cell lines resistant to induction of cell death by the HDACi vorinostat, using a AML-like histiocytic lymphoma cell line (U937).We observed that vorinostat induces resistance to some, but not all HDACi. Comparing the resistant cell lines to their parental counterparts, we found several striking differences. First, the vorinostat-resistant cell lines exhibit dramatically increased sensitivity toward chloroquine, an inhibitor of autophagy. Consistent with this, we observed various characteristics of active autophagy in both our resistant cell models growing in vorinostat U937-B8.  Inhibition of autophagy in vorinostat resistant U937 cells by knockdown of Beclin1 or Lamp-2 restores sensitivity to vorinostat. Interestingly, autophagy is also activated in parental U937 cells by de novo treatment with vorinostat. However, in contrast to the resistant cells, inhibition of autophagy decreases sensitivity to vorinostat. These data highlight the potential of designing combination strategies using modulators of autophagy and HDACi for the treatment of hematological malignancies. As well, a critical difference exists between the outcome of sequential and concurrent therapy when combining HDACi and modulators of autophagy.We subsequently extended our investigation by performing gene expression profiling in the resistant and parental cell lines. Strikingly, we found that development of HDACi resistance is associated with increased protein synthesis and proteasomal degradation which represent potential therapeutic targets. Consequently, cells resistant to HDACi have acquired increased susceptibility to proteasome inhibitors and this correlates with activation of the unfolded protein response. Importantly, using transcriptional signatures found in our resistant lymphoma cell line model, we show that tumors from DLBCL patients treated with, but unresponsive to HDACi therapy undergo similar changes. The work presented in this thesis shows that HDACi are priming agents in DLBCL and potentially in AML. Thus, we provide insights for new therapeutic options using HDACi in combination with drugs that target the processing of misfolded proteins, such as proteasome and autophagy inhibitors. This thesis highlights the importance of understanding the molecular effects of epigenetic therapy to better cure cancer.</description><description>Les gènes codant pour des enzymes épigénétiques sont fréquemment mutés dans les cancers hématologiques. Ces aberrations génétiques conduisent à l'inactivation des acétyltranferases et/ou à une augmentation de l'activité des désacétylases d’histones (HDAC) entrainant une diminution globale de l'acétylation des protéines. Conséquemment, les inhibiteurs de désacétylases (HDACis) offrent hypothétiquement un espoir dans la lutte contre les cancers hématologiques. Néanmoins, les études cliniques utilisant les HDACis n'ont pas réussi à démontrer une efficacité suffisante afin d’être approuvés dans le traitement des lymphomes diffus à grandes cellules B (DLBCL) et des leucémies myéloïdes aiguë (AML).  Étant donné la pléitropie des HDACs et leur implication dans de multiples voies de signalisation, les HDACis peuvent potentiellement agir sur plusieurs leviers du processus cancéreux. Ainsi, la planification de recherches cliniques utilisant les HDACi s'avère complexe et les résultats cliniques les plus probants seront probablement obtenus en thérapie combinatoire. Une meilleure compréhension des effets moléculaires et cellulaires des HDACi permettra d'établir des essais cliniques prometteurs.L'objectif du travail présenté dans cette thèse est de comprendre les effets moléculaires des HDACi dans les cancers hématologiques afin d'élaborer éventuellement des thérapies combinatoires plus efficaces. Dans cette optique, nous avons développé des lignées cellulaires de cancers hématologiques résistantes à la toxicité induite par le HDACi vorinostat, derivées des lignées de lymphome histiocytaire U937.Curieusement les lignées cellulaires résistantes aux HDACis présentent une sensibilité accrue à la chloroquine, un inhibiteur de l'autophagie. Ainsi, nous détectons plusieurs caracteristiques d'autophagie active dans les cellules résistantes. Nous avons aussi obervé que l'inactivation génique de Beclin1 ou lamp-2, deux gènes essentiels a l’autophagie, restaure la sensibilité au vorinostat. Fait intéressant, l'autophagie peut être induite dans les cellules parentales U937 suite à un traitement de novo au vorinostat. Cependant, contrairement à ce que l'on observe dans les cellules résistantes, l'inhibition de l'autophagie diminue la sensibilité au vorinostat. Ces données soulignent l'importance thérapeutique de cibler l'autophagie avec les HDACi dans le traitement des cancers hématologiques. Afin d'approfondir notre compréhension des effets cellulaires du vorinostat, nous avons effectué des profils d'expression génique dans le modèle cellulaire résistant et parental U937. Étonnamment, nous constatons que le développement de la résistance aux HDACi est associé à une augmentation de la synthèse des protéines et de leur dégradation par le protéasome. En conséquence, les cellules résistantes aux HDACi ont acquise une augmentation de la sensibilité aux inhibiteurs du protéasome correspondant à l'activation de la réponse protéotoxique. De plus, nous observons dans la biopsie de trois patients atteint de DLBCL des changements similaires suites à un traitement de 15 jours aux HDACi. Le travail présenté dans cette thèse démontre que les HDACi induisent la différenciation des cellules de DLBCL et, potentiellement de AML. Ainsi, notre travail suggère que les HDACi pourraient potentiellement être utilisés préalablement à certaines thérapies ciblées, comme des inhibiteurs du protéasome et des inhibiteurs de l'autophagie, afin d'augmenter leur potentiel thérapeutique.</description><creator>Dupéré-Richer, Daphné</creator><contributor>Wilson H Miller (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Resistance to histone deacetylase inhibitors in hematological malignancies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb31b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mz540</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dz30w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Il a été démontré que  le virus de l'hépatite C (VHC) est capable d’interférer avec la voie de signalisation insulinaire des hépatocytes causant un état de résistance à l'insuline ainsi qu’un stress oxydatif menant éventuellement à un état d'inflammation chronique du foie. La résistance à l'insuline, ainsi que l'état inflammatoire chronique conséquent, vont alors accélérer la progression de la fibrose hépatique. Récemment, la thérapie à l'insuline en utilisant la technique de pince normoglycémique hyperinsulinmique a été prouvée comme étant capable de potentialiser la capacité de régénération du foie et réduire l'état inflammatoire général. Par conséquent, nous émettons l’hypothèse que le traitement des patients infectés par le VHC avec l'insulinothérapie à haute dose ciblera la physiopathologie de la maladie aux niveaux cellulaires et moléculaires; ce qui pourrait éventuellement promouvoir la reprise de la fonction hépatique et potentiellement ralentir la progression de la maladie. Méthodes: Une étude interventionnelle pilote a été menée sur des patients atteints d'infection chronique par le VHC, qui ne sont pas candidats à un traitement à base d'interféron. Chaque patient a subi un minimum de quatorze semaines de séances de thérapie d’insuline de six heures de temps prévues à intervalle de deux fois par semaine. La technique hyperinsulinmique de la pince normoglycémique a été utilisée pour fournir deux milliunités d'insuline humaine régulière par kilogramme de poids corporel par minute. Les tests de la fonction hépatique, les marqueurs inflammatoires, les paramètres métaboliques, le volume du foie, et la qualité de vie reportée ont été recueillis au début, au milieu et à la fin de la période d'étude. Résultats: Tous les patients suivis par deux hépatologues ont été dépistés; treize patients qui répondaient aux critères d'inclusion et d'exclusion ont été interrogés. Trois patients ont accepté de participer à l'étude. Un patient a complété le protocole avec succès. Le patient a démontré des améliorations dans plusieurs paramètres liés à la fonction hépatique, du volume du foie et de la réponse inflammatoire sans amélioration apparente des paramètres métaboliques ou de la qualité de vie reportée. Le second patient n'a pas complété l'étude en raison d'une hospitalisation secondaire à une septicémie. Le troisième patient a été exclu avant la date de début de l'étude en raison d’une hospitalisation pour hémorragie de varices œsophagiennes. Discussion: L'application de l'insulinothérapie à haute dose chez les patients cirrhotiques est faisable et sécuritaire en milieu ambulatoire. L'insulinothérapie est une nouvelle technique qui pourrait modifier la réponse inflammatoire systémique et potentiellement favoriser la régénération du foie ainsi qu’améliorer la fonction hépatique chez les patients cirrhotiques suite à une infection chronique du VHC. Reconnaissant la limitation d'avoir un seul des patient inscrits seulement complétant l'étude, des travaux supplémentaires sont nécessaires pour confirmer les avantages et reconnaitre les désavantages potentiels de l'insulinothérapie à long terme pour les maladies du foie. Dans les projets futurs, les critères d'inclusion devraient être revus pour assurer un échantillon de taille adéquate tout en appliquant le concept dans des maladies à pathophysiologie comparable à celle d’une infection chronique de l'hépatite C.</description><description>Introduction: Hepatitis C Virus (HCV) has been shown to interfere with the hepatocytes’ insulin signaling pathway resulting in a state of insulin resistance besides causing oxidative stress leading to a state of chronic liver inflammation. Insulin resistance, along with consequent chronic inflammatory state, will speed up the progression of liver fibrosis. Recently, insulin therapy using the hyperinsulinemic normoglycemic clamp technique has been shown to potentiate the regenerative capacity of the liver and decrease the overall inflammatory state. Therefore, we hypothesize that treating HCV infected patients with high-dose insulin therapy will target the pathophysiology of the disease at both cellular and molecular levels; eventually promoting recovery of liver function and potentially slowing the disease progression. Methods: A pilot interventional study was conducted on patients with chronic HCV infection who are not candidates for interferon based therapy. Each patient underwent a minimum of 14 weeks of 6-hours each insulin therapy sessions scheduled twice per week. Hyperinsulinemic normoglycemic clamp technique was used to deliver 2 milliunit of human regular insulin per kilogram of body weight per minute. Testing of liver function, inflammatory markers, metabolic parameters, liver volume, and reported quality of life were collected at the beginning, middle and end of the study period. Results: All patients followed by 2 hepatologists were screened; thirteen patients met the inclusion and exclusion criteria and were interviewed. Three patients agreed to participate in the study. One patient successfully completed the protocol. The patient had noted improvements in multiple parameters related to the liver function, liver volume and the inflammatory response with no apparent improvement in metabolic parameters or in the reported quality of life.  The second patient didn’t complete the study due to hospital admission secondary to septicemia. The third patient was excluded before the study start date due to hospital admission for variceal bleed. Discussion: The application of high-dose insulin therapy in cirrhotic patients is feasible and safe in outpatient settings. Insulin therapy is a novel technique that can alter the systemic inflammatory response and potentially promote liver regeneration and improve liver function in patients with chronic HCV induced liver cirrhosis. Recognizing the limitation of having only one enrolled patient complete the study, further testing is needed to confirm benefits and rule out harm of long term insulin therapy for liver disease. For future work, inclusion criteria need to be revisited to assure adequate sample size while applying the concept in diseases with comparable patho-physiology to chronic hepatitis C infection.  </description><creator>Shaheen, Mohammed</creator><contributor>Mazen Hassanain (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Peter Metrakos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>High dose Insulin therapy to improve liver function in patients with Hepatitis C Virus induced liver cirrhosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v977.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz30w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fv53q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ivermectin (IVM) is a macrocyclic lactone (ML) endectocide. It acts on the glutamate gated chloride channels and causes paralysis and death of nematode parasites. It is used in veterinary and human health as well as in agriculture. Haemonchus contortus (H. contortus) is a very pathogenic nematode of livestock. Attempts to control it with anthelmintic pharmaceuticals, such as IVM, has rapidly led to the development of drug resistance against most of the known anthelmintics. Caenorhabditis elegans (C. elegans) is a free living nematode that can be easily grown and cultivated on culture plates. Both of these nematodes have proven excellent models to study drug resistance mechanisms. Observations that IVM selects on β-tubulin in some nematodes, including H. contortus led me to study recombinant H. contortus β- and α-tubulins, and microtubules formed when these tubulins polymerize. Unlike mammalian microtubules, we report that H. contortus microtubules do not depolymerize under cold conditions. This microtubule resistance to cold may help the free-living stages of this parasite to survive cold climatic conditions. Because of reports that IVM is selecting on nematode tubulin we investigated a possible direct relationship between IVM and tubulins. We demonstrate that IVM is binding at low micromolar concentrations to both H. contortus and mammalian tubulins in the taxol binding pocket and that this IVM-mediated effect is reversible. We also demonstrate that the single nucleotide polymorphisms (F200Y and F167Y) on the H. contortus β-tubulin, previously reported to increase in frequency with IVM selection, had no apparent effect on IVM binding. We did not find any significant differences in the binding of IVM and moxidectin, another ML, to H. contortus and mammalian tubulins. The amphids are sensory structures, rich in dendrites and microtubule bundles. The C. elegans strains N2 (IVM susceptible) and IVR-10 (IVM resistant) were used for lipophilic dye filling and IVM uptake experiments. We found that the IVR-10 strain was dye filling defective, that is the fluorescent dye did not enter the nematode amphids to the same extent as in susceptible nematodes. We also found that IVM may enter through the amphidial pore. These studies provide novel information on nematode tubulins, the role of tubulin in IVM and ML pharmacology and the possible role of amphids and microtubules in IVM uptake in nematodes. The findings advance knowledge of IVM pharmacology and enable better understanding nematode biology.</description><description>L’ivermectine (IVM) est une lactone macrocyclique (ML) endectocide. Elle agit sur les canaux chlorures glutamate-dépendants et entraîne la paralysie et la mort des parasites nématodes. L’IVM  est aussi bien utilisée en médecine vétérinaire et humaine qu’en agriculture.  Haemonchus contortus (H. contortus)  est un nématode de bétail très pathogène. L’utilisation d’anthelminthiques, comme l’IVM, a été largement -préconisée pour contrôler ce parasite. La résistance à la plupart des anthelminthiques  s’est rapidement développée. Caenorhabditis elegans (C. elegans) est un nématode libre qui peut  facilement être cultivé sur des plaques de culture. Ces deux nématodes sont d’excellents modèles pour étudier les méchanismes  de résistance aux médicaments. L’ivermectine sélectionne  la ß-tubulin  chez des nématodes notamment chez H. contortus. L’objectif de cette étude était d’étudier l’α- et la ß-tubuline recombinante d’H. contortus ainsi que les microtubules formées lors de la polymérisations de ces tubulines.  Nous avons observé qu’à la différence des microtubules de mammifères, les microtubules d’ H. contortus ne se dépolymérisaient pas avec le froid.  Cette résistance au froid des microtubules pourrait aider les stades libres de ce parasite à survivre dans des conditions climatiques froides.Nous avons aussi investigué la possible relation directe entre l’IVM et les tubulines. Nous avons démontré que l’IVM se fixait à faible concentration micromolaire aussi bien sur les tubulines d’H. contortus que sur les tubulines de mammifères au niveau de la zone de fixation du taxol et que cet effet était réversible. Nous avons aussi démontré  que chez H. contortus, les polymorphismes mononucléotidiques (F200Y et F167Y), connus dans la sélection à l’IVM, n’avaient pas d’effet sur la fixation de l’ivermectine sur la ß-tubuline. Nous n’avons pas trouvé de différences significatives entre la fixation de l’IVM et de la moxidectine (un autre ML) sur les tubulines d’H. contortus et de mammifères.Les souches N2 (sensible à l’IVM) et IVR-10 (résistante à l’IVM) de C. elegans ont été utilisées lors d’expériences d’absorption  de l’IVM et de remplissage avec des colorants lipophiles. Nous avons montré que la souche IVR-10 ne permettait pas à un colorant fluorescent de bien  pénétrer par les amphides de ces nématodes résistants contrairement aux amphides des nématodes sensible à l’IVM.  Nous avons observé que l’IVM pouvait entrer par les pores amphidiaux. Les amphides sont des structures sensorielles riches en dendrites et en faisceaux de microtubules. Ces études  fournissent de nouvelles informations sur les tubulines des nématodes, le rôle des tubulines dans la pharmacologie de l’IVM et des MLs et le possible rôle des amphides et des microtubules dans l’absorption de l’IVM par les nématodes. Ces  conclusions contribuent à  une meilleure connaissance de la pharmacologie de l’IVM et  une meilleure compréhension de la biologie des nématodes.</description><creator>Ashraf, Shoaib</creator><contributor>Roger K Prichard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>Tubulin and ivermectin pharmacology in the parasitic nematode «Haemonchus contortus»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d9549.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv53q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c20g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Distraction osteogenesis (DO) is a surgical technique widely used to treat complex orthopaedic conditions. One limitation of this technique is the long period the external fixator needs to be left in place until the newly form bone is completely consolidated. This might lead to significant morbidities in terms of persistent pain, risk of pin tracts infection and negative psychological impact on patients and their families. Although the use of sclerostin antibodies (Scl-Ab) has shown promising results to enhance bone repair in various animal models, its effect in DO remains to be determined.  We hypothesized that the systemic administration of Scl-Ab can accelerate bone regeneration in a mouse model of DO. A total of 110 mice were randomized to saline versus Scl-Ab injection groups. After DO surgery in the right tibiae, mice were injected intraveounsly once weekly with Scl-Ab (100mg/kg) versus saline (0.1 ml).  Mice were sacrificed at four time points, day 11 (mid-distraction phase), day 17 (end of distraction), day 34 (mid-conslidation) and day 51 (end of conslidation). Radiographic (Faxitron), microstructural (μCT), and qualitative histological analysis were performed for the lengthened tibiae at all time points. In addition, biomechanical testing was performed at day 34 and 51. Micro-CT results showed an increase of bone volume in the Scl-Ab treated group at day 11 (P=0.009) when compared to the saline group. A trend toward increase bone volume was observed in the Scl-Ab groups at day 17, 34 and 51 (P&gt;0.05). Histological results showed predominately presence of chondrocytes and fibrocartilages in Scl-Ab group at day 11 when compared to the saline group. Radiographic bone scores were higher in the Scl-Ab treated groups at all time points with P=0.04 at day 11. Biomechanical analysis revealed a trend toward higher values of ultimate force and work to ultimate point in Scl-Ab treated groups at day 34 and 51 (P&gt;0.05) when compared to the saline groups. In conclusion, our data demonstrate the benefits of Scl-Ab on acceleration of bone regeneration and suggest its potential utility in clinical situations to reduce the treatment period with an external fixator during DO procedures.</description><description>La distraction osseuse (DO) est une technique chirurgicale largement utilisé pour traiter des conditions orthopédiques complexes. Une des limites de cette technique est le temps que le fixateur externe doit être laissé en place jusqu'à l'os nouvel soit complètement consolidé. Cela pourrait conduire à des comorbidités significatives en termes de douleur persistante, augmenter le risque d’infection des broches et l'impact psychologique négatif sur les patients et leurs familles. Sclerostin, est une glycoprotéine sécrétée qui interagit avec la protéine liée à la lipoprotéine receptor-5 (LRP5) et inhibe la voie de signalisation Wnt intracellulaire, ce qui conduit à une diminution de l'activité de la formation osseuse par les ostéoblastes. Lorsque Sclerostin est inactivée, la formation osseuse est donc stimulée. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que l'administration systémique d'anticorps sclérostine (Scl-Ab) peut accélérer la régénération osseuse dans une modèle de souris de la DO. Un total de 110 souris ont été randomisés à injections salées contre les groupes d'injections Scl-Ab. Après la chirurgie DO dans la tibia droit, les souris ont reçu une injection une fois par semaine avec Scl-Ab intraveineuse (100 mg / kg) par rapport à une injection de solution saline (0,1 ml). Les souris ont été sacrifiées à quatre points differents, dans le jour 11 (phase mi-distraction), 17 jours (fin de la distraction), 34 jours (mi-conslidation) et à 51 jours (fin de conslidation). L'analyse radiographique (Faxitron), de la microstructure (μCT), et histologique qualitative ont été effectuées aux tibias allongé à tous les points de temps. Aussi, les tests biomécaniques ont été réalisée au jour 34 et 51. Les résultats de Micro-CT ont montré une augmentation du volume osseux dans le groupe traité Scl-Ab à 11 jours (p = 0,009) par rapport au groupe de solution saline. Une tendance vers le volume augmentation osseuse a été observée dans les groupes Scl-Ab au jour 17, 34 et 51 (P&gt; 0,05). Les résultats histologiques ont montré principalement la présence de chondrocytes et fibrocartilages dans le groupe Scl-Ab à 11 jours par rapport au groupe de solution saline. Les scores radiographiques de remplissage osseous étaient plus élevés aux groups avec Scl-Ab à tous les points de temps avec P = 0,04 au jour 11. L’analyse biomécanique révélé une tendance vers des valeurs plus élevées de force ultime et le travail à point ultime aux groupes avec Scl-Ab à 34 jours et 51 (P&gt; 0,05) par rapport aux groupes avec salins. En conclusion, nos données démontrent les avantages de Scl-Ab sur l'accélération de la régénération osseuse et suggère son utilité potentielle dans des situations cliniques afin de réduire la période de traitement avec un fixateur externe au cours des procédures DO.</description><creator>Makhdom, Asim</creator><contributor>C Reggie Hamdy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Frank Rauch (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>The effect of systemic administration of sclerostin antibodies in a mouse model of distraction osteogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666771b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c20g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451m645</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:48:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sustainable production of cranberry (Vaccinium macrocarpon) in Quebec fields requires the adoption of best management practices. A promising approach is the application of biochar combined with beneficial microbes as soil amendment, leading to a faster establishment of cranberry fields and reduced use of agrichemicals. This study was undertaken in order to determine whether the application of maple bark biochar amended with selected plant growth promoting rhizobacteria (PGPR) would stimulate vegetative growth of “Stevens” cranberry cuttings under controlled growth bed conditions and also to evaluate biochar effect on microbial populations present in the potting mix. Biochar was added at 1% (w/w) and used directly or mixed with three selected bacterial strains known to stimulate plant growth compared to treatments in which biochar was not added. Shoot and root dry weights increased upon the addition of 1% biochar and beneficial microbes at both harvesting dates compared to those in potting mix fortified with full dose of Actisol®. Under lower dose of Actisol®, biochar and bacteria amendment significantly increased root dry weight at 120 days after transplanting. Depending on the date of harvesting, the addition of 1% biochar and beneficial microbes significantly (P &lt; 0.05) increased the total abundance of microbes present in the rhizosphere and bulk soil of cranberry cuttings. In particular, there was an increase in the abundance numbers of fungal and Actinomycets phyla in bulk soil. Quantitative-PCR assays using species-specific primers showed that DNA copy numbers of PGPR and ericoid mycorrhiza in soil and in roots of cranberry cuttings varied with date of harvesting and with the type of biological sample tested.  Under the above conditions, our results indicate that the application of maple bark biochar yielded variable results and may not be the best-suited type of biochar for cranberry production in conjunction with selected beneficial microbes</description><description>La culture durable de la canneberge (Vaccinium macrocarpon) au Québec requiert l’adoption de meilleures pratiques de gestion. Une approche prometteuse est l’application de biocharbon et de rhizobactéries comme amendement de sol, menant à un rapide établissement en champs et à une diminution des intrants chimiques. Cette étude a été réalisée afin de déterminer si l’application de biocharbon d’écorce d’érable et de rhizobactéries bénéfiques pouvait stimuler la croissance de boutures de canneberges du cultivar « Stevens » en serre et d’évaluer ses effets sur la flore microbienne. 1% de biocharbon (p/p) a été utilisé seul et en combinaison avec trois rhizobactéries reconnues pour stimuler la croissance, puis comparé à un contrôle. La masse des tiges et des racines a augmenté suite à l’addition de 1% de biocharbon et de rhizobact.éries aux deux dates de récoltes comparé au traitement contenant 100% de la dose d’Actisol®.  Comparée à une plus faible dose d’Actisol®, la masse des racines a augmenté après 120 jours avec l’addition de biocharbon et rhizobactéries. Selon la date de récolte, l’addition de 1% de biocharbon et rhizobactéries a augmenté  de façon significative (P&lt;0.05) le nombre total de microorganisme présent dans le sol. Plus particulièrement, il y a eu une augmentation du nombre de populations fongiques et d’actinomycetes dans le sol non rhizosphérique des boutures. L’utilisation d’amorces spécifiques à l’espèce en PCR-quantitative, dans le but de déterminer le nombre de copies des rhizobactéries et de mycorhize éricoïdienne dans le sol et les racines des boutures, a démontré des résultats variant avec les temps d’échantillonnage et les types d’échantillons testés. Sous les conditions testées, nos résultats indiquent que l’application de biocharbon et de rhizobacteries bénéfiques en production de canneberge biologique produit des résultats variables et n’est peut-être pas la façon la plus adéquate d’améliorer l’établissement des boutures en champs.</description><creator>Bernard Perron, David</creator><contributor>Suha Jabaji (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Agriculture - Horticulture</subject><title>Effect of biochar amended with beneficial microbes on establishment and growth of cranberry («Vaccinium macrocarpon L.») cuttings under controlled conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j238.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451m645</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):47250</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>