<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:28:27Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34800" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt54f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary purpose of this study was to explore the differential gambling patterns of underage adolescents in order to identify the specific characteristics and determinants that influence the appeal of the lottery and their lottery playing behaviour. This study was an exploratory investigation of the structural characteristics of lottery products that are particularly appealing to youth (e.g., monetary value, attribute of the ticket, type of game, prize structure, advertisements, colour of ticket, etc.). This research consisted of three phases. Phase I consisted of the inclusion of 5 focus groups (47 children, age 12--19) designed to provide qualitative information on adolescent lottery playing behaviour; Phase II included the development and validation of an instrument to assess lottery playing and gambling behaviour; and Phase III included the participation of a large community sample of youth in Ontario who completed the questionnaire assessing their gambling behaviour in general, factors influencing lottery playing behaviour (e.g., structural characteristics of lottery tickets), and severity of gambling problems. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Felsher, Jennifer R.</creator><contributor>Derevensky, Jeffrey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Adolescent psychology.</subject><subject>Lotteries.</subject><subject>Gambling.</subject><title>Lottery ticket purchases by adolescents and their gambling behaviour : a qualitative and quantitative examination</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d173f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt54f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gq07n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an analysis as to whether or not Subcultural Theory may be utilized to understand how self-identification is configured within a subculture such as rave. Typically, subcultural membership requires various performative rites that express and maintain a group sensibility and identity. Rave, however, is a subculture that involves a relationship to space and technology that changes the nature of group affiliation within the subculture. This thesis focuses on how a body immersed in subcultural practices, and organized around varying technologies, must look toward an analysis of individual and subjective adaptations of those technologies. In essence, rave allows for identification that is shaped and altered by the participant, but only at each moment of interaction with the technologies of the club. Highly individualistic, dynamic, and technology-driven, the rave subculture offers the potential to examine the body as the site for identification, and escape, within an abstracting technological world.</description><creator>Fernandes, Nelson.</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Rave culture.</subject><subject>Raves (Parties)</subject><subject>Body, Human -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Subculture.</subject><title>Trippin' the body electric : towards a discourse on a tecnological body-subculture : the case of rave</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns66w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq07n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r279v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Teaching science using an inquiry approach is encouraged by several organisations responsible for defining teaching and learning guidelines in North America. However, using this approach can be difficult because of the complexity of inquiry. One source of difficulty is an inability to make sense of the data. Error variation, in particular, poses a significant barrier to the correct interpretation of data and therefore successful inquiry learning. A study was conducted to examine middle school students' ability to make sense of the data they collected in three related experiments. These data involved taking measurements of two continuous variables that were affected by error variation. The results indicated that students tended not to use abstract patterns to describe the data but rather used more local patterns that did not make use of the whole data set. However, many students also indicated an intuitive understanding that a greater amount of data could be used to generate results that are more accurate. This suggests a disparity between what the students understand about data and what they are capable of doing with data. Educational implications are that students may benefit from learning ideal patterns that can be compared to non-ideal data they collect.</description><creator>Chiarella, Andrew.</creator><contributor>Lajoie, Susanne P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Statistics -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</subject><subject>Science -- Study and teaching (Secondary)</subject><title>Statistical reasoning and scientific inquiry : statistics in the physical science classroom</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd482.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r279v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193b67b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine the extent of eating disorder symptoms and differences in exercise motivations in female distance runners at various exercise investment levels. One hundred and seven distance runners, aged 19 to 59 years, who run a minimum of five kilometers, three times per week, were asked to complete three questionnaires. The runners across exercise investment levels were not found to differ in Eating Disorder Inventory sub-scale scores. They differed from college women only in exhibiting fewer symptoms on Drive for Thinness (p &lt; .05), Body Dissatisfaction (p &lt; .001), and Interoceptive Awareness (p &lt; .001). Significant differences in the Exercise Orientation Questionnaire sub-scale scores were found between the least and most exercise-invested runners with the latter scoring significantly higher on Exercise Orientation (P &lt; .0001), Identity (p &lt; .004), and Competition (p &lt; .002). It was concluded that while eating disorder symptoms among female distance runners at various investment levels are no different, exercise motivations are different across levels of exercise.</description><creator>Canady, Andrea.</creator><contributor>Neil, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Runners (Sports) -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Running -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Women runners -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Eating disorders in women.</subject><title>Eating disorder symptoms and exercise motivations across exercise investment levels among female distance runners</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0324761.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193b67b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1618051</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work surveys currently available methods for measuring human brainwaves in order to generate music and technologies for real-time transmission of audio and music over the Internet. The end goal is to produce a performable music system which sends live human brainwaves over the Internet to produce sounding music at another, physically separated location.</description><creator>Brouse, Andrew.</creator><contributor>Depalle, Philippe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Music -- Physiological aspects -- Data processing.</subject><subject>Brain -- Data processing.</subject><title>The interharmonium : an investigation into networked musical applications and brainwaves</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w9282.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1618051</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903170k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Purpose. Post Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) is a disorder with important prevalence, morbidity, co-morbidity as well as economic cost. This study examines the comparative efficacy and effectiveness of pharmacotherapy and psychotherapy. Data sources. (1) MEDLINE search from 1966 to present using both McSH terms and related keywords; (2) reference lists from retrieved articles; (3) reference lists from systematic reviews and books (4) consultation with "key informants". Study selection. All studies that examined therapeutic interventions for at least 6 subjects with PTSD were targeted for retrieval. Studies in English and French, with data enabling the calculation of a within condition effect size (ES) were retained for the analysis. A random sample of excluded studies was read to confirm that no relevant study was missed with our inclusion criteria. Data extraction. Data on study design, study population, diagnostic method, co-morbidity, duration of illness, treatment type, outcome measure, outcome and duration of follow-up were extracted by two authors. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Wazana, Ashley.</creator><contributor>Perry, Chris (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>The meta-analysis of the efficacy and effectiveness for pharmacotherapy and psychotherapy for post traumatic stress disorder /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn425.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903170k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv431</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Relatively little is known about psychological and social factors as potential determinants for developing cervical cancer. Health related beliefs and detailed sociodemographic information were compared among women with different stages of cervical cancer precursor lesions, and among women with HPV infections from a high-risk area for cervical cancer. Both cytology and cervicography were used to obtain cervical lesion status of women, and HPV DNA detection was done by a polymerase chain reaction-based protocol (MY09/11). For cervical cancer precursor lesions, three different groups of women were compared to women remaining cytologically normal (N = 841) throughout four years of follow-up: (1) women with any abnormal cytological diagnosis, atypical squamous cells of undetermined significance, low-grade, and high-grade squamous intraepithelial lesions (ASCUS, LSILs, and HSILs respectively) (N = 487); (2) women with either LSILs or HSILs (N = 420); and (3) women with HSILs only (N = 37). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Yang, Seungmi, 1971-</creator><contributor>Franco, Eduardo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Health beliefs and sociodemographic factors as correlates of human papillomavirus infections and cervical cancer precursor lesions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161807k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv431</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225c78p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conjugated linoleic acid (CLA) has gained much attention recently due to its beneficial health and biological effects on animals and humans. However, the CLA-forming enzyme system has not been studied in details. Six strains of Lactobacillus acidophilus L11, L12, L14, L15, Lactobacillus fermentum and Lactobacillus reuteri were used to study the growth conditions and the production of CLA-forming enzyme in MRS media containing linoleic acid concentrations at 37°C. The purification and characterization of a CLA-forming enzyme were reported for the first time. The results showed that this enzyme has a molecular mass of 72 kDa, and is composed of two subunits. The optimal pH and temperature were 7.0 and 37°C, respectively. Kinetic study indicated that the enzyme has a high affinity for linoleic acid having a Km value of 1.49 x 10 -5 M and the Vmax was 17.1 muM/mg/min. The enzyme activity was inhibited by the metal chelators. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Wu, Haifeng, 1967-</creator><contributor>Lee, Beyong H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Linoleic acid.</subject><subject>Isomerases.</subject><subject>Lactobacillus acidophilus.</subject><title>Production, purification and characterization of a CLA-forming enzyme from Lactobacillus acidophilus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d174q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c78p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m354w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In cell cycle checkpoint control, the Chk2 family protein kinases play a central role in mediating the cellular responses to DNA damage or DNA replication block. However, at the beginning of this project, there was no evidence for a Drosophila homologue of Chk2. loki was identified in a screen for serine/threonine protein kinases that are expressed in the ovary. Using a phylogenetic analysis, I showed that loki is a Drosophila chk2 orthologue. To characterize the checkpoint function of loki in Drosophila development, we created a loki null mutant and generated anti-Loki antibodies. Under normal laboratory conditions, loki null mutants display no apparent defect during the whole life span. Further functional analysis revealed that loki is not required for the meiotic pachytene checkpoint, the essential DNA replication checkpoint control in syncytial embryos and the DNA damage/replication checkpoint during the larval stage. However, in postblastoderm embryos, loki is required for the DNA damage checkpoint activated by gamma irradiation. Embryos lacking loki are not able to arrest the cell cycle in response to gamma irradiation.</description><creator>Yang, Long, 1976-</creator><contributor>Suter, Beat (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Protein kinases.</subject><subject>Drosophila -- Molecular genetics.</subject><title>Functional analysis of the loki serinethreonine protein kinase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v97w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m354w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wk857</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis was to examine the sources and ecological behaviour of genotoxic organics in the St. Lawrence river system. A rapid and effective version of the SOS Chromotest was developed to accomplish the task of genotoxicity assessment. The method, validated with standard reference materials, is particularly well suited to complex environmental extracts. The endpoint investigated throughout the thesis, SOS genotoxicity, is empirically related to more familiar endpoints such as mutagenicity and carcinogenicity. Analyses of literature data confirmed correlations between SOS genotoxicity and both Ames/Salmonella mutagenicity and animal carcinogenicity. Analyses of industrial and municipal wastewaters revealed that organic and inorganic chemical production facilities, metal refining and founding facilities and petroleum refineries release high potency wastes. Loading values indicate that low potency sources (e.g. municipal wastewater and pulp &amp; paper facilities) often have exceptionally high loadings. A substantial portion (2.3-99.8%) of industrial genotoxins are associated with suspended particulates. Sorption partition efficients (K$ sb{ rm d-genotox}$) indicate that municipal wastewater and pulp &amp; paper facilities release particularly soluble genotoxins. Extracts of suspended particulate matter collected near industrial discharges are direct-acting. Bottom sediment extracts are less potent and usually require S9 metabolic activation. Genotoxicity of both bottom sediment and suspended particulates are empirically related to the genotoxicity of regional industrial emissions. Direct-acting substances in the water column appear to be less stable and may be converted to more stable pro-genotoxic substances present in the bottom sediments. A mass balance of genotoxicity for St. Lawrence surface waters revealed that domestic, rather than industrial sources make the largest contribution to observed genotoxicity. The importance of domestic wastes was confirmed</description><creator>White, Paul Andrew</creator><contributor>Rasmussen, Joseph B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Water -- Pollution -- Toxicology -- Saint Lawrence River</subject><subject>Genetic toxicology -- Québec (Province) -- Saguenay River</subject><subject>Water -- Pollution -- Toxicology -- Québec (Province) -- Saguenay River</subject><subject>Genetic toxicology -- Saint Lawrence River</subject><title>Detection, discharge and ecological behaviour of genotoxic organic contaminants in the St. Lawrence and Saguenay rivers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br025.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wk857</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv9354593</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cell adhesion molecules (CAM) have been implicated in the process of cancer metastasis. However, the interactions of metastatic tumor cells with organ parenchymal cells-hepatocytes particularly the relevance of tumor-cell-hepatocyte adhesion to liver metastasis is still not fully understood. We have investigated the role of tumor cell-hepatocyte interaction in liver metastasis using liver metastatic subline H-59 of the Lewis lung carcinoma. A monoclonal antibody (MAb) C-11 was produced which was highly specific to liver metastatic H-59 cells. Our in vitro studies showed that this MAb and its F(ab)2 fragments could block tumor H-59 cell adhesion to hepatocytes. The molecule detected by MAb C-11 on H-59 cells as well as on hepatocytes was a 64-71 kDa plasma membrane glycoprotein (designated C-11 BP). We found that this molecule contains approximately 43% of N-linked carbohydrates which were not involved in MAb C-11 recognition, but participated in the adhesion process. MAb C-11 could also block the stimulatory effect of hepatocytes on tumor cell proliferation indicating that the adhesion of H-59 cells to hepatocytes may be necessary for tumor cell growth. The in vivo role of the C-11 BP was subsequently tested and it was shown that MAb C-11 and its F(ab)2 fragments could significantly reduce the number of hepatic metastases when used to pretreat H-59 cells before intrasplenic injection, or when inoculated directly into the animals by the intraperitoneal and intravenous routes. This inhibitory effect resulted in an increase in the survival time of tumor-inoculated mice. In additional studies, a second molecule namely the membrane-associated endoplasmic reticulum protein ERp-72 was also implicated in the adhesion of H-59 cells to the hepatocytes, however its role in vivo remains to be confirmed. Our results suggest that CAM involved in tumor-hepatocyte adhesion play an important role in liver metastasis. Monoclonal antibody against tumor cell surface adhesion molecul</description><creator>Wang, Jian, 1961-</creator><contributor>Brodt, Pnina (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Role of tumor-hepatocyte adhesion in carcinoma cell metastasis to the liver</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1617772.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9354593</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c914s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new approach for computing qualitative part-based descriptions of 3D objects from single- and multi-view range data is presented. This research is motivated by both a theory of human image understanding (Recognition-by-Components) and the need for qualitative recognition by an autonomous robot in order for it to efficiently interact with its environment. Object descriptions are obtained in two consecutive steps: (1) object segmentation into parts and (2) part model identification. Segmentation is achieved by first computing the simulated electrical charge density distribution on a tessellated triangular mesh of the object surface. The algorithm then detects the object part boundaries where the charge density achieves a local minimum. The charge density distribution can simultaneously provide an indication of the gross and fine object structures. Parametric geons are introduced as the part models, which indicate both qualitative shape and quantitative attribute information. Model recovery is achieved by fitting all parametric geons to a part and then selecting the best model based on the minimum fitting residual. A new objective function used for model recovery is optimised by a global optimisation technique (Very Fast Simulated Re-Annealing). The advantages of this approach are demonstrated through experimentation. By using a physical analogy to the well known transversality principle, part segmentation does not require an assumption of surface smoothness or the choice of a particular scale to compute local surface features. The formulation for parametric geons provides a global shape constraint, which ensures reliable part model recovery even when the part shape is not an exact instance of a parametric geon. By directly comparing a part with all candidate models, this approach explicitly verifies the shape of the resultant part descriptions. The computed part-based descriptions are well suited for the object recognition task carried out by an autonomous robot.</description><creator>Wu, Kenong</creator><contributor>Levine, Martin D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>XComputing parametric geon descriptions of 3D multi-part objects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k879b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c914s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn59v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:47:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The accidental, or maybe not so accidental, equation of the Long $ rm lbrack TE rbrack$ with the dragon is a minor, yet in many ways symbolic, incident in Western European reinvention of China. This reinvention can be found in a wide variety of discourses, the authors of which range from Enlightenment philosophes to nineteenth-century political economists, to the recent Derrida, and from the even earlier Sir John Mandeville, Oliver Goldsmith, to Coleridge, to W. S. Landor and De Quincey. It covers all aspects of Chinese culture, including philosophy, religion, government, language, poetry, and folklore. This dissertation argues that the divergent, even contradictory, accounts of China as a culture Other, on the one hand reflect divergent or conflicting domestic agenda and, on the other, converge as products of an inherent epistemological ethnocentrism. As such, they can offer no substantial alternatives to "Orientalism," which is an ideology that functions in a cross-cultural context. However, Edward Said's delineation of Orientalism has the weakness of vacillating between the incompatible notions of "truth" and of discourse. And Dennis Porter's corrective, based on the "generic heterogeneity" within the West's cultural tradition, has a theoretical problem of traversing contextual boundaries. To contribute to the on-going debate, this dissertation proposes a distinction between internal and external perspectives, on the criteria of material, objective, and standard, in the representation of a cultural identity. With each perspective conscious of its own specific values, a cross-cultural textual dialogue may be pursued.</description><creator>Tao, Zhijian</creator><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>China -- Civilization</subject><title>Drawing the dragon : testimonies to the reinvention of China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd36p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn59v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jc91c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of estimating call blocking probabilities in ATM networks is addressed in this thesis. We develop a new, two-step iterated framework for call acceptance control (CAC). In the first step, we define a new variable bit rate (VBR) traffic descriptor called effective rate and we use a known effective bandwidth technique in the second step to estimate cell loss. This approach yields decoupled estimators at the call level so that loss systems models can be used to perform network analysis. Our work on loss systems is divided in three parts: single-link problems, reservation and network problems. In the single-link context, we generalize existing asymptotic approximation formulae for blocking probabilities and propose a uniform estimate under light up to critical loading conditions. We present the salient features of commonly used reservation schemes while proposing and reviewing ways to estimate blocking probabilities in each case. In the case of networks, we provide an overview of classical techniques to evaluate blocking probabilities such as fixed-point methods. We propose a novel fixed-point technique for large capacity systems which yields dramatic reduction in computational complexity. We also analyze loss networks from an analytic point of view using the Laplace method and a change of probability law technique. We obtain asymptotic formulae for every loading conditions and a number of asymptotic results regarding network behavior. Many numerical examples are provided as well as a model example where we illustrate how our asymptotic formulae can be used to perform network optimization.</description><creator>Théberge, François</creator><contributor>Mazumdar, Ravi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Large multiservice loss models and applications to ATM networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x298q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jc91c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q5658</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Remodelling of extracellular matrix (ECM) is a prominent feature of atherosclerotic lesions and contributes to lipoprotein retention as well as smooth muscle cell (SMC) activation. To gain further knowledge about ECM, certain ECM components and their degrading enzymes were studied in injury-induced arterial neointima, which shares features with early atherosclerotic lesions. It has been shown that synthesis of collagen and syndecan-1, a hybrid heparan/chondroitin sulfate proteoglycan, is enhanced. In situ hybridization indicates that syndecan positive cells are restricted to the arterial neointima. These data confirm the importance of arterial SMC in ECM metabolism and indicate that increased synthesis contributes to ECM accumulation in neointima. Remodelling of ECM in atherogenesis refers not only to increased ECM deposition, but also involves enhanced ECM catabolism. A family of zinc-containing proteinases, termed matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) has recently been implicated in atherosclerosis. Subsequently, we examined expression of two common MMPs, MMP-2 and MMP-9 in our model. The mRNAs for both MMPs are up-regulated, but their tissue distribution is different: MMP-2 positive cells are visible in neointima and in aortic media; whereas cells positive for MMP-9 are located only in neointima. MMPs are active at neutral pH and in tissue, their activity is regulated by tissue inhibitors of metalloproteinases (TIMPs) including TIMP-1. The enhanced MMP expression in neointima makes it relevant to examine the simultaneous expression of TIMP-1. To do this, we cloned rabbit TIMP-1 from neointima using a PCR-cloning technique. Transformation of the cloned gene resulted in synthesis of a TIMP-1 protein in E. Coli. The concentration of TIMP-1 in neointima was examined and a significant increase of both mRNA and protein levels was observed. It is suggested that the proteolytic activity of MMPs contributes to ECM breakdown. However, this digestion is limited, as continuous augmentation of TIMP-1 expression is observed after aortic de-endothelialization.</description><creator>Wang, He, 1965-</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Extracellular matrix metabolism in injury-induced atherosclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3333886.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q5658</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731554m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The electrical and mechanical properties of electrically conductive fiber composites were measured and related to composite microstructure. Samples were manufactured by compression molding, extrusion, and injection molding to determine the effect of processing method on fiber length and orientation. A strong correlation between the processing-induced fiber-phase microstructure and the measured properties is found. The results are highly dependent on the type of conductive fiber. Computer-generated flow-field models are able to illustrate the thermal and flow processes which affect microstructure. A simple orientation model gives good qualitative agreement with experimental observations in injection molded composites. Two models for predicting volume resistivity are proposed. One model assumes that the fibers are aligned end-to-end, and the effect of fiber orientation and concentration is obtained. The results agree qualitatively with experimental data, and give a lower bound or resistivity. More realistic fiber-fiber contacts are considered in the second model. The resistivity is expressed in terms of the area of contact, and orientation, length, and concentration of the fibers. Model predictions are in excellent agreement with experimental results.</description><creator>Weber, Mark, 1964-</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The processing and properties of electrically conductive fiber composites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p1921.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731554m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784n298</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>HEM13 encodes coproporphyrinogen oxidase, the sixth enzyme of the heme biosynthetic pathway. Expression of HEM13 is repressed under aerobic conditions. In the absence of heme or oxygen, the expression of HEM13 increases forty-fold. Mutations defining trans-acting factors involved in the regulation of HEM13 expression were isolated and analyzed. This analysis identified two different alleles of HAP1. HAP1 encodes an activator protein involved in the expression of a number of heme-dependent genes such as CYC1, which encodes iso-1-cytochrome c, and ROX1, which encodes a repressor of HEM13 expression. The hap1 mutant allele in one strain confers a phenotype much like that of the hap1::LEU2 allele in that HEM13 expression is elevated under repressing conditions and not fully inducible in the absence of heme. In addition, expression of ROX1 is constitutively low. The other mutant allele of HAP1 confers a novel phenotype. Expression of HEM13 is uninducible in a strain containing this other allele of HAP1 while that of ROX1 and CYC1 has become heme-independent. The mutation associated with this mutant allele of hap1 was localized to a glycine to aspartate change in amino acid 235 of HAP1. DNA binding assays indicated that the protein made from this HAP1 allele retains the ability to bind DNA, but that unlike wild-type HAP1 protein, this binding is not stimulated by heme. The regulatory sequences involved in HEM13 expression have been localized to a 365 bp region which contains several distinct positive and negative regulatory elements. Gel shift experiments with overlapping fragments containing sequences from this region of the HEM13 promoter indicate that multiple factors interact with the elements in this region.</description><creator>Ushinsky, Sophia C. (Sophia Constantin)</creator><contributor>Keng, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Identification of trans-acting factors involved in HEM13 expression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t86r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784n298</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732db540</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In many (social, economic, and political) strategic situations, conflict and cooperations coexist and group (or coalitional) behavior is as important as individual behavior. This dissertation studies several issues in such situations. Chapter 1 provides an overview of the theoretical background and motivates the analysis undertaken. Chapter 2 analyzes strategic situations with diverse coalitional interactions to ascertain the "stable" outcomes that will not be replaced by any rational (hence farsighted) coalition of individuals, and the coalitions that are likely to form. The analysis takes into full account the perfect foresight of rational individuals, which has been overlooked in the literature. Chapter 3 defines "negotiation-proof Nash equilibrium", a notion that applies to environments where players can negotiate openly and directly prior to the play of a noncooperative game. The merit of the notion of negotiation-proof Nash equilibrium is twofold: (1) It resolves the nestedness and myopia embedded in the notion of coalition-proof Nash equilibrium. (2) The negotiation process, which is formalized by a "graph", serves as a natural alternative to the approach that models pre-play communication by an extensive form game. Chapter 4 examines the notion of "renegotiation-proofness" in infinitely repeated games. It is shown that imposing renegotiation in all contingencies creates both conceptual and technical difficulties. A notion of self-enforcing agreements is offered: an agreement is self-enforcing if it is immune to any deviation by any coalition which cannot (confidently) count on renegotiation.</description><creator>Xue, Licun</creator><contributor>Greenberg, Joseph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Game theory.</subject><subject>Coalitions -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Coalitional stability in strategic situations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq37s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732db540</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483k875</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Injection molding is a cyclic process used for the fabrication of thermosetting and thermoplastic articles. The thermoplastic polymer is melted and injected into the cavity, where it is molded under pressure and ejected after solidification. The amount of polymer mass contained in the cavity is the part weight. The control of part weight is important to ensure quality injection molded parts. The part weight is determined by the state of the polymer at the time the cavity gate freezes. The bulk temperature and the peak cavity pressure at the gate are used to characterize this state. Measuring internal polymer temperature profiles in the injection mold cavity during molding is extremely difficult. This work presents a method which combines measurements of cavity surface temperatures, cavity pressure, and on-line calculations for estimating temperature profiles inside the cavity. These profiles are then used to estimate the bulk polymer temperature. Fitting the cycle-to-cycle values of bulk polymer temperature and peak pressure to a Tait equation of state yields a model to predict part weights. The part weight is controlled through the use of a control strategy for the cavity pressure and the part weight model, together with the on-line estimation of the bulk temperature. A self-tuning algorithm with an observer is employed for controlling the cavity pressure time profile to a set point trajectory. The dynamics and control of the bulk temperature are also studied.</description><creator>Varela, Alfredo E. (Alfredo Enrique)</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><title>Estimation and control of part weight and relevant process parameters in injection molding of amorphous thermoplastics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn054.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k875</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301287t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The isothermal crystallization kinetics, spherulite morphology, and thermal behavior of the melt-crystallized optically active R and S polyenantiomers, their blends, and the stereoblock form of poly(epichlorohydrin) (PECH) and poly(propylene oxide) (PPrO) have been investigated using polarized light microscopy (PLOM), atomic force microscopy (AFM), and differential scanning calorimetry (DSC). The novel optically pure polyenantiomers of PECH were synthesized from the optically active monomers using a triethylaluminum$ cdot$water (1:0.6) catalyst, which was also used in the polymerization of the racemic monomer to an isotactic crystalline stereoblock fraction. The optically pure polyenantiomers and the stereoblock form of PPrO were obtained by the quantitative dechlorination reaction of the corresponding PECH polymers, using LiAlH$ sb4$, with retention of configuration of the main chain chiral centers. The spherulite radial growth rates of the melt-crystallized PECH equimolar polyenantiomer blend are depressed relative to those of either optically pure components over the range of crystallization temperatures from the glass transition temperature ($T sb{ rm g} = -26 sp circ$C) to the equilibrium melting temperature ($T sb{ rm m} sp circ = 138 sp circ$C), which were determined to be the same for all of the PECH polymers. A further marked reduction in growth rates is recorded for the stereoblock polymer. Conversion of the PECH polyenantiomers to PPrO results in an overall order of magnitude increase in the spherulite radial growth rates. The growth rates of the PPrO stereoblock are only slightly depressed relative to those of either optically pure polyenantiomer over the range of crystallization temperatures from $T sb{ rm g}({-}65 sp circ$C) to $T sb{ rm m} sp circ(82 sp circ$C), which were determined to be the same for all of the PPrO polymers. An analysis of the linear spherulite radial growth rates of the PECH polymers in terms of the Hoffman-Lauritzen treatment gives evidence of a rougher lamellar fold surface in the stereoblock polymer than in the polyenantiomers, but suggests similar surface free energies among the polyenantiomers and stereoblock form of PPrO. The multiple melting behavior exhibited by the different forms of PECH is greatly dependent on DSC heating rate and isothermal crystallization time, for samples crystallized at low temperatures and high temperatures, respectively. The behavior is demonstrated to be due to reorganization during the DSC heating scan in the former case, and linked to the process of secondary crystallization in the latter. The optically pure polyenantiomers, their equimolar blend, and the stereoblock form of PPrO exhibit regularly banded spherulites, observed using PLOM. In contrast, only the optically active polyenantiomers of PECH form banded spherulites, whereas the equimolar polyenantiomer blend and the stereoblock display nonbanded, coarser spherulites. The birefringent extinction banding pattern of the PECH optically pure polyenantiomer spherulites corresponds directly to the surface topography mapped by AFM: Regularly alternating concentric ridges and valleys indicate the edges and the fold surfaces, respectively, of the radiating helicoidal lamellae. The direction or "sense" of an apparent surface spiral pattern of a banded spherulite is directly dependent on the chiral sense of the constituent polyenantiomer. It is suggested that the effects of the backbone chirality are being transmitted to the level of the gross spherulite morphology. On the basis of the observed differences in crystallization kinetics and spherulite morphology among the well characterized PECH polymers, a mechanism of stereospecific segregation at the growth front is proposed.</description><creator>Singfield, Kathy L. (Kathy Lee)</creator><contributor>Brown, G. Ronald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Crystallization and morphology of optically active polyethers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q64q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301287t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq382</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bovine fibroblasts and epithelial cells were isolated from surgically biopsied mammary tissue. Characterization of population doubling time, cytoskeletal intermediate filaments, cryopreservation survival, and viability were performed on all fibroblast and epithelial cells. Several clonal fibroblast cell lines were cotransfected with a plasmid bearing the SV-40 Large-T-antigen, and the pSV-2 neo plasmid. Transfected cells were subsequently selected with G418 sulfate and cloned. MAC-T cells and non-clonal primary bovine mammary epithelial cells proliferated in response to IGF-I, insulin, serum and serum albumin. MAC-T cells did not proliferate when cultured in EGF, estrogen, progesterone, estrogen+progesterone, growth hormone, prolactin, and only modest proliferation was obtained after TGF-$ alpha$ treatment. Subsequent experiments used serum, insulin or IGF-I (and its analogues) to stimulate cellular proliferation. Serum albumin was not added to serum-free media preparations since it stimulated cellular proliferation. TGF-$ beta$ receptors were characterized in MAC-T cells and normal fibroblasts. Affinity labelling studies revealed that MAC-T and MF-2 cells contained type I, II, and III autoregulatable receptors. Fibroblast proliferation, was inhibited 50% by TGF-$ beta$. TGF-$ beta$ inhibited MAC-T cellular proliferation at concentrations among the lowest ever reported, ED$ sb{ rm 50}$ = 4 pm. TGF-$ beta$ was not cytotoxic at concentrations 1000-fold higher. Retinoic acid (RA) also inhibited proliferation of MAC-T cells. Inhibition of proliferation did not occur when cells were growth stimulated by IGF-I analogues that do not bind IGFBPs. Unlike TGF-$ beta$, RA treatment increased IGFBP-2 and decreased IGFBP-3 protein expression by cells into media and on the cell's membrane. RA was cytotoxic at concentrations 10-fold higher than ED$ sb{100}$. Fibroblasts and epithelial cells expressed the gap junction (GJ) protein, connexin43, with transformed fibroblasts expressing significantly less connexin43. Perinuclear and cell surface connexin43 was immunodetected in epithelial and fibroblasts cells. TGF-$ beta$, RA or cAMP, increased connexin43 protein expression, especially phosphorylated species. Only cAMP noticeably altered immunolocalization patterns of connexin43, causing a shift from perinuclear pools to the cell surface. None of the growth inhibitors affected GJ communication as measured by dye transfer. Therefore, mammary epithelial cells are growth inhibited by TGF-$ beta$ and RA by distinct mechanisms and both growth inhibitors significantly enhance the gap junction protein, connexin43, without increasing GJ communication.</description><creator>Woodward, Terry L.</creator><contributor>Laird, Dale W. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Turner, Jeffrey D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Cells -- Growth -- Regulation.</subject><subject>Transforming growth factors.</subject><subject>Retinoids.</subject><subject>Udder.</subject><subject>Cell interaction.</subject><title>Inhibition of cellular proliferation by retinoids and transforming growth factor-betas in bovine mammary cells correlates with increased connexin43 expression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c59g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq382</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r9675197</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A modeling technique for simulating the fatigue behaviour of laminated composite materials with or without stress concentrations, called progressive fatigue damage modeling, is established. The model is capable of simulating the residual stiffness, residual strength and fatigue life of composite laminates with arbitrary geometry and stacking sequence under complicated fatigue loading conditions. The model is an integration of three major components: stress analysis, failure analysis, and material property degradation rules. A three-dimensional, nonlinear, finite element technique is developed for the stress analysis. By using a large number of elements near the edge of the hole and at layer interfaces, the edge effect has been accounted for. Each element is considered to be an orthotropic material under multiaxial state of stress. Based on the three-dimensional state of stress of each element, different failure modes of unidirectional ply under multiaxial states of stress are detected by a set of fatigue failure criteria. An analytical technique, called the generalized residual material property degradation technique, is established to degrade the material properties of failed elements. This analytical technique removes the restriction of the application of failure criteria to limited applied stress ratios. Based on the model, a computer code is developed that simulates cycle-by-cycle behaviour of composite laminates under fatigue loading. As the input for the model, the material properties (residual stiffness, residual strength and fatigue life) of unidirectional AS4/3501-6 graphite/epoxy material are fully characterized under tension and compression, for fiber and matrix directions, and under in-plane and out-of-plane shear in static and fatigue loading conditions. An extensive experimental program, by using standard experimental techniques, is performed for this purpose. Some of the existing standard testing methods are necessarily modified and improved. To validate the generalized residual material property degradation technique, fatigue behaviour of a 30-degrees off-axis specimen under uniaxial fatigue loading is simulated. The results of an experimental program conducted on 30-degrees off-axis specimens under uniaxial fatigue show a very good correlation with the analytical results. To evaluate the progressive fatigue damage model, fatigue behaviour of pin/bolt-loaded composite laminates is simulated as a very complicated example. The model is validated by conducting an experimental program on pin/bolt-loaded composite laminates and by experimental results from other authors. The comparison between the analytical results and the experiments shows the successful simulation capability of the model.</description><creator>Shokrieh, Mahmood M. (Mahmood Mehrdad)</creator><contributor>Lessard, L. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Progressive fatigue damage modeling of composite materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m82d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9675197</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw57d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Haemophilus influenzae type b (Hib) is a Gram-negative bacterium that causes meningitis in infants. A protein called porin of 341 amino acids, M$ rm sb{r}$ 37,782 daltons, is located in the outer membrane of Hib and allows for the diffusion into the periplasmic space of small solutes up to a molecular mass of 1400 daltons. Based on parameters of hydrophilicity and amphiphilicity a model for Hib porin was generated. The model proposed an organization of sixteen anti-parallel $ beta$-strands that traverse the outer membrane, eight long loops that connect the $ beta$-strands on one side and short turns on the other side. By flow cytometry, six out of a panel of nine monoclonal antibodies against Hib porin recognized amino acid sequences at the cell surface. Hib porin was purified and subjected to chemical and enzymatic digestions. The fragments were immunoblotted; N-terminal sequencing identified boundaries of fragments. C-terminal deletions of Hib porin generated in the baculovirus expression system identified C-terminal boundaries of monoclonal antibody reactivities. To map precisely the primary sequences to which these monoclonal antibodies bound, overlapping hexapeptides for the entire sequence of Hib porin were synthesized. These studies identified two surface-exposed regions in the mature sequence of Hib porin, amino acid residues 162-172 and 318-325. In the Hib porin model, these regions correspond to loops 4 and 8, respectively. Two regions between residues 112-126 (loop 3) and residues 148-153 were buried or inaccessible at the surface of the outer membrane. Recombinant Hib porin was expressed in Bacillus subtilis. The biophysical and immunological properties of this lipooligosaccharide-free recombinant Hib porin were compared with those of native Hib porin. In order to examine the role of loop 3, site-directed mutagenesis of the cloned Hib porin gene was undertaken. Six or twelve amino acid deletions in loop 3, expressed in a porin deletion strain, showed significant increase in sensitivities to several anti-microbial agents as compared to wild-type Hib porin. Deletion of twelve amino acids showed more pronounced phenotypes than deletion of six amino acids. Such mutagenesis experiments provided support to the notion that loop 3 in Hib porin folds back into the pore and produces a constriction of the channel.</description><creator>Srikumar, Ramakrishnan</creator><contributor>Coulton, James W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Topology of porin, the major outer membrane protein of Haemophilus influenzae type b</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0324558.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw57d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gh98p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Among the considerable manuscript production of the twelfth and thirteenth centuries, the Bible moralisee stands out by the number of miniatures and by the conception of the manuscript itself. The composition and many iconographical themes recall stained glass windows of contemporary cathedrals, such as Chartres, Sens, Bourges, or Canterbury in England. The manuscript of the Bible moralisee to which this study is partly dedicated, is located in the Treasury of the Toledo cathedral chapter in Spain. This study deals also with the duplicate copy which was realized soon afterwards. The interpretation and illustrations of the verses vary in number according to the books of the Bible. Though being one of the smallest biblical books, the Song of Solomon is given outstanding consideration, more than any other book in the Bible. The central theme--the espousal of the Bride and the Bridegroom, Christ and Ecclesia being its allegory--enjoyed a considerable success in medieval theology. It corresponded to the courtly love atmosphere of its time. Abundant commentary literature and the development of mariology made this book even more popular. About a quarter of the commentary illustrations are dedicated to the theme Christus-Ecclesia. Ecclesia, always crowned, holds the chalice which confirms her sacramental significance. In no other known iconographical medieval programme has Ecclesia such a position. The question raised by the problematic around this Bible is the eventual intention being at the origin of this order which, without any doubt, emanates from French royalty. Has it been produced to enhance the prestige of royalty? Is it a pedagogical work intended for the education of the royal children? Was it meant to be a royal political gift? The Ecclesia theme in the Bible is the exaltation of, or an hommage to the Church, spiritual or temporal, by the French royalty of the thirteenth century.</description><creator>Tuchscherer, Jean-Michel, 1942-</creator><contributor>Galavaris, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Catedral de Toledo. Treasury. Manuscript. 1</subject><subject>Bibliothèque nationale de France. Manuscript. Latin 11560.</subject><subject>Christian art and symbolism -- Medieval, 500-1500</subject><title>Sponsus - SponsaChristus - Ecclesia : the illustrations of the Song of Songs in the Bible moralisée de Saint-Louis, Toledo, Spain, Cathedral Treasury, Ms. 1 and Paris, Bibliothèque Nationale, Ms. lat. 11560</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn27d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gh98p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b265s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metal ion production by minerals alone and in pairs was studied by solution analysis, extraction with ethylene diamine tetraacetate (EDTA) and laser ion mass spectroscopy (LIMS) for combinations of pyrite, pyrrhotite, galena, and sphalerite. The effect of grinding, pH, and the presence of xanthate was studied. Metal ion transfer between sulphide minerals was determined. Metal ion production with minerals in pairs was different from that for single minerals. The amount of metal ion in solution followed a galvanic interaction model, increasing for the anodic mineral and decreasing for the cathodic mineral. However, from the EDTA extraction technique, the concentration of metal ions on the mineral surface increased for both minerals. The mechanism of additional metal ion production on the cathodic mineral is unclear, but may be related to reaction between the mineral and OH ions formed on the surface as a result of galvanic interaction. Metal ions transferred between two minerals in contact. In the case of pairing with pyrite, the larger proportion of Fe remained on pyrite, while 50% or more of Zn (from sphalerite) and Pb (from galena) transferred to pyrite. The effect of Pb ions on pyrite in the presence of xanthate, and diethylene triamine (DETA) was investigated by cyclic voltammetry, ex situ spectroelectrochemical analysis and zeta potential measurements. Once pyrite was contaminated by Pb ions, uptake of xanthate was promoted at pHs 9.2 and 10.5 with lime as pH modifier. The source of Pb--from solution or from contact with galena--was not a factor, and the effect was evident at Pb concentrations as low as 1 ppm. With soda ash as pH modifier, the effect of Pb was suppressed, perhaps due to formation of lead carbonate. The only xanthate product detected was dixanthogen, unless an initial potential less than $-$800 mV/SCE was imposed (when Pb$ sp{2+}$ is reduced to Pb$ sp0)$ and lead xanthate formed. Xanthate adsorption on Pb-contaminated pyrite was suppressed by DETA, but relatively large concentrations were required. DETA decreased the potential at the mineral/solution interface, which retarded oxidation of xanthate to dixanthogen. A mechanism of Pb "activation" of pyrite was proposed: adsorption of Pb(OH)$ sp+$ on pyrite provided sites for xanthate adsorption forming Pb(OH)X, on which xanthate ions were attached by hydrophobic interaction and oxidised to dixanthogen.</description><creator>Sui, Chihyu Caroline</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Metal ion transfer between sulphide minerals and effect on xanthate interaction with pyrite</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw18b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b265s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34825</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>