<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:32:49Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh923</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the etiology of pancreatitis, the activation of pancreatic trypsinogen by bile has been a controversial subject. In this experiment, an in vitro study was performed to determine if bile from human diseased gall bladders would activate canine trypsinogen. The influence of Calcium, E. coli, Strep. fecalis and trypsin inhibitor substance was also partially studied. The determinations for trypsin were made using the synthetic substrate Benzyol-L-Arginine ethyl ester. From this study, it was concluded that bile from human diseased gall bladders or human bile obtained from T-tubes following common bile duct explorations would not activate canine trypsinogen. Calcium was found to be of great importance in determining the amount of trypsin formed. With the addition of excess calcium to the pancreatic juice, the presence of trypsin inhibitor in canine pancreatic juice did not prevent the measurement of 95% of the total trypsinogen present. The addition of E. coli or Strep. fecalis to bile did not activate canine trypsinogen. A review of the literature with respect to pancreatitis and the "Common Channel Theory" is included.</description><creator>Morrow, Donald R.</creator><contributor>Thompson, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Bile and related factors in the activation of pancreatic trypsinogen</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g66b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh923</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816q629</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les mesures de la concentration rénale de la rénine et de l'index de granularité des cellules juxta-glomérulaires effectuées chez le rat ont constitué un apport fondamental pour la compréhension du rôle physiologique et physiopathologique du système rénine-angiotensine. De nouveaux progrès pouvaient être attendus d'une méthode de mesure de l'Activité Rénine Plasmatique.</description><creator>Menard, Joel</creator><contributor>Genest, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Application of a new micro-method of measurement of plasma renin and angiotensinogen in rats to the study of various physiological conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c40g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q629</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj4307799</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two studies were performed in compensated cirrhotic patients with combined hepatic and umbilico-portal catheterization. Pressures were recorded in the hepatic vein, in the wedged (W.H.V.P.) and free (F.H.V.P.) positions and in the portal vein (F.P.V.P.). The F.P.V.P. - F.H.V.P. gradient was used as an index of portal hypertension. Plasma volume was measured with B.S.P. and I.C.G. in fifteen patients. A significant correlation was found between portal hypertension and the plasma volume in these patients.</description><creator>Marleau, Denis</creator><contributor>Viallet, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Portal hypertension in cirrhosis of the liver correlation with plasma volume and bleeding from esophageal varices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz74q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj4307799</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rc127</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study of changes produced by autotransplantation of the small intestine was performed by dividing animals into three series. In each, animals acted as their own control. Series I animals had the procedure of autotransplantation performed. Series II and III had operative procedures which duplicated a portion of the trauma inflicted on a bowel undergoing autotransplantation, i.e., interruption of nerves, lymphatics, and ischemia. Thus, attempting to qualitate the changes due to autotransplantation, animals were also divided into groups prefed an elemental diet and others fed standard kennel rations. Animals were studied pre and postoperatively by numerous tests to assess the changes produced. The study suggests that the marked changes seen histologically are due to a combination of denervation with the super-imposed insult of ischemia. The cell’s metabolic functions are not altered significantly by the procedures performed. Elemental diet does not appear to provide protection to the bowel against this mechanical type of insult.</description><creator>Mackie, George G.</creator><contributor>Hinchey, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Autotransplantation of the small intestine: a study of the changes observed and their possible pathogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128f19p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc127</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hg28n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies have shown that lung mechanics and blood gas exchange may be impaired during anaesthesia. Whether these changes are interrelated and whether they are time dependent in the course of anaesthesia is a controversial issue. Lung mechanics and blood Bases were studied throughout the course of anaesthesia in 30 patients undergoing cerebral angiography, starting before premedication and continuing into the recovery period, each subject acting as his mm control. Pre-medication (0.015 mg/kg atropine) did not affect Cdyn (1), Qs/Qt and A-aDO2. Induction of anaesthesia resulted in a significant fall in Cdyn (1), but no alteration in Qs/Qt or A-aDO2 at comparable FIO2 levels. There were no further changes up to 96 minutes after induction. Cdyn (1) returned ta preoperative values during the recovery period, and Qs/Qt and A-aDO2 remained unaffected. The fall in Cdyn (1) was believed to be due to closure of some units with a shift of blood away from these regions and/or to an alteration of surface forces without closure of units.</description><creator>Louzada, Ney</creator><contributor>Becklake, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Lung mechanics and blood gases during anaesthesia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fm33x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hg28n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bf86p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A phonocardiograph and microphone fixed on the chest wall, have been used to record normal breath sounds at controlled lung volumes and flow rates in different lung zones and body positions. Breath sounds intensity varied with lung volumes, flow rate, body position and the site of recording on the chest wall. In upright position, as well as the lateral decubitus position, the relative intensity of breath sounds was always maximal at low lung volumes when recorded at the upper parts of the lung, but this maximum was reached at higher lung volumes when recorded at dependent parts of the lung. Our results correlate well with the differences in regional distribution of ventilation studied with radioactive gases.</description><creator>Leblanc, Pierre</creator><contributor>Macklem, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Breath sounds and distribution of pulmonary ventilation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sd63j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf86p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xm75s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study substantiates that steroid enzymatic activities are found in the buffer medium in which adrenal sections (rat or bovine) have been preincubated (PIM). When fresh rat adrenal tissue was used, PIM exhibited 1/3 to 1/2 the capacity of the corresponding bisects to hydroxylate progesterone-4-14C in presence of NADP+G-6-P. Under these conditions, both preparations displayed similar capacities to metabolize cholesterol-4-14C. Prefreezing the tissues increased the cleavage activity in both PIM and bisects. Under these conditions the hydroxylation of progesterone-4-14C at C-11 decreased markedly in PIM. Collection of PIM in absence of oxygen decreased its capacity to utilize both substrates. Epinephrine did not enhance the enzymatic activity of bovine PIM. The studies suggest that active leakage is a contributing factor to the enzymatic activities in PIM.</description><creator>Keswani, Indra</creator><contributor>Carballeira, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Steroid enzymatic activities in adrenal preincubation media (PIM) under various experimental conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x692b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm75s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d5700838</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this research project was to study the effects of modifying factors on experimental polyarthritis in rats, produced by Freund's Adjuvant (Adjuvant Polyarthritis-A.P.). The effects of the following factors were studied: 1) Injection of Paraffin Oil (0.1 cc). 2) Blood transfusion from convalescent rats of A.P. 3) Splenectomy performed three weeks prior to induction of Adjuvant Polyarthritis. Experimental Polyarthritis was produced in female rats of Sprague- Dawley strain in the control group, by a single intradermal injection (0.1 cc) of Freund's Adjuvant into the tail; all animals developed the typical lesion of peripheral joints of the extremities, beginning from the second week and persisting to more than three months in 30%. Injection paraffin oil produced a 75-80% decrease in the incidence of A.P. when injected three weeks or three months prior to induction of A.P. Paraffin injection ID into the back was less effective. Transfusion of convalescent blood from animals suffering from A.P. produced a 70% decrease in the incidence. The most effective means of influencing A.P. was splenectomy (90% decrease in incidence). The severity of lesions (graded from 1-20) was also markedly effected, being 2.5 and 0.6 respectively, in the paraffin group: 1.2 in the convalescent blood transfusion group and 0.6 in the splenectomy group. It was concluded that various immunological mechanisms are capable of modifying the course and scoring of Adjuvant Polyarthritis in rats; the various theoretical considerations are given.</description><creator>Kwo, Chin</creator><contributor>Laurin, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The suppression of adjuvant disease: the spleen and adjuvant disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q84d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d5700838</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161937h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of strontium and calcium perfusion on liver glycogenesis and blood glucose levels was studied. Livers were perfused over 1 hour period at the rate of 0.1 ml./min. Chlorides of both metals and 1mM of glucose were dissolved in Tris-HCl buffer at pH 7.4. Glycogen was estimated by anthrone method, blood glucose by autoanalyser, and urine glucose by Tes-Tape. Elevation of liver glycogen content was found in 250 uM Sr group (Anthrone method), larger amount of PA-Shiff positive granules in 500 uM Sr. group when compared with controls. Statistically significant increase of incorporation of radioglucose into liver glycogen was detected in radioassay. Blood glucose was significantly elevated and urine contained 0.1 % or more of glucose in the 500uM Sr group. Decrease in the glycogen level was found in the 500uM Ca group, detectable by all methods, while 250uM Ca group was comparable with control in all aspects investigated. It is concluded that strontium perfusion at the dosage stated increases significantly blood glucose level. There are also indications by indirect methods that liver glycogen content is elevated.</description><creator>Kalinowski, Janusz</creator><contributor>Skoryna, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Some aspects of carbohydrate metabolism following metal ions liver perfusion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k563n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161937h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd64t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation was undertaken to find a method of anti-deoxyribonucleic acid (anti-DNA) antibody measurement more accurate and more direct than complement (C') fixation. Anti-DNA antibodies were produced in rabbits by immunization with complexes of denatured E. coli 0111 B DNA and methylated bovine serum albumin. Dilutions of normal rabbit serum and anti-DNA antiserum up to 1/320 fixed different amounts of C' with denatured DNA. Above this dilution the difference became negligible. Normal rabbit serum enhanced the DNA polymerase-catalysed incorporation of nucleotides into a DNA template, Anti-DNA antisera failed to give statistically significant suppression. Anti-DNA antibodies cou1d be measured by precipitation of labelled DNA - antibody complexes with 50% saturated ammonium sulphate. Anti-DNA and normal sera precipitated different amounts of denatured DNA at dilutions below 1/320. This precipitation test did not provide a method of anti-DNA antibody measurement more accurate than C' fixation.</description><creator>Eaton, Bryan T.</creator><contributor>Vas, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Studies on antideoxyribonucleic acid antibodies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rh532.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd64t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dg783</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Investigation of the effects of Metopirone on the in vitro transformation of various precursors of testosterone by rat testicular preparations has shown: 1) inhibition of the side-chain cleavage of cholesterol, demonstrated by isolation of the labeled metabolites (17α-hydroxyprogesterone, testosterone, 5α-androstane-3α,17β-diol) from incubations with cholesterol-4-14C, and by measuring liberated labeled isocaproic acid in experiments with cholesterol-26-14C. In both types of experiments the degree of inhibition was 60 – 70% (Metopirone 1 x 10^-3M), 2) the inbibitory action of the drug is clearly dose-related, 3) the inhibition was not reversible by increasing exogenous supplementation (NADPH-generating system), 4) freezing of testicular tissue lowered overall conversion of cholesterol, without influencing the degree of inhibition, 5) conversion of pregnenolone-4-14C was inhibited by Metopirone (1 x 10^-3M) both in the presence of a NADPH-generating system (by 20%) and NAD (by 30%), 6) significant inhibition of the C-17 - C-20 lyase (Netopirone 1 x 10^-3M: 37%), 7) Metopirone influences the distribution pattern of reduced metabolites of testosterone.</description><creator>Durnhofer, Ferdinand</creator><contributor>Carballeira, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Effects of metopirone on various steps of the cholesterol testosterone biosynthetic sequence in rat testicular preparations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g67m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dg783</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk62q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neuroanatomists, using a variety of techniques, have demonstrated ascending fibers from the medial 2/3 of the brain stem reticular formation (RF). Neurophysiological studies by other investigators have shown that the nucleus gigantocellularis of the medulla is a relay in the spinoreticulothalamic pathway to nucleus centre median (CM). In the present work the midbrain reticular projection to CM was studied in the cat by means of unit and evoked pot entail analysis using a computer of average transients. Most CM units which responded to stimulation of the midbrain RF exhibited a pattern of early activation-inhibition and sometimes later activation. Units which were also tested with peripheral stimulation showed a similar response. The convergence of impulses from peripheral and midbrain stimulation is demonstrated by facilitation and occlusion of the slow wave response evoked in CM. The possible reticular pathways and the functional significance of the reticulothalamic projection are discussed.</description><creator>Dila, Carl J.</creator><contributor>Gloor, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery.</subject><title>A midbrain projection to the centre median nucleus of the thalamus: a neurophysiological study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb44n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk62q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts26w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Authorities in the field of lignin chemistry have agreed that the lignin complex is an extremely sensitive material which is chemically changed during isolation by mineral acids or alkalies, by acidulated organic solvents, by hot sulfite solutions or by many other reagents. Since present methods of isolating lignin involve such drastic treatments, the products probably bear only an indirect structural relationship to lignin "in situ". In consequence, very little is known of the nature of lignin as it exists in wood. The problem of isolating unchanged lignin seems to depend upon the development of methods that avoid drastic conditions of acidity and temperature.</description><creator>Ritchie, Paul Forrest.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Preparation and properties of periodate lignins.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397c41r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts26w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p782s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carbonic acid and carbonic acid combined with freezing and thawing, extract considerably less, and 0.5N hydrochloric acid only slightly more potassium from Greensboro pasture soil, than does extraction with\ ammonium acetate. The hydrochloric acid extraction indicates that this soil has a low supply of so-called moderately available potassium. Experiments with samples of fertilized Greensboro loam show little variation in the moderately available fraction.</description><creator>Robertson, William Kitchener.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W.(Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>A chemical study of some of the factors affecting the availability of potassium in soils.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z144.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p782s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945v10h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of the Jews in the schools of the Province of Quebec is a part of the general and educational history of the Province for the past century; an historical description is therefore needed for an adequate understanding of the present situation of the Jewish minority in the educational system of Quebec. The main problem throughout the compilation of this work has been the difficulty in obtaining and verifying data. The available bibliography and source material are restricted in quantity and extremely limited in character.</description><creator>Ross, Harold.</creator><contributor>Hughes, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Jews -- Canada.</subject><subject>Jews -- Education.</subject><title>The Jew in the educational system of the Province of Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r628x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v10h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82kb45x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>will deal with a group of i.atients afflicted with a particularly severe trauma, and, it is hoped, some light may be thrown on the means whereby a more successful treatment and rehabilitation can be affected. The patients in question are a group of Paraplegics.</description><creator>Dörken, Herbert.</creator><contributor>Alexander, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Paraplegia -- Québec (Province) -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Paraplegics -- Québec (Province) -- Hospital care.</subject><title>Personality factors associated with paraplegia.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt02r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kb45x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n39x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The preceding paragraphs have indicated the belt of townships under discussion and attention has been drawn to the early and most recent work, both in prospecting and geological surveying, that has been done in these areas.This thesis is a study to correlate published information on the belt of townships between the Porcupine District on the west, and the Beattie Mine Area in Duparquet township on the east. Most of the information has been compiled from Annual Reports of the Ontario Department of Mines. The sources of such information will be listed in the bibliography.</description><creator>Cunnington, Frank Albert.</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Porcupine-Beattie gold belt.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r1810.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n39x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000003203</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An area has been mapped in detail in the vicinity of the Box property ih the Goldfields district. The oldest formations are quartzites, dolomites, and various schists and gneisses. These are cut by granites and gabbros. The distribution and metamorphism of the rocks of the area are described. Cooke has considered the gabbro as younger than the granite, but the writer agrees with Alcock in considering the granite younger than the gabbro. The problem of the "Box granite" is discussed. The writer has shown that this" formation is composite, and has separated.on.the map gr.anitized sedimentary rocks from granites.</description><creator>Christie, Archibald Mowatt.</creator><contributor>Jolliffe, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The geology of the Goldfields area, Saskatchewan.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wt643.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000003203</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xm762</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Knowledge o£ the importance or a nutritional factor in the etiology of rickets may be said to date from the pioneer work of Mellanby in 1919. The therapeutic value of fish oils tor rickets. although recognized for centuries~ was shown to be due to a factor quite distinct from vitamin A. The exact identity of the factor. however~ was obscured for some time when it was found that sunlight and ultraviolet irradiation also had curative effects. In 1926 accidental discovery of the role of cholesterol and related sterols made it possible to conclude that sunlight and cod liver oil cure rickets because sunlight produces in the skin the sarne (or a similar) vitamin which cod liver oil provides ready made.</description><creator>Campbell, James Alexander.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the chick assay for vitamin D and some observations on chemical methods for its determination.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw97j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm762</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cp01b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A period of devastating war has ended. The identification of the. period that follows must await the passing of time. True and prosperous peace, depressed and stagnant peace amidst want and privation, ar.med peace with the spectre of war hovering ever in the background mark the range of possibilities. The battlefield period of World War II is concluded, the military has passed to public administrators the responsibilities for the conclusion of World War II in the economic sphere.</description><creator>Bush, Willard Schryer.</creator><contributor>Vineberg, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Industries -- Canada -- Finance.</subject><subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Economic aspects -- Canada.</subject><title>The effects of World War II upon the financial position of Canadian corporate industry.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z1328.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp01b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623g68w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It would appear, from a review of the literature on trichinosis, that the majority of the experiments, concerning the effects of chemical and physica~ agents on larvae of Trichinella spiralis, have been carried out, in vivo. On the other hand, in vitro studies of this nature have been relatively few in number, and information is therefore rather meagre. Possibly the differences of opinion, among the workers, in this. field, as to the value or such experiments, may account for the dearth of knowledge in this regard.</description><creator>Marchant, Edwin Howard James.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>Quantitative studies on the larvae of Trichinella Spiralis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g695.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623g68w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rh54b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The drying of foods was widely employed by ancient people as a means of food preservation. The original techniques were extremely crude but during the succeeding centuries the methods were gradually modified and improved. As is often the case with progress, the growth of the dried food industry in recent times has been motivated by war-time needs. These requirements have accelerated the development of improved dehydrating processes, which have resulted in products of relatively high quality.</description><creator>Moster, Julius Bernard.</creator><contributor>Chapman, R.(Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the chemical changes in the protein and carbohydrate fractions of milk powders during storage.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000321c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh54b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547v641</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Canica-Cawatose area is from 47° 15' N to 47° 30 1 N latitude, and from 76° 55' w to 77° 20' w longitude, and is thus between the gold bearing district of the Abitibi and the Grenville subprovince as characteristically exposed near Mount Laurier. G.K. Lowther has mapped Keewatin-type and Temiskaming-type rocks characteristic of the Abitibi zone in the Villebon-Denain area at a locality only twenty miles north of the northern boundry of the map area here described.</description><creator>Wahl, William George.</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological, Sciences.</subject><title>Canica-Cawatose map area.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj67h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547v641</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sg75f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An airscrew windmill has been designed for use in the north east trade wind regime of the Caribbean, which is shown to be particularly favourable for agricultural irrigation purposes. The high-speed fixed-pitch airscrew incorporates the most recent aerodynamic theory and is manufactured from fibre-glass reinforced epoxy resin. To compete with conventional prime movers high efficiency, low cost and long life are maintained by the use of standard industrial and automotive transmission components. The strength of the blades and supporting structure has been confirmed by structural proof tests. Field tests, in which the windmill was connected to a standard deep-well turbine pump for sprinkler irrigation, have been made to determine the aerodynamic integrity of the airscrew design. The detailed performance characteristics obtained over an extended operating range provide a guide for wind pumping performance prediction purposes in water resource development programmes in the Caribbean and elsewhere.</description><creator>Chilcott, Richard E.</creator><contributor>Broughton, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Agricultural Engineering.</subject><title>The design, development and testing of a low cost, 10 hp windmill prime mover</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x4496.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sg75f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977z15d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neutral and acidic fluid instillation tests were carried in dog denervated corpus gastric pouches with and without topical treatment of the pouches by saline or urea solutions to delineate the ionic fluxes involved with gastric mucosal competence and acidity regulation. Results showed a bidirectional chloride ion flux. The flux of chloride from lumen to mucosa was independent of the type of cation but seemed to be constant for the luminal concentration of chloride. Treatment with four molar urea solution results in the loss of the ability, of the pouch to contain an acid solution, the gastric mucosal competence. Weaker urea solution treatments result in only an influx of sodium chloride containing fluid into the pouch. The exact mechanism of gastric mucosal competence and acidity regulation could not be delineated but a probable mechanism is suggested.</description><creator>Chambers, Robert T.</creator><contributor>Wlodek, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Ionic fluxes in gastric pouches</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473059z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977z15d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>