<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:29:03Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bp730</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A significant deficit in concentration of cytochrome P-450 and in activity of drug-oxidative and electron transport enzymes in liver microsomes of newborn rats and rabbits has been shown. In rats, the rate of maturational development of drug-oxidative activity appears to be limited by development of electron transfer capacity, while in rabbits there is a closer relationship between increasing drug oxidation and increasing microsomal concentration of P-450. In immature male rats, NADPR cytochrome P-450 reductase activity increases more gradually than microsomal P-450 and consequently drug oxidation remains below adult levels until 5 weeks of age although P-450 reaches adult concentration by 3 weeks of age. This underdevelopment of mechanisms for the reduction of P-450 may be partly overcome in vitro through enhancement of NADPR cytochrome P-450 reductase by a Type l substrate (aminopyrine). Phenobarbital has been shown to "induce" all components of hepatic microsomal drug metabolism to adult levels or greater within 2 weeks of birth and this implies that the gene-expression system in the newborn rat hepatocyte is complete and capable of full synthetic activity in response to appropriate exogenous or endogenous stimuli. Preliminary data from humans suggest age-related deficiencies in hepatic microsomal drug oxidation and electron transport during infancy and during the sixth decade of life.</description><creator>MacLeod, Stuart M.</creator><contributor>Eade, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</subject><title>Hepatic microsomal drug oxidation and electron transport in immature rats, rabbits and humans.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nb96k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bp730</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848t64c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies of the relative incorporation of palmitate and glycerol, or glucose or choline revealed that more palmitate than the other subtrates is recovered as dipalmitoyl lecithin (DPC) indicating that DPC is not formed exclusively by de nova synthesis. Although in homogenates DPC is formed by the de novo synthesis pathway, the direct acylation of palmitoyl lysophosphatidyl choline (PLPC) with palmitoyl-CoA, and the intertransacylation of two molecules of PLPC, it appears some palmitate is esterified even in the absence of added PLPC, ATP and CoA, suggesting an additional pathway. Free palmitate exchanges with fatty acids esterified in lecithin, especially oleate, in both lung slices and homogenates. In homogenates, Ca++ (and probably Mg++) is required for the palmitate: oleate exchange. The lung contains sufficient l-palmitoyl-2-oleyl-lecithin to support this mechanism. It is concluded that palmitate is incorporated into DPC by exchange with oleate in l-palmitoyl-2-oleyl lecithin. It appears this involves two mechanisms, both of which my involve phospholipase A2. In vivo studies are consistent with this postulate.</description><creator>Keyi-Aboagye, Kwabena.</creator><contributor>Rubinstein, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Alternate pathways for the biosynthesis of diplamitoyl lecithin in the adult rabbit lung.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74ct74c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t64c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kn71b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An exonuclease and an endonuclease from N. crassa, highly specific for single-stranded nucleic acids, were used in structural studies on DNA. The exonuclease was used in the identification of repetitive sequences in E. coli DNA. Sheared, denatured E. coli DNA was annealed at 600 at a Cot of land treated with the exonuclease. Approximately 8% of the DNA was recovered as renatured, double-stranded DNA by chromatography on methylated albumin kieselguhr. This DNA was denatured a second time and annealed at various Cot values; about 40% ( 3% of the starting material ) reassociated at rates faster thon the total DNA indicating that a small portion of the E. coli genome comprises a heterogeneous collection of repetitive sequences. The endonuclease "nicked" UV-irradiated native DNA faster than unirradiated DNA; increasing doses of UV resulted in an increase in the nucleolytic activity. These results suggest that the endonuclease may be involved in an excision repair process. Superhelical RF 1 DNA was more sensitive to the action of the endonuclease than nonsuperhelical DNA suggesting that single-stranded regions may occur in superhelical DNA. The effects of UV-irradiation on superhelical DNA were also studied. The results of this investigation support the theory that superhelical DNA contains negative twists.</description><creator>Kato, Ann C.</creator><contributor>Fraser, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Structural studies on DNA using two single-strand specific nucleases from Neurospora crassa.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt42b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn71b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x2271</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A series of studies was undertaken with the aim of specifying the mechanisms responsible for age-related improvement in auditory short-term memory. Developmental trends were sought in both the post-linguistic and precategorical storage systems for children from grades three, five, and seven. The techniques of temporal grouping and running memory span were employed to evaluate the sensitivity of rehearsal strategies to changes with age. The stimulus suffix paradigm was used to uncover developmental changes in the precategorical storage system. The results suggest that spontaneous rehearsal strategies undergo significant developmental changes. Evidence for age-related changes in the precategorical storage system is not compelling. It is proposed that developmental changes in the post-linguistic rather than the precategorical storage system constitute the primary determinant of age-related improvement in auditory short-term memory.</description><creator>Frank, Hallie S.</creator><contributor>Rabinovitch, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>Mechanisms involved in developmental changes in auditory short-term memory.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182p124.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x2271</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c1378</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The properties and mechanisms of the dehydrohalogenation of haloalkanes on atomically clean surfaces of the first row transition metals have been investigated. To compare the properties of these metals, haloalkanes were selected from the catalytic (HX and olefin generated) and non-catalytic (all chlorine retained by surface) classes previously detected on titanium. The former reactions were similar on halided surfaces of all the metals. Kinetics and activation parameters were determined. Although all the chloride was retained during each reaction in the latter category, surface deactivation occurred rapidly for all the metals except titanium and manganese. Where possible, reaction order and activation parameters were determined. Initial reactions on unreacted or lightly reacted surfaces were also studied and three types of behavior detected: dehydrohalogenation, retentive adsorption and hydrogenation. Reaction mechanisms on halided surfaces were studied by time and concentration order determinations, halo-exchange experiments, examining the effect of reaction products and studying the specificity of halided surfaces for certain reactions.</description><creator>Egan, Robert W.</creator><contributor>Harrod, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Reactions of gaseous haloalkanes on clean transition metal surfaces.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dj71b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c1378</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mm96j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work presented in this thesis describes a method for the isolation of an antihistamine-like substance (KC-18) from the Hungarian oak gall extracts. Data obtained concerning the structure of KC-18 strongly suggested that it is an ester of piperonylic acid. In animal experiments, KC-18 was found to antagonize the actions of histamine in a dose-related manner when tested by the aerosol and capillary permeability methods. KC-18 also exerted anti-anaphylactic activity in actively sensitized guinea pigs. In addition, KC-18 inhibited histamine-induced hypotension and gastric acid secretion, but it could not antagonize the histamine-induced contraction of the isolated guinea pig ileum. The investigations also resulted in obtaining a highly purified oak gall extract which exerted potent anti-inflammatory activity in rats when tested by the carrageenan-induced paw edema test. The pretreatment of rats with this purified oak gall extract also partially protected the animals from the subsequent development of polyarthritis induced by the injection of mycobacterial adjuvant.</description><creator>Chu, David C.</creator><contributor>Kovacs, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Isolation of biologically active substances from oak galls exerting antihistaminic and anti-inflammatory activity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55zb852.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm96j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dg72f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The electron microscope, with or without radioautography, was used to examine the life history of the four cell types of the epithelium of the small intestine: columnar, mucous, argentaffin and Paneth cells. All four are derived from epithelial cells which are rich in free ribosomes and therefore, considered to be immature; they are situated next to Paneth cells at the base of the crypts. Young stages of each cell type are similar to the immature epithelial cells. This resemblance is gradually lost with age as the cells migrated away from the crypt base. Columnar and mucous cells behave in a similar way. Young cells are proliferative; as they mature they migrate up the villi and are lost into the lumen of the intestine. Most young argentaffin cells are not proliferative. Mature cells are also lost from the population via the villous tips. Paneth cells do not proliferate nor migrate but degenerate in situ and are phagocytosed by adjacent immature epithelial cells.</description><creator>Cheng, Hazel P.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1973</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Origin and renewal of the four types of epithelial cells in the mouse small intestine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p129j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dg72f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096b10z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Immunity to Salmonella typhimurium was investigated in a susceptible (C57BI/6J) and a resistant (A/J) strain of mice. Macrophages were compared for their phagocytic and bactericidal capacities. The effect of antibody on these activities was a also studied. Normal macrophages of both strains were equally phagocytic but those of the susceptible strain were twice as bactericidal as those of the resistant strain. Therefore, susceptibility in this instance did not result from inability of macrophages to phagocytize or to kill the organism. Macrophages from resistant animals intensively immunized with a phenol-killed vaccine demonstrated increased bactericidal activity in the absence of specific antibody. Similar immunization did not increase macrophage bactericidal activity in susceptible animals, but activity was enhanced by antibody. Immunity was, therefore, conferred by the combined activities of macrophages and antibodies. Initially, host macrophages restrict bacterial multiplication allowing development of a more potent bactericidal mechanism. The latter involves development of increased bactericidal capacity by macrophages and production of antibodies which act synergistically with them.</description><creator>Rose, Esmie A.</creator><contributor>Vas, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Microbiology.</subject><title>Experimental salmonellosis in mice: studies on the nature of the immunity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v99j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b10z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fp872</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mitochondrial monoamine oxidase (MAO) activity of livers from rats deficient in iron, copper or both those elements was compared with the activity in livers from normal rats. The activities towards isoamylamine, tyramine and benzylamine were studied by means of oxygen uptake using an oxygen electrode. MAO activity of the livers decreased significantly (P &lt; 0.01) when the levels of liver iron decreased. Copper-deficiency had no effect on the enzyme. Expired radioactivity collected from rats injected with [1-14C]n-pentylamine (5 microCi/kg) was measured as l4CO2 . The rate of catabolism of the amine decreased progressively in iron deficient rats, reaching about 60% of control values in 3 weeks. Feeding with iron yielded normal rates within 6 days. Catabolism of amyl alcohol, which shares a common pathway with n-pentylamine via valeraldehyde, was unaffected by iron-deficiency. These results are consistent with a function of iron in the maintenance of normal MAO activity in vivo. Some iron chelators and hemolytic agents also inhibited MAO. Polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis of the partly purified enzyme showed that MAO exists in multiple forms.</description><creator>Symes, Aston L.</creator><contributor>Sourkes, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Effects of deficiencies of iron, copper and riboflavin in the rat on monoamine oxidase activity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9999695.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fp872</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sk36t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous avons étudié le métabolisme in vivo de la l4alpha-hydroxytestostérone chez un volontaire à qui l'on a administré la l4C-14alpha-hydroxytestostérone par voie intraveineuse et la l4alpha-hydroxytestostérone non-marquée par voie buccale. Le substrat a été converti en un seul métabolite urinaire identifié comme étant la 3alpha, 14alpha-dihydroxy-5beta-androstan-17-one. Dans une autre étude, la l5alpha-hydroxyprègnénolone a été isolée de l'urine de grossesse du troisième trimestre. Dans deux expériences separées, le taux d'excrétion de ce steroide était de 2.1 et 3.6 pg par jour. Nous avons isolé des métabolites marqués des tissues des fétus injectés de la testostérone-14C. Les métabolites ont été isolés des placentas, des surrénales et des foies. Dans le foie, la conversion de la testostérone en 5beta-androstanediol chez les fétus féminins etait quelques 50% plus élevée que celle observée dans les fétus masculins. En utilisant des cultures primaires du foie fétal humain, la testostérone a été converti en l'androsténedione et l'étiocholanolone tandis que dans les sous-cultures, l'androstenedione a été le seul métabolite identifiable de la testostérone.</description><description>The in vivo metabolism of 14alpha-hydroxytestosterone in man was studied by the intravenous injection of 4-l4C-14alpha-hydroxytestosterone and the simultaneous oral administration of non-labelled l4alpha-hydroxytestosterone. The administered steroid was converted to a single urinary metabolite identified as 30alpha, 14alpha-dihydroxy-5beta-androstan-17-one. In another study, l5alpha-hydroxypregnenolone was isolated from two pools of late pregnancy urine. The excretion rate of this steroid was found to be 2.1 and 3.6 micrograms/day. In order to study the sex difference in metabolism of testosterone by the human midterm fetus, the labelled steroid was injected into the umbilical circulation at the time of laparotomy. Estrone and estradiol were isolated from the placentas; testosterone and llbeta-hydroxyandrostenedione from the adrenals; and testosterone, androstenedione, 5beta-androstanedione, etiocholanolone, androsterone and 5alpha- and 5beta-androstanediol from the livers. Etiocholanolone and 5beta-androstanediol were also isolated from the sulfate and glucuronide fractions of the livers. The conversion of testosterone to unconjugated 5beta-androstanediol in the livers of the female fetuses was some 50% higher than that observed in livers of male fetuses, although this sex difference was not manifested in the conjugated forms of 5beta-androstanediol. Using primary cultures of human fetal liver, testosterone was converted to androstenedione and etiocholanolone, while in subcultures, androstenedione was the only identifiable metabolite.</description><creator>Stern, Michael D.</creator><contributor>Solomon, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Studies on testosterone and ring D hydroxylated steroids in human pregnancy.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv86d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sk36t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz130</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two different sets of experiments are described in this thesis. When labeled pregnenolone was injected into the umbilical vein of a Rhesus monkey with the fetus in utero, the substrate was not metabolized to any extent in any of the tissues examined except in the liver. 3Beta-Hydroxy-5alpha-pregnan-20-one was isolated from the fetal heart, intestine, liver and from the placenta. Also, the conversion of pregnenolone to progesterone by the fetal liver was demonstrated. In another set of experiments, non-labeled and labeled l5alpha-hydroxydehydroisoandrosterone was synthesized chemically from l5alpha-hydroxyandrostenedione. After the isolation of 1.76 and 3.20 microgram/day of l5alpha-hydroxydehydroisoandrosterone from human late pregnancy urine, the metabolism of this compound together with l5alpha-hydroxyandrostenedione was studied in pregnant subjects. Following the intravenous injection of a mixture of 3H-l5alpha-hydroxyandrostenedione and l4C-l5alpha-hydroxydehydroisoandrosterone into two subjects in the third trimester of pregnancy, it was shown that the latter precursor was converted to urinary l5alpha-hydroxyandrostenedione, l5alpha-hydroxyestradiol and l5alpha-hydroxyestriol. However, l5alpha-hydroxyandrostenedione was a more efficient precursor of urinary l5alpha-hydroxyestradiol and l5alpha-hydroxyestriol than l5alpha-hydroxydehydroisoandrosterone. These findings were confirmed when the same substrates were introduced into two fetuses in utero during transfusion for erythroblastosis fetalis.</description><creator>Stanczyk, Frank Z.</creator><contributor>Solomon, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on the metabolism of pregnenolone in the pregnant rhesus monkey and 15alpha-hydroxylated steroids in human pregnancy.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827f72k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz130</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816q51s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an attempt to provide a theoretical and empirical model of the reserve holding behaviour of developing countries in the context of their efforts at economic development. In principle, the basic determinants of desired level of reserves turn out to be not only the levels of such variables as exports, aid/capital flows, lines of credit and the opportunity cost of holding reserves, but also the standard deviation of these variables. In order to make the theory amenable to empirical testing, use is made of an adjustment mechanism by which countries adjust their actual stocks of reserves to their desired levels in terms of a distributed lag analysis. Using data for the 1951 - 1965 period, our empirical analysis indicates that, on the average, developing countries are able to complete only less than half of the desired change in their reserves each year; that the reserve-import ratio is a more reasonable decision variable than the absolute level of reserves; and that, in the short run, the critical determinants are past reserve holdings and the current level of the ratio of capital goods imports to total imports, a "development" variable used as a proxy for the opportunity cost of holding reserves. On individual country basis, however, the above generalizations break down.</description><creator>Otchere, Danny K.</creator><contributor>Handa, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>The reserve holding behaviour of developing countries.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n032.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q51s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m992q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of the extracellular, dialysable nephrotoxin produced by a group A type 12 streptococcus on the rabbit was studied critically for the similarities to human acute glomerulonephritis. Nephrotoxin-treated rabbits have been found to have renal changes upon light and electron microscopic observations. In the latter case, numerous "humps" and cellular proliferation and edema were evident in the glomeruli. No consistent glomerular deposition of autologous gamma globulin could be found by using immunofluorescence microscopy. No alterations in serum complement activity were noted. Chemical characterisation of purified nephrotoxin was performed by end-group analysis, ultraviolet, fluorometric and infrared spectroscopy and quantitative assays, and following acid hydrolysis by thin-layer, paper and gas-liquid chromatography. Nephrotoxin is found in a semi-purified extract consisting chiefly of polypeptides but itself upon further purification appears to be a substance containing a prominent substituted aromatic or heterocyclic residue.</description><creator>Ng, Wei-wei.</creator><contributor>Matheson, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Experimental streptococcal glomerulonephritis in rabbits and further studies on the nature of nephrotoxin.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g565g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m992q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts207</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sheep beta-Lipotropic Hormone (beta-LPH) caused an increase in free fatty acids (FFA) levels in rabbits. Beta-LPH also produced hypocalcemia. In thyroidectomized rabbits beta-LPH administration caused lipolysis but did not affect the calcium. The lipolytic response of thyroidectomized rabbits was lower than the lipolytic response in normal rabbits. During the lipolysis induced by beta-LPH accumulation of calcium in fat tissue both in vitro and in vivo has been observed. Experiments with 45Ca++ and 3H-mannitol as well as the uptake of calcium by isolated fat cells are in favor of the view that calcium accumulates in fat cells rather than in the extracellular space. Beta-LPH stimulated the adenyl cyclase in isolated rat and rabbit fat cells. Stimulation of lipolysis by beta-LPH as well as the stimulation of adenyl cyclase by beta-LPH was demonstrated as calcium dependent. Differences in adenyl cyclase systems of rabbit and rat adipose tissue cells were described.</description><creator>Lis, Martin.</creator><contributor>Genest, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Physiological effects of beta-lipotropic hormone.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb450.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts207</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92gb34n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although strychnine and thebaine have very similar convulsant actions, mixtures of the two drugs were found to interact infra-additively in intact mice. It was established that this interaction also occurs at the postsynaptic inhibitory synapses on motoneurons in the cat spinal cord. Thebaine diminishes reflex inhibition, just as strychnine does. The drug also blocks direct, recurrent, and polysynaptic IPSP without altering membrane resting potential, resistance or potassiun permeability. No effect of thebaine on spinal synaptic transmission was discovered which could produce a physiological antagonism of the anti-inhibitory action of strychnine. It was concluded that the mechanism of the anti-inhibitory action of thebaine and strychnine is very similar and their interaction is probably a reflection of the competition of the two drugs for the same receptor site in the inhibitory synapse.</description><creator>Laskey, Wendy.</creator><contributor>Esplin, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Esplin, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</subject><title>A study on the mechanism of the interaction between strychnine and thebaine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t2368.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb34n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r171r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The chronological formation and development of three rat spermatozoon head components - the nucleus, acrosomic system and perinuclear theca - were investigated by electron microscopy during spermiogenesis and transit through the epididymis. Chromatin condensation involves an intermediate step of coarse chromatin filament formation. Coarse filaments aggregate into coarse chromatin clumps which, in turn, fuse into a dense homogeneous mass late in spermiogenesis. The completely formed acrosomic system is composed of the acrosome and head cap, both enclosed in a continuous unit membrane, and a separated portion of the head cap called the ventral flap running on the antero-ventral part of the head. During spermiogenesis, the acrosome and head cap are formed as distinct morphological entities, and the ventral flap ls split off from the head cap during step 14 of spermiogenesis. Perinuclear material forms adjacent to the nucleus in three areas which eventually become connected. The material of this continuous layer condenses during the last steps 18 and 19 of spermiogenesis to form the perinuclear theca, a continuous layer over the nucleus except around the attachment site of the flagellum.</description><creator>Lalli, Michael F.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>The head of the rat spermatozoon and its formation during spermiogenesis: an electron microscopic study.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m2513.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r171r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569737s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis traces the birth and growth of the stream of consciousness method in English fiction, paying particular attention to the way it has been handled by such literary artists as Dorothy Richardson, Virginia Woolf, and the late Katherine Mansfield. Chapter One deals with the growth of Modern Subjective fiction, from the writing of Henry James to that of James Joyce. Chapter Two endeavours to show how Dorothy Richardson has used the method in her series of novels, Pilgrimage. Throughout the ten volumes she has never gone outside the consciousness of her main character, Miriam Henderson. Chapter Three deals with Mrs. Woolf's experiments which have demonstrated with variations of technique, what heights of sensitive artistry the stream of consciousness can attain. Chapter Four studies the work of the late Katherine Mansfield, who by introducing the stream of consciousness method into the short story, has created original beauty and fresh technical resources in that medium.</description><creator>Milburne, Kathleen Estey.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1934</date><subject>ENGLISH FICTION -- HISTORY AND CRITICISM</subject><title>The stream of consciousness in recent English fiction by women.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z3934.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569737s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02871012w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electrophysiological studies with extracellular macro- and micro-electrodes in 58 cats revealed spontaneous rhythmic oscillations in the interpeduncular nucleus, ranging tram 3 - 4 HZ to 9 - 10 Hz under different anaesthetics. There was little obvious correlation between these waves and the spontaneous firing patterns of interpeduncular units. Possible origins of the waves are discussed. Stimulation of the habenula evoked in the nucleus brief positive-negative waves followed by a slow negative, and then a slow positive wave. The majority of interpeduncular units excited by habenular stimulation initially fired during the brief early waves. The unit discharge was either (i) a constant latency spike, which followed repetitive stimulation at 100 Hz or more, or (ii) at relatively variable latency, a single spike or a short burst of 2 - 6 spikes at 500 - 1000 HZ. Same units showed, after the habenular stimulus, sequences of initial excitation followed by inhibition, while other units showed pure inhibition. Over 80% of units either excited or inhibited by habenular stimulation were excited by acetylcholine applied micro-iontophoretically; this excitation was potentiated by neostigmine and blocked by atropine.</description><description>Au cours d'une étude électrophysiologique conduite sur 58 chats à l'aide de micro-électrodes, il a été mis en évidence dans le noyau interpédonculaire des oscillations spontanées rythmiques dont la fréquence varie de 3 ou 4 HZ á 9 ou 10 Hz selon le type d'anesthésie. La corrélation entre ces activités globales et les modalités de décharges spontanées des neurones du noyau interpédonculaire est faible et incertaine. Les origines possibles de l'activité ainsi décrite sont discutées. La stimulation de l'habénula évoque dans le noyau interpédonculaire une réponse qui se compose d'une onde rapide positive-négative suivie d'une onde lente négative et enfin lente et positive. La décharge initiale de la majorité des neurones interpédonculaires, en réponse à la stimulation de l'habénula, est synchrone des ondes rapides précoces. La réponse cellulaire est: soit un spike de latence constante pouvant suivre une stimulation répétitive à 100 Hz ou plus, soit, à une latence variable, un spike unique ou un train de 2 à 6 spikes à 500-1000 Hz. Quelques cellules sont excitées puis inhibées par la stimulation habénulaire et d'autres purement inhibées. Plus de 80% des cellules influencées d'une manière ou d'une autre par la stimulation habénulaire sont excitées par des injections micro-iontophorétiques d'acetylcholine; cette excitation est potentiée par la néostigmine et bloquée par l'atropinè.</description><creator>Lake, Norma.</creator><contributor>Krnjevic, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>The habenulo - interpeduncular pathway.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q76q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871012w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g353</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various factors that influence the skin allograft reaction were studied in mice, with the aid of anti-lymphocyte serum (ALS). H-2 incompatible allografts were rejected more rapidly in female than in male hosts treated with ALS. Male mouse submandibular glands contained a substance that was immunosuppressive for both cell-mediated and humoral immune responses. This substance, although only present in males, was not responsible for the sex difference in skin allograft survival. The sex difference was due instead to an immunopotentiating effect exerted by the ovaries of the female. ALS treatment was used in a weak histocompatibility system (H-1) to investigate the origin and possible role of a nonsensitized cell population in the allograft reaction. Bone marrow but not thymus or spleen cells were demonstrated to act as effector cells in allograft rejection. The experimental results are discussed in relation to a proposal that this effector cell is a monocyte-macrophage.</description><creator>Kongshavn, Patricia A.</creator><contributor>Bliss, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Lapp, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Studies on skin allograft reactions in ALS-treated mice.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f907j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g353</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd376076c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The etiology and the physiopathological mechanism of essential hypertension is, in 1972, still unknown. Many groups of workers, particularly that of Genest, Küche1, Nowaczynski and Boucher, have contributed to a better insight of humoral disturbances in this entity by their studies on renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system, mineralocorticoids, progesterone, catecholamines, and other parameters. [...]</description><creator>Hamet, Pavel.</creator><contributor>Genest, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Implication of cyclic AMP in the physiopathology of labile high blood pressure.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mz62p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd376076c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r855p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Normal outbred rabbits responded to antigenic stimulation with antibody formation through activation of either a two cell (antigen-reactive cell and antibody-forming cell) or one cell (antibody-forming cell) pathway system. Similarly multiple pathway systems were observed to be operative in the induction of cell-mediated immunity. This latter conclusion is based on the fin ding that lymphoid cells of a sensitized rabbit lost the capacity to transfer the delayed hypersensitivity skin reactivity to a normal recipient or to be inhibited in their migration in vitro by the specific antigen although the cell donors were still capable of giving optimal delayed hypersensitivity skin reactions. It was also demonstrated that the humoral and cell-mediated immune responses are activated through different and independent cell pathways. These studies of the humoral and cell-mediated immune responses in normal outbred rabbits therefore suggest the existence of multiple pathways mediating these two types of immune response.</description><creator>Haasz, Robert.</creator><contributor>Richter, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The relationship between cell-mediated and humoral immunity in the normal adult rabbit.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wq84h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r855p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x684n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bidirectional chloride and sodium ion fluxes,and net hydrogen ion fluxes were measured across segments of gastric oxyntic gland mucosa with intact blood supply, in anaesthetized dogs. Bidirectional chloride ion fluxes increased with increasing luminal sodium chloride or hydrochloric acid concentration. Chloride insorption was the same from equal concentrations of either sodium chloride or hydrochloric acid. Sodium ion was insorbed from sodium chloride solutions, but not from hydrochloric acid solutions. Sodium ion exsorption was independent of luminal electrolyte concentration. Stimulation of gastric acid secretion with histamine or bethanechol, resulted in a decreased chloride insorption. Treatment of the mucosa with two molar urea or twenty percent ethanol, led to an increased loss of HCl and gain of NaCl. Treatment of the mucosa with the local anaesthetic lidocaine, led to an initial disruption of the mucosal barrier, followed by a decrease in all transmucosal ionic fluxes.</description><creator>Greenberg, Leonard.</creator><contributor>Wlodek, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Surgery.</subject><title>The gastric mucosal barrier.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/000003157.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x684n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tg16v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>32P-labelled T2-phage were harvested from a shake culture and purified by CsCl equilibrium density gradient. Peritoneal exudate cells (PEC) were obtained from the peritoneal cavity 72 hrs after i. p. injection of beef heart infusion broth (B.H.I.B.). Anti-T2-phage antisera were prepared in both rats and rabbits. Evidence for the requirement of opsonin (IgM or IgG) from homologous or heterologous sera was provided by using in vitro sensitized antigen for phagocytosis by rat PEC in vitro. Homologous serum containing 7S IgG antibodies provided the highest degree of enhancement of antigen uptake by rat PEC. The specific opsonin was isolated by starch block electrophoresis of anti-T2-phage rat serum and identified by immunoelectrophoresis as IgG class of antibodies. The presence of specific anti-T2-phage antibodies was demonstrated by the phage neutralization technique. When antisera and opsonin were reduced with 0.2 M 2-ME and alkylated with iodoacetate and iodocacetamide, the phagocytosis promoting activity was reduced considerably. The attachment of antigen-antibody complexes onto the surface of phagocytic cells seems to be dependent on the intactness of the antibody molecule. An attempt was made to detect in vitro synthesis of anti-T2-phage antibodies by culture of lymph node fragment, using RNA preparations from macrophages which had been incubated in vitro with antigen. Only sma1l amounts of antibody were detected. Difficulties were encountered in the isolation of undegraded RNA from peritoneal exudate cells, which were attributed ta the presence of RNase in PEC. RNase activity ·in PEC was higher than in any of the other rat tissues examined, e.g., lymph nodes, thymus, spleen and liver. Polyvinyl sulfate was found to be the best of a number of RNase inhibitors tested.</description><creator>Gaekwar, Shakuntala M.</creator><contributor>Sehon, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>In vitro phagocytosis of antigen by rat peritoneal exudate cells.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wt529.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg16v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720g90n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Galactosylgalactosylglucosylceramide (CTH) was purified from normal human kidneys, and the kidney of a patient with Fabry's disease (characterized by a defect in the catabolism of CTH). NMR spectra of the intact molecules indicated the presence of two beta-D-glycopyranosyl residues and one alpha-D-glycopyranosyl residue. CTH and lactosylceramide labelled in the terminal galactose residues were used to show that the terminal galactosidic linkage of CTH, but not lactosylceramide, was susceptible to hydrolysis by an alpha-galactosidase from coffee beans. Labelled CTH and p-nitrophenyl- alpha-D-galactopyranoside were used to demonstrate concomitant deficiencies of CTH galactohydrolase and nonspecific alpha-galactosidase in the kidney of a patient with Fabry's disease. Following renal transplantation the excretion of CTH in the patient's urine fell from 35 times to 4-8 times normal levels. The concentration of CTH in the plasma decreased transiently then returned to preoperative levels. These findings indicate that 1) CTH cOlltains a terminal alpha-D-galactopyranosyl residue, 2) the nonspecific alpha-galactosidase deficiency observed in patients with Fabry's disease is a direct reflection of the deficiency of CTH galactohydrolase, and 3) renal transplantation has no place in the treatment of nonuremic patients with Fabry's disease at present.</description><creator>Clarke, Joe T.</creator><contributor>Wolfe, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The structure and metabolism of galactosylgalactosyiglucosylceramide.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207ts21h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g90n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz148</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this investigation was to establish an in vitro counterpart to the in vivo graft-versus-host reaction. The generation in vitro of plaque-forming cells from spleen of rabbits previously immunized with sheep red blood cells could he completely suppressed by the simultaneous incubation of the memory cells with allogeneic circulating lymphocytes, sacculus rotundus, appendix or Peyer's patches cells (collectively referred to as SAPP effector cells). Spleen and lymph node cells were less effective in inhibiting the in vitro immune response whereas thymus and bone marrow exhibited no inhibitory activity. It was demonstrated that the inhibition of the generation of plaque-forming cells is not mediated by the release of cytotoxic antibodies directed to the memory spleen cells by the allogeneic lymphocytes. Following immunization with the appropriate antigen, allogeneic lymphocytes or SRBC so as to induce cell mediated and humoral responses respectively, the effector cells were shown to migrate to the thymus, whereas antibody forming cells were shown to migrate initially to the Peyer's patches. These results support the conclusion that the reaction represents an in vitro counterpart of the graft-versus-host reaction and imply a SAPP organ origin for the cells mediating this reaction in the rabbit.</description><creator>Behelak, Youssef.</creator><contributor>Richter, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The organ sources(s) of the cells mediating a cellular immune reaction in vitro.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v826.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz148</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>