<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:31:19Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h254x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neuroimaging studies on visual priming have reported decreased  activity in extrastriate and inferior prefrontal cortices for the second  presentation of an object. This effect is also observed for alternative exemplars of  the initially presented object (e.g. two different pencils). An unanswered question  is whether this decrease in activity can be found for the successive presentation of  similar complex visual scenes. We used a test in which landscape pictures were  divided vertically into three segments. A first segment was presented and followed  several stimuli later by a second segment. Reaction time was faster for the second  segment than for the first one. The presentation of the second segment was  associated with reduced activity in late stage visual processing areas, which  replicates and extends the results on priming of different exemplars of objects, and  with increased activity mainly in frontal and parietal regions, which are known to  be associated with memory retrieval.</description><creator>Pomerleau-Blondin, François</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Neural correlates of priming elicited by similar but perceptually different complex visual scenes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666507w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h254x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430537c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy is a powerful  tool for probing protein structure-function relationships. With the use of isotope  editing, it can also be employed to elucidate protein-nucleic acid interactions.  This technique was used to study the sequence of heat-induced unfolding of the  uniformly labeled 13C regulatory subunit (RSU) of E. coli aspartate transcarbamylase  (ATCase) with its inhibitor CTP. The absorption of CTP in the amide I' region limits  our ability to detect protein conformational changes upon binding of CTP. Therefore,  by labeling the protein with 13C shifts the amide I' band ~ 40 cm -1 and  clearly separates the protein bands from those of CTP. Variable-temperature (VT)  FTIR spectroscopy was then employed to monitor the thermal unfolding of the labeled  RSU in the presence and absence of CTP. In addition, isotope editing was further explored to probe  domain-domain interactions of the two domains of RSU using intein technology. Intein  technology provides a novel means by which isotope editing can be performed to  extract information on protein inter-domain and inter-subunit interactions by  spectroscopic analysis but has not yet been exploited in Fourier transform infrared  (FTIR) spectroscopy. The objective of this project is to present for the first time  the feasibility of segmental labeling through intein-mediated protein ligation (IPL)  for the purpose of studying conformational changes by FTIR spectroscopy, using  ATCase as a model enzyme. In the first phase of this project, the RSU of ATCase,  which houses a Zn-binding domain and a nucleotide binding domain, was reconstructed  from its isolated domains using commercially available intein-base expression  vectors. As steps towards obtaining an isotope labeled RSU, we have fused each  domain to separate inteins. Following affinity purification, the intein tags were  chemically cleaved and the reactive ends of the two RSU domains were ligated  together to form a peptide. Although ligation was successful, improved yields are  required for the FTIR spectroscopic studies.</description><creator>Martinez, Sarah Jane</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Proteins -- Denaturation.</subject><subject>Aspartic acid -- Denaturation.</subject><title>Strategies for preparing segmentally isotopically labeled proteins for probing domain-domain interactions by FTIR spectroscopy by Sarah Jane Martinez.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs20d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430537c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472x00p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Current medical genetics research is dominated by a single  theory that supports the Human Genome Project rationale. This thesis investigates  this and several alternative hypotheses and the ethical context related to their  development. Firstly, the hypotheses are discussed in detail followed by a  subsection in which research evidence based on each hypothesis is cited. Secondly,  these medical genetics hypotheses are situated within the contemporary medical  paradigm. To conclude, the thesis examines in depth the ethical and practical  implications of medical genetics research. A framework of analysis of scientific  responsibility is used to explore these implications. Scientific responsibility, as  presented in this thesis, is a process consisting of three steps: (1) scientific  discourse; (2) the development of the nature of scientific responsibility; and, (3)  effective criticism. Once scientific responsibility is defined, the term is applied  specifically to the field of medical genetics research.</description><creator>Marshall, Jennifer</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Philosophy.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>The development of contemporary medical genetics research models and the need for scientific responsibility /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0967623.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472x00p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g8126</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clinoptilolite is a zeolite and an aluminosilicate that can be  fed to swine in order to reduce nutrients being excreted because of their molecular  sieving properties, high cation exchange capacities, and a high affinity for the  ammonium ion (NH4+). Preliminary research has been carried out on utilizing  zeolite's unique characteristics for dietary supplementation for livestock, however  much of this research is limited and is still in its infancy. The results from this study show that the zeolite with a  particle size distribution either &gt;250 mum or mixed (50% particles greater and  smaller than 250 mum) adsorbed the most NH4+. Macro mineral and heavy metal release  was similar among all particle size distributions tested, but varied between sources  of zeolite. Handling properties of zeolite were not affected by moisture content or  particle size. The feed trial indicated that zeolite supplementation, combined with  a low crude protein and energy diet and at an inclusion level of 4%, showed  potential as a feed additive in swine diets for the purposes of nutrient reduction.  Nevertheless, zeolite seemed to have a greater impact on energy ingestion, as  compared to crude protein. Even at 6% zeolite inclusion in the feed, hog muscle,  kidney and liver tissues showed no significant increase in heavy metal contents, as  compared to those fed any zeolite.</description><creator>Leung, Stanley</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Clinoptilolite.</subject><subject>Swine -- Feeding and feeds.</subject><subject>Feed additives.</subject><title>The effect of clinoptilolite properties and supplementation levels on swine performance /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n780.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g8126</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tp870</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Diverse eukaryotic proteins require the post-translational  addition of S-acyl chains to cysteine residues for proper function, a process known  as S-palmitoylation, or S-acylation. To study the effects of this lipid moiety,  various complex methods have been developed for the preparation of synthetic  lipopeptides. In order to facilitate this task, a novel technique employing  readily-prepared long-chain acyl thioesters has been devised. Using  S-phenylmercapto-palmitoyl thioester as well as other acyl thioesters, the  fluorescent-labeled peptide, myristoyl-GCG-caBim, was S-acylated to high  stoichiometry at halftimes as short as 20 min. (initial rate of S-acylation of 179.8  +/- 24.7%/hr) in homogeneous solution, without the presence of micelles or vesicles.  The chemical reaction occurred regioselectively on cysteine side-chains without  modification of serine or lysine derivatives of the peptide. This method was also  utilized to selectively S-acylate the fully deprotected Po peptide, IRYCWLRR-NH2.  Such an innovative technique should provide a useful scheme for the general  synthesis of S-acylated peptides.</description><creator>Leung Wai Sang, Stephane, 1980-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>S-acylation of fully deprotected peptides using thioesters as acyl donors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cw86r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp870</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr00d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Increased understanding of dietary habits of Aboriginal children  can contribute to improved nutrition education programs. To determine correlates of  high soft drink intake, high fruit intake and high vegetable intake, Aboriginal  children in grades 4-6 from two Kanien'keha:ka (Mohawk) communities completed  classroom-administered questionnaires and participated in anthropometric measures  and a run/walk fitness test. Independent correlates of high soft drink consumption  identified by multivariate logistic regression included higher levels of  television-watching, odds ratio [OR] 3.1, (95% confidence interval 1.5-6.4), and  higher levels of physical activity, OR 3.0 (1.3-7.1) among girls, and increased  video game-playing, OR 6.7 (1.8-25.5), and failing to meet the minimal fitness  standard on the run/walk test, OR 2.2 (1.2-4.2), among boys. Independent correlates  of high fruit consumption included each year of increasing age among boys OR 0.7  (0.5-1.0), and higher levels of physical activity among girls OR 4.0 (2.0-7.9) and  boys OR 3.5 (1.5-7.7). Independent correlates of high vegetable intake included age  among boys OR 0.7 (0.5-1.0), increased video game-playing among girls OR 4.5  (1.4-14.9), and higher levels of physical activity among girls OR 3.5 (1.5-7.7) and  boys OR 2.8 (1.2-6.5). These findings suggest targets for interventions aimed at  improving eating habits of Aboriginal children.</description><creator>Karunananthan, Sathya</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Education, Elementary.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><title>Correlates of dietary intake in Mohawk elementary school children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g40n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr00d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj2362556</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stress plays a significant role in the initiation and  continuation of drinking. Furthermore, epidemiological studies have shown a higher  incidence of alcoholism in males than females. Objective. The current studies aimed  to investigate the presence of gender differences in the interactions of ethanol and  stress with the Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal (HPA) axis. Methods. Participants  included 12 males and 10 females with no previous personal or familial history of  alcoholism. Plasma levels of ACTH and cortisol were estimated following a placebo  drink, a low and a high dose of alcohol and a psychological stress task performed 30  minutes after the ingestion of the placebo, the low and the high alcohol drinks.  Results. Male participants presented a more pronounced response of the HPA-axis to  both alcohol and psychological stress. Prior ingestion of the low and to a lesser  extent of the high dose of alcohol induced a more pronounced and longer lasting  attenuation of the HPA-axis response to stress in males than females. Conclusions.  There are gender differences in the interactions of ethanol and stress with the  HPA-axis, which may contribute to the gender differences in alcohol  consumption.</description><creator>Katopodis, Angela</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Psychology, Physiological.</subject><subject>Psychology, Psychometrics.</subject><title>Gender differences in the response of the HPA-axis to alcohol and stress</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f78r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj2362556</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591903d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anopheles species composition and relative seasonal abundance  were measured in an irrigated division (low historical malaria incidence) and in a  rain-fed division (high historical malaria incidence) of southern Sri Lanka. Twelve  species of anophelines were represented in adult and larval collections with  Anopheles vagus Donitz being the most abundant. In cattle-baited net trap  collections, Anopheles adults were significantly more abundant in the irrigated  division than in the rain-fed division. In pyrethrum-spray sheet collections,  cattle-baited but trap collections and larval collections, Anopheles abundance was  significantly greater in the rain-fed division. Houses were of poorer construction  in the rain-fed division, where pyrethrum-spray sheet collections consisted mainly  of Anopheles subpictus Grassi (98%) and Anopheles culicifacies Giles (2%). Hut trap  collections also consisted mainly of An. subpictus (88%) and An. culicifacies (7%).  Net trap collections consisted mainly of An. vagus (43%) and Anopheles peditaeniatus  Leicester (31%). Larval collections also consisted of An. peditaeniatus (24%) and  An. vagus (21%). Weak associations were found between species abundance and  environmental factors explored in this study (e.g., vegetation, water quality,  sunlight exposure). The greater malaria risk in the rain-fed division is due in part  to the occurrence of potential vectors in relatively higher numbers.</description><creator>Goodfellow, Angela Mary</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Mosquitoes as carriers of disease -- Sri Lanka.</subject><subject>Anopheles -- Sri Lanka.</subject><subject>Malaria -- Environmental aspects -- Sri Lanka.</subject><title>Malaria vectors in an irrigated and in a rain-fed division of southern Sri Lanka</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h499c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591903d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rt95r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microglia are the resident immune cells of the central nervous  system (CNS). Although the microglial response can be beneficial, there is  increasing evidence for detrimental effects of the microglial activation in cases of  acute CNS trauma and neurodegenerative disorders. To better understand the role of  these cells in CNS pathogenesis, we have created a mouse model with selective and  conditional ablation of microglia as well as other cells of myeloid origin in  proliferation. To achieve the elimination of proliferating microglia, transgenic  mice that express the suicidal gene herpes simplex virus 1 thymidine kinase (HSV-1  TK) driven by the myeloid specific promoter CD11b were generated. HSV-1 TK is itself  unable to mediate cell death. However, unlike the mammalian thymidine kinase, HSV-1  TK is capable of phosphorylating specific nucleoside analogues such as ganciclovir  which lead during cell proliferation to inhibition of DNA synthesis and cell death.  Here, we will describe the creation and the characterization of CD11b-TK mouse lines  that can be used to ablate proliferating myeloid cells in paradigms of acute CNS  injury.</description><creator>Gowing, Geneviève</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>A mouse model for the selective ablation of proliferating myeloid cells /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547r96p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rt95r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795826v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The major group of HIV-1 viruses that comprises the current  global pandemic evolved, during their worldwide spread, into at least 10 distinct  subtypes or clades. Subtype C predominates in sub-Saharan Africa and is responsible  for the majority of the worldwide HIV-1 infections, while subtype B predominates in  North America and Europe and subtype A/E is prevalent in Southeast Asia. Functional  distinctions in the arrangement of NF-kappaB elements within the long terminal  repeat (LTR) among HIV-1 subtypes have been identified, thus raising the possibility  that transcriptional divergence amongst the subtypes of HIV-1 has occurred. In  addition, significant amino acid variations have been observed amongst the  clade-specific Tat proteins. In the present study, we sought to examine clade  specific interactions between Tat, TAR and cellular proteins as well as to determine  how these interactions may modulate the efficiency of HIV-1 gene transcription. Our  results indicate that while sequence variation in the NF-kappaB region of the  clade-specific LTRs plays a modest role in altering HIV-1 expression, clade-specific  Tat proteins significantly modify viral gene expression.</description><creator>Desfossés, Yan</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Regulation of HIV-1 gene expression by clade-specific Tat proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xj212.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795826v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967423m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Galaxy shell, a sub component of Galaxy project, is designed and  implemented. Galaxy shell is a core component of the Galaxy services, which provides  an interface for Galaxy developers or other modules to access certain functions  supported by Galaxy system. Through Galaxy shell, developers can search, query, and  bind resources according to static or dynamic constraints, launch commands either  locally or remotely. Galaxy shell also supports some special functions, such as  remote pipeline and multicast remote execution. Galaxy shell not only provides a  valuable tool for the research and development of Galaxy project, but also can be  integrated into the core management module of Galaxy, Distributed Resource  Allocation Manager, to realize automatic discovery, dissemination, and allocation  Galaxy resources. The specification of Galaxy shell is also  provided. Galaxy shell is implemented based on Project JShell, an  emulation of a UNIX shell written in Java. Galaxy shell extends JShell by adding new  commands special for Galaxy resource management and consumption. Project JavaCC, a  parser generator and lexical analyzer generator is used for writing the token  manager and parser for Galaxy shell. Apache XML-RPC is used to implement remote  procedure calls.</description><creator>Deng, Ying, 1972-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Gshell : a command interpreter for a public computing utility</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t693v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967423m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t250s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the ubiquity of transposons in eukaryotic genomes, their  evolutionary role remains controversial. The discovery of several domesticated genes  has suggested that transposons can gain host functions, and thus contribute to the  evolution of their host. Here, I present the results of a genome-wide screen for  transposon-derived host genes, which was based on the idea that, once domesticated,  the open reading frame of such elements would be maintained, while terminal  structures necessary for transposition would be lost. Eight-hundred-and-sixty-three  such transposon-dissociated elements were mined from the genome of Arabidopsis  thaliana var. Columbia-0, of which less than 10% are associated with expression  data. Phylogenetic analysis of Mutator superfamily genes in the genomes of Oryza  sativa ssp. japonica (cv Nipponbare) and Arabidopsis, including 121 Mutator-derived  transposon-dissociated elements, found that only two gene families are taxonomically  widespread. MUSTANG1, a member of one of these families, appears to be under  purifying selection. Thus, despite the dearth of taxonomically widespread and/or  expressed transposon-dissociated elements, MUSTANG1, as well as three  transposon-dissociated elements that may be associated with mutant phenotypes, might  be newly discovered transposon-derived host genes.</description><creator>Cowan, Rebecca</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Molecular genetics</subject><subject>Transposons</subject><subject>Rice -- Molecular genetics</subject><title>Molecular domestication and transposon contributions to plant genome evolution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z835f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t250s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr02z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Markov Chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) methods are employed to sample  from a given distribution of interest, pi, where either pi does not exist in closed  form, or, if it does, there exist no efficient methods to simulate an independent  sample from it. MCMC methods create an ergodic Markov chain {Xn, n = 1, 2...} with  stationary distribution pi such that as n tends to infinity, the distribution of Xn  approaches pi. A wealth of diagnostic tools for convergence assessment of MCMC  methods have been proposed, yet none has proved to be completely dependable and easy  to implement. This thesis will review the literature on MCMC algorithms and  diagnostic tools, and it will present a new convergence assessment method based on  the principle of detailed balance. Moreover, the proposed diagnostic tool will be  implemented as a stopping criterion for the optimization algorithm known as  simulated annealing, which finds the global maximum or minimum of a function through  an iterative improvement approach.</description><creator>Cosma, Ioana Ada</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Principle of detailed balance and simulated annealing convergence assessment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qc733.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr02z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf157</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microarray expression analysis was applied as an approach for  identifying cancer-related genes on chromosome-X (CHR-X) in epithelial ovarian  cancer (EOC). The Hu6800 and U133A GeneChipsRTM were used to evaluate the expression  of 446 CHR-X genes in an in vitro EOC model system comprising 4 EOC cell lines and  12 primary cultures of normal ovary surface epithelia. Fifty-one new candidate CHR-X  genes were identified in addition to 49 genes previously implicated in cancer. Many  genes map to regions with frequent genetic aberrations in EOC tumours, or interact  with the known EOC tumour suppressors BRCA1 and BRCA2. Candidate genes described in  this study may provide novel markers for histopathological subtypes, or the  tumourigenic potential of EOC tumours. The X-inactive-specific-transcript (XIST) was  absent in two highly tumourigenic EOC cell lines, TOV21G and TOV112D. XIST mRNA is  important for the stability of X-chromosome-inactivation (XCI), as its absence  destabilizes the silencing of genes on the inactive-X. Aberrant bi-allelic  expression of FHL1, a gene subjected to XCI was detected in the cell line TOV21G but  not in the cell line TOV112D. Genotyping assays using polymorphic microsattelite  markers suggested that TOV21G has retained heterozygosity of CHR-X. The majority of  alleles tested for TOV112D were consistent with loss of heterozygosity of CHR-X.  Taken together these findings are consistent with two proposed mechanisms mediating  XIST loss-of-expression in cancer: (1) Duplication of the active-X followed by loss  of the inactive-X (TOV112D); or (2) Reactivation of the previously inactive-X  (TOV21G).</description><creator>Benoit, Marie-Helene</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Oligonucleotide microarray analysis of chromosome-X gene expression in human epithelial ovarian cancer cell lines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn690.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf157</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xs22z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Part I. In this work we show that P2X3 currents are acutely  modulated by the GPCRs mGluR5 and P2Y2, and by the neurotrophin TrkA receptor,  expressed in nociceptors, in the recombinant Xenopus oocyte system. The  intracellular C-terminal domain of P2X 3 plays an important role in its functional  coupling to TrkA. Preliminary studies suggest a role for PKC in the P2X3-TrkA  cross-talk, but other routes may also contribute. Part II. Neurogenic and  pharmacological stimulation of vascular smooth muscle P2X1 elicits a contractile  response that we found was potentiated by serotonin acting through 5HT2A. We also  found in Xenopus oocytes that P2X 1 currents in the desensitized state are  potentiated by M1 ACh receptors and by phorbol ester stimulation of PKC. Part III.  We have shown in Boue-Grabot et al. (2003) that there was an intracellular negative  cross-talk and physical interaction between P2X2 and 5HT3A receptors. We also found  a functional interaction between P2X2 and GABAA alpha2beta 3 receptor subtypes in  HEK293 mammalian cells and in Xenopus oocytes; and we confirmed the findings of  Sokolova et al. , (2001) in primary cultures of DRG neurons. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</description><creator>Bélanger, Danny</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Heterologous functional interactions of P2X ATP receptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b181z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs22z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f8765</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A Monsanto Automatic Capillary Rheometer and a sliding plate  rheometer were used to study the spurt phenomenon and to discover whether it is the  result of a system instability or a material property. The capillary rheometer has  been the only instrument able to operate at spurt stresses up to present time,  because capillary rheometers operate at shear stresses that are out of the range of  rotational shear rheometers. However, a sliding plate rheometer can generate shear  stresses in the spurt range. A comparative study using two linear polybutadiene  samples at 50°C was carried out using these two rheometers. Special  attention was paid to the evaluation of the actual pressure drop in the capillary in  order to determine the true shear stress at the wall. It was found that spurt occurs  only in the capillary rheometer. In other words, the flow curve generated by the  sliding plate rheometer is continuous in the shear stress range where spurt is  observed in the capillary rheometer. Slip velocities were determined using data from  the two rheometers, and the slip velocities for the post-slip capillary flow all  fall on the smooth curve based on sliding plate data, provided that the pressure  drop in the capillary, and not the overall driving pressure, is used to calculate  the wall shear stress.</description><creator>Smillo, Fabricio</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Wall slip and spurt of molten polymer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w786j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f8765</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qs57j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Optical delay line module is an important building block for  advanced communication systems such as OCDMA and OTDMA. The past decade has seen a  large research and development activity in this area. In this thesis, design and performance analysis of a tunable  optical delay line which employs pop-up MEMS micro-mirrors have been described. The  delay paths which their lengths are in binary fashion are free-space based delay  lines. Micro-mirrors operate as a switch to redirect the light through delay paths.  One of the main characteristic of this design is to provide constant optical power  loss for different delay times. Computer simulations have been shown to evaluate the  performance of the system to different sources of misalignments. The result of simulations suggests using correction mirrors in  order to decrease the optical power loss due to misalignment. It has been also  concluded that improvement of pop-up micro-mirrors as a main source of misalignment,  will alleviate the performance remarkably.</description><creator>Soleymani, S. M. Ali</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Design and analysis of micro-mirror based tunable optical delay line</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq26z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs57j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558d85s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A delivery method for the oral administration of thalidomide for  lowering tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNT-alpha), and thus Crohn's disease-related  inflammation in the proximal small intestine, using two separate engineered polymer  microcapsules is explored in this thesis. Membrane formation of both  alginate-polylysine-alginate (APA) and alginate-chitosan (AC) capsules are discussed  and thalidomide encapsulation procedures have been described. In-vitro tests have  been used to monitor capsule degradation and drug release in a simulated  gastrointestinal environment. Also, culture and use of RAW 264.7 mouse macrophage  cells for the simulation of the human intestine is described. Results show two  separate methods of drug delivery by the APA and AC capsules. APA capsules release  thalidomide in a timed-release fashion whereas AC capsules release the drug in a  burst manner. These results implicate the benefits of the use of both capsules to  target separate sites along the small intestine. Also the cultured macrophage  studies conclude that the proposed encapsulation therapy does indeed lower TNF-alpha  levels and could therefore be of benefit for the lowering of inflammation associated  with Crohn's disease. However, further animal study is needed before full potential  of this approach can be realized.</description><creator>Metz, Terrence</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacy.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Artificial cell microcapsules for oral delivery of thalidomide for use in Crohn's disease : design, preparation, and in-vitro analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z69v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d85s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h288</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A planar joint dyad consists of two rigid bodies connected by a  P (prismatic) or R (revolute) joint and similarly connected to a fixed third body.  The nature of the quadric constraint surface in the planar kinematic mapping image  space is investigated. The geometric reasoning concerning why five points in the  image space are sufficient to define an RR dyad and why four are enough to define  the workspace of a PR or RP dyad is described, explained and  exploited. A general algorithm that combines both type and dimensional  design synthesis to the planar joint dyad hence to the five-position Burmester  problem in relation to planar four-bar mechanisms is presented. In addition, a  special algorithm for the PR or RP dyad type selection is developed. It illustrates  that PR or RP dyad can be typed and extracted from the general solutions. Moreover,  the conditions under which five given poses admit 0, 2 or 4 real dyad solutions to  the Burmester problem are explained. In this thesis, examples which produce two RR dyad solutions and  four dyad ones with various combinations of RR and PR pairs are presented to  illustrate that the algorithm can be used to design planar four-bar  mechanisms.</description><creator>Nie, Jun, 1972-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>On planar dyads, four-bar linkages and image space insights into the design problem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53ww362.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h288</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h500x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three-dimensional (3D) ultrasound is an emerging new technology  with numerous clinical applications like measuring the volume of the prostate,  monitoring fetal development, or evaluating brain shift during neurosurgery.  Ultrasound probe calibration is an obligatory step in order to build 3D volumes from  2D images acquired in a freehand ultrasound system. The role of calibration is to  find the transformation that relates the image plane to a sensor attached on the  probe. This thesis is a comprehensive review of what has been published in the field  of ultrasound probe calibration for 3D ultrasound. The thesis covers the topics of  tracking technologies, ultrasound image acquisition, phantom design, speed of sound  issues, feature extraction, least-squares minimization, temporal calibration,  calibration evaluation techniques and phantom comparisons. The calibration phantoms  and methods have also been classified in tables to give a better overview of the  existing methods.</description><creator>Mercier, Laurence</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Review of ultrasound probe calibration techniques for 3D ultrasound</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fm055.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h500x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s3032</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis considers simplified decoding for a type of  full-rate non-orthogonal complex space-time block codes (STBCs) over Rayleigh fading  channels. More precisely, we propose a decision feedback symbol-by-symbol decoding  algorithm for the Quasi-Orthogonal code family, that comprises the Quasi-Orthogonal  code and the Improved Quasi-Orthogonal code, by using the QR decomposition. Compared  to optimal joint decoding, this algorithm significantly reduces complexity. For  performance evaluations of the simplified decoding algorithm for the  Quasi-Orthogonal code family over Rayleigh fading channels, we derive upper and  lower bounds for symbol error rate. Furthermore, by using high SNR asymptotics we  investigate the diversity orders provided by different decoding algorithms. The  analysis shows that because of the relative constellation rotation, the diversity  order provided by optimal decoding for the Improved Quasi-Orthogonal code is 4.  Also, because of the error propagation in the decision feedback, the diversity order  provided by the simplified decoding for the Improved Quasi-Orthogonal code is  reduced to 2. All analytical results match well the associated computer simulations.  Finally, we compare the performances of the simplified and optimal decoding for the  Improved Quasi-Orthogonal code over correlated Rayleigh fading channels by using the  "one-ring" channel model. Through computer simulations we show that the  relative performance loss between the simplified and optimal decoding decreases as  channel correlation increases. Therefore, the simplified decoding algorithm is  suitable for highly spatially correlated Rayleigh fading channels.</description><creator>Deng, Yunfei, 1974-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Simplified decoding for a Quasi-Orthogonal space-time code family</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd30f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s3032</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k315k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thin film transistors with different polymers (PTFTs) as active  channel layers have been fabricated and studied in this work. Three different  fabrication procedures were used to fabricate long and short channel PTFTs on  silicon substrates and long channel PTFTs on glass substrates. It has been shown  that the success rate of fabrication of PTFTs on glass substrates with anodic Al 2O3  gate dielectrics is higher than that on silicon substrates with thermally grown SiO2  gate dielectrics. The characteristics of PTFTs fabricated using several polymers  were studied. Among them, the ones based on regioregualr  poly[3-hexylthiophene-2.5diy] (RR-P3HT) have the best performance with a field  effect mobility (mueff) of about 0.01 cm2/V-s and ION/IOFF value of about 50 when  doped with FeCl3. Results of measurement suggested that FeCl3 doping of P3HT could  lead to a decrease of about 5 orders of magnitude in its contact resistance to Au  electrodes, giving rise to two orders of magnitude increase of its apparent  mobility. Therefore, it can be concluded that the contact resistances are the major  limitation of performance of many PTFTs and need to be studied intensively in the  future.</description><creator>Chen, Yi, 1974-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Organic thin film transistors based on conjugated polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv73k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k315k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c1034</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a previous study by our research group, parents and teachers  of gifted children disagreed about the importance of group work in the inquiry-based  classroom, with parents rating group work as less important than did teachers (Syer  &amp; Shore, 2001). The purpose of the present study was to attempt to understand  this difference of opinion. Parents (n = 15), teachers (n = 11), and a group who  were both parents and teachers (n = 5) of gifted children responded to a  researcher-designed telephone interview. Teachers perceived parents as competitive  and grade-oriented. Parents themselves, however, reported that their opinions of  group work were based on their children's negative experiences. Teachers reported  that their opinions were affected by their pedagogical knowledge regarding group  work. Although parents' and teachers' opinions differed, they were aware of each  other's point of view.</description><creator>Saunders, Katie, 1980-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Gifted children.</subject><subject>Group work in education.</subject><subject>Parents -- Attitudes.</subject><subject>Teachers -- Attitudes.</subject><title>Parents' and teachers' differing views of group work with gifted students</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zn962.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c1034</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838114w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There has been a substantial amount of research on aggression in  men's ice hockey. Although there is some research on aggression in women's ice  hockey, there is still a noticeable absence of empirical research on various aspects  of aggression. The purpose of this study was to investigate the prevalence and  intent of aggressive behaviors in university women's ice hockey. Two methods of data  acquisition were used: systematic observation (measured prevalence) and stimulated  recall interviews (measured intent). Results revealed the presence of several  aggressive techniques, such as body checking, punching, pushing, and cross checking.  Several reasons for these aggressive behaviors emerged from the analysis, including  frustration, intimidation, and protection. These findings augment the literature on  aggression in women's ice hockey, providing insight on the prevalence as well as the  mechanisms influencing aggressive behaviors.</description><creator>Shapcott, Kim M.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Aggressiveness</subject><subject>Women hockey players</subject><title>Prevalence and intent of aggressive behaviors in elite women's ice hockey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z836q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838114w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r8544</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:52:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines stress and distress experienced by working  age individuals in the urban environment. The goals of this research are twofold:  (1) to test for a social gradient in stress and distress; and (2) to test for  environmental effects on the reporting of stress and distress, specifically  focussing on variations in stress and distress across neighbourhoods in Montreal.  Montreal was selected as the focus of this study because it is a large metropolitan  region with some of the highest income disparities in Canada. Individual-level  logistic regression models and multilevel analyses of the 2000/01 Canadian Community  Health Survey were applied to identify the determinants of stress and distress and  to determine the degree of variation in stress (n = 1944) and distress (n = 1836)  captured at the neighbourhood level. Results showed that a social gradient exists  with distress in Montreal, but not stress, and that neighbourhoods have an effect on  distress above and beyond individual characteristics.</description><creator>Khan, Saeeda S.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Distress (Psychology) -- Social aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Metropolitan Area</subject><subject>Distress (Psychology) -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Metropolitan Area</subject><subject>Stress (Psychology) -- Social aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Metropolitan Area</subject><subject>Stress (Psychology) -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Metropolitan Area</subject><title>Neighbourhoods, stress and distress</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505109k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r8544</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>