<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:54:13Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):825" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm48j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work described herein represents a preliminary step in the characterisation of the human Tom20 protein and its role in the mammalian mitochondrial import machinery. A hexahistidine-tagged form of the human homologue of Tom20 has been over-expressed in Escherichia coli and purified under native conditions. This Tom20 protein has been shown, in these studies, to compete for the import of a matrix-destined mitochondrial precursor protein, pre-ornithine carbamoyltransferase (pOCT), into mitochondria isolated from a mammalian source (rat heart), as well as to directly bind the presequence-bearing pOCT in vitro. Furthermore, a protocol has been established for the isolation of import-competent outer membrane vesicles from rat liver mitochondria. These vesicles have been preliminarily characterised in terms of the import of two outer membrane-destined DHFR fusion proteins, Tom70(1-29)-DHFR and Tom20(1-28)-DHFR, and have been shown to exhibit similar characteristics/requirements for protein import as seen for intact mitochondria: temperature sensitivity, the dependence upon cytosolic ATP, and the requirement for protease-sensitive outer membrane surface components.</description><creator>Shroff, Hezuk</creator><contributor>Shore, Gordon C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, General.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Functional expression of the human mitochondrial import receptor Tom20 in escherichia coli</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb82x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm48j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd536</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A partially purified chlorophyllase, obtained from alga Phaeodactylum tricornutum, was assayed for its hydrolytic activity towards the pheophytin in ternary micellar systems of hexane/Tris-HCl/surfactant. A wide range of surfactants, sorbitans (Span 20, 40, 60, 80 and 85) and polysorbates (Tween 20, 40, 60, 80 and 85), was used. The use of either 50 $ mu$M of Span 85 or 1 $ mu$M of Tween 80 increased the hydrolytic activity of chlorophyllase by 110 and 23%, respectively. The optimum values of pH, enzyme content, incubation time and temperature for the hydrolytic activity of chlorophyllase were determined as 8.25, 8 $ mu$g protein/ml, 60 min and 27.5$ sp circ$C, respectively. The enzyme was assayed for its hydrolytic activity in the most appropriate ternary system containing Span 85 with purified pheophytin, as well as chlorophyll derivatives, as substrates. Moreover, the values of $V sb{ rm max}/K sb{ rm m}$ ratio for chlorophyllase, using the partially purified pheophytin as substrate, in ternary systems with Span 85 and Tween 80 as surfactants, were 0.15 and 0.08, respectively; however, the value of $V sb{ rm max}/K sb{ rm m}$ ratio for the enzyme, in the ternary system with Span 85, using purified pheophytin as substrate was 0.07. The addition of optimized amounts of individual membrane lipids, L-$ alpha$-phosphatidylcholine, L-$ alpha$-phosphatidyl-DL-glycerol and $ beta$-carotene increased the hydrolytic activity of chlorophyllase, using partially purified pheophytin as substrate, by 50, 36 and 10%, respectively, for Span 85, and 30, 48 and 15%, respectively, for Tween 80; in addition, these lipids increased the enzyme activity by 6, 23 and 31%, respectively, in the Span 85 media, using purified pheophytin as substrate. Phytol showed a competitive inhibitory effect on chlorophyllase activity in both Span and Tween systems containing partially purified pheophytin substrate; however, phytol had an uncompetitive inhibitory effect on the enzyme activity in the S</description><creator>Samaha, Hiba.</creator><contributor>Kermesha, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Hydrolases.</subject><subject>Chlorophyll.</subject><subject>Glycoproteins.</subject><subject>Organic solvents.</subject><subject>Plant enzymes.</subject><title>Biocatalysis of chlorophyllase in ternary micellar system using chlorophyll derivatives as substrates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v09m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd536</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n070h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to investigate if the ERG could be used to monitor the function of the retina as it is adapting to a new luminous environment, we measured the impact of pre-exposure to a bright luminous environment on the electrical response of the retina recorded (1) immediately after closure of this bright background luminance (i.e., at the onset of dark adaptation) and (2) immediately after a reduction of the background luminance from a brighter to a dimmer level. Our experimental approach resulted in highly significant and transient modifications in the amplitudes and in the peak times of most of the ERG components. This study also lead to a reinterpretation of the genesis of the oscillatory potentials as well as of the origin of the Light Adaptation Effect, a not yet explained retinal phenomenon previously reported by several investigators. We believe that our procedure could have a significant clinical value, as it seems to be suggested with our results obtained from two patients affected with congenital stationary night blindness with myopia.</description><creator>Rousseau, Sophie</creator><contributor>Lachapelle, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Ophthalmology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Dynamic electroretinography : exploring a novel approach to the study of retinal function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tx16m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n070h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182n24q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electron arc therapy is the treatment of choice for tumours involving large curved surfaces. At the Montreal General Hospital a unique approach to the electron arc therapy was developed in 1986 and has been used clinically ever since. The approach is based on the concept of the characteristic angle beta. We measured radial percentage depth doses in a polystyrene cylindrical phantom irradiated with electron arc beams having angles beta in the range from 5$ sp circ$ to 100$ sp circ,$ for 9 MeV, 12 MeV, 15 MeV, and 18 MeV electron beam energies. We showed that the characteristic angle-$ beta$ concept can be extended to the beams with nominal energy of 18 MeV. The validity of the empirical relationship, relating the doses in two beams with different energies, was confirmed. A linear relationship between the angle $ beta$ and the depth of dose maximum, the depth of the 85% depth dose, and the depth of the 50% depth dose, was established. The surface dose dependence on the angle $ beta$ was also determined and the bremsstrahlung contamination in the electron arc therapy studied.</description><creator>Robar, Vlado</creator><contributor>Podgorjak, Ervin B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Characteristic angle-beta concept in electron arc therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq18x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182n24q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t125j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The focus of this thesis is the study of relative definability of first-order boolean functions with respect to the language PCF, a paradigmatic typed, higher-order language based on the simply-typed $ lambda$-calculus. The basic core language is sequential. We study the effect of adding construct that embody various notions of parallel execution. The resulting set of equivalence classes with respect to relative definability forms a supsemilattice analoguous to the lattice of degrees in recursion theory. Recent results of Bucciarelli show that the lattice of degrees of parallelism has both infinite chains and infinite antichains. By considering a very simple subset of Sieber's sequentiality relations, we identify levels in the lattice and derive inexpressibility results concerning functions on different levels. This allows us to explore further the structure of the lattice of degrees of parallelism and show the existence of new infinite hierarchies. We also identify four subsemilattices of this structure, all characterized by a simple property.</description><creator>Pucella, Riccardo R.</creator><contributor>Panangaden, Prakash (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Investigations on relative definability in PCF</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br50t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t125j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d202p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The methods currently used to evaluate cultivator weed control are imprecise and often biased. A new method was tested. An experiment was carried out at two sites in 1993 and again in 1994, using a split-plot design with four repetitions. Cultivation was carried out on weed populations simulated with rye grass (Lolium spp L.) and mustard (Sinapis alba L.) in 1993 and on both simulated and natural weed population in 1994 with Rabe Werk, Hiniker and Kongskilde cultivators. Weed control was assessed by the effective weed kill and the percentage of the area of the simulated weed population which was affected, and by counts and visual observations on the natural weed population. The new method provided an objective assessment of the cultivation treatments, especially by the effective weed kill index. The area affected approach was not suitable for all cultivation treatments. There was agreement between the proposed method and the conventional methods. This validated the proposed new method. Overall, the Hiniker with ridgers performed the best. The Hiniker without ridgers, and the Kongskilde with or without ridgers performed similarly. The Rabe Werk without goosefoot attachment resulted in the poorest weed control. The degree of weed displacement varied among the cultivators and was associated with weed density. The degree of weed displacement onto the crop row from the inter-row area was low ($&lt;$1% in 1993 and up to 3.4 in 1994). The weed displacement distance was related to weed density and the degree of weed uprooting produced by cultivation.</description><creator>Portillo Nuñez, David.</creator><contributor>Smith, Donal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Weeds -- Control.</subject><subject>Cultivators -- Evaluation.</subject><subject>Tillage.</subject><title>Development and validation of a theoretical method to evaluate the efficacy of mechanical cultivators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qv02c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d202p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w37639044</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Leukocyte extravasation is a regulated mechanism involving the initial contact, adhesion, and transmigration of leukocytes through layers of endothelial cells into the surrounding tissue. L-selectin is the peripheral lymph node homing receptor mediating the initial interaction and weak adhesion between lymphocytes and endothelial cells. This thesis presents two non-traditional roles of L-selectin-involvement in cell division and signaling. Cytokinesis is the last phase of mitosis in which the plasma membrane invagination occurs between the newly formed daughter cells. L-selectin concentrates along the cleavage furrow of dividing Daudi cells. Arresting cells after completing mitosis results in detectable shed L-selectin in the culture supernatant. In contrast, no soluble L-selectin is detected after arresting cells in the G$ sb2$ phase. This suggests that the relocation and shedding of the L-selectin receptor is involved in cytokinesis of Daudi cells. In addition, calcium mobilization from internal stores is induced using the L-selectin monoclonal antibody, FMC46, on normal peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) and Daudi cells. Priming of PBMCs with FMC46 before Pokeweed mitogen (PWM) stimulation increased aggregation and proliferation at lower doses of PWM compared to lymphocytes stimulated with PWM alone. These data provide evidence for direct alteration of lymphocyte activation status after ligation of a specific L-selectin epitope. The physiological role of L-selectin-mediated signaling may be important in the priming of lymphocytes during extravasation such that lymphocytes are more responsive to antigenic stimulation after completing transmigration.</description><creator>Po, John Leander Zapanta</creator><contributor>Jensen, Gitte S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Novel roles of the L-selection receptor on lymphocytes in cell division and signal transduction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn432.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37639044</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623f59q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Some species of marine phytoplankton are believed to be more tolerant of high concentrations of trace metals than others, but no conclusive test of this hypothesis has been conducted. Eleven species of phytoplankton representing 5 classes were grown in Aquil medium containing Cd$ sp{2+}$ concentrations between 10$ sp{-9.85}$ and 10$ sp{-6.84}$ M. Growth rates and intracellular concentrations of Cd, C, N and S were measured. Cadmium quotas (mol Cd/litre-cell volume) were lower in members of Bacillariophyceae than in Chlorophyceae, Prymnesiophyceae, Dinophyceae and Cyanophyceae (ANOVA, p $&lt;$ 0.001). Cellular C:S molar ratios decreased in phytoplankton grown at high (pCd 7.37-6.84) compared to low Cd (no added Cd), as S/litre-cell volume increased. Similar results were observed for C:N molar ratios. In two species that were examined, C:S ratios decreased as a linear function of increasing Cd concentration. Mean Cd$ sp{2+}$ concentration that reduced growth rate to 50% of maximum (pCd$ sp{50})$ was not significantly different among phytoplankton classes (ANOVA, p $&lt;$ 0.05). When these experimental data were combined with pCd$ sp{50}$s calculated from published sources, Chlorophyceae were found to be the most resistant class (ANOVA, p $&lt;$ 0.01). Cadmium and Cu resistance (pCd$ sp{50}$ and pCu$ sp{50})$ were correlated (r = 0.52, p $&lt;$ 0.05), suggesting co-tolerance of phytoplankton to toxic levels of these metals. Chlorophyceae were most tolerant and Cyanophyceae the least tolerant of Cu (ANOVA, p $&lt;$ 0.01). No significant differences were observed among Bacillariophyceae, Prymnesiophyceae, and Dinophyceae, which were of intermediate sensitivity to both metals. The results confirm the existence of a phylogenetic dependence of resistance to trace metal toxicity in phytoplankton.</description><creator>Payne, Chris, 1971-</creator><contributor>Price, Neil M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Cadmium -- Toxicity testing.</subject><subject>Copper -- Toxicity testing.</subject><subject>Phytoplankton -- Phylogeny.</subject><title>Phylogenetic trends in phytoplankton resistance to Cd and Cu toxicity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg84b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f59q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r40k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) belongs to the group of the interstitial lung diseases and is characterized by inflammation, proliferation of fibroblasts and type II pneumocytes, and increased collagen deposition. Inflammatory cells, by releasing mediators and cytokines, participate in the pathogenesis of IPF. Endothelin-1 (ET-1), a vasoconstrictor and mitogenic peptide, is one of the mediators that has been shown to be involved in the fibrotic process of IPF in humans. There are, however, no studies examining the role of ET-1 in animal models of IPF. We used the rat model of pulmonary fibrosis, induced by bleomycin, to study the role of ET-1 and endothelin converting enzyme-1 (ECE-1) in IPF using immunohistochemistry (IHC). We also studied by morphometry the effect of bosentan, the mixed ET-A/B receptor antagonist, on the severity of the fibrosis. We found increased ET-1 and ECE-1 immunoreactivities in the lungs of the fibrosis group compared with the control group (P $&lt;$ 0.05), principally in epithelial cells. By morphometry, we found a decrease in the volume fraction (Vv) of air and an increase in the Vv of connective tissue in the fibrosis group compared with control. The fibrosis was significantly reduced by bosentan (P $&lt;$ 0.05). These results are consistent with the notion that ET-1 is an important mediator of bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis.</description><creator>Park, Sung-Hae, 1971-</creator><contributor>Michel, Rene P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Role of endothelin-1 and endothelin converting enzyme-1 in bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis in rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9355050.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r40k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw55q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In rat membranous nephropathy, complement C5b-9 induces glomerular epithelial cell (GEC) injury and proteinuria, which in some models is partially mediated by eicosanoids. Recently, it has been demonstrated that the C5b-9 complex activates a high molecular mass cytosolic phospholipase A$ sb2$ (cPLA$ sb2)$ in cultured rat GEC, which leads to release of arachidonic acid (AA) and eicosanoids, and may contribute toward plasma membrane injury. In this study, we investigated if C5b-9 can also activate other PLA$ sb2$ isoforms. In GEC stably overexpressing sPLA$ sb2$ (Type II PLA$ sb2,$ 14 kD) (produced by transfection), the C5b-9-stimulated increase in free $ sp3$H-AA, ($ sim$2 fold above basal) was not significantly different from neo (control) GEC. In contrast, in GEC overexpressing cPLA$ sb2,$ C5b-9 stimulated a $ sim$9 -fold increase in free AA, as compared to unstimulated cells. This result suggests that C5b-9 activates cPLA$ sb2,$ but not the sPLA$ sb2$ enzyme, to release free AA. In further studies, we addressed the regulation of cPLA$ sb2$ in C5b-9-stimulated GEC. The present model of cPLA$ sb2$ activation involves the combined effects of: (1) an increase in cytosolic calcium concentration, which induces translocation of cPLA$ sb2$ from the cytosol to the plasma membrane, and may be mediated by the amino terminal "CaLB" (Ca$ sp{+2}$-dependent lipid binding) domain, and (2) phosphorylation by MAP kinase. To test the role of the CaLB domain, release of AA was monitored in GEC stably transfected with three constructs; cPLA$ sb2$ wild type (wt), cPLA$ sb2 Delta$CaLB (i.e., cPLA$ sb2$-wt with deleted CaLB domain), and neo (control) GEC. In GEC overexpressing cPLA$ sb2$-wt, C5b-9 stimulated a marked increase in free AA (as above). In contrast, in GEC overexpressing the cPLA$ sb2 Delta$CaLB enzyme, the C5b-9 induced increase in free $ sp3$H-AA was comparable to neo, despite expression of cPLA$ sb2 Delta$CaLB at levels similar to cPLA$ sb2$-wt. The results indicate tha</description><creator>Panesar, Mandip</creator><contributor>Cybulsky, Andrey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Regulation of phospholipase A2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558g24g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw55q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t837x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An evolving environment can have such an impact on the requirements of an existing software system that it can render the system obsolete. We have experienced precisely such a loss in our research environment. The Congruence Evaluation System was an innovative proof of concept (CES POC) system, developed over two years with three person-years of effort. It was part of an environment which was constantly evolving, and this change in the environment dictated the fitness of the CES POC system in the environment. The system served excellently for the basic research goal of discovery and proof, but failed seriously in the long-term goal of evolvability of the entire suite of tools being built concurrently by several researchers in the team. In this thesis, we describe a case study of requirements changes in an evolving environment involved in the development of unprecedented systems. In particular, we identify requirements-oriented factors that caused the demise of an innovative system in such an environment. The thesis also describes some lessons learnt from this experience.</description><creator>Nanda, Vivek.</creator><contributor>Madhavji, N. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>The impact of environmental evolution on requirements changes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f3326.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t837x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w177f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various accounts have been proposed to explain the deficits found in children with specific language impairment (SLI). Since many of these hypotheses have been evaluated using English speaking subjects, there is an important need for cross-linguistic evidence. In this study, the language of Quebec French speaking language-impaired children was examined in an attempt to provide further information about the nature and characteristics of this impairment. The research examined the language of ten 7-year-old unilingual French language-impaired children. Their language was compared to language samples elicited from ten 7-year-old and ten 5-year-old normally developing children. Spontaneous language samples were elicited and analyzed in terms of correct use and error type in six linguistic structures: auxiliaries, copulas, verbs, articles, adjectives, and possessive adjectives. The findings were discussed in light of current competing explanatory hypotheses and were found to support hypotheses that suggest that language impairment is at the level of functional categories. Finally, future directions and clinical implications were addressed.</description><creator>Methé, Susan</creator><contributor>Crago, Martha (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Psychology, Developmental.</subject><subject>Language, Linguistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology.</subject><title>Grammatical morphology in French language-impaired children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c34z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w177f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn52h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work describes an investigation of the development of a Fourier Transform Infrared (FTIR) spectroscopic method for the determination of Solid Fat Index (SFI) of fats as a possible replacement of the traditional dilatometric procedure. The initial approach considered was the use of an existing FTIR analytical package which was designed to measure iodine value (IV), saponification number (SN), and cis and trans content. It was hypothesized that these measures could be related to SFI using multiple linear regression (MLR), thereby allowing the existing analytical package to simultaneously make SFI measures. It was found that there was a strong relationship between SN/cis/trans measurements and SFI, especially in sequentially hydrogenated oils. The MLR relationships, however, did not reproduce the dilatometric SFI values with sufficient accuracy in the general case, and this approach had to be abandoned. Subsequently, a partial least squares (PLS) calibration approach was investigated, relating the dilatometric SFI data directly to the spectral characteristics of the melted fats. It was found that suitable PLS calibrations could be developed for soybean and Canola oils. Based on these results, an FTIR system was programmed to determine SFI and the performance of the system validated using pre-analyzed "unknowns". It was shown that the SFI of either soybean or Canola oils could be determined to within $ pm$ 1.0 SFI. As configured, the FTIR system is capable of determining the SFI of a neat and clear, melted fat sample at 80$ sp circ$C in less than two minutes, providing four SFI values, representing the solids content at 50, 70, 80 and 92$ sp circ$F. In contrast to the standard dilatometric method, which takes over two hours to carry out, the FTIR approach provides a rapid means of determining SFI, the technique being suitable for routine quality control applications in the fats and oils industry.</description><creator>Memon, Khalida Perveen.</creator><contributor>Voort, F. R. van de (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Oils and fats, Edible -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><title>Solid fat index determination by Fourier transform (FTIR) spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999867d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn52h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977x04p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus (PPTg) has been proposed to be critical in drug and food reward. It is a major source of cholinergic inputs to the substantia nigra and ventral tegmental area, areas important in reward, and is believed to modulate activity of dopamine neurons through a cholinergic mechanism. The firing rate of cholinergic PPTg cells is regulated by muscarinic autoreceptors that can be blocked to increase cell firing. If the PPTg modulates dopamine neurons involved in reward, then a muscarinic antagonist microinjected into the PPTg should be rewarding. To test this hypothesis, bilateral microinjections of scopolamine methyl bromide (5 $ mu$g or 20 $ mu$g) or 0.9% saline were used as reward treatments in the conditioned place preference test. On the test day, rats from both doses of drug avoided the drug-paired chamber, which suggests that cholinergic PPTg cells are not involved in reward.</description><creator>Mehta, Rick R.</creator><contributor>Franklin, Keith B. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Mesencephalic tegmentum.</subject><subject>Reward (Psychology)</subject><subject>Cholinergic mechanisms.</subject><subject>Conditioned response.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><title>Microinjections of quaternary scopolamine into the pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus induce a conditioned place aversion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt64x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977x04p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zq59b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of rehabilitation in maximizing seniors' independence is becoming more important as Canada's population ages and as health care shifts to the community. It is necessary for rehabilitation professionals to understand the factors that contribute to seniors' independence in order to accurately focus services and to justify directions taken in the process of health care reform. The overall objective of this study was to determine the degree to which inner-city seniors are living independently today and to identify factors contributing to independent living. A cross-sectional study was conducted with subjects selected by a random telephone selection method. One hundred and sixty-one community-dwelling persons, aged 65 and over who live in Montreal's downtown core were interviewed over the phone to obtain information on sociodemographics, health and disability. Nearly 30% of participants reported their degree of independent living as only moderate or low on the three independent living outcomes. The vast majority reflect a positive portrait of physical function and integration. However, this group represents the tip of the iceberg because they are significantly healthier than non-participants. Several demographic, health and disability factors were identified as contributing to independent living in this group of community-dwelling seniors. These findings are important for rehabilitation professionals as many of the factors are modifiable from both societal and health points of view.</description><creator>Magnan, Lise D.</creator><contributor>Mayo, Nancy E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Sociology, Individual and Family Studies.</subject><subject>Gerontology.</subject><title>Factors contributing to independent living of inner-city seniors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/736666625.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq59b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg47j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Information retrieval in large data spaces using formal, structure oriented patterns of features has many possible applications. We developed and studied a system that can be used to localize code segments in a program. The system is built using a generic and extensible object oriented framework and uses the Viterbi dynamic programming algorithm on simple Markov models to calculate a similarity measure between an abstractly described code segment and a possible instantiation of it in the program. The resulting system can be incorporated in a larger cooperative environment of CASE tools and can be used during the design recovery process to perform concept localization.</description><creator>Magdalinos, Christos.</creator><contributor>Mori, Renato De (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>An information retrieval tool for reverse software engineering</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn76m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg47j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk82r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a conservative algorithm for the parallel simulation of billiard balls. Simulating billiard balls has become an important benchmark for parallel event driven simulation schemes. The approach distinguishes itself in that it makes use of shared variables to enable processors to ascertain the state of the computation at neighboring processors. The table is partitioned into segments which are simulated by different processors. The shared variable corresponds to a region at the boundary between table segments (referred to as the critical region). By making use of shared variables, a significant speed-up over the execution time of a purely conservative approach is obtained. The algorithm was implemented on a BBN Butterfly, as was a purely conservative algorithm. In the purely conservative algorithm, a processor wishing to process a ball in the critical region waits until the neighbouring processor's simulation time is greater than the time of the event it wishes to process. In our experiments, we examined three population levels of balls--2400, 4800 and 7200. These populations were chosen to reflect low, medium and high populations of balls. The shared-variable approach resulted in a 30 to 50 percent decrease in execution time with respect to purely conservative approach.</description><creator>MacKenzie, Peter A.</creator><contributor>Tropper, Carl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Parallel simulation of billiard balls using shared variables</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c57j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk82r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x1151</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent studies have shown that a variety of K$ sp+$ channels can be enhanced by somatostatin (SST; inward and delayed rectifier, muscarinic regulated K$ sp+$ channel, Ca$ sp{2+}$-activated K$ sp+$ channel, ...). Since a somatostatin receptor (SSTR) is heterogeneous, it is not clear which SSTR subtype (five are identified) is involved in regulating each K$ sp+$ channel, nor whether the regulation is and if so to what extent receptor subtype specific. In this study we characterized electrophysiologically the effect of somatostatin-14 (SST-14) in monkey kidney cells (COS-7) stably expressing one of the five recently cloned SSTR subtypes, human somatostatin receptor subtype 4, using whole cell voltage clamp technique at room temperature (20-23$ sp circ$C). The outward current produced by a sequence of depolarizing steps from a holding potential of $-$80 mV was enhanced by $&gt;$1 nM SST-14. Both the endogenous and SST-14 enhanced outward current had a high threshold ($ sim -$40 mV). The reversal potentials of their tail currents changed with a change of (K$ sp+ rbrack sb{ rm o}$ as expected for a current carried predominantly by K$ sp+$ ions. It was blocked by TEA (10-20 mM) and Ba$ sp{2+}$ (1 mM), but not by charybdotoxin (100 nM) and carbachol (50 $ mu$M) in the extracellular solution suggesting that it is largely due to a delayed rectifier K$ sp+$ channel. A smaller inward current at potentials negative to $ sim -$60 mV was also observed and was enhanced by SST-14 in a similar concentration range. It was blocked by Ba$ sp{2+}$ (1 mM) and Cs$ sp+$ (1 mM) suggesting that SST-14 also enhances an inward rectifier K$ sp+$ current. Both outward and inward currents enhanced by SST-14 were pertussis toxin and cAMP sensitive.</description><creator>Lu, Jun, 1969-</creator><contributor>Glavinovic, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Currents induced by somatostatin-14 in monkey kidney cells (COS-7) stably expressing human somatostatin receptor subtype 4</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq196.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x1151</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp45z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three hundred and twenty men and women were exposed to five levels of conventional sexism and affirmative action-induced discrimination. No perceptual minimisation of discrimination was found: instead participants linearly maximised the impact of discrimination. New measures of emotional responses to discrimination revealed changes in both internal (depression) and external (anger) negative affect, with varying intensities of anger and depression directed at different targets. Similarly, new measures of behavioural reactions to discrimination revealed more antinormative and collectivistic behavioural intentions than previous research. Minute but consistent effects of frame condition were observed in each sample. Finally, clear differences emerged between the responses of men and women, and between responses in the conventional and affirmative action-induced discrimination conditions.</description><creator>Louis, Winnifred R.</creator><contributor>Taylor, Donald M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Sexism.</subject><subject>Reverse discrimination.</subject><title>Towards an understanding of responses to discrimination</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m150m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp45z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h380r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the context of teleoperated mobile robotics, the use of video data is one of the most desirable sensing modalities for vehicle guidance. Unfortunately, maintaining reliable noise-free video transmission, especially in cost sensitive teleoperation applications is a frequent problem. We developed a mobile robot system for teleoperation using a robot mounted camera as a primary sensor. This system functions in a partially-known environment for which a 3D geometric map is available. In this thesis we describe aspects of the system related to enhanced reality, that is the augmentation of the returned video data with information extracted from the world knowledge base. If during robot navigation our sensor data (returned video) experiences transmission delays or becomes too noisy or obstructed, we superimposed artificially generated graphics (using the model representation) onto a regular video picture. Once a clear transmission was recaptured or the obscuring obstacle shifted from its old position, video data covering that area of the image was redisplayed for consequent navigation. This task of fusing these two representations together simultaneously, in an efficient and realistic fashion during robot teleoperation, was the goal of our research.</description><creator>Lonji, Kadima.</creator><contributor>Dudek, Gregory (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Mobile robot teleoperation using enhanced video</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p324.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h380r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j14q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A static chamber technique was used to measure methane emissions in July and August, 1995 from peatland sites in the Fort Simpson area, Northwest Territories, at the southern fringe of the discontinuous permafrost zone. Sites were classified ecologically and geomorphologically, and water table and temperature regimes were monitored. Methane emissions ranged from $-$3.3 to 1144.2 mg/m$ sp2 cdot$d, from raised frozen sites to pond sites, respectively, similar to emissions recorded from other boreal regions. Water table was the strongest predictor of CH$ sb4$ emission. Although peat temperature is significantly correlated to methane flux, it did not significantly improve the flux-water table relationship. Methane storage within the saturated portion of the peat profile ranged from 0.2 to 4.2 g/m$ sp2$ over depths ranging from 30 to 76 cm, and did not play a large role in surficial emissions. The zone immediately above and below the water table appears to regulate methane diffusion to the surface. Residence times (storage/flux) ranged from 12 to 30 days in poor fens, and from 6 to 5789 days in fens. Ranges and mean fluxes of methane were determined according to landform and water table position. Based on the geomorphology of the area, overall flux determined for the Fort Simpson area, map NTS 95H, NW1/4, is estimated to be 19 mg/m$ sp2 cdot$d.</description><creator>Liblik, Laura K. (Laura Kaarin)</creator><contributor>Moore, T. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Greenhouse gases -- Environmental aspects -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Simpson Region.</subject><subject>Water table -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Simpson Region.</subject><subject>Peatlands -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Simpson Region.</subject><subject>Atmospheric methane -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Simpson Region.</subject><title>Peatland methane emissions and influencing environmental factors in the southern fringe of the discontinuous permafrost zone, Fort Simpson, Northwest Territories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301339c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j14q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t402j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the present study, the polymerase chain reaction was used to generate a 0.75 kb cDNA clone encoding the mouse U1 snRNP specific C protein from a somatic cDNA library. The identity of the 0.75 kb fragment was confirmed by sequence analysis. This cDNA sequence encodes a protein that has been shown to associate specifically with the U1 snRNP. Northern blot analysis revealed that U1 snRNP C mRNA is a 0.75 kb transcript present in a variety of tissues in the mouse including, the testes, heart, intestine, lung, muscle, pancreas, spleen, kidney, brain and liver. In situ hybridization confirmed the somatic and haploid expression of the U1 snRNP specific C mRNA transcript. In an attempt to correlate RNA expression with protein distribution, light microscopic immunocytochemistry with the anti-Sm antibody was utilized to illustrate spliceosomal snRNP distribution within the mouse. Immunoblots of testicular homogenates probed with the anti-Sm antibody revealed several reactive proteins, of which one, a 21 kD polypeptide, appears to be the U1 snRNP specific C protein based on its predicted molecular weight. Immunoperoxidase staining using the anti-Sm antibody revealed protein localization predominantly within the nuclei of most cells examined, namely; hepatocytes, somatic and germ cells of the testis, neuronal cells within the cerebral cortex and cerebellum, cardiocytes, nephronic cells, intestinal cells, pancreatic acinar cells and Islet of Langerhans cells. However, exceptions in this nuclear reaction were noted in the nuclei of some pancreatic acinar cells, cells of the spleen, and in all elongated spermatids. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Leyne, Maire</creator><contributor>Morales, Carlos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Molecular cloning and tissue distributioin of snRNP specific protein in the mouse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s442z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t402j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb836</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We describe the geometric and dosimetric characteristics of a device developed to modify the penumbra of an electron beam and thereby improve the dose uniformity in the overlap region when fields are abutted. The device is a Lipowitz metal block placed on top of the electron applicator's insertion plate and positioned to stop part of the electron beam. The air-scattered electrons beyond the block increase the penumbra width from about 1.4 to 2.7-3.4 cm. The modified penumbra is broad and almost linear at all depths for the 9 MeV and 12 MeV electron beams used in this study. Film dosimetry was used to obtain beam profiles and isodose distributions. Without the penumbra generator, lateral setup errors of 2 to 3 mm may introduce dose variations of up to 20% in the junction region. Similar setup errors cause less than 5% dose variations when the penumbra generator is used to match the fields.</description><creator>Lachance, Bernard, 1967-</creator><contributor>Pouliot, Jean (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Podgorsak, Ervin B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>A new penumbra generator for matching of electron for matching of electron fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pz01v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb836</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m878p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The classical molecular dynamics model is used for a study of the possible nuclear phase transition in heavy ion collisions at intermediate energies. We implemented this model through Monte Carlo techniques. Different kinds of initial configurations are considered, as well as different methods of particles propagation. In order to simulate the canonical ensemble dynamic evolution we investigate two methods of keeping the temperature constant. We consider a system of 85 nucleons interacting through two-body nucleon-nucleon potential. The calculations are first carried out ignoring Coulomb interaction and then including it. Data on various thermodynamic quantities are obtained and the question of the existence of the phase transition is investigated. To estimate the effect of a finite particle number on critical parameters we go to a system of 200 nucleons.</description><creator>Kvasnikova, Ioulia.</creator><contributor>Gale, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>A classical molecular dynamics study of thermodynamic variables for finite nuclear systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx441.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m878p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x338g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:11:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents two applications of binary tries. Trie structures are used as indexes to store and query spatial data on secondary storage. This thesis deals with point and segment data. Maps are treated as a series of segments in the plane, and links between these maps and other maps or pictures are treated as point data. Maps are stored as Zoom tries on secondary storage. Zoom tries allow efficient accesses to the maps at different levels of resolution. They also allow efficient implementations of range queries. Furthermore, this trie organization provides good data compression. We implement four operations on maps to allow user interaction. We define a link between a map and another map or picture, by a position in the plane, a resolution level and a pointer to a target document. These links are represented as buttons on the maps where they are defined. Zoom tries are used to store and index the position and resolution parts of the link information. The choice of zoom tries as the data structure to store the position information of the links allows the definition of operations on the buttons that integrate naturally with those defined on maps. The contribution of this thesis is the representation of buttons as a zoom trie structure.</description><creator>Kekeh, Charles.</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Buttons as representations of links in variable resolution maps</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p020v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x338g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):850</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>