<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:26:18Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36300" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k791d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cast Al-Si and Al-Si-Mg alloys containing up to 12.6 wt. pct. silicon and 1.0 wt. pct. magnesium were prepared. The changes in electrical conductivity/resistivity of these alloys due to strontium additions have been investigated and explained in terms of variations in microstructure. The conductivity behaviour of strontium-containing and strontium-free alloys was found to exhibit marked differences, depending on the silicon and magnesium contents and the rate of solidification. The electrical conductivity of single phase alloys containing less than 1.60 wt. pct. Si decreased with increasing silicon and magnesium levels. However, strontium had no effect on the conductivity of these solid solution alloys since it does not dissolve appreciably in the aluminum matrix or change the solid solubility of silicon and magnesium in aluminum. Silicon precipitation processes in the supersaturated solid solution alloys of Al-Si and Al-Si-Sr have been examined using the Johnson-Mehl-Avrami equation and found to be isokinetic. Strontium, however, retarded the growth rate of silicon precipitates. Strontium did not affect the kinetics of G.P. zone formation in Al-Si-Mg alloys but it suppressed the formation of stable Mg$ sb2$Si precipitates during subsequent aging at 175$ sp circ$C. Unlike the single phase alloys, two phase Al-Si and Al-Si-Sr alloys, in the range of 2.0 to 12.6 wt. pct. Si, exhibited different electrical conductivity behaviour. The strontium-containing alloys showed a higher conductivity than alloys with no strontium, and this conductivity difference increased as the silicon and magnesium contents were increased and the solidification rate was decreased. It has been demonstrated this difference is due to changes in the silicon morphology. Electron scattering at the interface between the aluminum matrix and the eutectic silicon phase contributes significantly more to the resistivity of unmodified alloys than that of modified alloys. In addition, the resistivity of</description><creator>Mülazımoğlu, Mehmet Hașim</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Aluminum-magnesium-silicon alloys</subject><subject>Aluminum alloys -- Electrometallurgy</subject><subject>Electric conductivity</subject><title>Electrical conductivity studies of cast Al-Si and Al-Si-Mg alloys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405s997r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k791d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765371905</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The structure of the carbohydrate associated with glycoproteins was examined in various human colonic tumour cells in culture following incubation with labeled sugars. Glycopeptides obtained by pronase digestion of the cell surface glycoproteins of three human colon tumours (HCT-8R, CaCo-2, and HCT-15) were compared with those from cells (CCL 239) derived normal adult colon. The tumour cells contain large molecular weight fucose-labeled glycopeptides that are absent in the CCL 239 cells. The large molecular weight fucose- and glucosamine-labeled glycopeptides from HCT-8R cells contain mainly mild alkali labile O-linked oligosaccharides, whereas those isolated from CaCo-2 cells contain primarily N-linked polylactosaminoglycans which bind to Datura stramonium agglutinin-agarose and are sensitive to endo-$ beta$-galactosidase. Differentiation of CaCo-2 cells to polarized cells containing brush border enzymes characteristic of enterocytes is accompanied by a decrease in the relative proportion of fucose- and glucosamine-labeled N-linked polylactosaminoglycans-containing glycopeptides. These polylactosaminoglycans are found on a restricted set of glycoproteins of M$ sb{ rm r}$ 100,000-130,000. In undifferentiated cells, these glycoproteins contain a greater proportion of polylactosaminoglycans than those from differentiated cells.</description><creator>Youakim, Adel</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Tumour- and differentiation-associated changes in the carbohydrate structure of glycoproteins from human colonic cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kb41k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765371905</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35t9252</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At present, the only effective treatment for atherosclerotic arterial obstruction is surgical revascularization. Unfortunately, in some patients, this is unsuccessful due to the extent of the disease; most of these patients require amputation of the limb because of severe pain or gangrene. By expanding on the experimental work of others, we were able to successfully save the limbs of experimental animals (canine) with obstructed arteries by restoring circulation via the use of the venous system (which is not affected by atherosclerosis). Subsequently, we have also been able to save the limbs of a small group of patients using a similar procedure. Angiograms in the clinical and experimental setting revealed reversed flow in the venous bed with new vessel formation around and distal to the arteriovenous reversal. In the present study, we investigated whether or not the reversed venous flow provided nutrient perfusion to the hind limb, the role of severe ischemia in the development of the network of vessels appearing around and distal to the arteriovenous reversal and whether these vessel are newly formed. In addition, we also examined the role of lipid angiogenic factor and controlled exercise, as stimulants in the development of this network of vessels. We have demonstrated that the reversed venous flow provides nutritive perfusion to the limb as measured by transcutaneous oxygen. In addition, we have shown that severe ischemia plays a major role in neovascularization of the canine hind limb in the presence of arteriovenous reversal, as determined angiographically. We have also demonstrated that there is increased capillary growth in the presence of severe ischemia following arteriovenous reversal and that this capillary neoformation can be enhanced by in vivo administration of lipid angiogenic factor or controlled exercise. Finally, we have demonstrated increased tritiated thymidine uptake by endothelial cell nuclei in hind limbs with arteriovenous reversal, suggesting that there is new endothelial formation.</description><creator>Baffour, Richard</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Determination of the nature and mechanism of revascularization of ischemic limbs via the venous route</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st28g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35t9252</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb4949167</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the study was to examine factors related to identification with organizational goals in two Centres of re-education in Quebec. The personnel of these Centres are semiprofessionals with specialized training related to re-education. In a pretest it was found that identification of educators with the organizational goals was similar in both Centres in spite of a greater number of role conflicts in one Centre. This result was contrary to what could be expected. Therefore the question raised was what additional factors enter into the relationship between the organizational goals and educators. Factors examined in this study are based on Mintzberg's management roles descriptors, and substitutes for hierarchical leadership identified in the literature. Substitutes for leadership tested fall in three general domains: personal, job, and organizational characteristics. The following questions were examined: do the substitutes for hierarchical leaders differ in the two Centres; is the performance of management roles perceived as different in the two Centres. Data were obtained from questionnaires submitted to educators and managers in the two Centres. Results show significant differences in identification with the profession, intrinsic feedback from the task itself, perceived organizational formalization, and cohesiveness of the work group. These findings suggest that the educators in one Centre identified with the goals of the organization primarily through identification with the profession. Educators in the second Centre identified with the goals of the organization primarily through the task itself and the cohesive work group. These findings suggests that the educators in one Centre identified with the goals of the organization primarily through identification with the profession. Educators in the second Centre identified with the goals of the organization primarily through the task itself and the cohesive work group.</description><creator>Lamoureux, André.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Leadership</subject><subject>Teachers -- Attitudes</subject><subject>Teachers -- Job satisfaction</subject><subject>School management and organization</subject><subject>Organizational effectiveness</subject><title>Une étude des substituts au leadership hiérarchique en milieu de rééducation /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c46j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb4949167</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hs60x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Early image understanding seeks to derive analytic representations from image data. This thesis presents steps towards this goal for three-dimensional imagery by focusing on the inference of trace points (points belonging to surfaces), and the estimation of associated differential structure given by the principal curvature and direction fields over smooth surfaces. Computation of these fields is posed as the determination of a cross section through the bundle of curvature frames over the estimated trace. Algorithm robustness and the stability of results are essential for analysis of real images; to this end, I present a functional minimization algorithm where the principal direction cross section meets appropriate criteria for a minimum, and develop an implementation as an iterative constraint satisfaction procedure based on local surface smoothness properties. For shape description and eventual object recognition, the exact recovery of local structure everywhere is less important than the identification of singular surface points which prove stable to noise and small surface perturbations, in particular, the umbilic points of surfaces. Such points are computed naturally from the estimated local surface structure embodied in the principal direction cross section of the frame bundle. Examples of the recovery of local structure are presented for synthetic images degraded by noise and for clinical magnetic resonance images.</description><creator>Sander, Peter T.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Magnetic resonance imaging</subject><subject>Pattern recognition systems -- Mathematical models</subject><subject>Three-dimensional display systems</subject><title>On reliably inferring differential structure from three-dimensional images</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j72v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hs60x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v85r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Assuming that moral discourse is prescriptive, what distinguishes it from other types of prescriptive discourse? To say, as Hare does, that it is its overridingness, is subject both to criticisms that assume that overridingness could, in principle, be used to distinguish one type of prescriptive discourse from another, and then show that it is doubtful that moral discourse is overriding, and to the criticisms that claim that it is in principle impossible to use overridingness to distinguish one type of prescriptive discourse from another, because all of them are bound to be on a par in respect of overridingness. It is also impossible to distinguish moral discourse from other types of prescriptive discourse by saying that in it we use arguments based on imaginatively putting oneself in the shoes of others, because such arguments are used in prudential discourse as well. However, we can account for the distinction, if we realize that such arguments can be performed only on certain designated argument-places, and that in moral claims argument-places of two different types are designated for the purpose: those for moral agents and those for moral patients; while in prudential claims argument-places of only one type are designated: those for prudential agents. If this account is accepted, this raises a number of further questions. Examination of these questions leads to a form of relativism about membership in the sets of moral agents and moral patients. This form of relativism, however, leaves considerable room for rational discussion of membership in these sets and is compatible with the rejection of relativism about the content of moral rules.</description><creator>Hajdin, Mane</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Ethical relativism</subject><subject>Moral development</subject><title>Agents, patients, and moral discourse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8523.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v85r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v59v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In relational algebra, a recursive relation R is defined by an equation of the form R = f(R), where f(R) is a positive relational algebra expression. Such an equation can be solved by applying a general closure operator. Although some optimization is possible, the performance obtained using this approach is very dependent on the form of the equation which defines R. Principally for this reason, we have developed specialized closure operators for relations which are solutions to problems of practical importance such as transitive closure, accessibility, shortest path, bill-of-materials, and deductions by containment comparisons. This approach has led to the following general results: (1) design, classification, and analysis of many iterative methods for evaluating recursive relations, as well as analysis of experimental results; (2) formalization of the concept of iterative evaluation of a relation; (3) demonstration that domain algebra can be used to solve problems of concatenation and aggregation of the information associated with a recursive structure; (4) proof that relational division and general containment joins are left-monotone. More specific results consist of a collection of original algorithms which run well on secondary storage, as shown by simulations. Among them, we wish to emphasize the differencing logarithmic transitive closure (TC) algorithms, which are superior to the previously known relational TC algorithms, and the shortest path algorithms, which are in fact generic algorithms for path algebra problems.</description><creator>Clouâtre, André</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Recursive functions.</subject><subject>Relational databases.</subject><title>Implementation and applications of recursively defined relations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m484h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v59v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010q765</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study considers the labor organization of a group of northern Kenyan pastoralists. Since 1960, the Samburu have experienced substantial cattle loss and land circumscription and the work focuses both on herding and non-herding labor responses to a changing regional economy. The viability of Samburu pastoralism rests on specific labor forms which permit intensified production and economic diversification. Based on twenty-four months of fieldwork, primarily during the 1983-84 drought, the study emphasizes the interplay between the social and technical organization of labor. Social institutions of descent and age guide natural resource and delineate work roles, while encouraging the varied forms of cooperation which greatly extend the family workforce. The diversity of technical strategies, which are strongly shaped by cultural preferences, contrasts with the paucity of production materials. Several key findings have applicability to a range of pastoral locales, particularly proof of the positive relationship between labor input and animal output and of the higher efficiency of labor in larger versus smaller-scale herding units only under stable production conditions. Further, the quantitative material on dry season versus drought labor use as well as evidence for differential livestock survival rates represent unique accounts in themselves. Beyond insights into pastoralism, however, the analysis is structured so as to contribute to several important issues in small-scale rural production. The accounts of the interconnection of technology and social forms and of the integration of "on-farm" and "off-farm" enterprise have implications for defining the scope of any labor investigation. The discussions of the terms "labor" and "technology" pose wider questions of the content of such basic concepts. Finally, the methodological discourse on labor measurement should assist those similarly trying to distinguish between "use" and "demand" in predominantly noncapitalist societies.</description><creator>Sperling, Louise.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Samburu (African people)</subject><subject>Kenya -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Labor productivity -- Kenya</subject><title>The labor organization of Samburu pastoralism /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m7288.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010q765</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r9674408</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Within a theoretical framework that combines generative X-bar syntax (Chomsky 1986), a compositional interpretive semantics and elements of Aristotelian logic, this thesis studies the nature of the syntactic and semantic constituents involved in the subject-predicate relations of elementary sentences containing 'be'. Interpretation is characterized in terms of the entities of various types that speakers intend to refer to and the various ontological types that the referents are said to belong to. 'Be' is analyzed as a single lexical item. This analysis unifies all syntactic functions (e.g., auxiliary, copula, main verb) and all "senses" of 'be' (e.g., definitional, equative, predicative, etc.). Conceptually, 'be' in English is an explicit sign of attribution. The propositional content of simple sentences of the form (NP be XP) is the attribution of a certain ontological type or types to the referent(s) of the subject NP. Although the value of postulating a single ontological category to account for all the entities that speakers can refer to and talk about (such as an Aristotelian substance) is questionable, nevertheless, such categories and types seem pertinent for linguistic analysis. With respect to linguistic inference, pronominalization, and question words, an analysis based on ontological types is shown to be more explanatory than one based on the assignment of a fixed set of thematic relations to arguments.</description><creator>Styan, Evelyn Matheson</creator><date>1987</date><subject>English language -- Topic and comment</subject><subject>English language -- Syntax</subject><subject>English language -- Semantics</subject><title>Elementary sentences containing 'be' : a semantic analysis of subject-predicate relations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655h32m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9674408</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2685888</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Timing and electrical verification is an essential part of the design of VLSI digital MOS circuits. It consists of determining the maximum operating frequency of a circuit, and verifying that the circuit will always produce the expected logical behavior at or under this frequency. This complex task requires considerable computer and human resources. The classical simulation approach cannot be used to insure the timing and electrical correctness of the large circuits that are now being designed. The huge number of possible states in large circuits renders this method impractical. Worst-case analysis tools alleviate the problem by restricting the analysis to a limited set of states which correspond to the worst-case operating conditions. However, existing worst-case analysis tools for MOS circuits present several problems. Their accuracy is inherently limited since they use a switch-level model. Also, these procedures have a high computational complexity because they resort to path enumeration to find the latest path in each transistor group. Finally, they lack the ability to analyze circuits with arbitrarily complex clocking schemes. In this text, a new procedure for circuit-level timing analysis is presented. Because it works at electronic circuit level, the procedure can detect electrical errors, and attains an accuracy that is impossible to attain by other means. Efficient algorithms, based on graph theory, have been developed to partition the circuits in a novel way, and to recognize series and parallel combinations. This enables the efficient computation of worst-case, earliest and latest, waveforms in the circuit, using specially designed algorithms. The new procedure extracts automatically the timing requirements from these waveforms and can compute the clocking parameters, including the maximum clock frequency, for arbitrarily complex clocking schemes. A computer program was written to demonstrate the effectiveness of the new procedure and algorithms developed. It has been used to determine the clocking parameters of circuits using different clocking schemes. The accuracy obtained on these parameters is around 5 to 10% when compared with circuit-level simulations. The analysis time grows linearly with the circuit size and is approximately 0.5s per transistor, on a microVAX II computer. This makes the program suitable for VLSI circuits.</description><creator>Dagenais, Michel R.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Integrated circuits -- Very large scale integration -- Computer programs</subject><title>Timing analysis for MOSFETS, an integrated approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x86p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2685888</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m241m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lipid systems containing charged species are examined by both experiment and theory. Experimental studies of the mixing of phosphatidylcholine or phosphatidylethanolamine with phosphatidic acid show that calcium induces fast ($ leq$1s) phase separation of these otherwise miscible systems, and that this can occur in an isolated bilayer. Ionogenic behaviour is theoretically investigated using a new electrolyte model which explicitly includes both the solvent and particle sizes, and a binding model which uses Guggenheim combinatorics to treat non 1-1 binding stoichiometries. This work predicts a reduced dielectric constant near charged surfaces and strong repulsive forces between closely spaced ($&lt;$15A) surfaces. A reanalysis of data from charged monolayers experiments indicates (1) that the new electrolyte model describes double layer behaviour at high surface charge densities better than the traditional Derjaguin - Landau - Verwey - Overbeek (DLVO) theory, (2) that calcium and magnesium bind to phosphatidylserine monolayers with a 1-1 stoichiometry.</description><creator>Graham, Ian Stanley.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Phospholipids</subject><subject>Lipids</subject><title>Experimental and theoretical investigations of charged phospholipid bilayers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602136q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m241m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sq83g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of $ beta$-endorphin in the cardiovascular depressor response elicited by clonidine or by electrical stimulation of the nucleus tractus solitarii (NTS) was studied in awake as well as anesthetized rats. The opiate antagonists, naloxone or naltrexone, inhibited the hypotensive and bradycardic effects of clinidine in spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHR), in normotensive and steroid-salt hypertensive Sprague-Dawley (S-D) rats, but not in normotensive Wistar Kyoto (WKY) rats. The brain ACTH/$ beta$-endorphin fibre system originating in the arcuate nucleus was eliminated by neonatal treatment with monosodium glutamate (MSG). MSG-treatment abolished the naloxone-sensitive component of the effects of clonidine in SHR, while the naloxone-resistant effects of clonidine in WKY were not affected. Intra-NTS microinjection of clonidine (5 nmol) decreased blood pressure and heart rate, and these effects were inhibited by previous intra-NTS injection of dl- but not d-naloxone (270 pmol) in both SHR and normotensive S-D rats. Intra-NTS injection of $ beta$-endorphin (0.3 pmol) also reduced blood pressure and heart rate in both rat strains. In SHR, the effects of both clonidine and $ beta$-endorphin were inhibited by ICI 174864, a selective $ delta$ receptor antagonist, but not by $ beta$-funaltrexamine, a selective $ mu$ receptor antagonist (270 pmol, intra-NTS). In contrast, in normotensive S-D rats only the $ mu$ and not the $ delta$ antagonist was an effective inhibitor. In S-D rats made hypertensive by prolonged treatment with a mineralocorticoid and salt, the pattern of inhibition was the same as in SHR. The depressor baroreflex response was elicited by electrical stimulation of the NTS. In SHR, intra-NTS injection of an antiserum to $ beta$-endorphin inhibited, while an antiserum to met-enkephalin potentiated the hypotensive and bradycardic response to NTS stimulation. In similar experiments in WKY rats, the antisera were ineffective. These findings are interpreted to indicate that the cardiovascular effects of clonidine involve release of $ beta$-endorphin and subsequent stimulation of opiate receptors in the NTS. The most likely source of $ beta$-endorphin is nerve terminals whose cell bodies are in the arcuate nucleus. The released $ beta$-endorphin acts on $ mu$ receptors in normotensive or $ delta$ receptors in hypertensive rats, with no evidence for the additional involvement of peripheral opiate receptors. (Abstract shortened with permission of author.)</description><creator>Mosqueda-Garcia, Agustin Rogelio</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>The role of beta-endorphin in central cardiovascular control /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx728.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sq83g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924c472</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The murine F$ sb1$ hybrid model of graft-versus-host (GVH) disease was used to investigate the nature of GVH-induced T cell immunodeficiency. Chronic GVH reactions were induced in BAF$ sb1$ mice by the i.v. injection of 50 $ times$ 10$ sp6$ parental A strain lymphoid cells. At various days (43-139) after GVH induction the thymi and spleens were excised and used for in vitro functional studies. In addition, both lymphoid and non-lymphoid organs were evaluated histologically. Interleukin 1 (IL-1) and 2 (IL-2) were used as probes to assess the functional status of the peanut agglutinin positive (PNA$ sp-$) and peanut agglutinin negative (PNA$ sp+$) subpopulations. The results obtained strongly suggest that GVH-induced T cell immunodeficiency is due in part to a decreased responsiveness to IL-1 and IL-2, and to a marked deficiency in IL-2 production.</description><creator>Mendes, Mariza L.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>An investigation into the mechanism(s) of T-cell immunodeficiency associated with thymic dysplasia in murine graft-versus-host reactions /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nf46g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c472</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784m445</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Symbiotic interaction of Rhizobium with roots of legume plants leads to the formation of root nodules that are capable of reducing atmospheric nitrogen. In nodule cells, bacteria are always enclosed inside the peribacteroid membrane (pbm) which is derived from the plant cell plasma membrane. The pbm mediates all the molecular exchanges between the host plant and bacteria. The pbm of soybean (Glycine max) nodules induced by Bradyrhizobium japonicum was characterized for the presence of nodule-specific proteins (nodulins), which may be involved in some of the nodule-specific roles the pbm plays. The pbm was found to contain a number of nodulins, and most of them were shown to be of plant origin. The peribacteroid fluid (pbf) was also purified and shown to contain nodulins. Some of the pbf proteins were highly glycosylated. Immunological localization at the electron microscopic level has shown that pbm nodulins are inserted specifically in the pbm; almost none are detected in the plasma membrane (pm) of infected cells even though the pbm is derived from it. The amino acid sequences of three different pbm nodulins (nodulin-23, -24 and -26) do not share significant primary structure homology, neither do their tentative secondary structures. Our results do not preclude targeting based on pbm-nodulin-specific feature(s) of the proteins; but it is possible that pbm-specific localization is achieved by differential rates of membrane synthesis, or turnover, in pbm as compared to the plasma membrane.</description><creator>Fortin, Marc G.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Nitrogen -- Fixation.</subject><subject>Bacteria, Denitrifying.</subject><subject>Soybean.</subject><subject>Rhizobium.</subject><title>Modulins of the peribacteroid compartment in soybean nodules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk54h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784m445</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v610p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The accuracy of telephone-administered dietary recalls was determined for a group of 159 elderly subjects. Accuracy was assessed by comparing a telephoned 24-hour recall that included a meal consumed at a congregate meal site on the day prior to the telephone interview with data on observed intake for that meal obtained by trained dietitians. For 12 of the 15 nutrients evaluated, the bias in the mean recalled intake data was less than 10 percent. After appropriate adjustment for the imprecision in the data on observed intake, there was evidence of an attenuated regression slope relating the individual recalls to the true intakes for only five of the 15 nutrients evaluated. Two statistically significant models for predicting the accuracy of the dietary recall data on the basis of health, dietary, social and demographic characteristics were developed. Although this latter work was of a hypothesis-generating nature, the clustering of variables related to heightened awareness of what is eaten in one of the models suggests that further evaluation of these types of predictive variables is appropriate.</description><creator>Dubois, Sheila.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><title>Accuracy of telephone-administered dietary recalls in a group of free-living elderly subjects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967441j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v610p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h40j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Different types of biomass samples including fungi and algae were treated for their gold and cobalt uptake capacity. The performance of activated carbon and ion-exchange resins were compared with the metal uptake capacity of the biosorbents. Sargassum natans, a brown seaweed, exhibited a high gold uptake capacity outperforming the ion-exchange resin and equalling activated carbon. Algal biomass of Ascophyllum nodosum proved to be a very potent biosorbent for cobalt. While the temperature, agitation and biomass particle size did not affect the metal uptake process, the effect of pH was significant for both gold and cobalt uptakes. The optimum pH for gold uptake was 2.5 and for cobalt, was 4-5. The kinetics of cobalt biosorption was relatively rapid (5 min) at the initial concentration of the metal in solution, 100 mg/L. The biosorptive uptake of gold required 2 h to reach equilibrium when the initial concentration of gold was 100 mg/L. None of the tested cations, such as K$ sp+$, Ca$ sp{2+}$, Fe$ sp{2+}$, Cr$ sp{3+}$, UO$ sbsp{2}{2+}$, Ni$ sp{2+}$, Zn$ sp{2+}$, Ag$ sp+$, affected the gold uptake capacity of S. natans biomass under the optimum conditions. Anions, such as NO$ sbsp{3}{-}$, SO$ sbsp{4}{2-}$, CO$ sbsp{3}{2-}$, PO$ sbsp{4}{3-}$, and Pb$ sp{2+}$ suppressed the gold uptake somewhat. Under the optimum process conditions cations, except K$ sp+$ and Fe$ sp{2+}$, and anions, NO$ sbsp{3}{-}$ in particular, exhibited a pronounced negative effect on the cobalt uptake by A. nodosum biomass. Sequestered gold was eluted with a mixture of thiourea and ferric ammonium sulphate solution. Approximately 98% of sequestered gold was eluted with 17 h in a batch contacting system at the optimum solids (biomass)-to-liquid ratio of 5 and pH of 5. At increased temperatures, the gold elution rate increased only slightly. Efficient desorption of cobalt was achieved using CaCl$ sb2$/HCL solution at pH 3. Cobalt elution time was quite short. Temperature affected neither desorption rate nor the equilibrium. The optimum solid-to-liquid ratio was 12 for desorption of cobalt from A. nodosum biomass. The gold taken up by the biosorbent was deposited in its elemental form. Available mathematical models, including the REDEQL2 chemical equilibrium model, were tested for theoretical predictions of co-ion competition in attempt to better understand the biosorption mechanism. (Abstract shortened with permission of author.)</description><creator>Kuyucak, Nural.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Sorbents</subject><subject>Cobalt -- Recycling.</subject><subject>Algae</subject><subject>Gold -- Recycling.</subject><subject>Adsorption (Biology)</subject><title>Algal biosorbents for gold and cobalt</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb75j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h40j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z5973</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To examine the possibility that the diverse functions for which simian virus 40 (SV40) large tumor (T) antigen is required are carried out by the different structural subclasses of the protein, an electrophoresis system that uses nondenaturing polyacrylamide gradient gels was devised. It resolves the monomeric and various homologous and heterologous oligomeric forms of large T antigen into distinct bands which retain enzyme activity and immunoreactivity. The large T antigen analogue, D2T antigen, showed primarily a monomeric and three higher order bands on such gels. These were assayed for ATPase activity and protein kinase activity and found to exhibit different levels of these activities. One hypothesis for transformation by SV40 is that high molecular weight complexes between large T antigen and the cellular encoded p53 tumor protein play an essential role. The complexes are identified by their sedimentation rates through sucrose gradients and species sedimenting at 16S and 23S and above have been characterized. These species were examined further in SV40-transformed mouse (SVT2) and human (SV80) cells by nondenaturing gradient gel electrophoresis. The T antigen species resolved on the gels were visualized by Western blotting employing anti-D2T serum. The 16S and 23S peaks of large T antigen were resolved into three high molecular weight bands, two of which also reacted with antibodies specific for p53, indicating that SV40-transformed cells contain two forms of the large T antigen/p53 complex. The various bands were also reacted with antibodies against biologically distinguishable populations of the viral protein. The results obtained with these antibodies, together with those obtained on the enzyme activities of the different forms of D2T antigen, support the hypothesis that oligomerization yields subclasses of large T antigen with distinct sets of functions and biological activities.</description><creator>Stedman, Deborah.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Biology, General.</subject><title>The characterization of the high molecular weight forms of simian virus 40 T antigen /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd61x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z5973</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w796s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental study of laboratory populations of the stored-products moth, Cadra cautella (Lepidoptera: Phycitidae) and its larval parasitoid, Venturia canescens (Hymenoptera: Ichneumonidae) identified and quantified density- and age-dependent demographic characteristics of the host-parasitoid system. Host imago longevity and fecundity depended on larval weight at pupation. Observed effects of C. cautella larval competition for food on larval mortality, stage duration, and weight at pupation were successfully captured in a mathematical model. Host larval age significantly influenced inter-stage cannibalism and susceptibility to mortality resulting from parasitoid oviposition wounds. Both larval parasitoid developmental rates and adult parasitoid attack rates depended on host larval age. Long-term population experiments of host and host-parasitoid populations revealed that host populations fluctuated with a period slightly in excess of host generation time and that parasitoid populations were in synchrony with host populations.</description><creator>Gordon, David M.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Moths -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Host-parasite relationships.</subject><subject>Cadra cautella</subject><subject>Venturia canescens</subject><title>Population dynamics of a host-parasitoid system with particular reference to age-structure effects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x063.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w796s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j21z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An orbital dependent local spin density-functional (LSD) scheme with a generated exchange, the LSD GX scheme, has been developed based on the correct normalization conditions of an electron gas. This scheme contains no adjustable parameters; the B$ sb1$, B$ sb2$ and $ alpha sp lim$ are constant for all atoms once the shape of the Fermi hole is chosen. These parameters are rigorously calculated using an unspecified Fermi hole correlation factor and they give an exchange density which reduces exactly to the homogeneous free electron gas one at the high electron density limit. The LSD GX exchange density is corrected for self-interaction (SI) by splitting the total Fermi hole correlation factor into pure-exchange and self-interaction holes. These new LSD and SI corrected schemes are compared to each other. They also compare very well theoretically and numerically (total energies and eigenvalues) with other local schemes current in the literature. New equations for the IP and electronegativities of the atoms in these local schemes are derived which give good results.</description><creator>Manoli, Soheil Dimitri.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Nuclear spin</subject><subject>Spin exchange</subject><subject>Electron gas</subject><title>The generalized exchange local spin density-functional theory /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j630g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j21z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816n22x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of ribonucleoside phosphoramidites protected at the 2$ sp prime$-hydroxyl with alkylsilyl ethers was developed for the solid phase synthesis of oligoribonucleotides. A series of pentadecameric oligomers of various base composition was synthesized using this methodology and a complete protocol for the deprotection of synthetic oligoribonucleotides was developed. The use of $ beta$-cyanoethyl phosphate protection was compared to that of methyl protection in the synthesis of pentadeca-uridylic acid sequences and no significant difference between the use of the two protecting groups was found. Concurrently a procedure for the derivatization of long chain alkylamine controlled pore glass beads with ribonucleosides was used to provide an improved solid phase support for the efficient automated synthesis of long oligomers. A side reaction on this support was identified and a method for its prevention developed. A reaction occurring at the O$ sp6$-position of guanosine residues, which leads to chain cleavage, was identified. The basis of this reaction was characterized by both $ sp{31}$P nuclear magnetic resonance and the synthesis of oligoriboguanylate sequences. Three methods involving: protection of the O$ sp6$-position, the use of an alternate coupling cycle, and the use of a different phosphoramidite activator, were successfully applied to the resolution of this problem. The aforementioned procedures were utilized in the synthesis of a half E. Coli N- f - met tRNA molecule 43 units in length. Finally the cumulative knowledge gained from the above studies was applied to the synthesis of an entire E. Coli N- f - met analogue 77 units in length along with a number of other very long sequences. Methods for the deprotection of these oligomers were investigated culminating in the isolation of oligoribonucleotides which were successfully characterized by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis, enzyme degradation, enzymatic and chemical sequencing, terminal nucleotide analysis, and, in the case of the E. Coli f - met tRNA analogue, an aminoacylation assay.</description><creator>Usman, Nassim.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>RNA -- Synthesis</subject><subject>Oligoribonucleotides.</subject><title>Nucleoside phosphoramidites in the automated, solid phase synthesis of oligoribonucleotides and their analogues : the chemical synthesis of an E. Coli N-Formyl-Methionine tRNA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h0259.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n22x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tc719</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dietary factors such as the consumption of tryptophan, the precursor of serotonin, or sugar, may play an important role in influencing alcohol-induced impairment. Study I used an amino acid diet to manipulate plasma tryptophan in male social drinkers in a 3 (supplemented, balanced, and depleted tryptophan) x 3 (alcohol, placebo, sober) design with 12 subjects per cell. A variety of mood, memory, and psychomotor performance measures were taken at baseline, five hours after amino acid ingestion, and after alcohol consumption. Strong alcohol effects were produced but no tryptophan, nor alcohol-tryptophan interaction effects were found. Study II examined the combined effects of sucrose and alcohol in a 3 (100 g sugar, 35 g sugar, 0 g sugar) x 3 (alcohol, placebo, sober) design with 15 subjects per cell. Subjects were tested on tasks similar to those used in Study I at a variety of times following intoxication (i.e., 0.5 hours, 1.5 h, 3.5 h) in order to examine effects when blood glucose peaked as well as at a point when hypoglycemic rebound can occur in some subjects. A strong alcohol x sugar interaction was seen 0.5 h after drinking, with high doses of sugar attenuating intoxication without influencing blood alcohol levels. No hypoglycemia was produced after 3.5 h. Study III replicated Study II using a simpler design which controlled for the possible effects of aspartame (the placebo sweetener used in Study II). A variety of gastric or central mechanisms, which can account for the finding that sucrose can reduce the intoxicating effects of ethanol, are discussed.</description><creator>Zacchia, Camillo.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Alcohol -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Alcoholism -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><title>The effects of tryptophan and sucrose on alcohol-induced impairment /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx25n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc719</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm73g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prediction of flow and stress patterns in viscoelastic fluids flowing through channels of complex shape is of theoretical interest in non-Newtonian fluid mechanics but also of large practical interest in the materials processing industry. The first part of this work presents a finite difference computational analysis of the flow of an Upper Convected Maxwell fluid through various geometrically complex channels. The method of Boundary Fitted Curvilinear Coordinates is used to remove the problem of boundary complexity from the finite difference solution of flow problems on arbitrary domains. Several elastic effects, such as vortex growth in contractions and vortex suppression in expanding sections are predicted. The second part of this Thesis is concerned with the modelling of the filling stage of injection molding in a cavity of complex shape with an insert. Non-isothermality, viscoelasticity and the presence of an advancing interface are dealt with in this section. Solution adaptive curvilinear meshes are used for the numerical solution of the model equations on a time-dependent domain. Stress, temperature, pressure, velocity and shear rate profiles within the cavity have been obtained by this analysis. Parametric studies have revealed the effect of key process characteristics on the pressure and thermal gradients during filling. Model predictions are compared to experimental results obtained on an injection molding machine. The model is able to predict with satisfactory accuracy the pressure evolution as well as the pressure gradients developing in the cavity during filling. Finally, a three-dimensional solution of the energy equation revealed the strong spatial and temporal variation of temperature within the mold in both the planar and the thickness directions, and allowed for an evaluation of the crystallinity development in the solidified material during filling.</description><creator>Papathanasiou, Thanasis D.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Viscoelastic flows in complex geometries : an analysis of the filling stage of the injection molding of thermoplastics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/474299894.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm73g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tc72k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reactive complexes CpRu(PPh$ sb3) sb2$SR (Cp = $ eta sp5$-cyclopentadienyl; R = H, 4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me, 1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$, CHMe$ sb2$) were prepared by briefly heating CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)$ sb2$Cl with LiSR in refluxing THF. Treatment of the thiolates with CO gave CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SR. The reaction of CS$ sb2$ with CpRu(PPh$ sb3) sb2$SR gave the thioxanthate complexes CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(S$ sb2$CSR) (R = 4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me, 1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$, CHMe$ sb2$), wherein the CS$ sb2$ inserted into the Ru-S bond. A study of the kinetics of this reaction and the crystal structure of CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(S$ sb2$CS(1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$)) is also reported. Refluxing a toluene solution of CpRu(PPh$ sb3) sb2$SR (R = 1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$, CHMe$ sb2$) gave, via sequential loss of PPh$ sb3$ the dimeric complexes (CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)SR) $ sb2$ which converted into the complexes (CpRuSR) $ sb3$. The crystal structure of (CpRuS(1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$)) $ sb3$ is reported. The reaction of SO$ sb2$ with CpRu(PPh$ sb3) sb2$SR (R = 4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me, 1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$, CHMe$ sb2$) gave the complexes CpRu(SO$ sb2$)(PPh$ sb3$)S(SO$ sb2$)R. A reaction mechanism is proposed and the x-ray structure of CpRu(SO$ sb2$)(PPh$ sb3$)S(SO$ sb2$)(4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me) was determined. The stable complex CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)S(SO$ sb2$)(CHMe$ sb2$) was observed by $ sp1$H and IR spectroscopy. The complex CpRu(SO$ sb2)$(PPh$ sb3)$S(4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me) was prepared by melting CpRu(SO$ sb2)$(PPh$ sb3)$S(SO$ sb2)$(4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me). The complexes CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SER (E = S, SS and S(O); R = 4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me, 1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$, CHMe$ sb2)$ were prepared by the reaction of the thiol CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SH with the appropriate phthalimide sulfur transfer reagents REphth (phth = phthalimide). The x-ray structures of CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SS(CHMe$ sb2$), CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SSS(1-C$ sb3$H$ sb7$), CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SS(O)(CHMe$ sb2$) and CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SS(O)$ sb2$(4-C$ sb6$H$ sb4$Me) are discussed.</description><creator>Plouffe, Pierre-Yves</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>The chemistry of cyclopentadienyl ruthenium complexes containing thiolato or catenated polysulfano ligands /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm70w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc72k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913q56d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A literature review shows that qualitative dichotomies describing interspecific differences in the movement patterns of foraging animals are widely-used and biologically important, but fraught with ambiguity. Consistent use of the terminology from foraging theory and stronger quantification are proposed to increase clarity and facilitate more rigorous tests of hypotheses. Greater consideration of intraspecific variation is also needed. In forest bird and lizard communities, move-frequency distributions are bimodal, supporting a dichotomous view, but there is important variation within the statistical modes. Fish species with more red muscle are more mobile than species with less red muscle, but the frequency distribution of the proportion of red muscle does not match subjective, dichotomous classifications. A quantitative field investigation of foraging young-of-the-year brook charr (Salvelinus fontinalis) reveals significant individual differences in movement patterns that are more strongly related to microhabitat use and diet, than to morphological and environmental parameters thought to influence swimming capability.</description><creator>McLaughlin, Robert L. (Robert Louis)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Brook trout.</subject><subject>Predation (Biology)</subject><subject>Animal behavior</subject><title>Quantitative studies of the variation in movement patterns used by predators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s551j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q56d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr151</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:58:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Blends of cellulose (CELL) with polyvinyl pyrrolidone (PVP), poly(4-vinyl pyridine) (P$ sb4$VPy), polyvinyl alcohol (PVA), polyacrylonitrile (PAN), poly($ epsilon$-caprolactone) (PCL), and nylon 6 (Ny6), and of chitosan with PVA were investigated in an attempt to gain some insight into the factors that affect the miscibility of cellulose with synthetic polymers. The miscibility and the scale of mixing of the various blends were studied by differential scanning calorimetry, dynamic mechanical analysis, infrared and NMR spectroscopy, and proton spin-lattice relaxation measurements. The CELL/PVP, CELL/P$ sb4$VPy, and chitosan/PVA blends were shown to be homogeneous at the molecular level, while the CELL/PAN blends were shown to mix on a larger scale. In contrast the CELL/PCL and CELL/Ny6 blends were essentially immiscible; from this it was concluded that the potential for strong inter-molecular interactions is not a sufficient condition for miscibility to occur in cellulose/synthetic-polymer blends.</description><creator>Masson, Jean-François</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Cellulosesynthetic-polymer blends</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429990w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr151</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36325</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>