<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:43:54Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s360</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Marguerite Yourcenar was a prolific writer and we can deduce that in the course of her writings, the revised version played a very important role. Thus, several pieces of works such as D'apres Rembrandt, D'apres Greco, D'apres Durer gave birth to L'OEuvre au noir, Anna soror..., Un homme obscur and Une belle matinee. Denier du reve was rewritten twenty years later. The collection of short stories Nouvelles orientales underwent numerous changes during the course of more than fifty years. The "double" theme marks the different narratives of this work and the revised phenomena contributes to the emergence in all its elements. Therefore, all through this thesis, we will show the events which reveals the presence of the "double" such as a story within a story (mise en abyme) and flashbacks that are present in the narration, the theme of remembrance, the different microcosms contained in the macrocosms, but also the opposing split personalities present in most of the protagonists. In addition, we can discover that these characters are united in creation and in all elements of the cosmos. Also, we have the production of opposing forces between creation and man. In Yourcenar's work, especially in Nouvelles orientales, we notice that in the "double" an absolute quest is presented in its different play of mirrors. It is as if this fusion of the human with the universe brings each character to be part of the Universality, beyond time, space and the world of the material.</description><creator>De Blois, Isabelle.</creator><contributor>Desrosiers-Bonin, Diane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Yourcenar, Marguerite -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Doubles in literature.</subject><title>Le double dans les nouvelles orientales de Marguerite Yourcenar /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p895g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s360</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wm136</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When Renaissance linguists took charge of the French language and its evolution, trying to define what French eloquence would be, they relied mostly on classical Greek philosophers' theories about language. Divine inspiration, as evoked by Plato, was in the ancient times opposed to Aristotle's art of oratory and its more technical approach. In the same way, during the Renaissance, Ciceronians promoted Aristotelian rhetoric, whereas their opponents, such as Erasmus or Montaigne, revived Plato's thesis. Within this context, the present study is centred on two grammarians-philosophers living towards the end of the sixteenth century and the beginning of the next. In his Eloquence Francoise, Guillaume Du Vair propounded a conception of the Fench language inspired by the stoic theory of representation. Francois de La Mothe Le Vayer, on the other hand, refers to sceptic philosophers in orders to develop in his Considerations sur l'Eloquence de ce tems (1637) a theory of aestheticism based on doubt.</description><creator>Chenevert, Martin.</creator><contributor>Doiron, Normand (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>French language -- History.</subject><subject>La Mothe Le Vayer, François de, 1583-1672.</subject><subject>Philologists -- France.</subject><subject>Du Vair, Guillaume, 1556-1621.</subject><title>L'opposition savante dans le debat linguistique de la premiere moitie du dix-septieme siecle : Guillaume Du Vair et Francois de La Mothe Le Vayer</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j980q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm136</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n303z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following research depicts the perceptions and perspectives of thirteen teachers and two principals anticipating the implementation of the Curriculum Reform in Quebec schools. It aims to provide insight into teachers' perceptions of how the anticipation of change, induced by the Reform, is affecting them. It also seeks to provide an in-depth understanding of the world and its relations with others teaching in the context of change that is being brought on by the Reform in schools. This qualitative research takes into consideration two specific questions: What is the lived experience of teachers during the anticipation of the implementation of the Reform? What is the perception of teachers towards the Reform? Thirteen teachers and two administrators were interviewed, each representing at least one of the elementary, secondary, and high school vocational sectors of the English public education system of greater Montreal. These interviews took place during the Fall of 1999.</description><creator>Di Iorio, Carmela.</creator><contributor>Boston, Patricia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Educational change -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Curriculum change -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Teachers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes.</subject><subject>School principals -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes.</subject><title>The Quebec curriculum reform : perspectives and perceptions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t384t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n303z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td953</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this project was to extend a mathematical model of the cardiovascular circulation, originally built by Burkhoff and Tyberg [6]. The model was implemented in Simulink and consists of 6 lumped vascular compartments interconnected by segments allowing unidirectional blood flow. A set of 6 differential equations describe changes in blood volume in the four systemic and two ventricular compartments as functions of time in terms of the pressure across each compartment and the resistances between them. The model was used to investigate why pulmonary venous pressure rises after the onset of left ventricular dysfunction. Special attention was given to the pericardial and peripheral resistance effects. Sensitivity analysis showed that our parameter values and ratios were more appropriate than those of Burkhoff and Tyberg [6]. We conclude that, although stressed volume has a fundamental role in raising the pulmonary venous pressure, contractile strength and systemic arterial resistance also contribute considerably.</description><creator>Veerassamy, Shalini.</creator><contributor>Bates, J. H. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><title>Revisiting hemodynamic analysis of pulmonary edema after the onset of left ventricular dysfunction using a mathematical model of the cardiovascular system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w6664.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td953</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544br30b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently smooth-muscle tissue has been observed in the annular ligament of the moustached bat, Pteronotus parnellii. In order to lead to improved understanding of the function of this highly developed smooth-muscle system surrounding the tympanic membrane, a finite-element model was developed. The complex geometry of the middle ear was defined using both magnetic-resonance microscopy and histological data. Contributions were made to the locally written software which was used for image segmentation and finite-element mesh generation. The action of the smooth-muscle fibres is modelled by applying a radial load to the model of the tympanic membrane. The radial load is represented by placing load vectors tangential to the model of the tympanic membrane. Simulations were carried out in order to investigate convergence, sensitivity to tympanic-membrane shape, and to evaluate the effects of pressure and radial loads.</description><creator>Van Wijhe, Rene G.</creator><contributor>Funnell, W. R. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>A finite element model of the middle ear of the moustached bat /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf49m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br30b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt64p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The process of suppressing acoustic noise in audio signals, and speech signals in particular, can be improved by exploiting the masking properties of the human hearing system. These masking properties, where strong sounds make weaker sounds inaudible, are calculated using auditory models. This thesis examines both traditional noise suppression algorithms and ones that incorporate an auditory model to achieve better performance. The different auditory models used by these algorithms are examined. A novel approach, based on a method to remove a specific type of noise from audio signals, is presented using a standardized auditory model. The proposed method is evaluated with respect to other noise suppression methods in the problem of speech enhancement. It is shown that this method performs well in suppressing noise in telephone-bandwidth speech, even at low Signal-to-Noise Ratios.</description><creator>Thiemann, Joachim.</creator><contributor>Kabal, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Acoustic noise suppression for speech signals using auditory masking effects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139387f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt64p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj200</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A programmable display system for perceptual stability research is presented. The display system involves 96 programmable, independent, two-colored LED outputs, and can display a video with the time resolution of one millisecond. Because of the high time resolution, this system provides a means to study humans' perceptual stability with high precision. The system may display up to 24,576 frames repeatedly after each download. Hardware for video download, saving, and display, and software for video design were developed and implemented. The hardware consists of a control module, a storage and interface module, and a display module. The software offers a graphical user interface (GUI). Using this display system, we carried out two preliminary experiments to test the saccade target theory of how humans perceive stability during eye movements.</description><creator>Wang, Fang, 1973-</creator><contributor>Clark, James J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A programmable display system for perceptual stability research /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t40g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj200</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sr86h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the advance of composite materials in the past 50 years, fiber-reinforced polymer sheet piles are becoming increasingly popular in the marine and waterfront applications. While these materials possess high strength-to-weight ratio and are corrosion resistant, their durability in water has been not well studied due to the lack of historical data for these fairly new materials. The purpose of this research is to establish the absorption characteristics of a pultruded fiberglass-reinforced polyester composite for a sheet pile wall and quantify the effect of water on long term mechanical properties. The tests conducted were water absorption, tensile strength, flexural strength, and freeze/thaw cycling. An analytical model was developed to establish the nature of the absorption process and prediction of the change in mechanical properties. The results indicated that the water absorption process of the material followed a combination of Fickian diffusion and polymeric relaxation. The moisture saturation was 1.72% for the flange and 3.11% for web. The absorption process modeling indicated that saturation would be reached in 4.5 years for flange and 7 years for web in tap water, at room temperature. The coefficients of diffusion calculated were 4.2 10-6 mm2/s and 3.0 10-6 mm2/s respectively. During the water absorption test at 70°C and in boiling water, a mass loss of the material occurred. Tensile strength was found to decrease with the increase in percentage of water absorbed with no further degradation seen after saturation was reached. There was a decrease of 60% in the tensile strength at saturation. On the other hand, there was no noticeable change in the tensile modulus of elasticity during the water-ageing period. The freeze/thaw cycling test revealed that there were no significant changes in the tensile strength and the modulus after 564 cycles from 4.4°C to -17.8°C.</description><creator>Kouadio, Kouassi Serge P.</creator><contributor>Shao, Yixin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Marine and Ocean.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Durability of fiberglass composite sheet piles in water</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk00v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr86h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p8971</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An annular photo-reactor was designed to investigate precursors and mechanisms thought to promote the fouling of ultra-violet lamps in wastewater disinfection systems. Parameters investigated included temperature of the fouling surface (quartz sleeve) and average fluence applied to the wastewater under irradiation. The reactor was designed to independently control and monitor variations of these parameters. For experimentation, these parameters were manipulated individually and in various combinations to be able to separate those factor(s) that could affect the fouling potential of the system. The compact and mobile unit utilized a standard low-pressure mercury UV lamp surrounded by two concentric sleeves. The annulus immediately surrounding the lamp was used to control temperature (10--50°C) and fluence (10--100 mJ/cm2 using a chemical transmission filter) emitted by the lamp. The outer annulus was used for the passage and irradiation of wastewater flowing at 10--12 L/min (Re ≅ 1,000). A quartz sleeve separated these annuli. Hydraulic and heat transfer properties of the unit were fully characterized, and the stability of system operations was confirmed. Optimal lamp UV output approached 3 mW/cm2 and maximum skin temperatures were 45°C. A cupric sulfate solution (0--2 g/L) in distilled water was determined to be the most stable transmission filter. Application of temperature and fluence control revealed that both parameters influenced the disinfection potential of the unit (achieving 1--4 log reduction of fecal coliforms). Collimated beam tests and Point Source Summation computations were used to model fluence distributions within the reactor.</description><creator>Gray, Sandy-Kae A.</creator><contributor>Gehr, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><title>Development of an annular reactor to investigate fouling in UV disinfection systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm32n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p8971</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw47s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis seeks to demonstrate, by way of a multidisciplinary study, that consent is, despite its legal definition which refers to the free and enlighted expression of individual will, in fact, at times limited if not eliminated, by social considerations, arising from the medical, economic and legal context. These considerations reflect what one might call the social norm. An appropriate understanding of consent serves, therefore, to express the social norm as a constraint, which, in turn, acts as a measure of what it means to belong in society. Thus, while consent is often presented as the fundamental principle to be respected in biomedical research, it is in reality, merely one principle to respect among others. These limitations connected to consent are exacerbated in emergency situations where consent is sometimes reduced to mere signature, and in some cases it has been recognized that research can be undertaken without the subject's prior consent.</description><creator>Gauthier, Isabelle.</creator><contributor>Kasirer, Nocholas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Medicine -- Research -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Medical ethics -- Decision-making.</subject><subject>Human experimentation in medicine -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Medical ethics -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Informed consent (Medical law)</subject><subject>Medicine -- Research -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><title>Analyse de la norme sociale comme contrainte au consentement : l'exemple de la recherche biomédicale en situation d'urgence</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x731.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw47s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz47n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A system was developed for detecting gradual changes in background EEG, with a view to simplifying the tedious task of long-term monitoring in the neurological intensive care unit. Six-channel EEG recordings serve as input to the system. EEG from each hemisphere is segmented into variable length epochs described by nine-dimensional feature vectors. A fixed scaling operation is performed so that differentiation between segments using the Euclidean distance between feature vectors relies equally on each feature. Cluster analysis is performed to select five types of EEG that best represent the data spread for each hour. Color-coded circles representing clusters from every hour are mapped on a two-dimensional plot. The relative location of these circles reflects the difference between their associated EEG. Change between hours is detected by observing the movement of circles associated with each hour. Detection of change with this method agreed closely with that observed via manual review but was much simpler.</description><creator>Grennan, Eoin David.</creator><contributor>Gotman, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>A system to detect gradual change in long term EEG /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw382.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz47n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j721</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Children with an intellectual disability may significantly affect families in ways that have implications for other sibling's adjustment. In this thesis, 40 siblings of intellectually disabled children are compared to 40 siblings of healthy children. The goal is to determine (i) if a child with an intellectual disability affects the other siblings in the family, and (ii) if they are functions of siblings' age, grade, gender, ordinal position, age gap with the disabled child, sibling number, disabled child's severity of impairment, parental educational background, etc. The findings did not confirm that siblings of children with an intellectual disability have poorer adjustment than that of healthy children. However, the older sisters and older siblings of children with intellectual disability were found to have poorer adjustment in some of the area. Age gap and father's educational background is positively correlated to the adjustment of siblings of children with an intellectual disability. Then and other findings are discussed in the thesis.</description><creator>Kuo, Yeh-chen, 1965-</creator><contributor>John, Lindsay H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Children with mental disabilities -- Taiwan -- Taipei -- Family relationships.</subject><subject>Brothers and sisters.</subject><title>Siblings of a child with an intellectual disability : identifying those at risk</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z723q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j721</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jd15r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Child welfare agencies are currently being challenged to develop and implement educational and prevention programs that address sex education, STDs and HIV/AIDS. Based on two staff interviews, six adolescent and seven staff focus group discussions at Batshaw Youth and Family Centres, three main themes are addressed: first, that along with Batshaw Youth and Family Centres' mandate and initiatives, additional measures must be taken to translate policy into social work practice. Initiatives to educate staff and youth about sexuality, STDs and HIV/AIDS lacked consistency and continuity consequently, staffs and youth's experience and attitudes toward sex education, STDs and HIV/AIDS are affected. Implications for social work are also discussed.</description><creator>Di Sessa, Anna Maria.</creator><contributor>Rowe, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Sex instruction for youth -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Social service -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Batshaw Youth and Family Centres.</subject><subject>Sexually transmitted diseases -- Prevention</subject><title>Implementing a sex education, STDs and HIVAIDS prevention program in a child welfare setting : implications for service delivery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tn83x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jd15r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp246</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Comorbid substance use disorders are quite common among patients with schizophrenia. Such individuals' substance use has been associated with psychiatric instability, psychosocial problems and an increased use of health care services. An existing data set encompassing a range of health care services was analysed, along with patient demographics such as age, living arrangements and education. The subjects were 444 patients with a lifetime diagnosis of schizophrenia, with and without a secondary substance use disorder. It was found that 32.4% of the male patients and 14.7% of the female patients in this study had a concurrent disorder. The substance abusers tended to be younger than the non-abusers. Male patients who lived in group homes were less likely to have a substance use disorder than male patients in other living situations. Patients with a substance use disorder were more intensive users of hospital services. The need for the development of integrated services and role of the social worker was discussed.</description><creator>DeChambeau, Cathy.</creator><contributor>Duder, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Substance abuse.</subject><subject>Schizophrenia.</subject><title>Schizophrenia and substance use disorders : implications for social workers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn16x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp246</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kv684</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1995 the Government of Ontario introduced reforms that significantly changed the way welfare was delivered in the province. Welfare rates were cut and benefits became conditional on recipients participating in a workfare programme called Ontario Works. These reforms ignore women's responsibility for child care. Single mothers and their children will be the group most affected by these changes. Single mothers are interviewed about how these changes have affected them, with particular attention to their experiences with the Ontario Works programme and its impact on their ability to care for their children.</description><creator>Pearse, Janet.</creator><contributor>Davies, Linda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Single mothers -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Ontario -- Social policy.</subject><subject>Public welfare -- Ontario.</subject><title>Ontario works : mothering and neo-liberal social policy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257g82s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv684</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh86c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Heavy metals in the environment are a source of some concern because of their potential reactivity, toxicity, and mobility in the soil. Soil contamination by metals is placing human and environmental health at risk through possible contamination of food chain. Soil washing can be used to remove metals from the soil. Chemical treatment involves the addition of extraction agents that react with the contaminant and leach it from the soil. The liquid, containing the contaminants, is separated from the soil resulting in a clean solid phase. Six chelating reagents, EDTA, Citric acid, ADA, DTPA, SCMC, and DPTA, were employed to determine the relative extraction efficiencies of the six chelating reagents for the target metals. Recycling of chelating reagent was the main interest of this study. The experiments were divided into four parts: (1) preliminary studies on the preparation and characterization of soil that included grinding, sieving, soil texture measurements, total metals content post digestion and the distribution of metals in different soil fractions as well as (2) a comparison of the extraction efficiencies of six chelating reagents toward Cu, Pb, Zn, Fe, and Mn. Additionally, the chelating reagent was liberated and recycled by treatment of the metal-complexes with disodium diethyl dithiocarbomate (DEDTC). Additionally, supercritical CO2 was used to extract metal-DEDTC complexes using various surfactants to maintain the metal-DEDTC complexes in suspension. Finally, (4) magnesium metal was evaluated as an alternative method for liberating the water-soluble chelating reagent from the complex so as to be able to recycle this reagent as well. The different approaches were promising in terms of recycling the chelating reagents that suggests a means of optimizing the experimental conditions in future applications.</description><creator>Xie, Ting, 1971-</creator><contributor>Marshall, W. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Chelates.</subject><subject>Solvent extraction.</subject><subject>Heavy metals -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>Heavy metal removal from soil by complexing reagents with recycling of complexing reagents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k694m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh86c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s71t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to estimate, for stroke, the degree to which outcome of hospitalization, for death and discharge home, differed across hospitals in Quebec and the contribution of hospital-related factors to this variation. The outcomes of in-hospital death and discharge home (among survivors) were ascertained for the period April 1, 1992 to March 31, 1997, using the Quebec hospital discharge database (Med-Echo). The estimator of variation was the ratio of the hospital-specific observed number of stroke admissions that ended in death or discharge home to the risk-adjusted expected number of deaths or discharged home, obtained using logistic regression. A second stage of analysis involved estimating the contribution of hospital-related factors to the log odds of death or discharge home, using multiple linear regression. Over the five-year period of study, 43,357 acute stroke admissions occurred. For death, the estimator of variation varied 3 fold across hospitals (range of 0.6 to 1.8). For discharge home, the same estimator yielded a 2.6 fold variation (range of 0.5 to 1.3). Non-teaching hospitals are associated with higher rates of death (~OR: 1.3 depending on the number of acute stroke hospital admissions per year and the level of urbanization of the area a hospital is located). Hospitals with 40 to 100 acute stroke admissions per year are associated with higher rates of death (~OR: 1.4 depending on teaching status and level of urbanization). Hospitals situated in urban regions are associated with the lowest rates of discharge home (~OR: 1.1 depending on number of acute stroke admissions and teaching status).</description><creator>Venturini, Adriana.</creator><contributor>Mayo, Nancy E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Variation in outcome of hospitalization for stroke across hospitals in Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft26m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s71t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010s05m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Java provides many attractive features such as platform independence, execution safety, garbage collection and object orientation. These features facilitate application development but are expensive to support; applications written in Java are often much slower than their counterparts written in C or C++. To use these features without having to pay a great performance penalty, sophisticated optimizations and runtime systems are required. We present SOOT, a framework for optimizing Java bytecode. The framework is implemented in Java and supports three intermediate representations for representing Java bytecode: BAF, a streamlined representation of bytecode which is simple to manipulate; JIMPLE, a typed 3-address intermediate representation suitable for optimization; and GRIMP an aggregated version of JIMPLE suitable for decompilation. SOOT also contains a set of transformations between these intermediate representations, and an application programming interface (API) is provided to write optimizations and analyses on Java bytecode in these forms. In order to demonstrate the usefulness of the framework, we have implemented intraprocedural and whole program optimizations. To show that whole program bytecode optimization can give performance improvements, we provide experimental results for 10 large benchmarks, including 8 SPECjvm98 benchmarks running on JDK 1.2. These results show a speedup of up to 38%.</description><creator>Vallee-Rai, Raja.</creator><contributor>Hendren, Laurie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Soot : a java bytecode optimization framework</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w877.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s05m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c939n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prostanoids are important mediators of inflammation and tissue homeostasis. Cyclooxygenase (COX) is a key enzyme in the biosynthesis of prostanoids from arachidonic acid. Of the two isoforms of COX, COX-1 functions in tissue homeostasis whereas COX-2 is more abundant in inflammation. Selective COX-2 inhibition seems effective in reducing inflammation with fewer side effects compared with non-selective COX inhibitors. In this study, the expression of COX-2 in lung inflammation was investigated in two models, which include acute rejection and antigen-induced inflammation. The effect of selective COX-2 inhibition in these models was also determined. COX-2 was expressed in infiltrating cells in both models, in addition to constitutive expression in bronchial epithelium and bronchial smooth muscle cells. Selective COX-2 inhibition significantly reduced the extent of inflammation in both models. These results suggest that selective COX-2 inhibition may be effective in the treatment of acute rejection and asthma.</description><creator>Utsumi, Tomoki.</creator><contributor>Recklies, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Cyclooxygenase-2 in models of acute lung inflammation : expression of the enzyme and the effect of selective inhibition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f76m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c939n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv839</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Undernutrition and dysphagia in the institutionalized elderly are well documented in the literature. However, the clinical efficacy of diets to treat dysphagia have not been established. To offer a better understanding of the textural characteristics of the new Sainte-Anne's Hospital (SAH) modified texture reformed foods, rheological evaluations were performed. Apparent viscosity, consistency coefficient, flow behavior index and yield stress values were calculated for the thickened beverages. Texture profile analyses were performed on the reformed foods. Secondly, to evaluate the impact of SAH's reformed foods on nutritional intake and weight, a 12-week clinical trial was undertaken. Dysphagic frail elderly subjects (n = 17) of a long-term care facility of Montreal were randomly assigned to receive SAH reformed foods or traditional care. The experimental group demonstrated a significant increase in nutritional intake resulting in significant weight gain. These findings suggest that dysphagic frail elderly could reach healthy weight when adequately fed.</description><creator>Germain, Isabelle.</creator><contributor>Gray-Donald, Katherine (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Ramaswamy, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Deglutition disorders -- Diet therapy.</subject><subject>Deglutition disorders -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><title>The evaluation of the nutritional outcomes of advanced nutritional care for the treatment of dysphagia in the elderly /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b7925.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv839</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jw46r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The application of high pressure (HP) processing on trout and shrimps was investigated in order to study its effect on their quality attributes. Five levels of pressure, holding time and temperature were selected using a central composite rotatable design (CCRD), the central point being. 200 MPa, 30 min and 10°C. This design was used in order to permit the measurement and modeling of changes in various quality parameters as a result of changes in the process variables. The color parameters (L*, a*, and b* values), physical attributes (drip-loss, protein leaching and water holding capacity) and texture parameters (firmness and springiness) in each case were evaluated, and modeled as second order polynomial equations. Artificial Neural Network modeling was employed to investigate its ability in predicting the quality changes in both pressure-treated trout fillets and shrimp samples, and its performance was with statistical models. High pressure (HP) kinetics of the microbial destruction in both trout and shrimp was also studied. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Houjaij, Nada.</creator><contributor>Ramaswamy, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Shrimps -- Preservation.</subject><subject>Fish fillets -- Preservation.</subject><subject>High pressure (Technology)</subject><title>The application of high pressure treatment and its effect on the quality attributes of trout and shrimp /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj29g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw46r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c940d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this randomized, controlled trial was to test whether sweet taste and chewing modify self-report of pain intensity and negative affect caused by blood-draws and vaccination in children. Subjects were recruited (age mean +/- SD; 9.82 +/- 0.8 years) from schools (n = 115) and a hospital (n = 101). Subjects were assigned to Control, Sweet, Chew or Sweet+chew interventions. Pain intensity was rated on the Coloured Analogue Scale (CAS) and affective quality on the Faces Pain Scale (FPS). In school and hospital settings a Sex by Sweet by Chew interaction was seen on CAS (p = 0.29; p &lt; 0.01) and FPS (p &lt; 0.05; p &lt; 0.05) respectively. A consistent pattern was seen in which chewing reduced and sweet taste increased pain ratings in boys. The opposite effect was seen in girls. When sex was not considered no significant differences between groups were seen. Sweet taste and chewing appear not to have useful analgesic effects. Sex must be considered in future investigations.</description><creator>Lewkowski, Maxim D.</creator><contributor>Barr, R. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Young, S. N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Psychology, Physiological.</subject><subject>Psychology, Behavioral.</subject><title>Chewing gum analgesia : a test of the effects of physiological stimuli on pain intensity and affective responses to routine painful procedures in children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq01r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c940d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g6865</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This exploratory study examined the predictive ability of perceived work environment characteristics on employees' level of motivation to learn and growth need strength. It looked at motivation to learn within the context of two types of training: formal training and on-the-job training. It also examined the existence of group differences in motivation and in perceptions of the work environment. The sample was 117 middle management staff at a Canadian research university, varying in age, level of education, job classification, work unit, and job and institutional tenure. Data was collected using a questionnaire consisting of scales from the management and educational literature. Using multiple regression analysis and MANOVAs, workplace environmental characteristics were found to be predictors of employee motivation. The best predictor of motivation to learn was a composite measure of incentives, while the best predictor of growth need strength was a composite measure of lack of independence and freedom of choice. No group differences in motivational characteristics were found, however, there were differences in perceptions of the work environment.</description><creator>Godin, Michel.</creator><contributor>Grutter, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Design of a differential cantilever-based sensor : surface stress of self-assembled alkanethiols on gold-coated cantilevers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1587.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g6865</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j298j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study is based on Luthar's finding (1991) that resilient inner-city adolescents, those adolescents that displayed high behavioral competence despite high stress, experienced significant difficulties in domains of social-emotional adjustment. The characteristics of resilience were examined among 61 Native adolescents from a remote community. Stress was operationalized by scores on self-report measures of uncontrollable negative life events and demographic stressors. Definitions of social competence were based on school grades, peer ratings, and teacher ratings. In addition, social-emotional adjustment was based on self-report measures of depression and anxiety. Contrary to previous findings, resilient adolescents did not display significant amounts of depression or anxiety. Furthermore, the findings indicate that resilient adolescents have lower levels of anxiety than adolescents from high stress backgrounds with lower levels of competence. The prevailing constructs of social competence and stress, and their appropriateness for the study of resilience in Native adolescents, are discussed.</description><creator>Zygmuntowicz, Catherine E.</creator><contributor>Burack, Jacob A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Resilience (Personality trait) in adolescence.</subject><subject>Indians of North America -- Québec (Province) -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Social skills.</subject><title>The domain specificity of resilience in native adolescents from a remote community /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh440.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j298j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mr753</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary purpose of the present study was to examine various aspects of local and global perception in groups of children and young adults with average ages of 6, 8, 10, 12, and 22 years. The aspects examined included developmental differences in RT for local and global visual information, the influence of filtering on global and local perception, and role of distracter congruency and compatibility on processing local and global stimuli. At a general level, the findings revealed that participants processed global faster than local stimuli. With the presence of distracters, 6 and 8-year-old participants demonstrated slower RTs for global targets relative to local targets. Distracter congruency or compatibility did not differentially affect global and local processing. However, congruency did appear to be related to differential performance for 6-year old males versus females. These results indicate that the underlying processes involved in global and local perception may be separate, with global perception relying on attentional mechanisms to a greater extent than local perception.</description><creator>Porporino, Mafalda.</creator><contributor>Burack, Jacob A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Visual perception in children.</subject><subject>Visual perception.</subject><title>Developmental differences in global and local perception : is global perception more attention demanding than local perception</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs78n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr753</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>