<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:51:13Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12650" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vf71b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The original primary object of this research was to study the properties and reactivity of potassium diazomethionate with particular reference to its stability and usefulness as a synthetic tool. It was desired to establish whether potassium diazomethionate was completely analogous in behavior to other aliphatic diazo compounds such as diazomethane and diazoacetic ester as has been suggested in the literature. If this were the case, a ready method of synthesis would be available for a large number of interesting disulphonated aliphatic compounds which had not previously been prepared. A secondary object was to determine whether potassium diazomethionate could be used as an intermediate in a simple and practicable synthesis for monosubstituted hydrazines. Great interest has recently developed in the search for a practicable industrial process for the manufacture of hydrazine, since this substance is in great demand as a propellant and synthetic fuel for defence purposes. It was already known from the work of von Pechmann and Manck (89) that hydrazine sulphate could be prepared from potassium diazomethionate in two synthetic steps and it was requested by the Defence Research Board that a study be undertaken to determine whether such a process would be economically feasible. Hence, the object of the research was modified along these lines.[...]</description><creator>Bannard, R. A. B., 1922-</creator><contributor>Ross, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of certain nitrogen derivatives of methionic acid.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k843j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vf71b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n1796</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The extensive equipment which is described has been built up for the study of magnetic moments of nuclei, particularly for accurate comparison of their gyromagnetic ratios, and the relative spins of isotopes. The nuclear induction and the nuclear absorption resonances of the proton have been observed. The induction resonance of B^11 has been observed at around 10 mc. in an alkaline solution of KB02. Its frequency has been compared with that of the proton in the same field giving a measure of the ratio of the two gyromagnetic ratios: ɤB/ɤP = 0.320904 ± 4.3 x 10^-6 [...]</description><creator>Anderson, Donald Arthur.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Nuclear physics.</subject><title>The nuclear magnetic moment of boron of mass eleven.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt62t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n1796</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193d20v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Psychologists have found that noise reduces human efficiency. This effect may be considerable even for the most phlegmatic individuals. Moreover, almost everyone objects to unnecessary noises. In recent years there has arisen a very insistent demand for quieter electrical apparatus. This applies particularly to household apparatus such as refrigerator motors, vacuum sweepers and the like. Practically noiseless motors are also required for various drives ( refrigerating plants, circulation pumps of hot water systems, big ventilating systems for rooms, organ bellows etc. ) in non industrial plants such as storerooms, business houses, hotels, hospitals, churches, theatres etc&gt; where all noise should be suppressed. It must also be noted that the stage has been reached where it is taken for granted that the products of the better known manufacturers will give entirely satisfactory performance, and often, the deciding factor between various makes is only the quietness with which the equipment operates. However,noise and vibration are not merely annoyances which may affect the sale of a product or lower the efficiency of a worker. They are often evidences of defects in design and manufacture which seriously affect the life of the equipment and, in many cases, the safety of the user.[...]</description><creator>Attas, Isaac.</creator><contributor>Schippel, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Electric motors -- Noise.</subject><subject>Electric motors -- Vibration.</subject><title>Noise in induction motors.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p26770025.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193d20v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xg117</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thermal conductivity of gases has been the subject of experimental investigations over a period of several decades (54). The thermal conductivity (hereafter simply referred to as the "conductivity"), being, from a physical point of view, one of the basic properties of a gas, much of the classical kinetic theory was concerned with its interpretation. Its measurement was to examine the validity of the theory. The limits of this validity were similar to those imposed on the theory by other gaseous properities, which lead to the concept of the "ideal gas". As to the conductivity, the behaviour of the majority of naturally occuring gases approximated closely that of the "ideal gas" under normal conditions, i.e. at moderate or room temperatures and a pressure range up to atmospheric pressure. Serious deviations from experimental data occured, however, when it was attempted to apply the theory to gases at higher temperatures and pressures.[...]</description><creator>Weininger, Joseph L.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Gases -- Thermal properties</subject><subject>Heat -- Conduction </subject><title>The thermal conductivity of gases at high pressure.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv12z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xg117</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nh95t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The behaviour of high polymers in solution has been extensively investigated by many methods, but the diffusion of high polymers has received little attention experimentally, and limited progress has been made in its theoretical treatment. According to these theories, the rate of diffusion is governed in large measure by the shape of the polymer chain which, however, need not be the same in different solvents. Evidence for a change of shape in different solvents is obtained indirectly from experiments on viscosity, osmotic pressure, sedimentation velocity, and streaming birefringence, while direct evidence is provided by measurements of light scattering. Experimental studies on the diffusion of high polymers should therefore be of interest from two points of view, (i) to provide data by which to examine the validity of existing theories, and (ii) to obtain additional information about the extent to which a polymer may alter its configuration in different solvents. The, present work was undertaken with these two objectives.[...]</description><creator>Adelstein, Peter.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Polymers.</subject><subject>Diffusion.</subject><title>Diffusion studies of high polymer solutions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr31p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nh95t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g583d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The polymerization of alkylbutadienes has a long history, dating from Grenville William's experiments with isoprene, obtained from the destructive distillation of natural rubber (l). However no large scale production of polymers of butadienes was attempted until World War I, when the Germans manufactured over 2300 tons of polydimethylbutadiene. Until then the natural sources of rubber yielded adequate supplies for world needs. Some research was continued in the field of synthetic rubber andby 1939 the Germans, and later the Western Allies, were able to produce large quantities of synthetic elastomers (the name given to high polymers that possess rubber-like properties). A copolymer of butadiene and styrene, called Buna-S or GR-S, wasconsidered to be the best general purpose synthetic elastomer and this copolymer is produced on a large scale on this continent. Much research has been done on this material but the pure polymers, such as polybutadiene and polyisoprene, have not been investigated as thoroughly since they have failed to show promising properties. As copolymers have the extra variable of compositional heterogeneity, it is thought that the study of pure polymers may lead to an easier and better understanding of the problems involved in obtaining elastomers of the desired properties.[...]</description><creator>Aikin, Archibald McKinlay.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Polymers.</subject><title>The emulsion polymerization of alkylbutadienes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q7570.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g583d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w33w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A monokinetic beam of neutrons (0.07 e.v.) has been scattered by a gas, and the angular dependence of scattering measured over the range 0° to 90°. This isbelieved to be the first measurement of neutrons diffracted by gas molecules. The experiments were performed with a modified neutron crystal spectrometer using a beam of neutronsfrom the Chalk River pile. The gases studied, CO2 and O2, were at room temperature and approximately 60 atmospheres pressure. Observed intensity distributions are compared with calculated patterns. The latter are based on classical interference theory, so take no account of inelasticscattering. Good angular agreement of interference peaks is found for both gases. Good relative intensity agreement is found for 02, but the measured intensity for CO2 falls below thecalculated curve at small angles. A possible reason for this is given.</description><creator>Alcock, Norman Zinkan.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Neutrons.</subject><subject>Carbon dioxide.</subject><title>Diffraction of neutrons by gas molecules.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483n495.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w33w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462857c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Because of the polycultural character of Canada, the term "education of the Jews" must not be taken to be the same as "Jewish education". While the former denotes the kind and amount of educationJews get as citizens of a secular state, the latter is used here to describe the education they receive as members of a national - religious minority.[...]</description><creator>Zweig, David Norman</creator><contributor>Hughes, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Jews -- Canada.</subject><subject>Education -- Canada.</subject><subject>Jews -- Education.</subject><title>Jewish Education in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g85j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462857c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386n84h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Due a la centralite du Christ, vrai dieu et vrai homme, la theologieChretienne considere que l'aspect humain est un element essentiel aetudier. Au milieu des preoccupations environnementales, cependant, lacomprehension dominante de la personne humaine est mise en cause eten train d'etre revisee par les auteurs chn!tiens. Cette etude tachedecontribuer a l'effort plus vaste d'examiner le role de l'etre humainpanni des reponses theologiques chretiennes en face de la criseecologique, cette question se pose comme une preoccupation capitaledans la litterature emergente.[...]</description><description>Because of the centrality of Christ, truly God and truly human, Christiantheology regards the understanding of the human as one of its essentialtasks. In the wake of environmental concerns, however. the dominantself-understanding of the human is presently being chaUenged andrethought by Christians. This study is an attempt to contribute to thislarger effort of examining the role of the human in Christiantheological responses to the ecological "crisis." a question that issurfacing as a paramount concern in this emergent literature.[...]</description><creator>Scharper, Stephen B.</creator><contributor>Baum, Gregory (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Human ecology -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.</subject><subject>Theological anthropology -- Christianity -- History of doctrines -- 20th century.</subject><title>The Role of the Human in Christian Ecological Literature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9676894.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n84h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nx908</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present investigation arose out of a study on blood preservation which was begun in the Department of Biochemistry at McGill in January, 1940 by Collip and Denstedt. In the course of the investigation it became necessary to evaluate the efficiency of various methods of preservation and the viability of the preserved red cells. The only satisfactory method at that time, and even at the present date, was to transfuse the preserved blood and follow the elimination of the donor cells from the circulation of the recipient.</description><creator>McKerns, Kenneth W.</creator><contributor>Denstedt, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>A study on the agglutination of erythrocytes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj77r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nx908</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x247h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The marked growth of medical knowledge in the past hundred years has produced a wide range of modifications in medical practice. Habits and attitudes peculiar to medical practice have changed. Medical practice has become dependent upon a wide range of elements. Organizational or bureaucratic (1) devices have been utilized to help gain control over these factors. The utilization of bureaucracy in medical practice has introduced new contingencies which have the potential of interfering with high-standard medicine. Inter-dependence between medical practice and other elements of our culture has been greatly increased. The elements peculiar to a medical career have been considerably modified.</description><creator>McKay, Huntley Walker Farr</creator><contributor>Hall, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Sociology.</subject><title>Sociological analysis of a group practice : its effects upon the doctor and the hospital</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s24x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x247h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2677003f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is not certain to whom credit is due for the first description of the Adrenal glands. In the copper plates of human anatomy completed by Eustachius in 1552, the adrenals are shown. These plates were preserved in the Vatican library until published by Lancisi, physician to Pope Clement XI, in 1714 (1). In 1629, however, Jean Riolan (2) described and named the "Supra-renal capsules". One hundred years later the Academic des Sciences of Bordeaux offered a prize for the best essay on "Quel est l’usage des glandes surrenales", but apparently no plausible theory was forthcoming, as the adjudicator recommended that the prize should not be awarded.</description><creator>McIntosh, Hamish W.</creator><contributor>Cleghorn, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>A method for the evaluation of adrenal cortical functions in man</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zt87k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2677003f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30px10w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Photosensitization by resonance radiation is the process involved when an atom, optically excited by absorption of resonance radiation, transfers this energy by collision to another atom or molecule, thereby inducing a chemical reaction. Collisions in which energy of excitation is converted either into other energy of excitation or into kinetic energy are termed inelastic collisions of the second kind. Numerous examples of this type of reaction have been observed and the method has proven to be a powerful tool in elucidating the mechanisms of free radical and atomic reactions.</description><creator>McGilvery, James Duncan</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The mercury photosensitized decomposition of nitric oxide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w797b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30px10w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts339</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Whenever an evacuated solid is exposed to a gas, a part of the gas is taken up by the solid. If the process is true surface condensation, it is known as "adsorption". This is not to be confused with the term "absorption", which refers to a more or less uniform penetration of molecules into the molecular structure of the solid. McBain has proposed the term "sorption" to include cases where more than one process is occuring or those in which the exact nature of the process is yet unknown.</description><creator>McDermot, Henry Lloyd</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The density of water sorbed by charcoal and low pressure adsorption studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848t829.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts339</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr1721457</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the summer of 1949 the writer carried out exploration work on a group of eight mining claims, known as the McCuaig group. These claims are located in Pardee Township, Thunder Bay District, Ontario. The property may be reached by means of a gravel road two miles long that branches off to the north from the Scott Highway at a point forty miles west of Fort William. The Scott Highway is a paved highway between Duluth, Minnesota, and Fort William, Ontario.</description><creator>McCuaig, James Auley</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>A copper-nickel occurrence in Pardee township, Thunder Bay district, Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k573w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1721457</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rc20x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Ymir area (long. 117° - 117°15’, lat. 49°15'- 49°30') lies just southeast of Nelson in the southern part of British Columbia. It includes 300 square miles of the area lying between Kootenay Lake and the Columbia River (Figure I). The western part of the area is easily accessible from the Ymir-Salmo road which runs nearly north-south along the western border of the map area. A branch line of the Great Northern Railroad follows along this road.</description><creator>McAllister, Arnold Lloyd</creator><contributor>O’Neill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The geology of the Ymir map area, British Columbia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n662g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc20x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064913p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chapman (4) observed that the levels assumed by a population of poikilothermic animals depended upon the 'resistance' that the environment presented to the 'biotic potential' (ability of organisms to survive and reproduce) of the organisms of that population. He postulated that a modification of Ohm's law for electrical resistance could be used in the calculation of the resistance that any environment presents to a species. Thus the degree to which various environments affect the biotic potential of a species could be expressed by a series of exponential factors.</description><creator>Martin, Helen Jean</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Zoology.</subject><title>Some biotic parameters of an ebony strain of tribolium confusum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk48w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064913p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sn57q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the summer of 1949 an investigation of the aerobic bacteria found in the intestines and slime of pike (Esox lucius) was commenced. The fish were obtained, by the use of gill nets, from Lake Monroe, an unpolluted lake, in the Mont Tremblant Park region of the Laurentian Mountains in Quebec. Seventeen pike were used in the study. The length and weight of each fish and the depth and temperature of the water from which the fish were taken are given in Table I.</description><creator>Margolis, Leo.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Bacteriology.</subject><title>Aerobic bacteria in the slime and intestines of some fresh water fish</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xc90j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sn57q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999994h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For single crystals of graphite the conductivity is of the order of that of a poorly conducting metal, and as in the case of a metal the temperature coefficient of conductivity is negative. The following theory of metallic conductivity was first developed by Riecke, Drude, Lorentz and others: Consider a metal containing N electrons per unit volume and suppose that each electron can move freely for a mean time 2 tau, after which it suffers a collision and its momentum is destroyed. (tau is "time of relaxation”).</description><creator>Marcus, Alma</creator><contributor>Opechowski, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Temperature dependence of the mean free path of conduction electrons in graphite</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj20z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999994h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k5745</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De tous les genres littéraires, le roman est celui qui reflète le mieux la vie et la civilisation d'un pays ou d’un peuple. Qu'il le veuille ou non, le romancier fait plus ou moins consciemment, le tableau des habitants, de l’esprit et des coutumes du milieu qui l’intéresse, mais l'authenticité de ce tableau varie selon ses connaissances, son talent et son but. Cette thèse se propose de faire le tableau de la vie des campagnes du Canada-Français d'après les romans canadiens-français parus entre 1837 (date de publication du Premier roman) et 1900.</description><creator>Mahon, Rose Kathryn</creator><contributor>Launay, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>French.</subject><title>Les moeurs et les coutumes rurales au Canada-Franc̀ais dans le roman canadien-franc̀ais depuis les origines jusqu’à 1900</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zr75x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k5745</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gw995</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Radar has found one of its most useful applications in the investigation of atmospheric phenomena. Several new problems are introduced when the structure and mechanism of rain showers are studied using radar as a research tool. These problems necessitate the modification of existing theory on rain showers. Radar echoes from showers, associated with a cold front, produce a bright line on the radar screen at a height which corresponds to the freezing level of the shower.</description><creator>Magarvey, Raymond Halliday</creator><contributor>Marshall, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Heat transfer from warm falling drops</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g338d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw995</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t2589</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Water drops, 1.5 mm in radius, were allowed to fall through three-meter lengths of three different laboratory-produced clouds. From the increase in mass of these drops it was concluded that (1) every collision with a cloud droplet led to coalescence, and (2) Langmuir's (1948) theory of collision was valid. To adapt this theory to the non-terminal velocities encountered in the experiment, equations describing the free fall of drops through air were formulated and solved. The present thesis also describes in detail methods of determining the density and droplet size distribution of the clouds. A related problem involving both accretion and heat transfer is discussed.</description><creator>Hitschfeld, Walter</creator><contributor>Marshall, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Accretion and thermal processes in the development of precipitation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161947r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t2589</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jq02q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ilford Nuclear type plates loaded with uranyl acetate were exposed to 78 Mev. protons inside the vacuum chamber of the McGill cyclotron, and tracks from the resulting uranium fissions observed under high magnification. Bathing the plates in a very weak solution of chromic acid before development materially reduced the background of alpha tracks from the spontaneous disintegration of uranium and of fog due to the proton beam. A concentration of 0.13 mgms. of CrO3 per ml. of water inhibited development of the proton and alpha tracks, but left the fission tracks quite dense. Fission tracks in these plates appeared similar to those in equivalent plates exposed to thermal neutrons from the Chalk River pile. Detailed examination of a sample section of one of the former plates showed a density of 50 fissions per cm2, whose median total range was 23 microns, agreeing with published results for slow neutron fission. A rough estimate of the fission cross-section of uranium to protons of 2.0 x 10^-24 cm was obtained, appearing to be too great by a factor of about four. The main cause of this error was believed to be due to inaccuracy in measuring the density of the proton beam.</description><creator>Maclure, Kenneth Cecil</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Proton induced fission of uranium</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074z32b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jq02q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p798p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been known for some time that D-fructose condenses with methanol in the presence of hydrogen chloride to give a syrup consisting in the main of equal amounts of methyl a-and b-D-fructofuranoside. Earlier workers have isolated a portion of the a-isomer as a pure, crystalline compound, but the b-analogue has never been separated in a pure form. In view of the configurational relationship to sucrose of the latter isomer, attempts have been made to study the chemistry of this isomer and to obtain it in pure form.</description><creator>Macfarlane, Hugh Murray</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the alcoholysis products of sucrose</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3014656.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p798p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp563</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1.0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Migration from the parental home, and a shift from parental dependence to an independent occupation is characteristic behaviour of modern youth. The main problems of this thesis are the extent to which young people leave their home community, the occupations they enter, and the influences which affect these decisions. Choice of occupation represents one of the two main decisions made by a person in his lifetime. This decision does much to determine the individual's life; the type of work he does and the remuneration he receives influences his home, his clothes, his leisure time, and in many cases, even the length of his life.</description><creator>Lucas, Rex A.</creator><contributor>Hall, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Sociology.</subject><title>Occupational orientation of high school entrants in a bi-ethnic railroad town</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236560p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp563</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12675</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>