<record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <leader>09242nam a2200421 i 4500</leader>
   <controlfield tag="001">6703928</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="005">20141007150500.0</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="008">130927s2015    cau      b    001 0 eng d</controlfield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="010">
      <subfield code="a">  2013038717</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="7" ind2=" " tag="016">
      <subfield code="a">016621826</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Uk</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">9781483333113 (alk. paper)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">1483333116 (alk. paper)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
      <subfield code="a">ocn859168706</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">YDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">YDXCP</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">BTCTA</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">BDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">UKMGB</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">OKN</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">NQB</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">CDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">HAC</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">CRH</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">OCLCF</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">AEVC</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">ACHCU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="042">
      <subfield code="a">pcc</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="050">
      <subfield code="a">HV6570</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">.C756 2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="082">
      <subfield code="a">362.76</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">HV 6570 C756 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">ACHCU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">362.76 CRO</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">AEVC</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100">
      <subfield code="a">Crosson-Tower, Cynthia,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Confronting child and adolescent sexual abuse /</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Cynthia Crosson-Tower, Professor Emerta, Fitchburg State University</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
      <subfield code="a">Los Angeles :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">SAGE Publications,</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="264">
      <subfield code="c">©2015.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">xxi, 353 pages ;</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">23 cm</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
      <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
      <subfield code="a">unmediated</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
      <subfield code="a">volume</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
      <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references (pages 313-339) and index.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">pt. I. Overview of child sexual abuse -- 1. Yesterday and today : the history of sexual exploitation and intervention as a backdrop for today's understanding -- Children and sexuality in early history -- Little girls -- Little boys -- Incest and its prohibition -- Discovery of child sexual abuse -- Freud's cover-up -- Later phase of sexual abuse exploration -- The "rediscovery" of child sexual abuse as a type of child maltreatment -- New ares for the sexual exploitation of children -- Backlash -- Conceptualizing sexual abuse today -- Society's permeable boundaries -- The issue of consent -- Understanding and intervention -- 2. The dynamics of child sexual abuse -- Child sexual abuse as trauma -- Gender as an impediment to an inclusive model -- Ethnicity and the definition of child sexual abuse -- Myths about child sexual abuse -- Incidence of child sexual abuse -- Types of child sexual abuse -- Phases of child sexual abuse -- Engagement -- Sexual interaction and secrecy -- Disclosure -- Suppression -- Risk factors associated with child sexual abuse -- 3. Theories, models, and context of child sexual abuse -- Father-daughter incest and systems theory -- Theories of victim dynamics -- Theories of nonoffending parent responsibility -- Early theories around sexual offending -- Multifactorial theories -- Single-factor theories -- Descriptive theories -- Women who sexually abuse children -- Paraphilias : children and adolescents --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">pt. II. Victims, perpetrators, and nonoffending parents -- 4. Child victims of sexual abuse : development and symptomology -- Healthy sexual development -- Age and the impact on development -- World of the sexually abused child -- Symptoms and indicators of child sexual abuse -- Effects of child sexual abuse on victims -- Trust and betrayal -- Traumatic sexualization -- Stigmatization -- Powerlessness -- Post-traumatic stress disorder -- 5. Sexual offending against children -- Development and sexual offending -- Brain development and the role of attachment -- Progression of pathology -- Characteristics associated with male sexual offenders -- Self-esteem and social competence -- Sexuality -- Fantasy and sexual offending -- Relationship -- Influence of substances on sexual offending -- Characteristics associated with female sexual offenders -- Women who abuse young children -- Women who abuse adolescents -- Women who are initially coerced by men -- Other types of women offenders -- 6. Intrafamilial abuse or incest -- Family systems theory -- Feminist theory influence -- Incidence of familial abuse -- Dynamics within sexually abusive families -- Boundary issues -- Family stress and dysfunction -- Cultural implications -- Father-daughter incest -- Father-son incest -- Mother-daughter incest -- Mother-son incest -- Sexual abuse by siblings -- Sexual abuse by extended family members -- 7. Pornography, prostitution, and the Internet -- Child pornography -- Youth, the Internet, and child abuse -- Cybersex -- Children, youth, and pornography -- Child prostitution -- Girls in prostitution -- Boys in prostitution -- Juvenile prostitutes -- Exiting prostitution -- 8. Children and adolescents who sexually abuse -- Sexual abuse by juveniles -- Differentiating juvenile abusers from adult sexual offenders -- Separating sexualized behaviors from sexual abuse in young children -- Striving to understand the juvenile sexual abuser -- Typologies -- Maltreatment histories -- Family dynamics -- Relationships, attachment issues, and social skills -- Cognitive and academic functioning -- Behavioral disorders, delinquency, and mental health issues -- Sexual knowledge and experience -- Girls who sexually abuse -- Legal and ethical issues in working with juvenile sexual abusers -- Treatment issues for juveniles -- Risk for recidivism -- Working with juvenile sexual abusers -- 9. Offenders in roles of authority : teachers, coaches, day care providers, and therapists -- The McMartin Preschool -- The Fells Acres Day Care Center -- Day care abuse scandals -- Authenticity of reports of sexual abuse in day care -- MOtivation of the day care offender -- Impact of day care abuse on children -- Therapists and other treatment staff as abusers -- 10. Sexual abuse by clergy : a unique offender -- Sexual abuse and the Catholic Church -- Studying abuse by priests --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">pt. III. Intervention -- 11. Initial intervention in child sexual abuse -- Purposeful disclosure -- Accidental disclosure -- AMBER alerts -- Mandated reported -- Influence of culture on intervention -- True and false allegations -- Reactions of participants upon disclosure -- Child victim -- Perpetrator -- Family members of the victim -- Goals and roles in intervention -- The multidisciplinary team -- The Child Protection Agency -- Criminal Justice and child sexual abuse -- Divorce and custody battles and child sexual abuse -- 12. Assessment and treatment planning for children and family members -- The child interview model -- The joint investigation model -- The parent-child interaction model -- The comprehensive assessment model -- Assessing and planning for the needs of the child -- Interviewing the child -- Assisting family members in support of the child -- Court involvement in child sexual abuse -- Types of courts -- Court process -- Attorneys involved in child sexual abuse cases -- Children going to court -- 13. Treatment for victims and families -- Treating child and adolescent victims -- Treatment issues for children -- Treatment for sexually abused children -- Adolescent treatment -- Children and adolescents in out-of-home placements -- Treatment of families -- Treatment of nonoffending parents -- Treatment for siblings of sexually abused children -- 14. Assessment and treatment for adult sexual offenders -- Assessing treatability, compliance, and risk of recidivism -- Treatment of sexual offenders against children -- Treatment methods and outcomes -- Female offenders in treatment -- Special populations of offenders -- Offender reentry -- Sex offender registration -- Recidivism of sex offenders -- 15. Treatment of adult survivors : surviving child sexual abuse -- Repression, memory, and sexual abuse -- False memory controversy -- Residual effects of child sexual abuse -- Post-traumatic stress disorder and the impairment of everyday functioning -- Self-concept, growth, and achievement -- Physical, medical, and sexual issues -- Interpersonal relationships -- Treatment for adult survivors -- Working with the survivor within his or her environment -- Confronting perpetrators and other family members -- Work with partners and children -- 16. Working with child sexual abuse -- Countertransference in work with sexual abuse -- Vicarious traumatization -- Working within an agency -- 17. Working toward prevention -- Offender-centered (or potential offender-centered) prevention -- Victim-centered (or potential victim-centered) prevention -- Situational prevention -- Community awareness and prevention.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">"Confronting Child and Adolescent Sexual Abuse is the first text to examine the history, theory, treatment, and prevention of this complex phenomenon. With in-depth insights into the psychologies of victims, their families, and the perpetrators, this comprehensive text shows readers how to recognize the symptoms and impact of childhood sexual abuse, critically engage with the unique nature of each case, complete a thorough assessment, develop a treatment plan, and effectively intervene in critical situations. A national expert on child abuse and neglect and the author of numerous books and publications, Cynthia Crosson-Tower addresses a wide range of special topics and helps readers prepare for working in this challenging professional field."--</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">From publisher's description.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
      <subfield code="a">3 23</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Child sexual abuse.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Sexually abused children</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">Rehabilitation.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">362.76 CRO</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">DEWEY</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">33862001336621</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">NORQ_MAIN</subfield>
      <subfield code="p">$63.95</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">10/10/2014</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">HV 6570 C756 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">32860001077527</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">3/22/2016</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">3/3/2016</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">BURMAN</subfield>
      <subfield code="n">3</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">10/13/2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
</record>
