<record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <leader>05724nam a2200433 i 4500</leader>
   <controlfield tag="001">6812807</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="003">FlBoTFG</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="005">20150218112339.0</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="006">m|||||o||d||||||||</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="007">cr||||</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="008">150218t20152015fluad   ob    101 0 eng d</controlfield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">9781315720913 (e-book : PDF)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
      <subfield code="a">ocn898154094</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039">
      <subfield code="a">exclude</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">FlBoTFG</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">FlBoTFG</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">AEU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="050">
      <subfield code="a">TK7801</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">.I58 2014</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">AEU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="111">
      <subfield code="a">International Conference EITI</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">(2014 :</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Shenzhen, China).</subfield>
      <subfield code="j">Issuing body.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Electronics, information technology and intellectualization :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">proceedings of the International Conference EITI 2014, Shenzhen, China, 16-17 August 2014 /</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">editors, Young Min Song, Pusan National University, Busan, Korea; Kyung Sup Kwak, Inha University, Incheon, Korea.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
      <subfield code="a">Boca Raton :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">CRC Press,</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="264">
      <subfield code="c">©2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">1 online resource.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
      <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">txt</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
      <subfield code="a">computer</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">c</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
      <subfield code="a">online resource</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">cr</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
      <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references and index.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">Approximation properties of Kantorovich type q-Szász-Mirakjan-Schurer operators -- The tracking error analysis of a weld seam tracking follower system -- A recommendation algorithm and a system research of mobile platforms -- Optimization of HF-SCF on CPU-GPU hybrid parallel computing infrastructure -- Next generation malware analysis techniques and tools -- Research and implementation of hybrid parallel computing for force field calculation -- A stable quick sort algorithm (SQSA) for fragment-continuity-sequential data -- The design and implementation of network alarm and data fusion analysis systems based on cloud computing -- The development of an intelligentized information platform for tourism landscape management using GIS and GPS technology -- The creation of an intelligent index system, taking Gongqing digital eco-city as an example -- Research on digital forensics and its relevant problems -- Synchronization of fractional-order chaotic systems using adaptive linear feedback control -- A multi-utility framework for wireless sensor network design -- Research and practice of developing English majors' competence in e-commerce -- Discussion and analysis about the integration of information technology in Community Correction work -- A kind of visualization spatial clustering algorithm -- A dynamic packet assignment algorithm based on ECC -- A novel foreign object debris classification method for runway security -- Feature selection in medical text classification based on differential evolution algorithm -- Improving autocorrelation performance of 2-dimensional coupled logistic (2DCL) sequence using phase space methods -- Wavelength dependent birefringence in dual-core hybrid photonic crystal fibre -- Remote measurement and control system of nuclear radiation environmental accident emergency -- Research on superior mobile communications based on a fibre optic repeater system in a coal mine -- A staircase modulation scheme for the MMC allowing fundamental switching frequency.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">The identification and control method of a multiple audio codec based on volume settings -- The improved delay scheduling algorithm on Hadoop -- An enhanced Kernel Fuzzy C-Means Algorithm based on bio-inspired computing methods -- Based on low-carbon environment electric industry development ideas -- Melody composing algorithm for lyrics with meta-structures for melodic pieces -- Reappearing and interacting with real scenes system designs based on CAVE -- A racing game's design with research into its impact on users' behaviour based on teleoperation -- A MIMU-based gait and pace detection system designed for human powered energy harvest devices -- The contextual expression of fresco art in the information society -- The analysis of digital design's application in textile design -- An investigation on smartphone user behaviour and dependency -- The secondary development of CMACAST management system in Shenyang City and counties -- A study on operational standardization of urban delivery vehicles -- Fuzzy clustering based on intuitionistic fuzzy similarity relations -- Designing human-computer interaction software -- Analysis and simulation of a flue gas flow model with a 90° rectangular large-diameter bend -- A new fast gas recognition algorithm based on the ion mobility spectrum -- An improved medical imaging denoising method based on independent component analysis -- Design of a relay protection algorithm based on Matlab/Simulink and FPGA -- Study on the development trend of fire detection alarm systems -- Exploration and practice for the agricultural value of unmanned helicopters -- MRI image segmentation using information granules and MRFs -- A v-support vector regression for the inversion of sound speed profiles -- Metallogenic prediction based on GIS through automatic database building and extraction of regional gravity and magnetic structure -- The research for informatization online music enterprise and its integration strategies.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="506">
      <subfield code="a">Access restricted to authorized users and institutions.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
      <subfield code="a">44</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Electronics</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Congresses.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Information technology</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Congresses.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="7" tag="655">
      <subfield code="a">Electronic books.</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">lcsh</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Song, Young Min,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Kwak, Kyung Sup,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="2" ind2=" " tag="711">
      <subfield code="a">International Conference EITI.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="856">
      <subfield code="3">University of Alberta Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://marc.crcnetbase.com/isbn/9781315720913</subfield>
      <subfield code="z">(Unlimited Concurrent Users)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949">
      <subfield code="h">UAIN</subfield>
      <subfield code="z">CRC</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">6812807-1001</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">INTERNET</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">UAINTERNET</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">E-RESOURCE</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">2/26/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">E-BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="z">CRC</subfield>
   </datafield>
</record>
