<record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <leader>08215pam a2200505 i 4500</leader>
   <controlfield tag="001">6786504</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="005">20141231121030.0</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="008">140501s2015    pau      bf   001 0 eng  </controlfield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="010">
      <subfield code="a">  2014017338</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="7" ind2=" " tag="016">
      <subfield code="a">101631746</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">DNLM</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="7" ind2=" " tag="016">
      <subfield code="a">016683838</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">Uk</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">9781451192988</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">1451192983</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
      <subfield code="a">ocn866618325</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DNLM/DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">BTCTA</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">BDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">YDXCP</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">UKMGB</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">NLM</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">VET</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">OCLCQ</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">UAB</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="042">
      <subfield code="a">pcc</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="050">
      <subfield code="a">RA645.5</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">.E44 2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="060">
      <subfield code="a">WB 39</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="060">
      <subfield code="a">WB 39</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">E54e 2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="082">
      <subfield code="a">616.02/5</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">RA 645.5 E445 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">AEU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="130">
      <subfield code="a">Emergency medicine (Antonsen)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Emergency medicine :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">the practical-changing studies /</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">[edited by] Emily L. Aaronson, MD, Arjun K. Venkatesh, MD, MBA, MHS, Erik L. Antonsen, MD, PhD ; special editors, Ron M. Walls, MD, FACEP, FRCPC, Jonathan N. Adler, MD, MS, FACEP, FAAEM.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
      <subfield code="a">Philadelphia :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">Wolters Kluwer,</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">xiii, 255 pages ;</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">23 cm</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
      <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">txt</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
      <subfield code="a">unmediated</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">n</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
      <subfield code="a">volume</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">nc</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
      <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references and index.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">Machine generated contents note: Section 1: Abdominal Authors: Kathryn Hawk, Paulina Sergot. CT in the Diagnosis of Acute Appendicitis. Proton Pump Inhibitors in Bleeding Peptic Ulcer Disease. Somatostatin in Variceal Bleeding. Diagnostic Nasogastric Tubes in Hematemesis. Spontaneous Ureteral Stone Passage. Oral Ondansetron in Gastroenteritis. Oral vs. IV Rehydration in Children. Section 2: Airway Authors: Andrew Eyre, Brock Daniels, Anita Rohra. Non-Invasive Ventilation in Pulmonary Edema. End Tidal CO2 in Sedation. RSI in ED Training. Hemoglobin Desaturation after Succinylcholine. Laryngeal View Improvement in Laryngoscopy. Section 3: Allergy Authors: Christina Wilson, Brock Daniels. Cephalosporins in Penicillin Allergic Patients. Histamine Antagonists in Acute Allergic Reactions. Section 4: Cardiology Authors: Kenneth Bernard, Stephanie Burgos, Peter Pruitt, Harman Singh Gill, Joshua Keegan. TIMI risk score for ACS. Missed ACS in the ED. Acute MI without Chest Pain. Troponins in Chest Pain. Beta Blockers in AMI: The COMMIT Trial. Aspirin in AMI: The ISIS-2 Trial. Heparinizing Unstable Angina. Low Molecular Weight Heparin in Unstable Angina. PCI vs Lytics in Acute MI: The Gusto IIb Trial. PCI Timing in ACS. tPA in Acute MI: The Gusto Trial. Delaying Defibrillation for CPR in Cardiac Arrest. Therapeutic Hypothermia in Cardiac Arrest. CPR Quality in Out of Hospital Cardiac Arrest. Chest Compression only CPR. Amiodarone in Ventricular Fibrillation. Epinephrine in Cardiac Arrest. tPA in PEA Cardiac Arrest. Vasopressin vs. Epinephrine for Cardiac Arrest. Pill in the Pocket for Atrial Fibrillation. Rhythm Control in Atrial Fibrillation: The Affirm Trial. Risk of Stroke in Atrial Fibrillation Cardioversion. Section 5: Endocrine Authors: Daphne Morrison-Ponce. ABG vs. VBG in DKA. Bicarbonate in DKA. Section 6: Infectious Disease Authors: Kito Lord, Ashley Kockankek, Jennifer Carne. Early Goal Directed Therapy in Sepsis. The PORT Score in Pneumonia. Dexamethasone in Pediatric Bacterial Meningitis. Steroids in Adult meningitis. Doxycycline in Lyme disease. Intervention to Decrease Catheter-Related Bloodstream Infection. Delayed Antibiotic Treatment for Acute Otitis Media. Centor Criteria for Strep Throat. The Febrile Infant -- 3 Stories. Bacterial Infection in Febrile Infants with RSV. Section 7: Neurology Authors: David Yamane, Michael Billington. CT before Lumbar Puncture in meningitis. Steroids and Antivirals in Bell's Palsy. Prochlorperazine in Migraine. Metoclopramide in Migraine. tPA for Acute Ischemic Stroke: The NINDS Trial. Intra-arterial tPA in Acute Ischemic Stroke: The Proact II Study. Timing of tPA in Acute Ischemic Stroke. Expanded window for tPA in Stroke: The ECASS III Study. Determining Stroke Risk after TIA. Urgent Follow up for TIA: The EXPRESS Study. The Epley Maneuver for Vertigo. Risk of Seizure Recurrence in Pediatrics. Section 8: Operations Authors: Christina Wilson, Ije Akunyili. Chest Pain Protocols in the ED. Stress Testing in the Emergency Department. Social Interventions for Alcohol Abuse. Section 9: Orthopedics Authors: Andrew Eyre. The Ottawa Knee Rules. The Ottawa Ankle Rules. Section 10: Pain Authors: Michael Billington. Morphine and the Clinical Abdominal Exam. Ketorolac vs Ibuprofen in Musculoskeletal Pain. Pain Management in the ED: The PEMI Study. Section 11: Venous Thromboembolism Authors: Fan Yang. Clinical Diagnosis of PE. The PERC Rule in PE. D-dimer in DVT and PE. VQ Scan in Acute PE: The PIOPED Trial. CT Imaging for Acute PE: The PIOPED II Trial. Section 12: Psychiatry Authors: Daphne Morrison-Ponce. Pharmaceutical Restraints for Psychotic Agitation. Section 13: Pulmonary Authors: Radhika Sundarajan, Joshua Keegan. Low Tidal Volume Ventilation in ARDS. Magnesium in Asthma. Dual bronchodilators in Asthma. Dexamethasone for Croup. Oral vs. IV Steroids in COPD. Antibiotics in COPD exacerbations. Pulse-Oximetry replaces Arterial Blood Gases. Section 14: Toxicology Authors: Sabrina Poon, Fan Yang, Spencer Greene, Silpa Gadiraju .Fomepizole in Ethylene Glycol Poisoning. Hyperbaric Oxygen in CO Poisoning. Acetaminophen Poisoning and Toxicity: The Rumack Mathew Nomogram. NAC in Acetaminophen Overdose. Hydroxocobalamin in Cyanide Poisoning. Digoxin Immune Fab in Digitalis Toxicity. Crotalidae Immune Fab in Snakebites. Section 15: Trauma Authors: Andrew Eyre, Eva Tovar, David Beversluis. Laparotomy in Abdominal Gun Shot Wounds. Permissive Hypotension in Trauma. Level One Trauma Center and Mortality. CT vs. X-Ray in Traumatic Cervical Spine Injury. The NEXUS Criteria and the Canadian C-Spine Rules. New Orleans Criteria and the Canadian Head CT Rules. ED Thoracotomies. Pediatric Head Trauma. Section 15: Ultrasound Authors: Christina Wilson, Dapnhe Morrison-Ponce. Point of Care Echo in Penetrating Cardiac Injury. Ultrasound in Central Line Placement. Ultrasound in Trauma. Ultrasound in Resuscitation Termination.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">"Ramp up your knowledge of the clinical trials and evidence that laid the groundwork for current emergency practice with Emergency Medicine: An Evidence Based Review. Brief, easy-to-read, and accessible, this time-saving quick-reference allows you to quickly familiarize yourself with the 100 most practice-changing clinical trials in emergency medicine. Features Master key information through one-page synopses of the 100 most-practicing changes clinical trials in emergency medicine. Explore landmark clinical trials in all areas of emergency medicine, including abdominal, airway, allergy, cardiology, endocrine, infectious disease, neurology, operations, orthopedics, pain, PE/DVT, psychiatry, pulmonary, toxicology, trauma, and ultrasound. Access crucial information you need to enter the world of evidence-based emergency medicine. Key findings in practical tips and commentary to improve your study Now with the print edition, enjoy the bundled interactive eBook edition, offering tablet, smartphone, or online access to: Complete content with enhanced navigation A powerful search that pulls results from content in the book, your notes, and even the Cross-linked pages, references, and more for easy Highlighting tool for easier reference of key content throughout the Ability to take and share notes with friends and Quick reference tabbing to save your favorite content for future"--Provided by publisher.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
      <subfield code="a">42</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Emergency medical services.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="2" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Clinical Trials as Topic</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Handbooks.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="2" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Evidence-Based Emergency Medicine</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Handbooks.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="2" ind2="2" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Emergencies</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Handbooks.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="2" ind2="2" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Emergency Treatment</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Handbooks.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Antonsen, Erik,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Aaronson, Emily,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Venkatesh, Arjun,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Walls, Ron M.,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Adler, Jonathan,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949">
      <subfield code="a">RA 645.5 E445 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="h">UAHL-B</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">0162035220191</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">RA 645.5 E445 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">0162035220191</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">3/1/2016</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">2/1/2016</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">UAHLTHSC</subfield>
      <subfield code="n">3</subfield>
      <subfield code="p">$150.00</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">1/21/2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
</record>
