<record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <leader>06565cam a2200445 i 45 0</leader>
   <controlfield tag="001">6805613</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="005">20150217154808.0</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="006">m     o  d        </controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="007">cr cn|||||||||</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="008">140911t20152015flua    ob    000 0 eng d</controlfield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">9781466589612</subfield>
      <subfield code="q">(e-book)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">1466589612</subfield>
      <subfield code="q">(e-book)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="z">9781466589605</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
      <subfield code="a">ocn891387126</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039">
      <subfield code="a">exclude</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">E7B</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">pn</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">E7B</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">OCLCO</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">YDXCP</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">TXM</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">CAUOI</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">CRCPR</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">OCLCQ</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">CDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">AEU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="050">
      <subfield code="a">QD37</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">.M348 2015eb</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="4" tag="082">
      <subfield code="a">540</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">AVC</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100">
      <subfield code="a">May, Paul W.,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Molecules that amaze us /</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Paul May, Simon Cotton.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
      <subfield code="a">Boca Raton, Florida :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">CRC Press,</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">2015.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="264">
      <subfield code="c">©2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">1 online resource (717 pages) :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">illustrations</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
      <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">txt</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
      <subfield code="a">computer</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">c</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
      <subfield code="a">online resource</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">cr</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
      <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">Chapter 1. Adenosine triphosphate (ATP) -- chapter 2. Adrenaline/epinephrine (noradrenaline/norepinephrine) -- chapter 3. Ammonium nitrate -- chapter 4. Artemisinin -- chapter 5. Aspirin -- chapter 6. Caffeine -- chapter 7. Capsaicin -- chapter 8. Carbon dioxide -- chapter 9. B-carotene -- chapter 10. Chlorophyll -- chapter 11. Cholesterol -- chapter 12. Cisplatin -- chapter 13. Cocaine -- chapter 14. Deet -- chapter 15. Difluorodichloroethane, CF2Cl2 : (Freon-12, CFC-12 or R-12) and related compounds -- chapter 16. DDT -- chapter 17. Digitalis -- chapter 18. Dimethylmercury -- chapter 19. Dimethylsulfide -- chapter 20. Dopamine -- chapter 21. Epibatidine -- chapter 22. Estradiol -- chapter 23. Glucose -- chapter 24. Glycerol -- chapter 25. Heavy water : deuterium oxide, D2O -- chapter 26. Heme -- chapter 27. Hexenal -- chapter 28. Hydrogen peroxide -- chapter 29. Insulin -- chapter 30. Kisspeptin -- chapter 31. Lauric acid -- chapter 32. Limonene -- chapter 33. Linoleic acid -- chapter 34. Lysergic acid diethylamide (LSD) -- chapter 35. Medroxyprogesterone acetate -- chapter 36. Methamphetamine -- chapter 37. Methane -- chapter 38. 2-Methylundecanal -- chapter 39. Monosodium glutamate -- chapter 40. Morphine, codeine and heroin -- chapter 41. Nandrolone -- chapter 42. Nicotine -- chapter 43. Nitrous oxide, N2O -- chapter 44. 1-Octen-3-ol -- chapter 45. Oxygen (and ozone) -- chapter 46. Oxytocin -- chapter 47. Paracetamol/acetaminophen -- chapter 48. Penicillins -- chapter 49. Prostanoic acid and prostaglandins -- chapter 50. Psilocybin and mescaline -- chapter 51. Quinine -- chapter 52. Sodium hypochlorite -- chapter 53. Serotonin -- chapter 54. Skatole -- chapter 55. Sucrose -- chapter 56. 'Sweaty' acid, (E)-3-Methyl-2-Hexenoic acid -- chapter 57. Taxol (paclitaxel) -- chapter 58. Testosterone -- chapter 59. Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) -- chapter 60. Tetrahydrogestrinone (THG) -- chapter 61. Tetrodotoxin -- chapter 62. Thujone -- chapter 63. Trimethylamine -- chapter 64. TNT -- chapter 65. Vancomycin -- chapter 66. VX gas -- chapter 67. Water.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="506">
      <subfield code="a">Access restricted to authorized users and institutions.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">"The world is composed of molecules. Some are synthetic while many others are products of nature. Molecules That Amaze Us presents the stories behind many of the most famous and infamous molecules that make up our modern world. Examples include the molecule responsible for the spicy heat in chilies (capsaicin), the world's first synthetic painkiller (aspirin), the pigment responsible for the color of autumn leaves (carotene), the explosive in dynamite (nitroglycerine), the antimalarial drug (quinine), the drug known as "speed" (methamphetamine), and many others. Other molecules discussed include caffeine, adrenaline, cholesterol, cocaine, digitalis, dopamine, glucose, insulin, methane, nicotine, oxytocin, penicillin, carbon dioxide, limonene, and testosterone. In all, the book includes 67 sections, each describing a different molecule, what it does, how it is made, and why it is so interesting. Written by experts in the field, the book is accessible and easy to read. It includes amusing anecdotes, historical curiosities, and entertaining facts about each molecule, thereby balancing educational content with entertainment. The book is heavily illustrated with relevant photographs, images, and cartoons--the aim being both to educate and entertain."--</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Provided by publisher.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">"In the mid 1990s, soon after the World Wide Web became a reality, several chemists decided that Molecule of the Month websites would be a good way of disseminating information about interesting molecules in an accessible way. One of these websites, based at Bristol University in the UK, was set up in 1996 by one of the authors (PWM) and administered by him ever since - making it one of the longest running chemistry websites on the web! Over the years, the other author (SAC) contributed over 50 articles for the site, and it has now become a valuable chemistry resource for schools, colleges, or the interested layperson alike. At a time when more teaching materials are produced in an electronic format, the reader may wonder why the authors have bucked the trend, essentially proceeding in the reverse direction and turning electronic articles into a hardcopy book. Well, words in print still have life in them, and some readers do prefer to have a book in their hands. It also cannot be denied that there is a feel- good factor in seeing the articles in a more permanent form. Some of these articles have appeared on the Bristol MOT M site before, but all have been updated for these pages, and many are brand-new. We hope that they appeal to a wide readership; the chemistry is meant to be intelligible to a high-school student, but the stories that lie behind the molecules can appeal to any interested person. Chemicals are morally neutral; they can be put to either good or bad uses. We have tried to be light-hearted in our approach to the subject matter, but rest assured, every fact stated here is believed by the authors to be utterly true"--</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Provided by publisher.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="588">
      <subfield code="a">Print version record.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
      <subfield code="a">52</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Chemistry</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Popular works.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Chemistry</subfield>
      <subfield code="v">Humor.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Cotton, S. A.</subfield>
      <subfield code="q">(Simon A.),</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">1946-</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="856">
      <subfield code="3">Lakeland College Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://site.ebrary.com/lib/lakelandcollege/Doc?id=10925562</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">6805613-2001</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">INTERNET</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">LAKELND_IN</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">E-RESOURCE</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">2/17/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">E-BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="z">EBRARYLL</subfield>
   </datafield>
</record>
