<record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <leader>05570cam a2200433 i 4500</leader>
   <controlfield tag="001">6742699</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="005">20141117103342.0</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="008">140807s2015    flu      b    001 0 eng  </controlfield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="010">
      <subfield code="a">  2014024201</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">9781482247060 (hardback)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">1482247062 (hardback)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
      <subfield code="a">ocn886381244</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">YDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">YDXCP</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">BDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">CRCPR</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">AEU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="042">
      <subfield code="a">pcc</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="050">
      <subfield code="a">HD31.2</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">.R68 2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="082">
      <subfield code="a">658.4/063</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="084">
      <subfield code="a">BUS042000</subfield>
      <subfield code="a">BUS053000</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">bisacsh</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">HD31.2 .R68 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">AEGMCT</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100">
      <subfield code="a">Roth, William F.,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">Out of the box thinking for successful managers /</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">William F. Roth, PhD.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
      <subfield code="a">Boca Raton, FL :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">CRC Press, Taylor &amp; Francis Group,</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">xv, 213 pages ;</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">25 cm</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
      <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
      <subfield code="a">unmediated</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
      <subfield code="a">volume</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500">
      <subfield code="a">"A Productivity Press book."</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
      <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references (pages 195-198) and index.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">1. Six sigma : or, here we go again -- 2. Downsizing : the cure that can kill -- 3. The myth that competition in the workplace is the best way to increase productivity -- 4. Is it possibly time for management by objective to bite the dust? -- 5. Get rid of performance appraisals -- 6. Doing it wrong : or, how can quality improvement efforts possibly get so screwed up? -- 7. Doing it right : or, moving beyond the Baldrige -- 8. Who makes the most productive executive? -- 9. How to design more profitable businesses -- 10. The Matter of Ethics -- 11. Replacing the Protestant work ethic with the development ethic -- 12. Training for the modern age -- 13. Is a better approach to improving safety possible? -- 14. Unions : from leadership to playing catch-up -- 15. Reinterpreting the concept of Laissez-Faire economics.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">"During the author's decades of experience consulting in the corporate world and teaching management theory at the university level, he has often questioned many modern-day management practices. For example, why do so many companies have evaluation and reward systems that force employees to compete against each other while these same organizations preach the gospel of cooperation and teamwork? Why do companies continue to downsize when this practice has proven antithetical to long-term success? Out of the Box Thinking for Successful Managers explains, in a user-friendly and sometimes humorous manner, why these practices are based on worn-out logic in some cases and complete falsehoods in others. Questioning numerous management practices that have been popular for decades, it details their weaknesses and explains why they continue to hamper attempts to improve productivity. The book reviews a range of management theories, including Six Sigma, downsizing, and management by objective. After showing where the holes lie, it offers alternative approaches that have proven effective in a growing number of private and public sector organizations, including some that enable a more positive workplace culture. Illustrating practical application with case studies, the book provides simple suggestions for change that can be highly beneficial to your organization. It addresses the major myths that managers need to examine and eventually do away with or, at least, replace with modified versions that make more sense in today's increasingly competitive business environment"--</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Provided by publisher.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">"Preface During my years spent in the corporate world, first as an employee, then as a consultant, and during the close to 20 years I have taught management theory at both the undergraduate and graduate levels, I have tripped continually over management practices that don't make much sense. For example, why do so many companies have evaluation and reward systems that force employees to compete against each other while, at the same time, these companies preach the gospel of cooperation and teamwork? Why is MBO still so popular? Why do companies continue to downsize when this practice has been proven antithetical to long-term success? Why do we continue to pay homage to the Baldrige Quality Award criteria when so many companies that have shaped their cultures around these criteria, even companies that have won the award, continue to run into serious problems afterward? Why do executives keep flocking to the next version of Frederick Taylor's scientific management as the holy grail in terms of increasing productivity when all the versions previously introduced have fallen short, and for the same reason? Why do efforts to improve the ethical climate in organizations continue to focus on "converting" the individual employee, rather than on redesigning the processes that encourage, that sometimes even force, unethical behavior? Some of these practices I have written about in books--Quality Improvement: A Systems Perspective in 1998; The Roots and Future of Management Theory: A Systems Perspective in Au: OK to change heading to Preface? AU: Please use full term for MBO"--</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Provided by publisher.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
      <subfield code="a">29</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Management.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Success in business.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Corporate culture.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Creative ability in business.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="4" ind2="2" tag="856">
      <subfield code="3">Cover image</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://images.tandf.co.uk/common/jackets/websmall/978148224/9781482247060.jpg</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949">
      <subfield code="a">HD31.2 .R68 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="h">GMCT-OS-B</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">1007428533</subfield>
      <subfield code="p">61.01</subfield>
      <subfield code="k">AVAIL_SOON</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">HD31.2 .R68 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">1007428533</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">5/29/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">1/16/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">GR_MACEWAN</subfield>
      <subfield code="n">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="p">$58.10</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">11/26/2014</subfield>
   </datafield>
</record>
