<record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <leader>07271nam a2200565 i 4500</leader>
   <controlfield tag="001">6813178</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="005">20150222143501.0</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="006">m    eo  d        </controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="007">cr cn |||m|||a</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="008">150222s2015    caua   foab   000 0 eng d</controlfield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">9781627055895</subfield>
      <subfield code="q">ebook</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="z">9781627055888</subfield>
      <subfield code="q">print</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="7" ind2=" " tag="024">
      <subfield code="a">10.2200/S00610ED1V01Y201410ENG024</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">doi</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
      <subfield code="a">ocn903883157</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039">
      <subfield code="a">exclude</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">CaBNVSL</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">CaBNVSL</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">CaBNVSL</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">AEU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="050">
      <subfield code="a">TA342</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">.P723 2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="4" tag="082">
      <subfield code="a">620.0011</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">AEU</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100">
      <subfield code="a">Prantil, Vincent Carl.,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="4" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">The captains of energy :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">systems dynamics from an energy perspective /</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Vincent C. Prantil, Timothy Decker.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
      <subfield code="a">San Rafael, California (1537 Fourth Street, San Rafael, CA  94901 USA) :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">Morgan &amp; Claypool,</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">2015.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">1 online resource (xxii, 196 pages) :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">illustrations.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
      <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
      <subfield code="a">electronic</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">isbdmedia</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
      <subfield code="a">online resource</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="490">
      <subfield code="a">Synthesis lectures on engineering,</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">1939-523X ;</subfield>
      <subfield code="v"># 24</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500">
      <subfield code="a">Part of: Synthesis digital library of engineering and computer science.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
      <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references (pages 193-194).</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">Preface -- Language of mathematics -- The language of experts -- The importance of triangulation -- The captains of energy story -- Outline of book -- Acknowledgments --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">1. If you push it, it will flow -- 1.1 The effort-flow analogy -- 1.1.1 System elements -- 1.1.2 The energy balance principle --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">2. Governing dynamics -- 2.1 Deriving a governing differential equation -- 2.2 The four casts -- 2.3 System order -- 2.4 Linearity --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">3. The electrical cast -- 3.1 Effort and flow variables -- 3.2 Storage elements -- 3.2.1 Potential energy storage character -- 3.2.2 Kinetic energy storage character -- 3.3 Dissipative elements -- 3.4 Single storage element scripts -- 3.4.1 RC circuits -- 3.4.2 RL circuits -- 3.4.3 A generalized mathematical form for the single storage element script -- 3.5 Multiple storage element scripts -- 3.5.1 Series RLC circuits -- 3.5.2 Parallel RLC circuits -- 3.5.3 Idealized LC circuits -- 3.5.4 A generalized mathematical form for the dual storage element script -- 3.6 Chapter activities --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">4. The mechanical cast -- 4.1 Effort and flow variables -- 4.2 Storage elements -- 4.2.1 Potential energy storage character -- 4.2.2 Kinetic energy storage character -- 4.3 Dissipative elements -- 4.4 Single storage element scripts -- 4.4.1 Spring-damper systems -- 4.4.2 Mass-damper systems -- 4.4.3 A generalized mathematical form for the single storage element script -- 4.5 Multiple storage element scripts -- 4.5.1 The classical mass-spring-damper system -- 4.5.2 Idealized mass-spring systems -- 4.5.3 A generalized mathematical form for the dual storage element script -- 4.6 Rotational mechanical systems -- 4.6.1 Effort and flow variables -- 4.6.2 Storage elements -- 4.6.3 Dissipative elements -- 4.6.4 The simple pendulum -- 4.7 Chapter activities --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">5. A common notion -- 5.1 Time domain solutions of 1st order systems -- 5.1.1 Transient response -- 5.1.2 Forced response -- 5.1.3 Dimensionless solutions for 1st order systems -- 5.1.4 Universal truths for 1st order system response in the time domain -- 5.2 Time domain solutions of 2nd order systems -- 5.2.1 Free response -- 5.2.2 Forced response -- 5.2.3 Dimensionless solutions for 2nd order systems -- 5.2.4 Characteristic times for transients in 2nd order systems -- 5.2.5 Universal truths for 2nd order system response in the time domain -- 5.2.6 Energy storage and dissipation for 2nd order system response in the time domain -- 5.3 Chapter activities --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">6. Going nowhere? -- 6.1 Frequency domain solutions of 1st order systems -- 6.1.1 Transfer function analysis for harmonic input -- 6.1.2 Steady-state response and Bode plot analysis -- 6.1.3 An interpretation of dimensionless frequency ratio -- 6.1.4 Filtering characteristics of 1st order systems -- 6.1.5 Universal truths for 1st order systems subject to harmonic input -- 6.1.6 Energy storage and dissipation in 1st order systems subject to harmonic input excitation -- 6.2 Frequency domain solutions of 2nd order systems -- 6.2.1 Transfer function analysis for harmonic input -- 6.2.2 Steady-state response and bode plot analysis -- 6.2.3 Universal truths for 2nd order systems subject to harmonic input -- 6.3 Redesigning systems for steady-state behaviors -- 6.4 Energy storage and dissipation in 2nd order systems subject to harmonic input excitation -- 6.5 Chapter activities --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">7. The fluid and thermal casts -- 7.1 Fluid systems -- 7.1.1 Fluid effort and flow variables -- 7.1.2 Storage elements -- 7.1.3 Dissipative elements -- 7.1.4 Single storage element scripts -- 7.1.5 Multiple storage element scripts -- 7.2 Thermal systems -- 7.2.1 Thermal effort and flow variables -- 7.2.2 Storage elements -- 7.2.3 Dissipative elements -- 7.2.4 Single storage element scripts -- 7.3 Chapter activities --</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">8. Summary -- Afterword -- Bibliography -- Authors' biographies.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="506">
      <subfield code="a">Access restricted to authorized users and institutions.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="3" ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">In teaching an introduction to transport or systems dynamics modeling at the undergraduate level, it is possible to lose pedagogical traction in a sea of abstract mathematics. What the mathematical modeling of time-dependent system behavior offers is a venue in which students can be taught that physical analogies exist between what they likely perceive as distinct areas of study in the physical sciences. We introduce a storyline whose characters are superheroes that store and dissipate energy in dynamic systems. Introducing students to the overarching conservation laws helps develop the analogy that ties the different disciplines together under a common umbrella of system energy. In this book, we use the superhero cast to present the effort-flow analogy and its relationship to the conservation principles of mass, momentum, energy, and electrical charge. We use a superhero movie script common to mechanical, electrical, fluid, and thermal engineering systems to illustrate how to apply the analogy to arrive at governing differential equations describing the systems' behavior in time. Ultimately, we show how only two types of differential equation, and therefore, two types of system response are possible. This novel approach of storytelling and a movie script is used to help make the mathematics of lumped system modeling more approachable for students.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="588">
      <subfield code="a">Title from PDF title page (viewed on February 22, 2015).</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
      <subfield code="a">44</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Mathematical models.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Dynamics</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">Mathematical models.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
      <subfield code="a">Decker, Timothy.,</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="830">
      <subfield code="a">Synthesis digital library of engineering and computer science.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="830">
      <subfield code="a">Synthesis lectures on engineering ;</subfield>
      <subfield code="v"># 24.</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">1939-523X</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="856">
      <subfield code="3">University of Alberta Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">http://dx.doi.org/10.2200/S00610ED1V01Y201410ENG024</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949">
      <subfield code="h">UAIN</subfield>
      <subfield code="z">SYNTHDIG</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">6813178-1001</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">INTERNET</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">UAINTERNET</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">E-RESOURCE</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">3/2/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">E-BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="z">SYNTHDIG</subfield>
   </datafield>
</record>
