<record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <leader>06240cam a2200421 i 45 0</leader>
   <controlfield tag="001">6849500</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="005">20150306120937.0</controlfield>
   <controlfield tag="008">150105s2015    nju           001 0 eng  </controlfield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="010">
      <subfield code="a">  2014038168</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">9781118997420 (hardback)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
      <subfield code="a">1118997425 (hardback)</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
      <subfield code="a">ocn889736174</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
      <subfield code="a">DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">DLC</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">BTCTA</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">BDX</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">AFMK</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="042">
      <subfield code="a">pcc</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="050">
      <subfield code="a">HF5382.6</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">.M37 2015</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="082">
      <subfield code="a">650.1082</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="084">
      <subfield code="a">BUS000000</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">bisacsh</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
      <subfield code="a">HF 5382.6 M37 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">AFMK</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100">
      <subfield code="a">Marcus, Bonnie R.,</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">1948-</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="1" ind2="4" tag="245">
      <subfield code="a">The politics of promotion :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">how high-achieving women get ahead and stay ahead /</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Bonnie R. Marcus.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
      <subfield code="a">Hoboken, New Jersey :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">Jossey-Bass,</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">2015.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
      <subfield code="a">xiv, 239 pages :</subfield>
      <subfield code="b">illustrations ;</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">23 cm</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
      <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
      <subfield code="a">unmediated</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
      <subfield code="a">volume</subfield>
      <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500">
      <subfield code="a">Includes index.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
      <subfield code="a">Machine generated contents note: Introduction Chapter 1: Politics in the Workplace. How it works and how women fit into it. Derailed in New York City What is Political Savvy? The Importance of Political Will Stage 1: Naïve Nancy Stage 2: Great Work Greta Stage 3: Strategic Sarah Stage 4: Political Pam Your Political Skill In This Chapter, We Have Learned: The Political Toolkit: Your Secret Weapon to Compete in a Political Environment Here Are the Tools You Need in Your Political Toolkit Chapter 2: The Mirror: Your Tool for Savvy Self-Promotion The Reality of the Workplace Our Upbringing Our Failure to See Self-Promotion as a Leadership Skill Our Fear of Potential Backlash: the Double Bind Lack of Understanding Our Contribution to Business Outcomes: Our Value Proposition Your Unique Value Proposition Connecting the Dots: Going from Me to We Demonstrate Your Value Proposition In This Chapter, We Have Learned: Chapter 3: The Magnifying Glass: Observing Workplace Dynamics The Power The Rules The Culture Virtual Culture Summary In This Chapter, We Have Learned: Chapter 4: The Pass Go and Collect $200 Card: Strategic Networking Women and Networking Finding the Right People: Who Do You Know and Who Do You Need to Know? Building a Power Network That Supports Your Career Goal Your Power Network Your Networking Mindset Find Commonality Find out What They Want and Need Filling Your Favor Bank How and When to Network Your External Network Online Networking Building Relationships Across Cultures Summary In This Chapter We've Learned: Chapter 5: The Get Out of Jail Free Card: Sponsorship Mentors versus Sponsors The Importance of Sponsorship for Women The Benefits of Having a Sponsor Women and Sponsorship How to Find a Sponsor Company Sponsorship Program Independent Sponsorship Make Yourself Sponsor Ready Framing the Relationship Summary In This Chapter, We've Learned: Chapter 6: The GPS: Executive Coaching What is coaching? Different Types of Executive Coaching The Importance of a Career Gps for Women How the GPS Works with the Other Tools in the Political Toolkit How Coaching Helps What to Look for in a Coach Find the Right Coach Frame the Relationship Return on Investment Summary In This Chapter, We've Learned: Chapter 7: Staying Ahead The Danger of Being an Outsider How to Use the Political Toolkit to Stay Ahead Coaching Helps You Cope with the Pressure of Your New Position Coaching Helps You Overcome Your Superwoman Complex Summary In This Chapter, We've Learned: Chapter 8: Moving Forward: Are you ready? Now What? Where Do You Go from Here? Where do you feel the most resistance? Staying the Course Acknowledgments About the Author Index .</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
      <subfield code="a">"Break into the power circle and build relationships that advance careersThe Politics of Promotion offers women the tools and guidance they need to successfully navigate the realities of their organization, emphasizing the need to understand office politics to get the promotions and recognition they deserve. Written by Bonnie Marcus, a professional coach who focuses on helping women advance their careers, this book demonstrates the impact of relationships and sponsorship on career trajectory. Readers will learn why excellence and achievement aren't propulsion enough to get ahead, and how networking with power and intention can make all the difference in perception, reputation, and promotion. Far beyond the typical advice of "be assertive" and "embrace ambition," this book provides a unique and proven method for becoming a bigger player in the workplace and avoiding unexpected trip-ups that can add years to the climb--or end it for good.Many women focus on performance, thinking that good work garners promotion. Too often, they're left outside of the circles of power and influence where decisions are made that affect their careers. The Politics of Promotion provides a framework for breaking into that circle, and taking control of one's own career path, specifically showing how to: Navigate office politics successfully Build and nurture key relationships Get comfortable with self-promotion Avoid potentially disastrous "blindsides" Women who want to advance cannot afford to view politics as "dirty." It's the reality of the workplace, one that differs between organizations and fluctuates over time. Although being savvy about office politics is important for both genders, unconscious bias and stereotypes create special challenges for women. Learning to navigate these complex rules and customs is the key to professional recognition for women, fostering relationships that reach far beyond the next evaluation. Women looking to get ahead will find that the insights in The Politics of Promotion can help smooth the way"--</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">Provided by publisher.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Women</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">Vocational guidance.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Office politics.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Women</subfield>
      <subfield code="x">Promotions.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Career development.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Interpersonal relations.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
      <subfield code="a">Business networks.</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1="0" ind2="8" tag="776">
      <subfield code="i">Online version:</subfield>
      <subfield code="a">Marcus, Bonnie R., 1948-</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">Politics of promotion</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">Hoboken, New Jersey : Jossey-Bass, 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="z">9781118997123</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">(DLC) 2015003510</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
      <subfield code="a">8</subfield>
   </datafield>
   <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
      <subfield code="a">HF 5382.6 M37 2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
      <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="i">34917001374839</subfield>
      <subfield code="d">5/22/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="e">5/20/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield>
      <subfield code="m">KEYANO</subfield>
      <subfield code="n">1</subfield>
      <subfield code="p">$26.04</subfield>
      <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
      <subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield>
      <subfield code="u">3/6/2015</subfield>
      <subfield code="o">.STAFF. Rec'd Apr/15 MW</subfield>
   </datafield>
</record>
