<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Alberta Research Council</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-a91e9dbba212ef2b7a143d13402f98d4">
        <p>In October, 1919 a committee was convened by the Provincial  Secretary to advise on matters relating to industrial research.  A preliminary survey of resources was conducted, with encouraging  results, and in 1921 the Scientific and Industrial Research  Council of Alberta was formally established by Order-in-Council.  Research was to be conducted in cooperation with the University  for laboratory and other facilities.  The President of the University was a member of the Council; the Provincial Secretary  and the Premiers of the Province have acted as Chair.  In 1930, under new legislation, the Council was reorganized to be  an advisory body to the Cabinet.  A Cabinet Minister was Chair of  the Council; the President of the University was Chair of the  Technical Advisory Committee and Director of Research.  At this  time the Council's name was shortened to the "Research Council of  Alberta"; it is now known as the Alberta Research Council.  With the onset of the Great Depression the work of the Council  halted.  The University took over its funding, work, and staff in  1933; the Council itself did not meet from 1934 to 1942.  In 1943,  the Research Council Act was amended to include ten members, of  which two were from the cabinet (one to act as chair); the President of the University; the Director of Research, and members  at large. Until 1950 the President of the University was Director  of Research.  Dr. N.H. Grace was appointed the Councilþs first  full-time Director in October, 1951.  The Council was the first provincially funded, scientific research agency in Canada.  It undertakes, promotes, and funds research  which might not otherwise be undertaken. Chairs: 1919-1923 J. L. Cote; 1923-1925 Herbert Greenfield; 1925-  1926 Alex Ross; 1926-[1930] J.E. Brownlee; 1930-[1950] Cabinet  Ministers assigned to Chair; [1946-1947] Nathan Eldon Tanner;  1950-1951 Robert Newton; 1951-1961 Nathaniel H. Grace; 1961  William Albert Lang (Acting); 1962-1977 Ernest J. Wiggins; 1977-  1978 Brian Hitchin (Acting); 1978-1983 Giles Cloutier; 1984- 1987 Robert W. Stewart; 1987-  Clem W. Bowman;</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/alberta-research-council-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Alberta Research Council fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/alberta-research-council-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Alberta Research Council fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1919-1983</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
