<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Alberta Heritage Foundation for Medical Research</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-9aaa3ed9179bd2f73f0ec7e791135586">
        <p>The Alberta Heritage Foundation for Medical Research (AHFMR) was established by the Government of Alberta in 1980 to support biomedical and health research at Alberta universities, affiliated institutions, and other medical and technology-related institutions. Operating funds come from a portion of the interest revenue from a Government endowment, with an initial investment of $300 million. AHFMR supports more than 200 senior researchers recruited from Alberta and around the world, and approximately 350 researchers-in-training. Since 1980, AHFMR has supported more than 8500 positions, providing unprecedented opportunities for research careers. AHFMR is governed by a Board of Trustees with representatives from the universities, the medical profession and the general public. AHFMR is headed by a President who is the CEO. The Board of Trustees are advised by an international Scientific Advisory Council and other groups, including committees of researchers who assess applications for awards. AHFMR reports to the people of Alberta through the Minister of Innovation and Science but is arms-length from government. Every six years an International Board of Review assesses AHFMR Programs and submits a report to AHFMR and the Government of Alberta.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/alberta-heritage-foundation-for-medical-research-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Alberta Heritage Foundation for Medical Research fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/alberta-heritage-foundation-for-medical-research-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Alberta Heritage Foundation for Medical Research fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1976-1982</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
