<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Canadian Association for Research in Home Economics</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-e8a568964b09b64783551cb602a8e52f">
        <p>In 1959, the Canadian University Teachers of Home Economics/ Professeurs d'Economie Familiale des Universités Canadienne (CUTHE/PEFUC) was organized at a Learned Societies meeting in Saskatoon. It was founded for the purpose of bringing together Home Economics Faculty Members to hear and discuss scholarly papers and to study matters of common concern. In 1977 CUTHE affiliated with the Social Science Federation of Canada in order to become more active in the academic community and in 1982 was formally linked with the Canadian Home Economics Association. In 1985, in attempt to broaden its mandate CUTHE changed its name to the Canadian Association for Research in Home Economics/ Association Canadienne pour la Recherche in Economie Familiale  (CARHE/ ACREF) and allowed graduate student members. CARHE holds an annual conference affiliated with the Learned Societies, publishes conference proceedings, publishes a newsletter twice yearly, and funds graduate research in home economics. In 1990, CARHE had 127 members.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/canadian-association-for-research-in-home-economics-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Canadian Association for Research in Home Economics fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/canadian-association-for-research-in-home-economics-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Canadian Association for Research in Home Economics fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1988-1995</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
