<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Canadian Circumpolar Institute</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-5f3fed65fd1d05e363b112d210bad2ef">
        <p>Established as the Boreal Institute for Northern Studies, this research group has as its prime  objective the gathering and dissemination of information about the North in an effort to increase  understanding and awareness of that part of Canada.  To achieve this goal, the Institute has adopted  a fourfold mandate:  to promote scholarly research on the North; to foster communication among  northern-oriented researchers at the University of Alberta and beyond; to disseminate knowledge  about the North; and to encourage the involvement of Northerners in the activities of the Institute. Long-term and comprehensive research programs as well as grant-funded and contract projects are  also operated under the aegis of the Institute.  The Institute maintains active liaison with all faculties  offering courses in northern studies, especially the Department of Geography. The Institute established a multi-disciplinary library of information on polar and cold regions.  The collection  continues as the Canadian Circumpolar Library, under the administration of the University Libraries  (Calendar, 1990/91).  The name of the Boreal Institute was changed to the Canadian Circumpolar Institute/Institut circumpolaire canadien in 1990. Directors: 1960-1968 Advisory Board Directorate; 1968-1972 J. Jameson Bond; 1972-1973 Robbie  S. Jamieson (Acting); 1973-1976 Don Gill; 1974-1975 Robbie S. Jamieson (Acting); 1976-            1984  Robbie S. Jamieson; 1984-1987 Ahmad Sami Abdel Mohsen (Acting); 1987-[1990] Ross W. Wein;  [1990]-  Clifford G. Hickey.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/canadian-circumpolar-institute-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Canadian Circumpolar Institute fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/canadian-circumpolar-institute-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Canadian Circumpolar Institute fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1959-1989</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
