<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Flaherty, Kathleen</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-28b9cdbda2a397288b3fbf09ddf1ce7a">
        <p>Dramaturge, Radio Producer, ca. 1957- Kathleen Flaherty received her M.A. from the University of Calgary in 1982. She moved to Toronto in 1984 and began working as a dramaturge and director, working at Factory Theatre, Theatre Passe Muraille and other smaller alternative theatres. In 1988, she directed the Canadian premiere of John Mighton's Scientific Americans at Theatre Passe Muraille and was winner of a Dora Minor Moore award for that season. She was also a frequent dramaturge at Edmonton's Playwright's Workshop, spent a year at Theatre New Brunswick, and was a script consultant for CBC radio drama. In 1991, she became radio drama producer at CBC Edmonton, producing a number of broadcasts of plays by Edmonton writers. She also directed or dramaturged several Edmonton Fringe Plays and served as occasional dramaturge at Catalyst Theatre and Workshop West. In 1993, she directed the premiere of Carol Shield's &lt;i&gt;Thirteen Hands&lt;/i&gt; at Winnipeg's Prairie Theatre Exchange. Ms. Flaherty has also published several articles on dramaturgy in Canadian Theatre Review. In September 1997, she was transferred to CBC Vancouver as drama and features producer.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/kathleen-flaherty-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Kathleen Flaherty fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/kathleen-flaherty-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Kathleen Flaherty fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1988-1997</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
