<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Ford, Lee Ellen</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-497634dd6dd1a31c63906c8dfa46aede">
        <p>Lee (Leola) Ellen Ford was born in Auburn, Indiana in 1917. She received her B.A. (1947) from Wittenberg University; an M.S. (1949) from the University of Minnesota; a Ph.D. in Cytogenetics and Botany (1952) from Iowa State University and a J.D. (1972) from the University of Notre Dame. Upon graduation from high school, Ms. Ford was employed in business work and accounting for various corporations (1934-1944) before attending Wittenberg University. Dr. Ford was Associate Professor of Biology (1950-1951) at Gustavus Adolphus College and Anderson College (1952-1955); visiting Professor of Biology (1955-1956) at the University of Alberta; Associate Professor of Biology (1956-1962) at Pacific Lutheran University; and Professor of Biology and Cytogenetics (1962-1964) at Mississippi State College for Women. She was also a faculty member (1965 -1968, 1970) at Carson College (Nevada) and Dominican College (N.Y.). In addition, Dr. Ford was the chief cytogeneticist (1964-1965) for the Pacific Northwest Research Foundation and held the position of economist (1966-1968) for the Manpower Program in Nevada. In 1969, she accepted the job of Director of Research at the Institute of Basic Research in Mental Retardation in Staten Island, N.Y.  Dr. Ford was also the Director of the Canine Genetics Consultation Service (1963-1969); founder of the Companion Collie for Adult and Jr. Blind (1955-1965); and Director of the Genetics Research Laboratory (1955-1975). After receiving her law degree and being admitted to the Indiana Bar in 1972, Dr. Ford was appointed as Executive Assistant to Otis Bowen, Governor of Indiana. She was responsible for minority rights issues particularly in regards for women and the handicapped and was a participant on numerous committees. Dr. Ford was also owner, editor, and publisher (1972-1976) of the Dekalb Record-Herald and president of Ford Association Publishers (1972-1987). She resides in Butler, Indiana.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/lee-ellen-ford-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Lee Ellen Ford fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/lee-ellen-ford-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Lee Ellen Ford fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1990-1992</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
