<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Hole, Lois</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-1eb1dd26ec72ea248aec443b35562eee">
        <p>Businesswoman, Author, University Chancellor, Alberta Governor General, 1933-.  Lois Hole was born in Buchanan, Saskatchewan, and moved to Edmonton while in her teens. Along with her husband Ted, Mrs. Hole started and ran Hole's Greenhouse, a successful gardening operation in St. Albert, just outside of Edmonton. She has become one of Canada's best known gardening personalities and opinion makers. Mrs. Hole has written eight best-selling, award-winning gardening books and published five issues of her annual Spring Gardening magazine; she also wrote regular columns for the Edmonton Sun, the Edmonton Journal, and the Globe &amp; Mail.  During the late 1990s, Lois made monthly appearances on CBC-TV's Canadian Gardener. In addition to her work in gardening, Mrs. Hole has been a longtime supporter of the University of Alberta, and Mrs. Hole's efforts were recognized in 1992 when she was awarded an honourary degree from the U. of A.  In 1997, Mrs. Hole was named the 16th Chancellor of the University of Alberta and in 1999 was named the Governor General of Alberta.  In addition to her official duties, Mrs. Hole continues to write gardening books, publishing four books in 2000.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/lois-hole-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Lois Hole fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/lois-hole-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Lois Hole fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1965-2000, predominant 1988- 2000</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
