<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Rempel, Sharon</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-9f8b952c5db099019d1527d0ac9275a9">
        <p>Agronomist, agricultural historian. After receiving a B.Sc. from the University of Alberta, Sharon Rempel received her M.A. in Conservation Studies, 'Historic Gardens and Landscapes' option from the Department of Archaeology, Institute of Advanced Architectural Studies at the University of York, England. She also attended a 10-day course in Heritage Gardens from the University of Victoria, in Victoria, British Columbia. Since 1989, Ms. Rempel has operated Sharon Rempel and Associates, a consulting firm that offers heritage garden research and restoration services. Ms. Rempel's clients have included Craigflower Farm, Hudson Bay site, Victoria (1850s); the Grist Mill at Keremeos, B.C. (1880s); Fort Steele Heritage Town, Cranbrook, B.C. (1890s); Ukrainian Cultural Heritage Village, Edmonton Alta. (1900s); Mennonite Heritage Village, Steinbach Manitoba (1900s); Highlands Historical Society, Edmonton, Alta. (1908);  and Parks Canada, Jasper, Alberta (1920s). Ms. Rempel has also done biodiversity conservation consultation work with: The Garden Institute of Alberta; Seeds of Diversity Canada (SoDC); Canadian University Service Overseas (CUSO) in Laos, PDR; United Nations work for Canada in Rome; and The Greek Gene Bank</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/sharon-rempel-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Sharon Rempel fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/sharon-rempel-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Sharon Rempel fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1994-1996</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
