<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Thomas, Lewis Herbert</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-7b0716fbb839fd4e2f875c88a8bbdfca">
        <p>Lewis H. Thomas was born April 13, 1917 in Saskatoon, Saskatchewan.  A graduate of the University of Saskatchewan with high honours in history and economics, Dr. Thomas obtained his PhD from the University of Minnesota.  His thesis, The Struggle for Responsible Government in the North-West Territories, was first published by the University of Toronto Press in 1956 and confirmed his reputation as a leading figure in the developing field of Western Canadian history. Dr. Thomas was Provincial Archivist of Saskatchewan from 1948 to 1957. He joined the University of Alberta in 1964, and assumed the Chairmanship of the Department o of History the following year.  He presided over a period of rapid growth in the department until illness forced him to give up his administrative duties in 1968.  Dr. Thomas continued to write and teach at the University, and was Chairman of the Archives and Documents Committee from 1964 to 1976.  Following his retirement in 1982 from the University of Alberta, Dr. Thomas returned to Regina to live.  He was awarded the Order of Canada in October 1982, and passed away there in November 1983.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/lewis-herbert-thomas-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Lewis Herbert Thomas fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/lewis-herbert-thomas-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Lewis Herbert Thomas fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1913-1984 (predominant 1964-1979)</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
