<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Universities Coordinating Council</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-3db7b30133acdfbc97135ae027bb629b">
        <p>The Universities Coordinating Council was created with the  Universities Act of 1966.  It consists of representatives from  each Alberta university:  the President and Vice-President (Academic), two Deans, two academic staff members appointed by the  General Faculties Council, and three academic staff members appointed by the Coordinating Council. The Council can inquire, investigate, recommend and advise on any matter that affects all  the members; it can set the terms of affiliation with colleges and  entrance requirements from colleges to the universities.  The Council also has authority over the administration of professional examinations. The University Act, as revised in 1910, provided the University of Alberta with the power to arrange with the incorporated professional associations or societies in the province which had the legislated right to prescribe examinations for candidates  applying for registration in such societies, to administer and  conduct the examinations, appoint examiners, and report results  to the societies.  Any incorporated professional society could  apply for such arrangements, or administer its own examinations  and accreditation procedures. Between 1942 and 1955 the responsibility for overseeing the  examinations was held by the General Faculties Council at the  University; between 1955 and1966 GFC delegated this authority to the Board of Examiners of each profession.  The substantial reorganization of higher education under the Universities Act of 1966 created the Universities Coordinating Council, which received jurisdiction over the conditions of entrance to cooperating  learned professions and callings.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/universities-coordinating-council-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Universities Coordinating Council fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/universities-coordinating-council-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Universities Coordinating Council fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p>1912-1989</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
