<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eac-cpf xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-33-4" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <control>
    <maintenanceAgency>
      <agencyName>University of Alberta Archives</agencyName>
    </maintenanceAgency>
    <conventionDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>conventionDeclaration</abbreviation>
    </conventionDeclaration>
    <localTypeDeclaration>
      <abbreviation>detailLevel</abbreviation>
      <citation>http://ica-atom.org/doc/RS-2#5.4</citation>
    </localTypeDeclaration>
  </control>
  <cpfDescription>
    <identity>
      <nameEntry>
        <part>Wheeler, Anne</part>
        <authorizedForm>conventionDeclaration</authorizedForm>
      </nameEntry>
    </identity>
    <description>
      <biogHist id="md5-baf0c217464a48fe5e88df4b09c9d407">
        <p>Writer, Director, Filmmaker. 1946-.  Anne Wheeler was born in Edmonton, Alberta, in 1946. Upon completing high school, Ms. Wheeler entered the University of Alberta, graduating with a B.Sc. in Mathematics in 1967. During her twenties, Ms. Wheeler was employed at a variety of careers including computer programming, teaching high school and acting. In 1971, Ms. Wheeler joined a collective of nine individuals determined to document in film the trials and tribulations of life in Western Canada. The collective, entitled Film West, and with no previous filmmaking experience, was within a year winning awards from major film festivals for their documentaries. In 1976, Ms. Wheeler left the collective and continued her career in film as a freelancer, primarily by writing and directing documentaries and short films for the National Film Board of Canada.  In 1981, she wrote and directed her first feature film, A War Story (1981), starring Donald Sutherland and based on her father's experiences as a doctor in a Japanese Prisoner of War camp. Ms. Wheeler has gone on to produce numerous other feature films including Bye Bye Blues (1990), Better Than Chocolate (1999), Loyalties (1984) and Angel Square (1989). Ms. Wheeler has also directed several vehicles for television including a Movie of the Week adaptation of Margaret Laurence's The Diviners (1990) which received a Genie Award for best M.O.W. in 1990. Ms. Wheeler has also directed episodes of Canadian television dramas such as Davinci's Inquest and Cold Squad. Ms. Wheeler's works have received acclaim and won awards in Canada, the United States, and Europe, and she has been the recipient of six honorary doctorates including her alma mater, the University of Alberta in 1990. Ms. Wheeler was also elected an Officer of the Order of Canada in 1994.</p>
      </biogHist>
    </description>
    <relations>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="subjectOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/anne-wheeler-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Anne Wheeler fonds</relationEntry>
      </resourceRelation>
      <resourceRelation resourceRelationType="creatorOf" xlink:href="https://edit.albertaonrecord.ca/anne-wheeler-fonds" xlink:type="simple">
        <relationEntry>Anne Wheeler fonds</relationEntry>
        <descriptiveNote>
          <p> 1975 - 1990</p>
        </descriptiveNote>
      </resourceRelation>
    </relations>
  </cpfDescription>
</eac-cpf>
